{"id": 254, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "pT2 - pT4 tumors including inflammatory breast cancer", "note_date": "2022-08-30", "note": "A 59-year-old female patient presented to our outpatient clinic with a palpable mass in her left breast. The patient had no family history of neither breast cancer, endometrial nor ovarian cancer and no comorbidities except for hypertension which was controlled. On examination the mass was suspicious and hard inconsistency; a mammogram was done, and it revealed a BIRADS (4) breast mass 13.5 \u00d7 8.5 mm at 3 o\u2019clock position.\r\nFine needle aspiration cytology (FNAC) was done and it showed moderately differentiated invasive ductal carcinoma. Metastatic workup was requested including Chest X-rays, computed tomography (CT) scans and positron emission tomography (PET) scans, and were all free. Preoperative laboratory works up were all within normal ranges; CA.15.3 was 16 U/ml, creatinine: 1.1 mg/dl and HB; 10 mg/dl.\r\nPreoperative laboratory examination was all within normal ranges; CA.15.3 was 16 U/ml, creatinine: 1.1 mg/dl and HB; 10 mg/dl. The patient went for conservative breast surgery in the form of wide local excision with intraoperative frozen section examination which confirms the malignant nature of the mass and ensures that there was no invasion at the surgical margins, so we proceed also to Levels 1 and 2 axillary lymph nodal clearance. The mass was excised, and the patient was discharged on the next day with no postoperative complications.\r\nHistopathological paraffin examination confirmed that it was invasive ductal carcinoma (IDC) grad 2, T1, with no intraductal component, free surgical margins and no axillary lymph nodal metastasis LN: 0/15. There were neither tumor emboli nor tumor necrosis and the mitotic index was low. Immunohistochemistry showed that the mass is positive for Estrogen (Score8/8), positive for Progesterone (score8/8) and negative for HER2 protein overexpression (Score0/8).\r\nShe was scheduled to take 30 sessions of radiotherapy and then to be on hormonal therapy in the form of Tamoxifen 20 mg/day for 5 years. During the last post-operative follow-up\u20143 months later\u2014the patient complains of right hypochondrial pain; furthermore, the patient was scheduled for a multi-slice Triphasic Pelvi-abdominal CT which demonstrated the presence of a highly vascular renal mass with enhancement in the arterial phase and fading out in the later phases of examination suggestive for malignancy with patent inferior vena cava (IVC) and renal vein. There was no peri-renal or abdominal lymphadenopathy.\r\nConsequently, the patient was scheduled for Rt radical nephrectomy which was done through Rt transverse paramedian incision. The postoperative course went smoothly except for the wound infection which was managed conservatively. Histopathological examination showed that it was clear cell renal carcinoma, grade 2, T3a, free renal vein and lymph nodes were also free from any metastatic deposits (Score0/8).\r\nThe patient was followed with PET-CT after 1 year and then a mammogram every year and pelvi-abdominal U/S every 6 months and there was not any evidence of regional recurrence or distant metastasis at 5 years follow-up.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with breast cancer?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["invasive ductal carcinoma"]}, {"question": "If so, list all the breast tumor stages that this patient has been diagnosed with over the time period covered by this note, and, for each cancer stage, indicate the date of staging diagnosis. Separate the stage and the date by semicolon. If the tumor stage or the date are not presented in the note, return NA in the output.", "answer": "T1 | NA", "justification": ["invasive ductal carcinoma (IDC) grad 2, T1"]}]}
{"id": 268, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "Active collagen vascular disease, specifically dermatomyositis with a CPK level above normal or with an active skin rash, systemic lupus erythematosis, or scleroderma.", "note_date": "2023-03-22", "note": "A previously healthy 12-year-old boy was admitted to Driscoll Children\u2019s Hospital in Corpus Christi, TX, USA, with a 9 day history of fever, and 7 day history of pain and weakness in the lower extremities. Three days prior to admission, he was seen by a nurse practitioner and diagnosed with otitis media and pharyngitis. He received intramuscular penicillin and was prescribed cefixime for 3 days without improvement. He progressed and he became unable to walk without assistance. He had no gastrointestinal, respiratory or genitourinary complaints. On admission, his temperature was 36.8\u00b0C and the physical examination was significant for antalgic, broad-based gait and tender gastrocnemius \u2013 soleus muscles. Biceps, quadriceps and psoas muscle strength was graded at 3/5. Sensation and deep tendon reflexes were normal with absent Romberg\u2019s and Babinski\u2019s sign. The white blood cell count was 8300 cells per cubic mm with 60% neutrophils and 40% lymphocytes, hemoglobin was 13.5 g/dL, and the platelet count was 172,000 cells per cubic mm. His CRP was 1.5 mg/dL. The ESR and urine analysis were normal. Creatinine phosphokinase (CPK) was elevated at 2394 \u03bc/L, aspartate aminotransferase (AST) was 222 \u03bc/L and, alanine aminotransferase (ALT) was 143 \u03bc/L.\r\nA diagnosis of myositis was made and the patient was given analgesics and oral prednisone as dermatomyositis and polymyositis were amongst the differential diagnosis. Rhabdomyolysis was considered in the differential diagnosis and the patient was started on one and a half maintenance intravenous fluids. He did not have dark urine or hyperkalemia or myoglobinuria or renal failure. Our patient\u2019s clinical course was not severe and did not develop the complications usually associated with rhabdomyolysis. On day 2 of his hospital stay, he was able to stand up with support and CPK levels came down to 1713 U/L. Cerebrospinal fluid analysis showed a protein concentration of 62 mg/dL and white blood cell count of 4. Electromyography and nerve conduction studies did not show evidence of Guillain Barre Syndrome. A multiplex respiratory viral PCR was positive for rhinovirus and negative for Influenza A and B, parainfluenza, metapneumovirus and adenovirus. Lyme disease serology and monospot for Epstein Barr Virus were reported negative. Arboviral titers for West Nile virus was negative and so was the Rocky Mountain spotted fever titers. On the day 3 of his hospitalization, his upper extremity strength significantly improved to 5/5 and lower extremity to 4/5. Hence he was able to sit up and walk down the hallway without support. Rickettsia typhi IgM was elevated at 512 and IgG at 1024. Serum was evaluated by use of an indirect immunofluorescence antibody (IFA) test kit for immunoglobulin G (IgG) to Rickettsia typhi and Rickettsia rickettsii. Reciprocal titers >64 were considered positive. CPK, ALT and AST levels were noted to have a downward trend. Blood and cerebrospinal fluid cultures showed no growth. The complete recovery of the patient took about 48 hours which included 100 mg of doxycycline given twice daily by mouth. He was discharged home on doxycycline to complete a 10 day course and prednisone was discontinued.", "qa_list": [{"question": "List all the collagen vascular diseases that the patient has been diagnosed with. If none, return NA in the output.", "answer": "Dermatomyositis/Polymyositis", "justification": ["A diagnosis of myositis", "as dermatomyositis and polymyositis were amongst the differential diagnosis"]}, {"question": "If so, list all CPK values of the patient and the respective dates of measurement, separated by semicolon. If unknown, return NA in the output.", "answer": "2394 U/L|NA, 1713 U/L|NA", "justification": ["Creatinine phosphokinase (CPK) was elevated at 2394 \u03bc/L", "CPK levels came down to 1713 U/L"]}, {"question": "If so, has the patient currently an active skin rush?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 269, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "Current therapy with any endocrine therapy such as raloxifene (Evista\u00ae), tamoxifen, or other selective estrogen receptor modulators (SERMs), either for osteoporosis or breast cancer prevention. (Short course endocrine therapy of < 6 weeks duration is acceptable post core biopsy pre surgery if the Oncotype DX Recurrence Score is assessed on the biopsy core and is less than or equal to 18.)", "note_date": "2022-03-22", "note": "Breast cancer was diagnosed in this 60-year-old woman in July 2015. Initial treatment consisted of surgery, radiotherapy, and chemotherapy. AI therapy with letrozole was started in February 2016 for 5 years. She had no other risk factors for osteoporosis. A DXA performed in March 2016 revealed osteoporosis. BMD T-scores were \u22122.9 at the lumbar spine and \u22121.9 at the total hip. Vertebral morphometry confirmed the absence of fractures. The 10-year probability of major osteoporotic fractures assessed by FRAX\u00ae was 13%. A treatment with 60 mg denosumab every 6 months and adequate daily calcium and vitamin D supplementation started in March 2016. She received 12 half-yearly injections of denosumab, the last one in August 2021. \r\nLetrozole treatment ended in November 2021. A DXA performed in November 2021 showed no more osteoporosis. The lumbar spine and total hip T-score values were \u22121.7 SD (+18%) and \u22121.4 SD (+8%), respectively. Vertebral morphometry confirmed the absence of fractures. CTX (fasting blood sample in the early morning, normal range for premenopausal women: 25\u2013573 ng/l) were measured at 33 ng/l today, 7 months after last denosumab injection. To prevent the high-turnover bone loss associated with denosumab discontinuation, an antiresorptive treatment was proposed. She refused bisphosphonates for fear of side effects. Raloxifene 60 mg daily was accepted and started today.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Is the patient currently receiving treatment for osteoporosis or prophylaxis for breast cancer?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Raloxifene 60 mg daily was accepted and started today", "To prevent the high-turnover bone loss"]}, {"question": "If so, list all therapies that the patient is currently receiving for the abformentioned indications and the starting date of each therapy, separated by semicolon. If unknown, return NA in the outcome.", "answer": "Raloxifene| 2022-03-22", "justification": ["Raloxifene 60 mg daily was accepted and started today.", "Note date: 2022-03-22"]}, {"question": "If so, list all values of the Oncotype DX Recurrence Score of the patient. If unknown, return NA in the output.", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 272, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04187833", "criterion": "Subjects must have received prior checkpoint inhibitor therapy (defined as anti-CTLA4 or anti-PD-1 or combination anti-CTLA4/anti-PD-1), either for metastatic or unresectable disease or adjuvant therapy.", "note_date": "2021-04-10", "note": "A 62-year-old male was diagnosed with BRAF-negative stage IVa completely excised acral melanoma in February 2019. He was considered for adjuvant nivolumab 3 mg/kg every 2 weeks. In June 2019, after the third cycle/dose, he presented to the emergency room with severe asthenia and fatigue. He claimed not to have shortness of breath, thoracic pain, fever, or bleeding episodes. Physical examination showed mild conjunctival jaundice. The rest of the clinical examination was unremarkable. Routine laboratory tests showed 5.8 g/dL haemoglobin levels, 1,200 absolute neutrophil count, indirect hyperbilirubinaemia 2.4 mg/dL, high lactate dehydrogenase (LDH) 912 U/L, and low haptoglobin <10. The direct antiglobulin test was positive for complement 3d but negative for IgM and IgG. Our diagnosis was AIHA. Considering that the patient was currently on immunotherapy treatment and given the timing association between nivolumab and anaemia, we could establish the immune-related adverse event grade 4. The patient had not started other concomitant medications associated with AIHA, so we concluded it could be reasonably related to nivolumab. We started treatment with a high dose of methylprednisolone (1 mg/kg) and 3 red blood cell transfusions. After 4 days, the haemoglobin levels raised to 9.5 g/dL, the bilirubin levels became normal, and LDH levels took a bit longer to normalize. The patient was feeling well, so he was discharged from the hospital with a slow descending dose of cortisone. We decided to stop adjuvant treatment and start controls. The first recurrence was detected after 1 year. In May 2020, he came with skin metastases, and CT scans showed one unique 6-mm temporal cerebral lesion. He underwent radiosurgery with complete response. Despite having suffered a CTCAE grade 4 immuno-related event, we thought to give a chance with ipilimumab (anti-CTLA4) as it was another mechanism of action. The first cycle was given at 1 mg/kg and next at 3 mg/kg. No immune-related adverse events were found during the treatment. Four weeks after the fourth cycle of ipilimumab, abdominal adenopathies and new skin metastases appeared. In August 2020, he started second line with fotemustine 80 mg/m2 every 2 weeks. After 7 cycles, a PET scan was performed with partial response only, persisting one skin metastasis in the pretibial zone. In December 2020, he received surgery of the unique active focus on the skin with free margins. He continued with fotemustine every 3 weeks for better tolerance. In the last follow-up in April 2021, PET scan showed complete metabolic response.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with melanoma?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["A 62-year-old male was diagnosed", "acral melanoma"]}, {"question": "If so, list all the checkpoint inhibitor therapies that the patient has received and the corresponding dates of starting the therapy, separated by semicolon. Separate the pairs of therapy|date, by comma. If unknown, return NA in the output.", "answer": "Nivolumab| May 2019, Ipilimumab|May 2020", "justification": ["He was considered for adjuvant nivolumab 3 mg/kg every 2 weeks. In June 2019, after the third cycle/dose,", "Four weeks after the fourth cycle of ipilimumab", "In August 2020"]}]}
{"id": 277, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-08-30", "note": "A 47-year-old woman with RA who was being treated with methotrexate, was diagnosed with a spitzoid melanoma in March 2010 and the tumor was surgically removed. In 2016, the RA treatment was changed to infliximab (Remicade). After almost 10 years of a tumor-free period, the patient returned to our clinic in May 2019 with swollen left axillary lymph nodes. Nodal metastasis was confirmed after fine-needle aspiration. A PET scan showed pulmonary, liver, and subcutaneous metastasis as well. Infliximab was stopped and metastasectomy of the left axilla was performed. Treatment with ipilimumab was started at 3 mg/kg every 3 weeks for 4 cycles in an expanded access program in August 2019. One week following the first injection of ipilimumab, the patient developed classic symptoms of severe arthritis affecting both hands and feet as well as both knees. Clinically, the patient showed swelling and redness of all extremities. The right knee was painful but with good range of motion. Inflammatory markers were elevated with a C-reactive protein (CRP) of 35 mg/L (N <5 mg/L) and no sign of leukocytosis. No radiological joint scan was performed at this point. An anti-inflammatory and analgesic therapy with a nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drug (ibuprofen) was prescribed and a local injection of corticosteroids in the knee was performed. Furthermore, the patient was started on sulfasalacin (2 g/day) for RA. After 4 cycles of ipilimumab, melanoma progression was radiologically confirmed in February 2020, and dacarbacin 1,600 mg was given every 3 weeks from April 2020 for a period of 3 months. In August 2020, the patient underwent treatment with pembrolizumab (2 mg/kg) every 3 weeks following recurrent disease progression. The symptoms of RA remained always under control with no signs of active disease.", "qa_list": [{"question": "List all diagnoses of the patient and the corresponding date of diagnosis, separated by semicolon. Separate the pairs diagnosis|date by comma. If unknown, return NA.", "answer": "Rheumatoid arthritis|NA, Spitzoid melanoma|March 2010, pulmonary, liver, and subcutaneous metastasis|May 2019,", "justification": ["spitzoid melanoma in March 2010", "A 47-year-old woman with RA", "pulmonary, liver, and subcutaneous metastasis", "in May 2019"]}, {"question": "If so, list all therapies that the patient has received, separated by comma. If unknown, return NA.", "answer": "Methotrexate, infliximab, ipilimumab, ibuprofen, corticosteroids, sulfasalacin, dacarbacin, pembrolizumab", "justification": ["was being treated with methotrexate", "treatment was changed to infliximab", "Treatment with ipilimumab was started", "nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drug (ibuprofen) was prescribed and a local injection of corticosteroids in the knee was performed.", "the patient was started on sulfasalacin", "and dacarbacin 1,600 mg was given", "underwent treatment with pembrolizumab"]}, {"question": "If so, list all procedures that the patient has undergone, separated by comma. If unknown, return NA.", "answer": "Metastasectomy of the left axilla", "justification": ["metastasectomy of the left axilla was performed"]}]}
{"id": 310, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04134260", "criterion": "Prior systemic chemotherapy for the study cancer; note that prior chemotherapy for a different cancer is allowed (completed > 3 years prior to registration)", "note_date": "2022-05-16", "note": "2022-5-16 1:10 PM\r\nINTRATHECAL CHEMOTHERAPY\r\nReason: 48yo with leukemia who is receiving chemotherapy. Scheduled\r\nTRANSCATH THERAPY \r\nLUMBAR SPINAL PUNCTURE \r\nMULTI-PROCEDURE SAME DAY\r\nTRANS CATH INFUSSION\r\nGUIDANCE FOR NEEDLE PLACEMENT\r\nMEDICAL CONDITION:\r\n48 year old man with lymphoma/leukemia\r\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION:\r\n48yo with leukemia who is receiving chemotherapy. Scheduled to receive\r\nintrathecal chemotherapy however LP has been unsuccessful. He is s/p L4-L5\r\nlumbar surgery.\r\nPlease page fellow with time and will infuse intrathecal chemotherapy down in L2.\r\nFINAL REPORT\r\nCLINICAL HISTORY:  48-year-old male with history of lymphoma and leukemia.\r\nHere for intrathecal chemotherapy.\r\nThis procedure is performed in conjunction with Oncology\r\nInformed consent was obtained from the patient\r\nThe patient was brought to the fluoroscopic suite and placed on the fluoroscopic table in\r\nprone position.  Assess to lumbar subarachnoid space was obtained at the level\r\nof L3-4 under local anesthesia with aseptic precautions.  Approximately 3 cc\r\nof CSF was collected which was turbid.\r\n50 mg of Cytarabine and mixed with 25 mg of hydrocortisone in 3 cc solution\r\nwas injected under fluoro guidance into the lumbar subarachnoid space as per recommendation. This infusion was performed over a period of 5\r\nminutes.\r\nThis was uneventful and the patient tolerated the procedure well.  The patient\r\nwas sent to the floor with orders.\r\nIMPRESSION:\r\nSuccessful fluoro guided intrathecal Cytarabine+steroid  injection", "qa_list": [{"question": "List all cancer diagnoses of the patient separated by comma. If unknown, return NA.", "answer": "Lymphoma, Leukemia", "justification": ["48-year-old male with history of lymphoma and leukemia."]}, {"question": "If so, list pairs of the cancer diagnosis and the corresponding chemotherapy separated by semicolon. Separate the pairs diagnosis - chemotherapy by comma. If unknown, return NA.", "answer": "Lymphoma|NA, Leukemia|Cytarabine", "justification": ["48yo with leukemia who is receiving chemotherapy", "50 mg of Cytarabine"]}]}
{"id": 274, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2021-04-10", "note": "A 62-year-old male was diagnosed with BRAF-negative stage IVa completely excised acral melanoma in February 2019. He was considered for adjuvant nivolumab 3 mg/kg every 2 weeks. In June 2019, after the third cycle/dose, he presented to the emergency room with severe asthenia and fatigue. He claimed not to have shortness of breath, thoracic pain, fever, or bleeding episodes. Physical examination showed mild conjunctival jaundice. The rest of the clinical examination was unremarkable. Routine laboratory tests showed 5.8 g/dL haemoglobin levels, 1,200 absolute neutrophil count, indirect hyperbilirubinaemia 2.4 mg/dL, high lactate dehydrogenase (LDH) 912 U/L, and low haptoglobin <10. The direct antiglobulin test was positive for complement 3d but negative for IgM and IgG. Our diagnosis was AIHA. Considering that the patient was currently on immunotherapy treatment and given the timing association between nivolumab and anaemia, we could establish the immune-related adverse event grade 4. The patient had not started other concomitant medications associated with AIHA, so we concluded it could be reasonably related to nivolumab. We started treatment with a high dose of methylprednisolone (1 mg/kg) and 3 red blood cell transfusions. After 4 days, the haemoglobin levels raised to 9.5 g/dL, the bilirubin levels became normal, and LDH levels took a bit longer to normalize. The patient was feeling well, so he was discharged from the hospital with a slow descending dose of cortisone. We decided to stop adjuvant treatment and start controls. The first recurrence was detected after 1 year. In May 2020, he came with skin metastases, and CT scans showed one unique 6-mm temporal cerebral lesion. He underwent radiosurgery with complete response. Despite having suffered a CTCAE grade 4 immuno-related event, we thought to give a chance with ipilimumab (anti-CTLA4) as it was another mechanism of action. The first cycle was given at 1 mg/kg and next at 3 mg/kg. No immune-related adverse events were found during the treatment. Four weeks after the fourth cycle of ipilimumab, abdominal adenopathies and new skin metastases appeared. In August 2020, he started second line with fotemustine 80 mg/m2 every 2 weeks. After 7 cycles, a PET scan was performed with partial response only, persisting one skin metastasis in the pretibial zone. In December 2020, he received surgery of the unique active focus on the skin with free margins. He continued with fotemustine every 3 weeks for better tolerance. In the last follow-up in April 2021, PET scan showed complete metabolic response.", "qa_list": [{"question": "List all diagnoses of the patient and the corresponding dates of establishing the diagnoses, separated by semicolon. Separate the pairs diagnosis|date, by comma. If unknown, return NA.", "answer": "Acral melanoma|February 2019, Autoimmune hemolytic anemia|June 2019, recurrent melanoma|May 2020", "justification": ["acral melanoma in February 2019", "Our diagnosis was AIHA.", "In June 2019", "The first recurrence was detected after 1 year", "In May 2020, he came with skin metastases"]}, {"question": "If so, list pairs of established diagnoses|therapies that the patient received for each established diagnosis, separated by semicolon. Separate the pairs by comma. If unknown, return NA.", "answer": "acral melanoma|adjuvant nivolumab, AIHA|methylprednisolone and red blood transfusions and cortisone, recurrent melanoma|radiosurgery and ipilimumab and fotemustine", "justification": ["adjuvant nivolumab", "after the third cycle/dose", "diagnosis was AIHA", "started treatment with a high dose of methylprednisolone (1 mg/kg) and 3 red blood cell transfusions", "a slow descending dose of cortisone.", "recurrence was detected after 1 year.", "He underwent radiosurgery", "give a chance with ipilimumab", "The first cycle", "he started second line with fotemustine"]}]}
{"id": 282, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-10-20", "note": "Record date: 2020-10-20\r\nEMERGENCY DEPT VISIT\r\nBIRD,TERRI   809-10-69-0                    VISIT DATE: 10/20/20\r\nPRESENTING COMPLAINT:\r\nHISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  The patient is a 70 year old\r\nfemale with long past medical history of medical problems,\r\nincluding abdominal aortic aneurysm repair, chronic pneumonia,\r\nchronic wound infection, history of chronic urinary tract\r\ninfections, change in mental status, peripheral vascular disease,\r\nhypertension, and coronary artery disease.  The patient was in her\r\nusual state of poor health when she was noticed by caregivers to be\r\nconfused and lethargic.  The patient was transferred to the\r\nemergency room department.\r\nREVIEW OF SYSTEMS:\r\nPAST MEDICAL HISTORY:\r\nMEDICATIONS:  Unknown medications at this time.\r\nALLERGIES:  Sulfa and penicillin.  Aspirin and all cephalosporins.\r\nSOCIAL HISTORY AND FAMILY HISTORY:\r\nPHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Temperature 101.6 degrees, pulse 90,\r\nrespiratory rate 18, blood pressure 114/60, room air saturation\r\n91%.  HEENT:  Normocephalic, atraumatic.  Pupils equal, round, and\r\nreactive to light and accommodation.  Neck supple and nontender.\r\nChest:  Bibasilar crackles.  Left sided rhonchi.  Abdomen:  Obvious\r\ninfected wound.  Minimally tender.  Extremities:  Negative.\r\nNeurologic:  Symmetric.  Alert and oriented times two.  Reflexes\r\nnormal, strength normal.\r\nLABORATORY EVALUATION:  WBC 28.\r\nTHERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  The patient was given IV\r\nantibiotics and will be admitted to the medical service for workup.\r\nPROCEDURES:\r\nCONSULTATIONS (including PCP):\r\nFINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Urosepsis.\r\nDISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  She was admitted\r\nin poor condition.", "qa_list": [{"question": "List all diagnoses of this patient separated by semicolon. If none return NA in output", "answer": "abdominal aortic aneurysm repair; chronic pneumonia; chronic wound infection; history of chronic urinary tract infections; change in mental status; peripheral vascular disease; hypertension; coronary artery disease", "justification": ["history of medical problems,\r\nincluding abdominal aortic aneurysm repair, chronic pneumonia,\r\nchronic wound infection, history of chronic urinary tract\r\ninfections, change in mental status, peripheral vascular disease,\r\nhypertension, and coronary artery disease"]}, {"question": "List the dates of diagnosis confirmation of the patient separated by semicolon. If unknown return NA in output", "answer": "NA; NA; NA; NA; NA; NA; NA; NA", "justification": ["NA", "NA", "NA", "NA", "NA", "NA", "NA", "NA", "NA"]}, {"question": "List all the therapies that the patient is currently receiving, separated by semicolon. If unknown return NA", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["Unknown medications at this time."]}, {"question": "List all the compounds or therapies that the patient is allergic to, separated by semicolon; if unknown return NA in output.", "answer": "Sulfa; penicillin; aspirin; all cephalosporins", "justification": ["ALLERGIES:  Sulfa and penicillin.  Aspirin and all cephalosporins."]}, {"question": "List all procedures the patient has undergone, separated by semicolon, if unknown return NA in output", "answer": "Na", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "List all laboratory values and the date of measurement, separated by semicolon. Separate the laboratory value and the respective day of measurement by comma.", "answer": "WBC=28", "justification": ["WBC 28"]}]}
{"id": 273, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-09-20", "note": "9/20/2020 12:00:00 AM\r\nENDOMETRIAL CARCINOMA\r\nAdmission Date :\r\n09/20/2020\r\nReport Status :\r\nSigned\r\nDischarge Date :\r\n09/22/2020\r\nADMISSION DIAGNOSIS :\r\nENDOMETRIAL CANCER .\r\nDISCHARGE DIAGNOSIS :\r\nENDOMETRIAL CANCER .\r\nPROCEDURES :\r\nTOTAL ABDOMINAL HYSTERECTOMY AND BILATERAL SALPINGO-OOPHORECTOMY\r\nHISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS :\r\nThis is a 48-year-old G 3 P 3 who presented to Dr. Jones 's clinic after having an abnormal pap smear followed by an endometrial biopsy that was suggestive of grade 1 endometrial cancer .\r\nThis is a patient who , over the past year , has had no menses and thought she had become menopausal .\r\nShe then began spotting for several months with some constant brown discharge .\r\nA pap smear that was obtained by her primary care physician showed an endometrial cell and thus she was referred to a gynecologist for an endometrial biopsy .\r\nThe endometrial biopsy showed grade 1 endometrial cancer .\r\nA decision was made to proceed with surgical management for this finding .\r\nPAST MEDICAL HISTORY :\r\nMigraines .\r\nALLERGIES :\r\nPenicillin .\r\nPAST SURGICAL HISTORY :\r\nTwo cesarean sections .\r\nPAST GYN HISTORY :\r\nMenarche at 13 , regular menses to the age of 46 .\r\nThen becoming irregular for several years .\r\nShe had her first child at age 21 .\r\nShe has had one normal spontaneous vaginal delivery and two cesarean sections .\r\nSOCIAL HISTORY :\r\nThe patient was a prior off-and-on smoker but has quit in 01/19 .\r\nShe is married .\r\nMEDICATIONS ON ADMISSION :\r\nImitrex ; Indocin ; Celebrex ; Verapamil for migraines .\r\nFAMILY HISTORY :\r\nMother with colonic polyps .\r\nShe has a maternal uncle and maternal aunt both with colon cancer who have passed away from this disease .\r\nThere was no additional history of breast , ovarian or uterine cancer in her family .\r\nPHYSICAL EXAMINATION :\r\nGENERAL :\r\nShe is a well-developed , well-nourished female .\r\nShe is 5 foot 4 inches and 159 pounds .\r\nBREASTS :\r\nNo masses .\r\nLUNGS :\r\nClear to auscultation .\r\nHEART :\r\nRegular rate and rhythm .\r\nABDOMEN :\r\nSoft , mildly obese with Pfannenstiel scar visualized .\r\nPELVIC :\r\nNormal introitus , normal appearing cervix , a small , mobile uterus .\r\nNo additional masses or nodules appreciated on exam .\r\nHOSPITAL COURSE :\r\nThe patient was admitted on the day of her surgery which was 09/20/2020 .\r\nShe underwent a TAH-BSO which was uncomplicated.\r\nDetails of the procedure can be found in the operative dictation .\r\nIn short , frozen pathology from the uterus showed that there was a grade 1 cancer with no invasion of the myometrium .\r\nThere was no nodal dissection done at that time .\r\nThe patient tolerated the procedure extremely well and did well during her postoperative course .\r\nBy postoperative day #2 she was eating , ambulating and voiding on her own .\r\nShe decided to now be discharged home at this time .\r\nShe was discharged home with the following medications :\r\nDISCHARGE MEDICATIONS :\r\nPercocet ; Colace .\r\nFOLLOWUP :\r\nShe will have a follow up appointment with Dr. Jones in four weeks .", "qa_list": [{"question": "List all the diagnoses of this patient, separated by semicolon, if none return NA in output", "answer": "endometrial carcinoma; Migraines", "justification": ["ENDOMETRIAL CARCINOMA", "PAST MEDICAL HISTORY: Migraines"]}, {"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with cancer?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["ADMISSION DIAGNOSIS: ENDOMETRIAL CANCER ."]}, {"question": "If so, list the type of cancers the patients has been diagnosed with separated by semicolon, if unknown return NA in output", "answer": "Endometrial cancer", "justification": ["ADMISSION DIAGNOSIS: ENDOMETRIAL CANCER ."]}, {"question": "List all the procedures that confirmed the diagnoses, separated by semicolon if unknown return NA in output", "answer": "Endometrial biopsy", "justification": ["The endometrial biopsy showed grade 1 endometrial cancer"]}, {"question": "List all the procedures that the patient has undergone separated by semicolon, if none return NA in output", "answer": "Total abdominal hysterectomy and bilateral salpingo-oophorectomy; two cesarean sections", "justification": ["PROCEDURES: TOTAL ABDOMINAL HYSTERECTOMY AND BILATERAL SALPINGO-OOPHORECTOMY", "PAST SURGICAL HISTORY: Two cesarean sections."]}, {"question": "List the dates of each procedure, separated by semicolon, if unknown return NA in output", "answer": "09/20/2022; NA", "justification": ["The patient was admitted on the day of her surgery which was 09/20/2020 .\r\nShe underwent a TAH-BSO which was uncomplicated.", "NA"]}, {"question": "List all therapies that the patient is currently receiving, separated by semicolon, if unknown return NA", "answer": "Imitrex; Indocin; Celebrex; Verapamil for migraines .", "justification": ["Imitrex ; Indocin ; Celebrex ; Verapamil for migraines"]}, {"question": "List all therapies that the patient is allergic to separated by semicolon, if none return NA in output", "answer": "Penicillin", "justification": ["ALLERGIES: Penicillin."]}]}
{"id": 278, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03957876", "criterion": "Any active malignancy (unrelated, non-hematological malignancy) diagnosed within the past 6 months of starting the study drug (other than curatively treated carcinoma-in-situ of the cervix or non-melanoma skin cancer).", "note_date": "2022-04-08", "note": "CHIEF COMPLAINT:,  Right hydronephrosis.,HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS: , The patient is a 56-year-old female who has a history of uterine cancer, breast cancer, mesothelioma.  She is scheduled to undergo mastectomy in two weeks.  In September 1999, she was diagnosed with right breast cancer and underwent lumpectomy and axillary node dissection and radiation.  Again, she is scheduled for mastectomy in two weeks.  She underwent a recent PET scan for Dr. X, which revealed marked hydronephrosis on the right possibly related to right UPJ obstruction and there is probably a small nonobstructing stone in the upper pole of the right kidney.  There was no dilation of the right ureter noted.  Urinalysis today is microscopically negative.,PAST MEDICAL HISTORY: , Uterine cancer, mesothelioma, breast cancer, diabetes, hypertension.,PAST SURGICAL HISTORY: , Lumpectomy, hysterectomy.,MEDICATIONS:,  Diovan HCT 80/12.5 mg daily, metformin 500 mg daily.,ALLERGIES:,  None.,FAMILY HISTORY: , Noncontributory.,SOCIAL HISTORY:,  She is retired.  Does not smoke or drink.,REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:,  I have reviewed his review of systems sheet and it is on the chart.,PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:,  Please see the physical exam sheet I completed.  Abdomen is soft, nontender, nondistended, no palpable masses, no CVA tenderness.,IMPRESSION AND PLAN: , Marked right hydronephrosis without hydruria.  She believes she had a CT scan of the abdomen and pelvis at Hospital in 2005.  I will try to obtain the report to see if the right kidney was evaluated at that time.  She will need evaluation with an IVP and renal scan to determine the point of obstruction and renal function of the right kidney.  She is quite anxious about her upcoming surgery and would like to delay any evaluation of this until the surgery is completed.  She will call us back to schedule the x-rays.  She understands the great importance and getting back in touch with us to schedule these x-rays due to the possibility that it may be somehow related to the cancer.  There is also a question of a stone present in the kidney.  She voiced a complete understanding of that and will call us after she recovers from her surgery to schedule these tests.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Does the patient have an active malignancy?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "List all diagnoses of the patient separated by semicolon, if none then return NA in output", "answer": "Uterine cancer; breast cancer; mesothelioma; diabetes; hypertension", "justification": ["MEDICAL HISTORY: , Uterine cancer, mesothelioma, breast cancer, diabetes, hypertension"]}, {"question": "List all procedures the patient has undergone separated by semicolon if none then return NA in output", "answer": "Lumpectomy; hysterectomy", "justification": ["PAST SURGICAL HISTORY: , Lumpectomy, hysterectomy"]}, {"question": "List all current therapies the patient is receiving separated by semicolon, if unknown return NA", "answer": "Diovan HCT; metformin", "justification": ["Diovan HCT 80/12.5 mg daily, metformin 500 mg daily"]}, {"question": "List the doses of each therapy separated by semicolon, if unknown return NA in output", "answer": "80/12.5 mg; 500 mg", "justification": ["Diovan HCT 80/12.5 mg daily, metformin 500 mg daily"]}, {"question": "List the frequency of each therapy, separated by semicolon if unknown return NA in output", "answer": "daily; daily", "justification": ["Diovan HCT 80/12.5 mg daily, metformin 500 mg daily"]}, {"question": "Does the patient have any allergies?", "answer": "No", "justification": ["ALLERGIES:  None."]}]}
{"id": 279, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03957876", "criterion": "Any active malignancy (unrelated, non-hematological malignancy) diagnosed within the past 6 months of starting the study drug (other than curatively treated carcinoma-in-situ of the cervix or non-melanoma skin cancer).", "note_date": "2020-09-19", "note": "Record date: 2020-09-19\r\nPersonal Data and Overall Health\r\nPatient is a 81 yr. old male who presents to Dr. James for multiple tooth extractions on 10/01/20.\r\nHistory of Present Illness\r\nThe patient complains of a hx. of tooth abscesses.\r\nPast Surgical History\r\nPrior surgery includes:\r\n1.) excision l. neck mass for post l. neck lipoma 6/27/16- under local, no complications\r\n2.) bowel surgery 15 yrs ago- g.a.- no complications\r\n3.) hernia repair- 20 yrs ago- GA. no complications\r\n4.) appendectomy-40 yrs ago- GA- no complications\r\n5.) hemorroids- 2002-per patient done under spinal- had severe post spinal headache.\r\nFamily History\r\nThere in no family history of adverse reactions to general anesthesia.\r\nPast Medical History\r\nCurrent medical problems include:\r\n1.) HTN\r\n2.) DMx20yrs- per patient glucose levels run 125-150 range\r\n3.) hx. of tooth abscesses\r\n4.) hypercholesterolemia\r\nSocial History\r\nSmoking: no\r\nAlcohol use: no history of excessive use\r\nSubstance abuse: none\r\nReview of Systems\r\nMedications:\r\ninsulin- 5 R/25N in am, 15 R in evening\r\nhctz-25mg qd\r\ncaptopril 25mg 2x/day\r\nlipitor 10mgqd\r\nzyrtec prn\r\necasa\r\nvit e\r\nAllergies: shellfish\r\nCardiovascular: history of hypertension, no MI; denies CP, DOE, syncope, ankle edema\r\nRespiratory: no history of asthma or chronic lung disease; denies unusual shortness of breath\r\nNeurological: no history of neurological problems\r\nGastrointestinal: no history of PUD; denies reflux\r\nHepatobiliary: no history of liver disease; denies jaundice or hepatitis\r\nRenal/Genitourinary: no history of renal failure; denies hematuria, dysuria, obstructive uropathy\r\nMusculoskeletal: denies pain or limitation of movement\r\nEndocrine/metabolic: history of diabetes last 20 yrs, hypercholesterolemia\r\nHeme/Onc:  no history of bleeding, blood diseases; no history of malignancy, chemotherapy, or radiation therapy\r\nPsychiatric: no significant psychiatric problems\r\nExam\r\nSaO2: 98% RA\r\nHt:6'1\"\r\nWt:209\r\nBP:180/74\r\nP:79\r\nHEEN&T:  good range of motion, no masses, neck veins flat, no bruits\r\nAirway:  Mallampatti Class I or II\r\nTeeth:  in good repair\r\nLungs:  clear bilaterally\r\nHeart:  regular rhythm, no murmurs, S1=S2, no gallop\r\nAssessment\r\nASA Physical Status:  II\r\nWell prepared for surgery; no unusual concerns related to medical problems.\r\nPlan\r\nProposed Anesthetic: general anesthesia\r\nMonitors:  standard\r\nPain Management:  IVPCA\r\nAutologous blood:  none\r\nPremedication:  none\r\nUsual Medications:  take on day of surgery\r\nMedications to be held on day of surgery:  lipitor\r\nDiabetic medications:  counseled to old am insulin regimen\r\nNSAIDS:  avoid for 3 days before surgery\r\nAspirin:  avoid for 7 days before surgery\r\nNPO: after midnight\r\nExternal Labs\r\nNot available\r\nAttending Anesthesiologist Reassessment Note\r\nI have reviewed this preanesthetic assessment and concur with the assessment and recommended plan with the following exceptions:", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with cancer?", "answer": "No", "justification": ["no history of malignancy"]}, {"question": "List all procedures the patients has undergone separated by semicolon, if unknown return NA in output", "answer": "excision l. neck mass for post l. neck lipoma; bowel surgery; hernia repair; appendectomy; hemorroidectomy", "justification": ["Prior surgery includes:\r\n1.) excision l. neck mass for post l. neck lipoma 6/27/16- under local, no complications", "2.) bowel surgery 15 yrs ago- g.a.- no complications", "3.) hernia repair- 20 yrs ago- GA. no complications", "4.) appendectomy-40 yrs ago- GA- no complications", "5.) hemorroids- 2002-per patient done under spinal- had severe post spinal headache."]}, {"question": "List all diagnoses of the patient separated by semicolon, if none return NA in output", "answer": "Hypertension; diabetes mellitus; tooth abscess; hypercholesterolemia", "justification": ["Past Medical History\r\nCurrent medical problems include:\r\n1.) HTN", "2.) DMx20yrs", "3.) hx. of tooth abscesses", "4.) hypercholesterolemia"]}, {"question": "List the dates of each procedure separated by semicolon, if unknown return NA in output", "answer": "6/27/16; 2005; 1980; 2002", "justification": ["Prior surgery includes:\r\n1.) excision l. neck mass for post l. neck lipoma 6/27/16- under local, no complications", "2.) bowel surgery 15 yrs ago- g.a.- no complications", "3.) hernia repair- 20 yrs ago- GA. no complications", "4.) appendectomy-40 yrs ago- GA- no complications", "5.) hemorroids- 2002-per patient done under spinal- had severe post spinal headache."]}, {"question": "List the date of confirmation of each diagnosis separated by semicolon, if unknown return NA in output", "answer": "NA; 2000; NA; NA", "justification": ["Current medical problems include:\r\n1.) HTN", "2.) DMx20yrs- per patient glucose levels run 125-150 range", "3.) hx. of tooth abscesses", "4.) hypercholesterolemia"]}]}
{"id": 281, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-02-03", "note": "CHIEF COMPLAINT (1/1):, This 59 year old female presents today complaining that her toenails are discolored, thickened, and painful. Duration: Condition has existed for 6 months. Severity: Severity of condition is worsening.,ALLERGIES: ,Patient admits allergies to dairy products, penicillin.,MEDICATION HISTORY:, None.,PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:, Past medical history is unremarkable.,PAST SURGICAL HISTORY:, Patient admits past surgical history of eye surgery in 1999.,SOCIAL HISTORY:, Patient denies alcohol use, Patient denies illegal drug use, Patient denies STD history, Patient denies tobacco use.,FAMILY HISTORY:, Unremarkable.,REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:, Psychiatric: (+) poor sleep pattern, Respiratory: (+) breathing difficulties, respiratory symptoms.,PHYSICAL EXAM:, Patient is a 59 year old female who appears well developed, well nourished and with good attention to hygiene and body habitus. Toenails 1-5 bilateral appear crumbly, discolored - yellow, friable and thickened.,Cardiovascular: DP pulses palpable bilateral. PT pulses palpable bilateral. CFT immediate. No edema observed.  Varicosities are not observed.,Skin: Skin temperature of the lower extremities is warm to cool, proximal to distal. No skin rash, subcutaneous nodules, lesions or ulcers observed.,Neurological: Touch, pin, vibratory and proprioception sensations are normal. Deep tendon reflexes normal.,Musculoskeletal: Muscle strength is 5/5 for all groups tested. Muscle tone is normal. Inspection and palpation of bones, joints and muscles is unremarkable.,TEST RESULTS:, No tests to report at this time.,IMPRESSION:, Onychomycosis.,PLAN:, Debrided 10 nails.,PRESCRIPTIONS:, Penlac Dosage: 8% Topical Solution Sig:", "qa_list": [{"question": "List all diagnoses of this patient separated by semicolon. If none return NA in output", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["Past medical history is unremarkable"]}, {"question": "List all procedures the patient has undergone, separated by semicolon. If none return NA in output", "answer": "eye surgery", "justification": ["past surgical history of eye surgery"]}, {"question": "List the date of each procedure, separated by semicolon. If unknown return NA in output", "answer": "1999", "justification": ["eye surgery in 1999"]}, {"question": "List all drugs or compounds the parties tis allergic to, separated by semicolon. If unknown return NA in output.", "answer": "Dairy products; penicillin", "justification": ["ALLERGIES: ,Patient admits allergies to dairy products, penicillin"]}, {"question": "List all adverse or hypersensitivity reactions the patient presented to these drugs or compounds, separated by semicolon. If unknown return NA in output", "answer": "NA; NA", "justification": ["NA", "NA"]}]}
{"id": 283, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-04-08", "note": "CHIEF COMPLAINT:,  Patient AF is a 50-year-old hepatitis C positive African-American man presenting with a 2-day history of abdominal pain and distention with nausea and vomiting.,HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS: , AF's symptoms began 2 days ago, and he has not passed gas or had any bowel movements.  He has not eaten anything, and has vomited 8 times.  AF reports 10/10 pain in the LLQ.,PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:,  AF's past medical history is significant for an abdominal injury during the Vietnam War which required surgery, and multiple episodes of small bowel obstruction and abdominal pain.  Other elements of his history include alcoholism, cocaine abuse, alcoholic hepatitis, hepatitis C positive, acute pancreatitis, chronic pancreatitis, appendicitis, liver hematoma/contusion, Hodgkin's Disease, constipation, diarrhea, paralytic ileus, anemia, multiple blood transfusions, chorioretinitis, pneumonia, and \"crack chest pain\" ,PAST SURGICAL HISTORY: , AF has had multiple abdominal surgeries, including Bill Roth Procedure Type 1 (partial gastrectomy) during Vietnam War, at least 2 exploratory laparotomies and enterolysis procedures (1993; 2000), and appendectomy,MEDICATIONS:,  None.,ALLERGIES:,  Iodine, IV contrast (anaphylaxis), and seafood/shellfish.,FAMILY HISTORY:,  Noncontributory.,SOCIAL HISTORY:,  AF was born and raised in San Francisco.  His father was an alcoholic.  He currently lives with his sister, and does not work; he collects a pension.,HEALTH-RELATED BEHAVIORS:,  AF reports that he smokes 1 to 2 cigarettes per day, and drinks 40 ounces of beer per day.,REVIEW OF SYSTEMS: , Noncontributory, except that patient reports a 6 pound weight loss since his symptoms began, and reports multiple transfusions for anemia.,PHYSICAL EXAM:,Vital Signs:  T:  37.1", "qa_list": [{"question": "List all the diagnoses of the patient, separated by semicolon.  If none return NA.", "answer": "small bowel obstruction; alcoholism; cocaine abuse; alcoholic hepatitis; hepatitis C positive; acute pancreatitis; chronic pancreatitis; appendicitis; liver hematoma/contusion; Hodgkin's disease; constipation; diarrhea; paralytic ileus; anemia; chorioretinitis; pneumonia crack chest pain", "justification": ["episodes of small bowel obstruction", "history include alcoholism, cocaine abuse, alcoholic hepatitis, hepatitis C positive, acute pancreatitis, chronic pancreatitis, appendicitis, liver hematoma/contusion, Hodgkin's Disease, constipation, diarrhea, paralytic ileus, anemia", "chorioretinitis, pneumonia, and \"crack chest pain"]}, {"question": "List all procedures the patient has undergone, separated by semicolon. If unknown return NA in output", "answer": "Bill Roth Procedure Type 1 (partial gastrectomy); exploratory laparotomies; enterolysis procedures; appendectomy", "justification": ["Bill Roth Procedure Type 1 (partial gastrectomy)", "at least 2 exploratory laparotomies and enterolysis procedures (1993; 2000), and appendectomy"]}, {"question": "List the dates of each procedure separated by semicolon if unknown return NA in output", "answer": "NA; NA; 1993, 2002; NA", "justification": ["NA", "NA", "enterolysis procedures (1993; 2000)", "NA"]}, {"question": "List all current therapies of the patient separated by semicolon. If none return NA in output", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["None"]}, {"question": "List all compound or drugs the patient is allergic to separated by semicolon. If unknown return NA in output", "answer": "Iodine; IV contras; seafood/shellfish", "justification": ["ALLERGIES:,  Iodine, IV contrast (anaphylaxis), and seafood/shellfish"]}, {"question": "List all allergic or hypersensitivity reactions the patient has experienced due to each of these drugs or compound separated by semicolon. If unknown return NA in output", "answer": "NA; anaphylaxis; NA", "justification": ["NA", "IV contrast (anaphylaxis)", "NA"]}]}
{"id": 284, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-05-07", "note": "5/7/2020 12:00:00 AM\r\n\r\nAdmission Date :\r\n05/07/2020\r\nReport Status :\r\nSigned\r\nDischarge Date :\r\n05/15/2020\r\nADMISSION DIAGNOSES :\r\n1. LEFT ELBOW PAIN .\r\nDISCHARGE DIAGNOSES :\r\n1. LEFT ELBOW PAIN .\r\nPROCEDURE :\r\nLeft total elbow replacement .\r\nHISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS :\r\nThis is a 58 year old right hand dominant female with a past medical history of rheumatoid arthritis scheduled for a left total elbow replacement .\r\nThe patient is status post arthroscopic debridement at Anh Tal Tersper Rehabilitation Hospital in 10/93 .\r\nThe patient has developed progressive loss of motion , increase in pain of left elbow .\r\nShe now presents for a left total elbow replacement .\r\nPAST MEDICAL HISTORY :\r\nThe patient has a past medical history of rheumatoid arthritis x 25 years , osteoporosis with a history of compression fracture and rib fractures , history of phlebitis .\r\nPAST SURGICAL HISTORY :\r\nShe is status post hysterectomy in 1978 , status post tuballigation , status post tonsillectomy , status post appendectomy , status post left elbow arthroscopy in 1993 .\r\nALLERGIES :\r\nShe has allergies to MORPHINE , CODEINE and SULFA .\r\nMEDICATIONS ON ADMISSION :\r\nAt the time of admission , the patient was on Rheumatrex Dospak , Plaquenil 20 mg PO b.i.d. , Prednisone 5 mg PO q. day , Estraderm .05 mg patch , calcium 600 mg PO b.i.d. , Ocuvite 1 POq. day , multivitamins 1 PO q. day , Folic acid 1 PO q. day , Motrin 800mg PO prn , Citrucel q. day and nasal spray prn .\r\nPHYSICAL EXAMINATION :\r\nHer physical examination is most notable with left elbow with range of motion of 32 to 110 degrees .\r\nShe has approximately 10 degrees of supination and 90 degrees of pronation .\r\nHer CSM is otherwise intact .\r\nHOSPITAL COURSE :\r\nThe patient was taken to the Operating Room on ais where she underwent an uncomplicated left elbow replacement .\r\nThe patient tolerated the procedure without problems .\r\nShe was transferred to the Recovery Room and to the floor .\r\nShe was treated perioperatively with IV antibiotics .\r\nPostoperatively , the patient was noted in the Recovery Room to have paresthesias which gradually improved .\r\nIt was felt that these were accountable related to tourniquet .\r\nThe patient 's postoperative hematocrit was 33.2 .\r\nShe started work on physical therapy on postoperative day # 2 when she started range of motion exercises .\r\nShe had an x-ray checked prior to discharge which showed good placement of her prosthesis .\r\nThe patient was subsequently discharged home with MVWH support .\r\nDISPOSITION :\r\nMEDICATIONS ON DISCHARGE :\r\nAt the time of discharge , the patient was on remaining medications in addition to Percocet .", "qa_list": [{"question": "List all diagnoses of the patient separated by semicolon. If unknown return NA in output", "answer": "rheumatoid arthritis; osteoporosis with compression fracture and rib fracture; phlebitis", "justification": ["past medical history of rheumatoid arthritis x 25 years , osteoporosis with a history of compression fracture and rib fractures , history of phlebitis ."]}, {"question": "List the date of diagnoses confirmation, separated by semicolon. If unknown return NA in output", "answer": "1995; NA; NA", "justification": ["history of rheumatoid arthritis x 25 years", "NA", "NA"]}, {"question": "List all procedures the patient has undergone separated by semicolon if none then return NA in output", "answer": "hysterectomy; tuballigation; tonsillectomy; appendectomy; left elbow arthroscopy", "justification": ["PAST SURGICAL HISTORY :\r\nShe is status post hysterectomy in 1978 , status post tuballigation , status post tonsillectomy , status post appendectomy , status post left elbow arthroscopy in 1993."]}, {"question": "List the dates of each procedure separated by semicolon, if unknown return NA in output", "answer": "1978; NA; NA; NA; 1993", "justification": ["post hysterectomy in 1978", "NA", "NA", "NA", "left elbow arthroscopy in 1993"]}, {"question": "List all the therapies the patient is currently receiving separated by semicolon", "answer": "Rheumatrex Dospak; Plaquenil; Prednisone; Estraderm; calcium; Ocuvite; multivitamins; Folic acid; Motrin; Citrucel; nasal spray", "justification": ["patient was on Rheumatrex Dospak , Plaquenil 20 mg PO b.i.d. , Prednisone 5 mg PO q. day , Estraderm .05 mg patch , calcium 600 mg PO b.i.d. , Ocuvite 1 POq. day , multivitamins 1 PO q. day , Folic acid 1 PO q. day , Motrin 800mg PO prn , Citrucel q. day and nasal spray prn"]}, {"question": "List the dose of each therapy, separated by semicolon if unknown return NA in output", "answer": "NA; 20mg; 5mg; 5mg; 600mg; 1; 1; 800mg; NA; NA", "justification": ["Rheumatrex Dospak", "Plaquenil 20 mg PO b.i.d. , Prednisone 5 mg PO q. day , Estraderm .05 mg patch , calcium 600 mg PO b.i.d. , Ocuvite 1 POq. day , multivitamins 1 PO q. day , Folic acid 1 PO q. day , Motrin 800mg PO prn", "Citrucel q. day", "nasal spray prn"]}, {"question": "List the frequencies of each therapy, separated by semicolon, if unknown return NA", "answer": "NA; b.i.d.; q. day; b.i.d.; q. day; q. day; q. day; prn; q. day; prn", "justification": ["patient was on Rheumatrex Dospak", "Plaquenil 20 mg PO b.i.d. , Prednisone 5 mg PO q. day , Estraderm .05 mg patch , calcium 600 mg PO b.i.d. , Ocuvite 1 POq. day , multivitamins 1 PO q. day , Folic acid 1 PO q. day , Motrin 800mg PO prn , Citrucel q. day and nasal spray prn"]}, {"question": "List all compounds or drugs the patient is allergic to separated by semicolon. If unknown return NA in output", "answer": "morphine; codeine; sulfa", "justification": ["has allergies to MORPHINE , CODEINE and SULFA ."]}, {"question": "List all allergic or hypersensitivity reaction the patient present to each drug or compound respectively separated by semicolon. If unknown return NA in output", "answer": "NA; NA; NA", "justification": ["NA", "NA", "NA"]}]}
{"id": 285, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-01-17", "note": "Record date: 2020-01-17\r\n\r\nPlease see the written documentation undertaken by Dr. P,\r\nthe resident who saw the patient primarily.  I have seen and\r\nexamined the patient personally, reviewed the written\r\ndocumentation and agree with the assessment and plan.\r\nHISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  Mr. Holmes is a 68-year-old\r\ngentleman without significant past medical history, who is\r\nactually being seen here by his primary care physician who\r\nhappens to be a resident rotating ____ normally sees him in MIMAIMA\r\nClinic.  According to Dr. P, his PCP, he generally does\r\nnot have very much past medical history, but when he gets\r\ninfected, he gets confused.  He presents today with confusion.\r\nHis visiting nurse today noticed that he has been having weakness\r\nand fatigue over the last few days, but today, he was confused as\r\nhe has been when he has been ill in the past.\r\nPAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Dementia, SVT, hypertension, and diabetes\r\ntype 2.\r\nSOCIAL HISTORY:  He is a former smoker.\r\nPAST SURGICAL HISTORY:  Otherwise, negative.\r\nREVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Otherwise negative except as previously\r\ndictated.\r\nMEDICATIONS:  Lisinopril, hydrochlorothiazide, omeprazole,\r\nRisperdal, Tegretol, verapamil, and Tylenol #3.\r\nALLERGIES:  He has no known drug allergies.\r\nPHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  He is a healthy, well-appearing Caucasian\r\ngentleman who nevertheless is disoriented to time.  He knows\r\nplace and name.  His heart rate is 101, respiratory rate is 20,\r\nblood pressure is 121/92, and oxygen saturation is 96% on room\r\nair, and his temperature is 101.5.  He had left lower lobe\r\ncrackles in his lung exam.  The remainder of his physical exam\r\nwas otherwise normal.  Mucus membranes were moist.  Abdomen was\r\nsoft.  Extremities had no clubbing, cyanosis, or edema.\r\nLABORATORY DATA:  The patient had a normal chest x-ray, negative\r\nurinalysis.  White blood cell count was 7.12.  He had a\r\ncreatinine of 1.24, up from his baseline and a lactate of 3.8.\r\nHis chest x-ray showed no acute process.\r\nIMPRESSION:  My impression is that the patient has severe sepsis\r\nby virtue of evidence of change in his mental status and his\r\ncreatinine, he was given a liter of normal saline in the\r\nEmergency Department as a bolus.  Given that pneumonia and\r\nurinary tract infection were highest on the list, we decided to\r\ntreat him with Rocephin and azithromycin.  He will be admitted to\r\nthe Medical Service.\r\nJONES, JOHN M.D.\r\nD: 01/17/2020\r\nT: 01/17/2020", "qa_list": [{"question": "List all diagnoses of the patient separated by semicolon. If unknown return NA in output", "answer": "Dementia; SVT; hypertension; diabetes type 2", "justification": ["PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Dementia, SVT, hypertension, and diabetes\r\ntype 2."]}, {"question": "List the date of each diagnoses confirmation, separated by semicolon. If unknown return NA in ouput", "answer": "NA; NA; NA; NA", "justification": ["NA", "NA", "NA", "NA"]}, {"question": "List all procedures the patient has undergone separated by semicolon if none then return NA in output", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "List all current therapies the patient is receiving separated by semicolon, if unknown return NA", "answer": "Lisinopril; hydrochlorothiazide; omeprazole; Risperdal; Tegretol; verapamil; Tylenol", "justification": ["MEDICATIONS:  Lisinopril, hydrochlorothiazide, omeprazole,\r\nRisperdal, Tegretol, verapamil, and Tylenol #3."]}, {"question": "List the doses of each therapy separated by semicolon, if unknown return NA in output", "answer": "NA; NA; NA; NA; NA; NA; NA", "justification": ["NA", "NA", "NA", "NA", "NA", "NA", "NA"]}, {"question": "List all drugs or compounds the patients is allergic to separated by semicolon. If unknown return NA in output", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["ALLERGIES:  He has no known drug allergies."]}]}
{"id": 286, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-04-02", "note": "S: Pt is a 55 yo female admitted to Hospital from an unresponsive episode. Pt has a past medical history of sarcoidosis (hepatic), hypothyroidism, COPD, Cardiomyopathy with EF of 40%, Colonic AVM, diverticulitis, CVA/TIA, and Raynauds Disease.\r\nO: Stable pt, called out to the floor, alert and oriented x 4, stable blood pressure and HR, tol full liquids well, commode at bedside, foley remains until after hepatic stenting procedure (scheduled to be performed today), poor enous supply, 20 g PIV placed in L hand, no c/o pain, independent bed mobility, intact skin with healing L hand venous ulcer.\r\nA: Pt with a significant past medical history causing impaired neurological function.\r\nP: Cont to monitor and assess as ordered, prepare for possible surgery today to widen hepatic stent, transfer to medical surgical floor.", "qa_list": [{"question": "List all diagnoses of the patient separated by semicolon. If unknown return NA in output", "answer": "Hepatic sarcoidosis; hypothyroidism; COPD; Cardiomyopathy; Colonic AVM; Diverticulitis; CVA/TIA; Raynauds Disease", "justification": ["past medical history of sarcoidosis (hepatic), hypothyroidism, COPD, Cardiomyopathy with EF of 40%, Colonic AVM, diverticulitis, CVA/TIA, and Raynauds Disease."]}, {"question": "List all procedure the patients has undergone, separated by semicolon. If unknown return NA in output", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "List all the therapies that the patient is currently receiving, separated by semicolon. If unknown return NA", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 287, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "The patient must have an ECOG performance status of 0 or 1.", "note_date": "2020-07-03", "note": "A 72-year-old Japanese woman presented with abnormal chest opacity at an annual health checkup. She was a nonsmoker and had no specific medical history. Her Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status was zero. Chest computed tomography (CT) revealed a pulmonary nodule measuring 2.5\u00d71.6 cm in the left lower lobe. She underwent left lower lobectomy and systemic lymph node dissection. Based on the analysis of the nodule, she was diagnosed with adenocarcinoma (pT2aN2M0 Stage IIIA) harboring an EGFR exon 18 G719X mutation. She underwent four cycles of adjuvant chemotherapy with cisplatin plus vinorelbine. Recurrence with multiple intrapulmonary metastases and malignant pleural effusion were observed later. Genetic analysis of the pleural effusion at that time showed an EGFR exon 18 G719X mutation, as previously detected. Subsequently, she was treated with gefitinib for 15 months, and then, increased pleural effusion and carcinomatous lymphangiomatosis were noted. Both EGFR exon 18 G719X and exon 20 T790M mutations were detected in her plasma (Cobas\u2122 EGFR Mutation Test v2, Hoffman-La Roche Ltd., Basel, Switzerland). Her ECOG performance status declined to 2 because of worsening dyspnea, and she was treated with osimertinib. She died 9 days later from worsening respiratory failure with disease progression.", "qa_list": [{"question": "List all ECOG performance status values of the patient separated by semicolon. If unknown return NA in output", "answer": "0; 2", "justification": ["Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status was zero", "ECOG performance status declined to 2"]}, {"question": "List the date on which each score was calculated, separated by semicolon. If unknown return NA in output.", "answer": "NA; NA", "justification": ["NA", "NA"]}, {"question": "Does this patient have cancer?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["pulmonary nodule measuring 2.5\u00d71.6 cm", "diagnosed with adenocarcinoma"]}, {"question": "If so, name the type of cancer and the staging separated by comma. If unknown return NA", "answer": "Pulmonary adenocarcinoma, T2aN2M0 Stage IIIA", "justification": ["diagnosed with adenocarcinoma", "pT2aN2M0 Stage IIIA"]}, {"question": "If so, list all therapies the patient has received for each cancer, separated by semicolon", "answer": "cisplatin; vinorelbine; geftinib; osimertinib", "justification": ["adjuvant chemotherapy with cisplatin plus vinorelbine.", "treated with gefitinib", "treated with osimertinib"]}]}
{"id": 288, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2021-09-05", "note": "INDICATIONS: , Preoperative cardiac evaluation in the patient with chest pain in the setting of left hip fracture.,HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:,  The patient is a 78-year-old white female with no prior cardiac history.  She sustained a mechanical fall with a subsequent left femoral neck fracture.  She was transferred to XYZ Hospital for definitive care.  In the emergency department of XYZ, the patient described six to seven seconds of sharp chest pain without radiation, without associated symptoms.  Electrocardiogram was obtained, which showed nonspecific ST-segment flattening in the high lateral leads I, aVL.  She also had a left axis deviation.  Serial troponins were obtained.  She has had four negative troponins since admission.  Due to age and chest pain history, a cardiology consultation was requested preoperatively.,At the time of my evaluation, the patient complained of left hip pain, but no chest pain, dyspnea, or symptomatic dysrhythmia.,PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:,1.  Mesothelioma.,2.  Recurrent urinary tract infections.,3.  Gastroesophageal reflux disease/gastritis.,4.  Osteopenia.,5.  Right sciatica.,6.  Hypothyroidism.,7.  Peripheral neuropathy.,8.  Fibromyalgia.,9.  Chart review also suggests she has atherosclerotic heart disease and pneumothorax.  The patient denies either of these.,PAST SURGICAL HISTORY:,1.  Tonsillectomy.,2.  Hysterectomy.,3.  Appendectomy.,4.  Thyroidectomy.,5.  Coccygectomy.,6.  Cystoscopies times several.,7.  Bladder neck resuspension.,8.  Multiple breast biopsies.,ALLERGIES: , NO KNOWN DRUG ALLERGIES.,MEDICATIONS:,  At the time of evaluation include, 1.  Cefazolin 1 g intravenous (IV).  2.  Morphine sulfate.  3.  Ondansetron p.r.n.,OUTPATIENT MEDICATIONS: , 1.  Robaxin.  2.  Detrol 4 mg q.h.s.  3.  Neurontin 300 mg p.o. t.i.d.  4.  Armour Thyroid 90 mg p.o. daily.  5.  Temazepam, dose unknown p.r.n.  6.  Chloral hydrate, dose unknown p.r.n.,FAMILY HISTORY: , Mother had myocardial infarction in her 40s, died of heart disease in her 60s, specifics not known.  She knows nothing of her father's history.  She has no siblings.  There is no other history of premature atherosclerotic heart disease in the family.,SOCIAL HISTORY: , The patient is married, lives with her husband.  She is a lifetime nonsmoker, nondrinker.  She has not been getting regular exercise for approximately two years due to chronic sciatic pain.,REVIEW OF SYSTEMS: ,GENERAL:  The patient is able to walk one block or less prior to the onset of significant leg pain.  She ever denies any cardiac symptoms with this degree of exertion.  She denies any dyspnea on exertion or chest pain with activities of daily living.  She does sleep on two to three pillows, but denies orthopnea or paroxysmal nocturnal dyspnea.  She does have chronic lower extremity edema.  Her husband states that she has had prior chest pain in the past, but this has always been attributed to gastritis.  She denies any palpitations or tachycardia.  She has remote history of presyncope, no true syncope.,HEMATOLOGIC:  Negative for bleeding diathesis or coagulopathy.,ONCOLOGIC:  Remarkable for past medical history.,PULMONARY:  Remarkable for childhood pneumonia times several.  No recurrent pneumonias, bronchitis, reactive airway disease as an adult.,GASTROINTESTINAL:  Remarkable for past medical history.,GENITOURINARY:  Remarkable for past medical history.,MUSCULOSKELETAL:  Remarkable for past medical history.,CENTRAL NERVOUS SYSTEM:  Negative for tic, tremor, transient ischemic attack (TIA), seizure, or stroke.,PSYCHIATRIC:  Remarkable for history of depression as an adolescent, she was hospitalized at State Mental Institution as a young woman.  No recurrence.,PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:,GENERAL:  This is a well-nourished, well-groomed elderly white female who is appropriate and articulate at the time of evaluation.,VITAL SIGNS:  She has had a low-grade temperature of 100.4 degrees Fahrenheit on 11/20/2006, currently 99.6.  Pulse ranges from 123 to 86 beats per minute.  Blood pressure ranges from 124/65 to 152/67 mmHg.  Oxygen saturation on 2 L nasal cannula was 94%.,HEENT:  Exam is benign.  Normocephalic and atraumatic.  Extraocular motions are intact.  Sclerae anicteric.  Conjunctivae noninjected.  She does have bilateral arcus senilis.  Oral mucosa is pink and moist.", "qa_list": [{"question": "List all diagnoses of the patient separated by semicolon. If unknown return NA in output", "answer": "Mesothelioma; recurrent UTIs; Gastroesophageal reflux disease/gastritis; osteopenia; right sciatic; hypothyroidism; peripheral neuropathy; fibromyalgia", "justification": ["1.  Mesothelioma.,2.  Recurrent urinary tract infections.,3.  Gastroesophageal reflux disease/gastritis.,4.  Osteopenia.,5.  Right sciatica.,6.  Hypothyroidism.,7.  Peripheral neuropathy.,8.  Fibromyalgia."]}, {"question": "List all procedure the patients has undergone, separated by semicolon. If unknown return NA in output", "answer": "tonsillectomy; hysterectomy; appendectomy; thyroidectomy; coccygectomy; cytoscopies; bladder neck resuspension; multiple breast biopsies", "justification": ["1.  Tonsillectomy.,2.  Hysterectomy.,3.  Appendectomy.,4.  Thyroidectomy.,5.  Coccygectomy.,6.  Cystoscopies times several.,7.  Bladder neck resuspension.,8.  Multiple breast biopsies"]}, {"question": "List the date that each procedure was performed, separated by semicolon. If unknown return NA in output", "answer": "NA; NA; NA; NA; NA; NA; NA; NA", "justification": ["NA", "NA", "NA", "NA", "NA", "NA", "NA", "NA"]}, {"question": "List all current therapies of the patient separated by semicolon. If none return NA in output", "answer": "Robaxin; Detrol; Neurontin; Armor Thyroid; Temazepam; Chloral hydrate", "justification": ["1.  Robaxin.  2.  Detrol 4 mg q.h.s.  3.  Neurontin 300 mg p.o. t.i.d.  4.  Armour Thyroid 90 mg p.o. daily.  5.  Temazepam, dose unknown p.r.n.  6.  Chloral hydrate, dose unknown p.r.n"]}, {"question": "List the dose and the frequency of each drug separated by semicolon. Separate the dose and frequency by comma. if unknown return NA in output", "answer": "NA, NA; 4mg, q.h.s.; 300mg, t.i.d.; 90mg, daily; NA, p.r.n.; NA, p.r.n.", "justification": ["1.  Robaxin.  2.  Detrol 4 mg q.h.s.  3.  Neurontin 300 mg p.o. t.i.d.  4.  Armour Thyroid 90 mg p.o. daily.  5.  Temazepam, dose unknown p.r.n.  6.  Chloral hydrate, dose unknown p.r.n"]}]}
{"id": 289, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "The patient must have an ECOG performance status of 0 or 1.", "note_date": "2020-03-05", "note": "A 51-year-old woman was transferred from a nearby hospital after receiving heavy pretreatment for disseminated breast cancer. At the time of admission to our hospital in July 2017, the patient\u2019s general condition was poor, with an Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 4. She complained of widespread skin metastases with discharge and generalized edema (). According to her medical history, the patient was diagnosed with inoperable advanced TNBC and underwent 10 cycles of palliative chemotherapy with docetaxel and doxorubicin from May to December 2015, resulting in a partial response. However, the treatment was terminated owing to intolerance of the cumulative doxorubicin dose. Thereafter, the patient underwent a palliative modified radical mastectomy in December 2015. With ongoing disease progression, she received palliative radiotherapy and multiple lines of chemotherapy, including paclitaxel, gemcitabine, capecitabine, vinorelbine, and eribulin, before visiting our hospital.\r\nAt the time of admission, the patient\u2019s vital signs were stable and she was alert. Her chest computed tomography (CT) scan demonstrated a diffuse infiltrative mass lesion in the anterior chest wall with bilateral pleural effusion and multiple metastatic lymphadenopathies in both the neck and axilla. The abdomen-pelvis CT scan revealed multiple liver, lymph nodes, and abdominal wall metastases. Tissue biopsy of the right chest wall tumor mass identified the tumor as a triple-negative-type invasive ductal carcinoma (). Cisplatin monotherapy was selected based on the results of several pilot studies, which revealed a remarkable efficacy of cisplatin for TNBC [,]. We also took into consideration the patient\u2019s poor general condition and the mild cisplatin-induced toxicity. The patient received 75 mg/m2 of cisplatin every 3 weeks, along with standard hydration and antiemetic prophylaxis. Chemotherapy was administered in an in-patient setting because of the patient\u2019s poor general condition and the extensive dressing care needed for the metastatic skin lesions. After three cycles of cisplatin, the occurrence of skin ulcerative lesions was remarkably decreased. As the patient\u2019s ECOG performance status was dramatically improved to 1, the treatment was continued in an outpatient setting. After six cycles of the regimen, responses were further noted in both the liver and skin lesions (). With regard to adverse events, transient neutropenia and mild nausea were identified, yet both were manageable. The patient recently completed her 17th cycle of cisplatin with a good performance and minimal peripheral neuropathy ().\r\nAlthough she has no family history of breast or ovarian cancer, germline and somatic BRCA mutation tests were performed in the peripheral blood and primary/residual malignant tumor tissues for the potential use of a PARP inhibitor. However, no pathogenic BRCA mutation was identified ().\r\nThe patient provided written informed consent for publication of clinical details and images.", "qa_list": [{"question": "List all ECOG performance status values of the patient separated by semicolon. If unknown return NA in output", "answer": "4; 1", "justification": ["Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 4", "ECOG performance status was dramatically improved to 1"]}, {"question": "List the date on which each score was calculated, separated by semicolon. If unknown return NA in output.", "answer": "NA; NA", "justification": ["NA", "NA"]}, {"question": "Does the patient have cancer>", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["pretreatment for disseminated breast cancer"]}, {"question": "If so, list the type of cancers, separated by semicolon. If unknown return NA in output.", "answer": "breast cancer", "justification": ["pretreatment for disseminated breast cancer"]}]}
{"id": 290, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2021-04-21", "note": "Record date: 2021-04-21\r\nPROGRESS NOTE\t\t\t\t            \tDOB:\t\t07-17-64\r\nHISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  This is a 62-year-old gentleman with past medical history significant schizophrenia/personality disorder, tonsillectomy, cholecystectomy, left arm fracture, chronic fatigue, mole, seborrheic dermatitis, pancreatitis, hyperlipidemia, who returns for a follow-up of Lipitor. He stopped taking this medicine five days ago when the prescription ran out.  He states that he did not understand that it could be refilled.  He denies chest pain, shortness of breath, nausea.  He noted no bloating or abdominal pain with his medication.\r\nREVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Otherwise negative.\r\nPAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  As above.\r\nMEDICATIONS:  Prozac, Lisinopril 10 q.d., Zyprexa, aspirin.\r\nALLERGIES:  No known drug allergies.\r\nHEALTH CARE MAINTENANCE:  Stool cards due.  Immunizations current.\r\nPHYSICAL EXAM:  The patient is in no acute distress.  Blood pressure 124/88.  Weight is 237.  Pulse is 80 and regular.  Lungs: Clear to auscultation bilaterally without wheezes, rhonchi or rales.  Cardiac:  Regular rate and rhythm.\r\nASSESSMENT AND PLAN:\r\n(1)\tThe active issues today is hyperlipidemia.  Fasting cholesterol is to be drawn tomorrow as well as liver function tests; however, he has been off the medicine for five to seven days and it may be elevated.  I explained to him the importance of compliance with this medicine and I recommended that he continue taking it on a regular basis.\r\n(2)\tWith regard to healthcare maintenance issues, he was given stool cards today and he will have a complete physical over the summer.  Immunizations are current.", "qa_list": [{"question": "List all diagnoses of the patient separated by semicolon. If unknown return NA in output", "answer": "schizophrenia/personality disorder; tonsillectomy; cholecystectomy; left arm fracture; chronic fatigue; mole; seborrheic dermatitis; pancreatitis; hyperlipidemia", "justification": ["past medical history significant schizophrenia/personality disorder, tonsillectomy, cholecystectomy, left arm fracture, chronic fatigue, mole, seborrheic dermatitis, pancreatitis, hyperlipidemia"]}, {"question": "List all therapies the patient is currently receiving, separated by semicolon.", "answer": "Prozac; Lisinopril; Zyprexa; Aspirin", "justification": ["MEDICATIONS:  Prozac, Lisinopril 10 q.d., Zyprexa, aspirin."]}, {"question": "List the dose and frequency of each therapy separated by semicolon. Separate the dose and the frequency of each drug by comma. If unknown return NA", "answer": "NA, NA; 10, q.d.; NA,NA; NA, NA", "justification": ["Prozac,", "Lisinopril 10 q.d.", "Zyprexa", "aspirin."]}, {"question": "List all allergies of the patient, separated by semicolon. If unknown return NA", "answer": "None known", "justification": ["ALLERGIES:  No known drug allergies."]}]}
{"id": 299, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "Patient had a mastectomy", "note_date": "2021-02-15", "note": "HPI:\r\n60 yo female w/ h/o breast CA metastatized to the liver s/p R\r\ntrisegmentectomy, cholecystectomy, Roux-en-Y hepaticojejunostomy, RFA\r\nand R adrenalectomy. The patient was first diagnosed with BC in 2018\r\nand underwent a R mastectomy and four rounds of chemotherapy followed\r\nby prophylactic bilateral mastectomy in 2018.\r\nIn 2021-2-15, CT scan of the abdomen demonstrated extensive\r\ninvolvement of the R liver love and liver biopsy showed poorly\r\ndifferentiated carcinoma. She underwent R hepatic vein embolization on\r\n2021-3-17.  Now s/p R trisegmentectomy, RFA of L lobe lesions, R\r\nadrenalectomy.  Got 5L crystal, 500 hespan, PRBC x1, UOP 550, EBL 1L\r\nChief complaint:\r\nabd pain\r\nPMHx:\r\n2018: ER positive HER-2 positive breast CA with extensive mets to\r\nliver treated with cytoxan, adriamycin, Taxol and herceptin\r\n- notable for agoraphobia, anxiety\r\nPSH:\r\n- 2020: right portal vein embolization\r\n- 2020: completion of Right mastectomy\r\n- 2018: L mastectomy\r\n- 2018: R parital mastectomy\r\n- 2018: D&C\r\n- 2017: appendectomy\r\nCancer (Malignant Neoplasm), Hepatic (Liver)\r\nAssessment:\r\nVital signs stable\r\nPt alert and oriented X3\r\nHaving occasional periods of confusion, but easily reoriented\r\nVery anxious all evening\r\nimpulsive behavior bordering on unsafe\r\nPt denies pain meds, but appears uncomfortable\r\nAbd softly distended, + BS, + flatus\r\npassing 2 small stools\r\nAbd dressing intact\r\nJP cont to drain mod amount of sero-sang drg\r\nT tube draining small amount bile\r\nAction:\r\nPt OOB to chair several times this past eve\r\nBack rubs and repositioning very frequently\r\nMed with dilaudid at 2300,& 0200 for noticeable discomfort\r\nResponse:\r\nPt resting in long naps for remainder of night\r\nVital signs remain stable\r\nPlan:\r\nEmotional support for pt and family", "qa_list": [{"question": "Does the patient have cancer?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["first diagnosed with BC"]}, {"question": "If so, what type of cancer does the patient have?", "answer": "Breast cancer", "justification": ["first diagnosed with BC"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the cancer diagnosed?", "answer": "2018", "justification": ["first diagnosed with BC in 2018"]}, {"question": "Has the patient undergone mastectomy?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["prophylactic bilateral mastectomy"]}, {"question": "If so what type of procedures did the patient undergo for this cancer?", "answer": "Bilateral mastectomy", "justification": ["prophylactic bilateral mastectomy"]}, {"question": "List the date of each procedure, separated by semicolon. If unknown return NA in output", "answer": "2018", "justification": ["prophylactic bilateral mastectomy in 2018"]}, {"question": "What type of therapies did the patient receive for the canceR?", "answer": "chemotherapy", "justification": ["four rounds of chemotherapy"]}]}
{"id": 300, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "Patient had a mastectomy", "note_date": "2021-04-15", "note": "2021-4-15 11:10 AM\r\nUNILAT DIAGNOSTIC MAMMOGRAM LEFT                                \r\nReason: h/o r mastectomy\r\nMEDICAL CONDITION:\r\n81 year old woman with\r\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION:\r\nh/o r mastectomy\r\nFINAL REPORT\r\nINDICATION:  S/p right mastectomy.  S/p left lumpectomy and radiation therapy\r\nin [**2108**].  Patient on Tamoxifen.  Further history reveals menarche at age 10\r\nand first full-term pregnancy age 31.\r\nLEFT DIAGNOSTIC MAMMOGRAM:  Breast tissues are relatively fatty with\r\narchitectural distortion in the lower inner quadrant.  No primary or secondary\r\nsign of malignancy is seen today.\r\nIMPRESSION:  No evidence of new or recurrent malignancy in the left breast.\r\nPostop changes in lower inner quadrant. BIRADS 2--benign findings.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Does the patient have cancer?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, list all types of cancer, separated by semicolon. If unknown return NA in output", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "List all procedures the patient has undergone, separated by semicolon.", "answer": "Right mastectomy", "justification": ["right mastectomy."]}, {"question": "List all therapies the patient is currently receiving separated by semicolon. If unknown return NA.", "answer": "Tamoxifen", "justification": ["Patient on Tamoxifen"]}]}
{"id": 306, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04187833", "criterion": "Subjects must have histologically or cytologically confirmed diagnosis of primary or recurrent metastatic melanoma.", "note_date": "2021-12-31", "note": "54 yo male S/P left craniotomy, 2020-7-22 with resection of tumor (metastatic melanoma involving the meningies(leptomenigeal). Patient overnighted in PACU for management of HTN with nipride drip. Patient started on po meds but was unable to wean from nipride drip. Hydralizine iv was given; patient had episode of reflexive tachycardia with ischemia- c/o chest pressure with ST changes. Episode resolved with lopressor 5mg ivp. Cardiology consult was obtained. Plan includes beta-blockers (lopressor), ace inhibitor(lisinopril), treat pain & anxiety(prn pain and anti anxietals available), avoid nipride and hydralizine, follow serial enzymes & EKG, ASA when ok with neurosurgical team, and give IVF if hypotension occurs.\r\nPMH: recently diagnosed with melanoma by biopsy of scalp lesion in 2020-02-30. Neck swelling bx also positive for melanoma. Pt had left modified neck dissection in 2020-3-28 with diagnosis of stage 111C melanoma. Patient developed seizures ~ 3 weeks ago, described as right arm shaking, asphasia, and  with right face twitching with most recent seizure activity on 2020-7-20. Keppra therapy was started. MRI revealed a bleed in left frontoparietal area with underlying lesion.\r\nHTN diagnosed in 2003 but not treated\r\nLVH\r\npatient states 'murmur' since childhood\r\n**family history of melanoma: mother and 2 sisters**\r\nMEDS: keppra 1500mg \r\nlabetalol 100mg\r\ndecadron (since  4mg TID (weaning doses)\r\nfish oil qd\r\nALLERGIES: no known allergies\r\npatient states he has a gluten intolerance but denies formal diagnosis of such.\r\nSOCIAL- patient is divorced father of 2 grown children(son & daughter).\r\nlives with son in [**Name (NI) 45**]\r\nis self employed as a landscaper; worked up until admission for surgery.\r\nSee careview for objective data.\r\nNEURO- awake, alert, oriented x3; MAE's and follows commands consistently. Normal strength in all extremities except RUE which he can lift & hold but exhibit weak grasp and some pronator drift. Patient denies sensory deficit. Perrl at 3mm/brisk with left pupil asymmetrical(reported as baseline). Speech is clear and coherant. No seizure activity noted, keppra dosing continues. + cough/gag.\r\nStates incisional discomfort [**3-2**] without change following 2 percocets but improved following ativan .5mg po. Patient exhibiting moderate anxiety- improved following ativan dose.(per family report: patient has baseline anxiety- untreated)\r\nDecadron therapy.\r\nAwaiting Post-op MRI.\r\nCVS- SB in 50 range without ectopy. EKG reveals T wave inversion in L1 &L & V [**1-28**] depression. Blood pressure goal per cardiology is ~ 130 systolic. Initial troponin negative with second serial specimen pending. Arterial line has fling artifact; NBP ranges less than 130 at this time. Lopressor dosing continues. No complaint of chest pressure.\r\nRENAL- adequate output per hour, IVF infusing at 80cc/hour\r\nGI- tolerating regular diet(gluten free). PPI therapy. Abdomeen soft with bowel sounds. Bowel regimen", "qa_list": [{"question": "List all diagnosis of the patient, separated by semicolon.", "answer": "metastatic melanoma; hypertension; LVH", "justification": ["resection of tumor (metastatic melanoma)", "HTN diagnosed in 2003 but not treated\r\nLVH"]}, {"question": "Does the patient have cancer?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["resection of tumor (metastatic melanoma)"]}, {"question": "If so, what type of cancer does the patient have?", "answer": "Melanoma", "justification": ["resection of tumor (metastatic melanoma)"]}, {"question": "If so, is the cancer metastatic?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["resection of tumor (metastatic melanoma)"]}, {"question": "If so, has the cancer been histologically or cytologically confirmed?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["recently diagnosed with melanoma by biopsy of scalp lesion"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the cancer diagnoses?", "answer": "2020-02-30", "justification": ["recently diagnosed with melanoma by biopsy of scalp lesion in 2020-02-30"]}, {"question": "List all therapies the patient is receiving, separated by semicolon.", "answer": "keppra; labetalol; decadron; fish oil", "justification": ["keppra 1500mg \r\nlabetalol 100mg\r\ndecadron (since  4mg TID (weaning doses)\r\nfish oil qd"]}, {"question": "List the dose of each drug separated by semicolon. If unknown return NA in output", "answer": "1500mg; 100mg; 4mg; NA", "justification": ["keppra 1500mg \r\nlabetalol 100mg\r\ndecadron (since  4mg TID (weaning doses)\r\nfish oil qd"]}]}
{"id": 307, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04187833", "criterion": "Diagnosis of Myelodysplastic Syndrome (MDS)", "note_date": "2020-09-01", "note": "A 32-year-old male, without significant past medical history, he was admitted in the department of clinical hematology for a diagnostic workup for fatigue and dyspnea on exertion. At admission, patient appeared pale but vital signs were within normal limits. Physical examination revealed nail dystrophy (), leukokeratosis plaques on the tongue (), Hyperkeratotic and pigmented patches were present on the back, neck, trunk and palms (). Patient did not have a history of tobacco usage. The onset of the cutaneous lesions was at 7 years of age with slow and progressive accentuation. Patient mentioned presence of similar case in his family (brother, uncle {maternal side}). Mental retardation was not observed. Admission labs included WBC: 2.200 cells/ul, Absolute neutrophil count: 1.500 cells/ul, hemoglobin 8 g/dl, platelet: 65 000/ul, creatinine: 1 mg/dl, ALT: 13 U/L, international normalization ratio (INR):1.9. Bone marrow aspiration and biopsy was done and showed normocellularity with trilineage dysplastic changes, dysplastic changes in RBC lineage were characteristic ). According to these findings, the diagnosis of myelodysplastic syndrome (MDS) was confirmed. Ultrasound (US) of the abdomen revealed, coarsened hepatic echotexture, moderate splenomegaly 15.5 cm and an important dilation of the splenic veins at the splenic hilum and the portal veins. Therefore, portal hypertension was suspected due to hepatic cirrhosis/fibrosis. The patient was referred for gastrointestinal consultation then prepared for high-digestive endoscopy, which revealed, grade I esophageal varices. Unfortunately, percutaneous liver biopsy was contraindicated due to tendency to bleed because of thrombocytopenia and prolonged INR. Therefore, prophylactic propranolol was initiated. Viral marker for hepatitis B or C that could cause pancytopenia showed no specific viral infection. The patient did not present with respiratory complaint, chest X-ray indicated hilar enlargement after which CT of the chest showed no abnormality. Epiphora was mentioned and punctual atresia was suspected but the patient refused to be referred for ophthalmologic consultation. The patient in this study presented all the components of the triad, in addition to bone marrow dysplasia, hepatic cirrhosis and ophthalmologic manifestation. We started the treatment with danazol a synthetic androgen derivative also known as 17\u03b1-ethinyl testosterone. Three-week later a good hematologic response was observed, WBC: 5500 cells/ul, Absolute neutrophil count: 3000 cells/ul, Hgb: 9 g/dl and Plt: 95 000/ul. The patient currently undergoing outpatient treatment at the hematology and gastroenterology outpatient clinics.", "qa_list": [{"question": "List all diagnosis of the patient, separate by semicolon.", "answer": "Myelodysplastic syndrome", "justification": ["diagnosis of myelodysplastic syndrome (MDS)"]}, {"question": "List all procedure the patients has undergone, separated by semicolon. If unknown return NA in output", "answer": "Bone marrow aspiration; biopsy", "justification": ["Bone marrow aspiration and biopsy"]}, {"question": "List all imaging exams that the patient has undergone separated by semicolon.", "answer": "US of the abdomen; chest CT; chest X-ray", "justification": ["Ultrasound (US) of the abdomen revealed", "CT of the chest showed", "chest X-ray indicated"]}]}
{"id": 308, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04187833", "criterion": "Diagnosis of Myelodysplastic Syndrome (MDS)", "note_date": "2020-09-07", "note": "transfer and progress note.\r\na 59 year old man with a past medical history of iddm x 12 years, cad, mi in 2017, syncopal episodes was cath for 3 vessel dz ef was 40%.water skiing accident in 2028 .has no allergies.\r\ns/p cabg x4 on 2018-2-1 was uneventfull.on ntg post op.has had no blood products.\r\nneuro:awake,alert oriented x3.moves all exremities on command.was able to stand and pivot to chair.\r\nresp:breath sounds clear,but diminished bibasilar.spo2 98%on 4l np.coughing and raising clear white secretions.\r\npain:medicated with toradol and 2 percoets with good relief.\r\ncv:remains in nsr with stable bp.not started on lopressor as yet.\r\ngu:foley to cd draining clear yellow urine.had ist dose of lasix,\r\ngi:abd soft with positive bowel sounds.tolerates full diet.no stool today.\r\nsocial:wife visited.", "qa_list": [{"question": "List all diagnoses of the patient, separated by semicolon.", "answer": "IDDM; CAD; MI; syncopal episodes", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "Does the patient have myelodysplastic syndrome?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "List all procedures the patient has undergone, separated by semicolon.", "answer": "CABG x3", "justification": ["cabg x4"]}, {"question": "List the date of each procedure, separated by semicolon, if unknown return NA.", "answer": "2018", "justification": ["2018-2-1"]}]}
{"id": 309, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-07-28", "note": "07/28/2020\r\nPRESENTING COMPLAINT:  Chest pain.\r\nHISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  The patient was seen in the\r\nemergency department with Dr. Holden.  History was reviewed with Dr.\r\nHolden and patient.  Briefly, this is a 59 year old gentleman with a\r\npast medical history positive for insulin dependent diabetes, CVA,\r\npeptic ulcer disease, who presented to the emergency department\r\nwith acute substernal chest pain radiating to the left arm,\r\npositive diaphoresis and shortness of breath, three or four\r\nepisodes in the last few hours, the last episode lasting 20\r\nminutes.\r\nREVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  As documented by Dr. Holmes.\r\nPAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  As documented by Dr. Holmes.\r\nMEDICATIONS:  As documented by Dr. Holmes.\r\nALLERGIES:  As documented by Dr. Holmes.\r\nSOCIAL HISTORY AND FAMILY HISTORY:  As documented by Dr. Holmes.\r\nPHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  No acute distress.  Blood pressure is\r\n120/100, pulse 100 and regular, respirations 16, afebrile, O2 sat\r\non room air 97%.  Negative HEENT.  Patent airway.  Neck:  Supple,\r\nno JVD, nodes or bruits.  Lungs:  Clear, equal breath sounds.\r\nHeart:  Regular rate, no murmur.  No chest wall tenderness.\r\nAbdomen:  Soft, positive bowel sounds.  Extremities:  No\r\ndeformities.  Guaiac negative.  Neurologic:  Alert, nonfocal.  The\r\nrest of the examination is unremarkable.\r\nLABORATORY EVALUATION:  Electrolytes, BUN and creatinine were\r\nwithin normal limits.  Glucose of 26.  CBC negative.  CK 75,\r\ntroponin 0.  EKG shows hyperacute T wave in V1 and V2.\r\nTHERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  In the emergency department, the\r\npatient was treated with IV Heparin, Nitroglycerin, aspirin.\r\nSymptoms improved markedly, and he was transferred to the Cardiac\r\nService for further evaluation and treatment.\r\nFINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Chest pain, rule out M.I.", "qa_list": [{"question": "List all diagnoses of the patients, separated by semicolon, If unknown return NA.", "answer": "insulin dependent diabetes; CVA; peptic ulcer disease", "justification": ["insulin dependent diabetes, CVA,\r\npeptic ulcer disease"]}, {"question": "List all therapies the patient is currently receiving, if unknown return NA.", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "Does the patient have cancer?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 305, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2021-04-30", "note": "2021-4-30 11:23 AM\r\nMR HEAD W & W/O CONTRAST; MR CONTRAST GADOLIN\r\nReason: metastatic esophageal cancer to the brain\r\nContrast: MAGNEVIST Amt: 15\r\nMEDICAL CONDITION:\r\n48 year old man with h/o esoph cancer\r\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION:\r\nmetastatic esophageal cancer to the brain\r\nFINAL REPORT\r\nINDICATIONS:  Esophageal cancer, metastatic to the brain. Followup study.\r\nMRI OF THE BRAIN WITH GADOLINIUM ENHANCEMENT:\r\nTECHNIQUE:   Multiplanar T1 and T2W gadolinium enhanced images were obtained.\r\nFINDINGS:  Comparison  to previous films from 2021-3-29 reveals considerable\r\nreduction in the extent of the enhancement, particularly the dural based\r\ncomponents within the right side of the posterior fossa. The ring enhancing\r\nintra-axial cerebellar lesion has also decreased in size this locale. There is\r\ndramatic reduction in the FLAIR signal hyperintensity in this area and there\r\nis compression of the fourth ventricle or hydrocephalus at this time.\r\nCONCLUSION:  Dramatic reduction in extent of pathological enhancement within\r\nthe posterior fossa, suggesting response to therapy.", "qa_list": [{"question": "list all PSA levels of the patient in the order that they are mentioned in the note, separated by comma", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, list the corresponding time of each PSA level measurement presented, separated by comma. If there is no date associated with the PSA level, return NA", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 304, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2022-11-19", "note": "37 yo female with extensive metastatic colon cancer now with mets to\r\nbrain, lung, abd wall and pelvis, s/p hemicolectomy, chemo, radiation,\r\nand recent craniotomy in 10-25 for new brain mets, presents with 3 wks\r\nof worsening cough and sob, ruled out for flu, intubated\r\npersistent hypoxemic respiratory failure despite optimal treatment of\r\npneumonia and exploration of all options for further intervention to\r\nmaintain airway patency explored and nothing further able to be\r\noffered.  No further therapy for cancer available per oncology team at\r\nthis point.\r\ntwo days ago ruled out for flu as outpatient and started on levofloxacin, presents to ed today with O2sats of 85 %, on RA and RR in the 50s, no improvement noted on NRB, pan cultured,\r\nextensive discussions with patient and HCP regarding cost/benefit of\r\nintubation, patient elected to be intubated, pt intubated, CVL placed,\r\ngiven 2 L of IVP for borderline low BPs, and transferred to MICU for\r\nfurther management", "qa_list": [{"question": "List all diagnoses of the patient, separated by comma. If unknown, return NA.", "answer": "Colon cancer with brain, lung, abdominal wall and pelvis metastases.", "justification": ["metastatic colon cancer now with mets to\r\nbrain, lung, abd wall and pelvis"]}, {"question": "If so, list all respective dates of diagnosis for each diagnosis, separated by date. If unknown, return NA.", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 301, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "Patients intending to continue on oral, transdermal, or subdermal estrogen replacement (including all estrogen only and estrogen-progesterone formulas) are not eligible. Patients that discontinue oral, transdermal, or subdermal estrogen replacement prior to registration are eligible.", "note_date": "2022-04-29", "note": "2022-4-29 2:42 PM\r\nPELVIS, NON-OBSTETRIC; PELVIS U.S., TRANSVAGINAL\r\nReason: R/O endometrium thickening\r\nMEDICAL CONDITION:\r\n55 year old woman with postmenopausal bleeding, on estrogen/progesterone.\r\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION:\r\nR/O endometrium thickening\r\nFINAL REPORT\r\nHISTORY: Post-menopausal bleeding. Patient is on hormonal replacement therapy.\r\nTransabdominal ultrasound demonstrates a uterus that measures 7.6 by 4.7 by\r\n3.8 cm. Transvaginal ultrasound was performed for further evaluation of the\r\nendometrium and ovaries. There is a large calcified fundal fibroid that\r\ndeflects the endometrium posteriorly which measured 3.5 by 2.9 by 3.4.\r\nendometrium measured 6 mm and is unremarkable. The left ovary is identified\r\nand measured 1.4 by 1.3 by 1 cm and is unremarkable. The right ovary is\r\nsuboptimally evaluated. There is no right adnexal masses. There is no free\r\nfluid. Evaluation of the kidneys demonstrates no hydronephrosis.\r\nIMPRESSION:\r\nFibroid uterus, the largest of which is located fundally and deflects the\r\nendometrium posteriorly. This limits evaluation of the endometrium.", "qa_list": [{"question": "List all estrogen replacement therapies that the patient has received, separated by comma.", "answer": "estrogen/progesterone replacement", "justification": ["woman with postmenopausal bleeding, on estrogen/progesterone."]}, {"question": "If so, is the patient currently under estrogen replacement therapy?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["woman with postmenopausal bleeding, on estrogen/progesterone."]}]}
{"id": 303, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2022-01-19", "note": "2022-1-19 3:21 PM\r\nCHEST (PORTABLE AP)\r\nReason: evaluate line placement.\r\nAdmitting Diagnosis: MYELODYSPLASTIC SYNDROME;FEVER;NEUTROPENIA\r\nMEDICAL CONDITION:\r\n54 year old man with myelodysplastic syndrome, neutropenic fever.  port\r\nleaking and with poor return.  evaluate line placement\r\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION:\r\nevaluate line placement.\r\nFINAL REPORT\r\nCLINICAL HISTORY:  Myelodysplastic syndrome, fever, line placed, check\r\nposition.\r\nThe film is underpenetrated on the exact position of the end of the line,\r\ncannot be assessed.  It probably has not changed in position since prior chest\r\nx-ray.  Again noted is, consolidation in the right lower lobe and some new\r\natelectasis in the left lower lobe is seen.\r\nThe opacity in the left upper lobe is again noted.\r\nIMPRESSION:  Position of central line probably unchanged, but difficult to\r\nevaluate.  Right lower lobe pneumonia persists as does density in the left\r\nupper lobe.", "qa_list": [{"question": "List all estrogen replacement therapies that the patient has received, separated by comma. If unknown, return NA.", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, is the patient currently under estrogen replacement therapy?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 302, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04187833", "criterion": "Subjects must have histologically or cytologically confirmed diagnosis of primary or recurrent metastatic melanoma.", "note_date": "2020-08-06", "note": "A 35-year-old male nonsmoker was referred to us for evaluation of cough and breathlessness of two weeks duration. He had malignant melanoma (nodular type) of scalp eight months ago but did not undergo surgery. There was no history of any other significant illness. On physical examination, there was biopsy scar over the occipital region and naevi all over the body. There was no digital clubbing or significant lymphadenopathy. Chest examination showed features of bilateral pleural effusion. Abdominal examination revealed nodular hepatomegaly. Other systems including eyes were clinically normal. A chest radiograph showed bilateral pleural effusion, massive on left side. Upon diagnostic thoracentesis on both sides, dark colored pleural fluid was aspirated and its cytological examination showed malignant cells, some of them contained variable amount of melanin pigment in their cytoplasm. The cytoplasmic pigment stained black with Fontana Masson's cytoplasmic stain, highlighting the presence of cytoplasmic melanin within the tumor cells.\r\nA cytological diagnosis of metastatic malignant melanoma was made. Ultrasound examination of abdomen showed hepatomegaly. Pleural effusion re-accumulated rapidly despite repeated therapeutic pleurocenteses. Tube thoracostomy was done on left side for drainage of the pleural fluid. After three days, the left lung expanded completely showing patchy opacities over upper lobe and the daily pleural fluid drainage was less than 100ml. The pleurodesis was attempted with 2 mg of vincristine diluted in 50 ml of normal saline through thoracostomy tube after clamping it distally. Intramuscular tramadol was given to reduce the pain after the pleurodesis. The chest tube was unclamped after two hours and removed the next day as pleural drainage was less than 50ml. Two months later, the patient presented with cough and right sided pleuritic chest pain of one week duration. Cough was occasional and nonproductive.\r\nChest radiograph showed increase in size of left upper lobe mass and pleural effusion on right side. Cytological examination of pleural fluid showed metastatic malignant melanoma. The chest pain improved with the oral morphine and the pleurodesis was done for right sided pleural effusion using vincristine. After discharge, patient did not come for review and was lost to follow up.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Does the patient have cancer?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["cytological diagnosis of metastatic malignant melanoma was made"]}, {"question": "If so, does what type of cancer does the patient have?", "answer": "Metastatic malignant melanoma", "justification": ["cytological diagnosis of metastatic malignant melanoma was made"]}, {"question": "If so, is the cancer metastatic?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["cytological diagnosis of metastatic malignant melanoma was made"]}, {"question": "Was the cancer histologically or cytologically confirmed?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Cytological examination of pleural fluid showed metastatic malignant melanoma"]}]}
{"id": 298, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04187833", "criterion": "Platelet count \u2265 90,000/mcL.", "note_date": "2023-01-09", "note": "MICU NPN 1900-0700\r\nNeuro: Pt lethargic, opens eyes to voice, follows commands intermittently. Oriented to person only. Low speech, but clearer than initial assessment. Denies pain. At 0500, pt with increased RR and BP, pt said she was nervous, and received 1mg Ativan IVP.\r\nResp: On 50% face tent. Breath sounds coarse with scattered ronchi in all fields. RR 20's, shallow at times. Weak, congested cough, but unable to completely clear secretions. ABG last pm was 7.42/32/72.\r\nCV: ST, no etopy noted. BP stable. Afebrile overnight, skin warm, dry, brisk cap refill. + peripheral pulses x4 limbs. 2+ LE edema. Received 1U platelets for plt count 26, repeat plt count was 86. Goal platelet count>30, goal Hct>30.\r\nID: Increasing WBC count 3->9->13.5 over 24 hours. AM labs pending. Treated with cyclosporin, flagyl, cefepime, caspofungin, bacitracin. Vancomycin dosed on levels. Vancomycin and Cyclosporin levels pending. BMT precautions.\r\nIV access: RSC 3-lumen Hickman, R wrist #18g, R hand #20g. Left radial Aline patent with sharp waveform.\r\nF/E/N: Abdomen soft, nontender with + bowel sounds. TPN infusing at 62.5 cc/hr. Brown liquid stool, rectal bag intact. Blood sugar 133, no SSI required. K+ replaced, repeat lab pending. Foley patent with clear yellow UOP. Diuresed with 40 mg lasix last pm with excellent results.\r\nDerm: Gums bleeding. Nystatin oral suspension used. Lips dry and chapped, vaseline used.\r\nSoc: Husband and mother updated on pt's condition.", "qa_list": [{"question": "List all platelet count values of the patient, separated by comma. If unknown, return NA.", "answer": "26, 86", "justification": ["plt count 26, repeat plt count was 86."]}, {"question": "If so, what is the most recent platelet count value of the patient?", "answer": "86", "justification": ["repeat plt count was 86"]}, {"question": "If so, what is the date of measurement of the most recent platelet count value, on a date relative to the clinical note?", "answer": "2023-01-09", "justification": ["Note date : 2023-01-09", "Received 1U platelets for plt count 26, repeat plt count was 86"]}]}
{"id": 297, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04187833", "criterion": "Platelet count \u2265 90,000/mcL.", "note_date": "2021-07-09", "note": "2021-7-9 8:50 PM\r\nCHEST (PA & LAT)\r\nReason: confirm PICC line placement for use, determine pulm/cardio p\r\nMEDICAL CONDITION:\r\n76 year old man with low platelet count.\r\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION:\r\nconfirm PICC line placement for use, determine pulm/cardio processes.\r\nFINAL REPORT\r\nINDICATION:  Low platelet count, confirm PICC placement.\r\nCOMPARISON:  None.\r\nPA AND LATERAL VIEWS OF THE CHEST:  Right PICC tip terminates within the upper\r\nSVC.  Heart size is top normal.  The mediastinal and hilar contours are\r\nunremarkable.  There is a probable small right subpulmonic effusion, with\r\nsmall amount of pleural fluid loculated along the right lateral base of the\r\nhemithorax.  The lungs are otherwise clear.  No left-sided pleural effusion is\r\nseen, and there is no pneumothorax.  Multilevel degenerative changes are\r\npresent within the thoracic spine with anterior osteophyte formation.\r\nIMPRESSION:\r\n1.  Right PICC tip terminates in the upper SVC.\r\n2.  Small right subpulmonic effusion, with loculated pleural effusion along\r\nthe right lateral base.", "qa_list": [{"question": "List all platelet count values of the patient, separated by comma. If unknown, return NA.", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, what is the most recent platelet count value of the patient?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, what is the date of measurement of the most recent platelet count value, on a date relative to the clinical note?", "answer": "2021-07-09", "justification": ["2021-7-9 8:50 PM", "76 year old man with low platelet count."]}]}
{"id": 296, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2021-08-12", "note": "ADMITTING DIAGNOSES:  Left renal cell carcinoma, left renal cyst.\r\nDISCHARGE DIAGNOSIS: Left renal cell carcinoma, left renal cyst.\r\nSECONDARY DIAGNOSES: 1.  Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease.,2.  Coronary artery disease.\r\nPROCEDURES: Robotic-Assisted laparoscopic left renal cyst decortication and cystoscopy.\r\nHISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS: Mr. Humphrey is a 70-year-old male who has been diagnosed with a left renal cell carcinoma with multiple renal cysts.  He has undergone MRI of the abdomen on June 18, 2021 revealing an enhancing mass of the upper pole of the left kidney consistent with his history of renal cell carcinoma.  Of note, there are no other enhancing solid masses seen on this MRI.  After discussion of multiple management strategies with the patient including: 1.  Left partial nephrectomy., 2. Left radical nephrectomy., 3.  Left renal cyst decortication.  The patient is likely to undergo the latter procedure.\r\nHOSPITAL COURSE: The patient was admitted in 08/08/2021, to undergo left renal cyst decortication as well as a cystoscopy.  Intraoperatively, approximately four enlarged renal cysts and six smaller renal cysts were initially removed.  The contents were aspirated and careful dissection of the cyst wall was performed.  Multiple specimens of the cyst wall were sent for pathology.  Approximately one liter of cystic fluid was drained during the procedure.  The renal bed was inspected for hemostasis, which appear to be adequate.  There were no complications with the procedure.  Single JP drain was left in place.  Additionally, the patient underwent flexible cystoscopy, which revealed no gross strictures or any other abnormalities in the penile nor prostatic urethra.  Furthermore, no gross lesions were encountered in the bladder.  The patient left OR with transfer to the PACU and subsequently to the hospital floor. The patient's postoperative course was relatively uneventful.  His diet and activity were gradually advanced without complication.  On postoperative day #2, he was passing flatus and has had bowel movements.  His Jackson-Pratt drain was discontinued on postoperative day #3 that being the day of discharge.  His Foley catheter was removed on the morning of discharge and the patient subsequently passed the voiding trial without difficultly.  At the time of discharge, he was afebrile.  His vital signs indicated hemodynamic stability and he had no evidence of infection.  The patient was instructed to follow up with Dr. Waldorf on 8/12/2021 at 1:50 p.m. and was given prescription for pain medications as well as laxative.\r\nDISPOSITION: To home. \r\nDISCHARGE CONDITION:  Good.\r\nMEDICATIONS: Please see attached medication list.\r\nINSTRUCTIONS: The patient was instructed to contact Dr. Waldorf's office for fever greater than 101.5, intractable pain, nausea, vomiting, or any other concerns.\r\nFOLLOWUP: The patient will follow up with Dr. Waldorf for a postoperative check on 08/12/2021 at 1:50 p.m. and he was made aware of this appointment.", "qa_list": [{"question": "List all cancer diagnoses of the patient, separated by comma. If unknown, return NA.", "answer": "Left renal cell carcinoma", "justification": ["ADMITTING DIAGNOSES:  Left renal cell carcinoma"]}, {"question": "If so, list the corresponding date of diagnosis for each cancer diagnosis, separated by comma. If unknown, return NA.", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, list all anti-cancer therapies that the patient has received, separated by comma. If unknown, return NA.", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 295, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2022-07-23", "note": "A 49-year-old premenopausal woman had undergone total mastectomy and sentinel lymph node biopsy for stage I right breast cancer in April 2013. The histological diagnosis was invasive ductal carcinoma of the right breast with no metastasis in one sentinel lymph node. Immunohistochemical (IHC) examinations of the tumor cells showed negative results for both estrogen receptor (ER) and progesterone receptor (PgR) and showed weak membrane staining of HER-2 (1+ score). Fluorescence in situ hybridization (FISH) analysis found no HER-2 amplification in the primary tumor (ratio, 1.1). The patient received postoperative adjuvant chemotherapy consisting of 4 cycles of epirubicine 75 mg/m2 and cyclophosphamide 600 mg/m2 every 3 weeks. After the completion of adjuvant chemotherapy, she became postmenopausal and was followed without any treatment.\r\nSix years and 10 months after primary surgery, she noticed lumps in her left axilla. An ultrasonography and computed tomography (CT) scan confirmed left axillary and infraclavicular lymph node swellings. FDG-PET (2-[18F]Fluoro-2-deoxyglucose positron emission tomography) showed an accumulation of FDG in the left axilla and infraclavicular lymph nodes. The patient subsequently underwent ultrasonography-guided fine needle aspiration (FNA) cytology of the left axilla lymph node. Cytological findings revealed breast cancer metastases and FISH analysis of FNA samples showed HER-2 gene amplification (ratio 5.7). Immunohistochemical examinations of FNA sample showed positive results for both ER and PgR. A PET-CT scan did not reveal any other metastases, and no malignancies were detected in any other organs, including her left breast. With these clinical and cytological findings, she was diagnosed as having HER-2-positive recurrent breast cancer after primary treatment of right triple-negative breast cancer. At this point, there was the possibility of left axillary lymph node metastases from right breast cancer or left occult breast cancer. Initially, we decided to perform chemotherapy before surgery to evaluate the responsiveness to chemotherapy.\r\nShe was treated with weekly paclitaxel (80 mg/m2, 3 weeks on, 1 week off) in combination with weekly trastuzumab (initially 4 mg/kg followed by 2 mg/kg every week). After 3 courses of administrations, a PET-CT scan showed complete remission of swelling lymph nodes and no accumulation of FDG was detected. The elevated CEA was normalized. Complete remission of disease was maintained for more than 4 weeks with normalized tumor markers and she was diagnosed as having a complete clinical response by RECIST criteria. No severe adverse event above grade 3 was noted (alopecia grade 1, neutropenia grade 2). She underwent the combination chemotherapy of weekly paclitaxel and trastuzumab for 1 year and continues to show a complete remission of disease with tolerable neuropathy. Monotherapy with trastuzumab alone chemotherapy is ongoing and additional radiotherapy and surgery are being considered to confirm the local control.", "qa_list": [{"question": "List all cancer diagnoses of the patient, separated by comma. If unknown, return NA.", "answer": "Breast cancer", "justification": ["ductal carcinoma of the right breast"]}, {"question": "If so, list all therapies that the patient has received for cancer, separated by comma. If unknown, return NA.", "answer": "Epirubicine, cyclophosphamide, paclitaxel, trastuzumab", "justification": ["postoperative adjuvant chemotherapy consisting of 4 cycles of epirubicine 75 mg/m2 and cyclophosphamide", "paclitaxel (80 mg/m2, 3 weeks on, 1 week off) in combination with weekly trastuzumab"]}, {"question": "If so, list all therapeutic procedures that the patient has undergone for cancer, separated by comma. If unknown, return NA.", "answer": "Total mastectomy", "justification": ["had undergone total mastectomy and sentinel lymph node biopsy for stage I right breast cancer"]}]}
{"id": 294, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "The tumor must have been determined to be HER2-negative by current ASCO/CAP guidelines.", "note_date": "2021-02-15", "note": "2021-2-15 12:57 PM\r\nL-SPINE (AP & LAT)\r\nReason: fracture ?\r\nMEDICAL CONDITION:\r\n52 year old woman with Her2 pos BC, s/p radiation to L4/L5, now new backpain in\r\npreviously irradiated area.\r\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION:\r\nfracture?\r\nFINAL REPORT\r\nHISTORY:  HER-2 positive, status post radiation L4-5, new back pain in\r\npreviously radiated area, question fracture.\r\nL-SPINE (AP & LAT)\r\nThere are five non-rib-bearing vertebral bodies.  Assessment of fine bony\r\ndetail is moderately limited by osteopenia and overlying soft tissues.\r\nAllowing for this, no compression fracture is detected.  Vertebral body\r\nheights are preserved.  There is relative lucency with faint surrounding\r\nsclerosis in the anterior portion of the L4 vertebral body, corresponding to\r\nthe area of the abnormality in L4 seen on the 2021-8-11 MRI.  There is mild\r\nmultilevel disc space narrowing.  No subluxation.\r\nIMPRESSION:\r\nNo fracture detected. Faint irregular mineralization in L4 is consistent with\r\nknown lesion. Mild degenerative changs.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with breast cancer?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["woman with Her2 pos BC"]}, {"question": "If so, what is the most recent HER-2 status of the tumor?", "answer": "HER-2 positive", "justification": ["52 year old woman with Her2 pos BC"]}, {"question": "If so, when was HER-2 status diagnosis established?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, list all in situ hybridization and immunochemistry test results that confirm the patient's most recent HER-2 status, separated by comma. If unknown, return NA.", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 293, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "The tumor must have been determined to be HER2-negative by current ASCO/CAP guidelines.", "note_date": "2021-08-23", "note": "A 49-year-old premenopausal woman had undergone total mastectomy and sentinel lymph node biopsy for stage I right breast cancer in April 2013. The histological diagnosis was invasive ductal carcinoma of the right breast with no metastasis in one sentinel lymph node. Immunohistochemical (IHC) examinations of the tumor cells showed negative results for both estrogen receptor (ER) and progesterone receptor (PgR) and showed weak membrane staining of HER-2 (1+ score). Fluorescence in situ hybridization (FISH) analysis found no HER-2 amplification in the primary tumor (ratio, 1.1). The patient received postoperative adjuvant chemotherapy consisting of 4 cycles of epirubicine 75 mg/m2 and cyclophosphamide 600 mg/m2 every 3 weeks. After the completion of adjuvant chemotherapy, she became postmenopausal and was followed without any treatment.\r\nSix years and 10 months after primary surgery, she noticed lumps in her left axilla. An ultrasonography and computed tomography (CT) scan confirmed left axillary and infraclavicular lymph node swellings. FDG-PET (2-[18F]Fluoro-2-deoxyglucose positron emission tomography) showed an accumulation of FDG in the left axilla and infraclavicular lymph nodes. The patient subsequently underwent ultrasonography-guided fine needle aspiration (FNA) cytology of the left axilla lymph node. Cytological findings revealed breast cancer metastases and FISH analysis of FNA samples showed HER-2 gene amplification (ratio 5.7). Immunohistochemical examinations of FNA sample showed positive results for both ER and PgR. A PET-CT scan did not reveal any other metastases, and no malignancies were detected in any other organs, including her left breast. With these clinical and cytological findings, she was diagnosed as having HER-2-positive recurrent breast cancer after primary treatment of right triple-negative breast cancer. At this point, there was the possibility of left axillary lymph node metastases from right breast cancer or left occult breast cancer. Initially, we decided to perform chemotherapy before surgery to evaluate the responsiveness to chemotherapy.\r\nShe was treated with weekly paclitaxel (80 mg/m2, 3 weeks on, 1 week off) in combination with weekly trastuzumab (initially 4 mg/kg followed by 2 mg/kg every week). After 3 courses of administrations, a PET-CT scan showed complete remission of swelling lymph nodes and no accumulation of FDG was detected. The elevated CEA was normalized. Complete remission of disease was maintained for more than 4 weeks with normalized tumor markers and she was diagnosed as having a complete clinical response by RECIST criteria. No severe adverse event above grade 3 was noted (alopecia grade 1, neutropenia grade 2). She underwent the combination chemotherapy of weekly paclitaxel and trastuzumab for 1 year and continues to showe a complete remission of disease with tolerable neuropathy. Monotherapy with trastuzumab alone chemotherapy is ongoing and additional radiotherapy and surgery are being considered to confirm the local control.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with breast cancer?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["The histological diagnosis was invasive ductal carcinoma"]}, {"question": "If so, what is the most recent HER-2 status of the tumor?", "answer": "HER-2 positive.", "justification": ["she was diagnosed as having HER-2-positive recurrent breast cancer"]}, {"question": "If so, when was HER-2 status diagnosis established?", "answer": "02-2020", "justification": ["had undergone total mastectomy and sentinel lymph node biopsy for stage I right breast cancer in April 2013.", "Six years and 10 months after primary surgery"]}, {"question": "If so, list all in situ hybridization and immunochemistry test results that confirm the patient's most recent HER-2 status, separated by comma. If unknown, return NA.", "answer": "FISH analysis : HER-2 gene amplification", "justification": ["FISH analysis of FNA samples showed HER-2 gene amplification"]}]}
{"id": 291, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04187833", "criterion": "Use of hormonal contraceptives (oral, parenteral, vaginal, or transdermal) for at least 3 months before the first study drug administration.", "note_date": "2022-07-10", "note": "A previously healthy 18-year-old woman presented today to our emergency department (ED) with 5 days of worsening intermittent periumbilical, epigastric and right upper quadrant (RUQ) abdominal pain. She had nausea with the pain, though no vomiting or fever. The pain was crampy in nature and not exacerbated by eating. She was sexually active with one partner and had used the NuvaRing as contraception for the previous two years. She smoked approximately 5 cigarettes per day and denied any family history of coagulation disorders. On physical examination she was afebrile, with tenderness in the periumbilical, epigastric and right upper quadrant (RUQ) areas of her abdomen. She had no rigidity, guarding, or other peritoneal signs.\r\nLaboratory examinations sent from the ED included: a complete blood count, renal profile including electrolytes, liver function tests, serum lipase, urinalysis and a urine pregnancy test. The only abnormality noted was a mildly elevated serum alanine-amino transferase (ALT) level of 46 IU/L. A RUQ ultrasound of the abdomen was ordered to evaluate for cholelithiasis. While no abnormalities of the biliary tract were seen, splenomegaly was noted as an incidental finding. Because of the patient\u2019s ongoing and unexplained pain, a computerized tomographic (CT) scan with intravenous (IV) contrast of the abdomen and pelvis was performed. A large superior mesenteric vein thrombosis was identified with enlargement of the liver and spleen.\r\nThe patient was anticoagulated with IV heparin and admitted to the hospital with surgical and hematologic consultants. The NuvaRing was removed at the time of admission. Evaluations for prothrombotic conditions including: protein C, protein S and antithrombin III deficiency; factor V, prothrombin and MTHFR gene mutation; lupus anticoagulant, cardiolipin IgA and IgG antibodies were all negative. The patient\u2019s hospital course progressed without complication as she was bridged to anticoagulation with warfarin sodium, and she was discharged on day 5 with instructions to refrain from using hormonal birth control in the future.", "qa_list": [{"question": "List all hormonal contraceptives that the patient has received. If unknown, return NA in the output.", "answer": "Etonogestrel and ethinylestradiol vaginal ring", "justification": ["had used the NuvaRing"]}, {"question": "If so, what was the most recent date that the patient received hormonal contraceptives, on a date relative to the clinical note?", "answer": "2022-07-10", "justification": ["The NuvaRing was removed at the time of admission.", "note date: 2022-07-10"]}]}
{"id": 292, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04187833", "criterion": "Use of hormonal contraceptives (oral, parenteral, vaginal, or transdermal) for at least 3 months before the first study drug administration.", "note_date": "2021-10-13", "note": "2021-10-13  4:23 PM\r\nCT CHEST W/O CONTRAST; CT ABDOMEN W/O CONTRAST\r\nCT PELVIS W/O CONTRAST\r\nReason: Please assess for change in effusions, position of chest tub\r\nAdmitting Diagnosis: ACUTE RENAL FAILURE;METASTATIC OVARIAN CANCER\r\nMEDICAL CONDITION:\r\n74 year old woman with ovarian mass, compatible with metastatic ovarian cancer.\r\nHas chest tube that was found to be under the diaphragm, was pulled out, but\r\nstill with very high output.\r\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION:\r\nPlease assess for change in effusions, position of chest tubes.\r\nNo contraindications for IV contrast\r\nPFI REPORT\r\nBilateral pigtail catheters in the pleural space in standard location with\r\npersistent bilateral pleural effusions, bibasilar atelectasis, generalized\r\nanasarca, and intraperitoneal free fluid.  Generalized lymphadenopathy likely\r\nfrom known metastatic ovarian cancer without short-term interval changes since\r\n2021-10-8.", "qa_list": [{"question": "List all hormonal contraceptives that the patient has received. If unknown, return NA in the output.", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, what was the most recent date that the patient received hormonal contraceptives, on a date relative to the clinical note?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 280, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2021-06-02", "note": "2021-6-2 9:11 AM\r\nSMALL BOWEL ONLY (BARIUM)                                      1\r\nReason: r/o small bowel crohn's disease/post op recurrence\r\nMEDICAL CONDITION:\r\n50 year old woman with known crohn's colitis, s/p partial colectomy.\r\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION:\r\nr/o small bowel crohn's disease/post op recurrence\r\nFINAL REPORT\r\nSMALL BOWEL EXAM\r\nHistory of Crohn's colitis with right hemicolectomy and intermittent abdominal\r\npain.\r\nBarium passes freely through the small bowel entering the colon at the site of\r\nthe ileal mid transverse colostomy within one hour.  The small bowel is normal\r\nin caliber, contour, and mucosal pattern.  Specifically, no evidence for\r\nCrohn's disease in the preanastomotic segment of the ileum or elsewhere within\r\nthe small bowel.\r\nIMPRESSION:  No evidence of Crohn's disease of small bowel.  Status post ileo-\r\nmid transverse colostomy.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with cancer?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "List all diagnoses of the patient separated by semicolon, if unknown return NA in output", "answer": "Crohn's disease", "justification": ["with known crohn's colitis"]}, {"question": "List all procedures the patient has undergone for each diagnosis separated by semicolon, if unknown return NA", "answer": "partial colectomy", "justification": ["s/p partial colectomy."]}]}
{"id": 275, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03957876", "criterion": "Any active malignancy (unrelated, non-hematological malignancy) diagnosed within the past 6 months of starting the study drug (other than curatively treated carcinoma-in-situ of the cervix or non-melanoma skin cancer).", "note_date": "2020-04-02", "note": "CHIEF COMPLAINT:,1.  Chronic lymphocytic leukemia (CLL).,2.  Autoimmune hemolytic anemia.,3.  Oral ulcer.,HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS: , The patient is a 72-year-old gentleman who was diagnosed with chronic lymphocytic leukemia in May 2018.  He was noted to have autoimmune hemolytic anemia at the time of his CLL diagnosis.  He has been on chronic steroids to control his hemolysis and is currently on prednisone 5 mg every other day.  He comes in to clinic today for follow-up and complete blood count.  At his last office visit we discontinued this prophylactic antivirals and antibacterial.,\r\nCURRENT MEDICATIONS:,  Prilosec 20 mg b.i.d., levothyroxine 50 mcg q.d., Lopressor 75 mg q.d., vitamin C 500 mg q.d., multivitamin q.d., simvastatin 20 mg q.d., and prednisone 5 mg q.o.d.,\r\nALLERGIES:  ,Vicodin.,REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  ,The patient reports ulcer on his tongue and his lip.  He has been off of Valtrex for five days.  He is having some difficulty with his night vision with his left eye.  He has a known cataract.  He denies any fevers, chills, or night sweats.  He continues to have headaches.  The rest of his review of systems is negative.,PHYSICAL EXAM:,VITALS:", "qa_list": [{"question": "Does the patient have an active malignancy?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["diagnosed with chronic lymphocytic leukemia"]}, {"question": "If so, list the type of malignancies the patient has separated by semicolon, if unknown return NA", "answer": "chronic lymphocytic leukemia", "justification": ["diagnosed with chronic lymphocytic leukemia"]}, {"question": "If so, list the date of diagnoses confirmation, separated by semicolon, if unknown return NA", "answer": "May 2008", "justification": ["diagnosed with chronic lymphocytic leukemia in May 2008."]}, {"question": "List all the diagnoses the patients has separated by semicolon", "answer": "Chronic lymphocytic leukemia (CLL);  Autoimmune hemolytic anemia; Oral ulcer.", "justification": ["Chronic lymphocytic leukemia (CLL).,2.  Autoimmune hemolytic anemia.,3.  Oral ulcer."]}, {"question": "List all the therapies the patient is currently receiving separated by semicolon", "answer": "Prilosec; levothyroxine; Lopressor; vitamin C; multivitamin; simvastatin; prednisone", "justification": ["Prilosec 20 mg b.i.d., levothyroxine 50 mcg q.d., Lopressor 75 mg q.d., vitamin C 500 mg q.d., multivitamin q.d., simvastatin 20 mg q.d., and prednisone 5 mg q.o.d.,"]}, {"question": "Lit all the doses of each therapy separated by semicolon, if unknown return NA", "answer": "20 mg; 50 mcg; 75 mg q.d; 500 mg; NA; 20 mg; 5 mg", "justification": ["Prilosec 20 mg b.i.d., levothyroxine 50 mcg q.d., Lopressor 75 mg q.d., vitamin C 500 mg q.d., multivitamin q.d., simvastatin 20 mg q.d., and prednisone 5 mg q.o.d.,"]}, {"question": "List the frequencies of each therapy, separated by semicolon, if unknown return NA", "answer": "b.i.d.; q.d.; q.d.; q.d.; q.d.; q.d.; q.o.d.,", "justification": ["Prilosec 20 mg b.i.d., levothyroxine 50 mcg q.d., Lopressor 75 mg q.d., vitamin C 500 mg q.d., multivitamin q.d., simvastatin 20 mg q.d., and prednisone 5 mg q.o.d.,"]}]}
{"id": 276, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2022-12-21", "note": "A 46-year-old man presenting with hematuria underwent a diagnostic CT urogram revealing a 14.2\u00d710.6\u00d79.3 cm left renal mass with proximal renal vein thrombosis and retroperitoneal adenopathy. Chest imaging at the time identified small pulmonary nodules which were too small for characterization. The patient underwent a left radical nephrectomy with pathological evaluation identifying a T3N1M0 (14.2\u00d710.6\u00d79.3 cm) renal cell carcinoma with sarcomatoid differentiation (40%).\r\nTwo months after nephrectomy, surveillance scans identified extensive presumed metastases in the abdomen, pelvis and both lungs, with the largest mass consisting of a left renal fossa mass measuring 8.9\u00d73.2 cm. Biopsy of a presumed metastatic lesion in left anterior abdominal wall was consistent with poorly differentiated carcinoma with 50%\u201360% rhabdoid and sarcomatoid differentiation that stained for Pax-8, suggesting metastatic renal cell carcinoma. The patient was considered poor risk as assessed by IInternational Metastatic RCC Database Consortium.\r\nAfter 3 months on maintenance nivolumab therapy, the size of the patient\u2019s retroperitoneal and abdominal wall metastases approximately doubled as assessed by CT scanning of the abdomen and pelvis. In consideration of possible subsequent treatments, we noted the patient\u2019s prior response to ipilimumab, previous tolerance of combined immunotherapy, good performance status, and sRCC histology which has historically poor outcomes with VEGF inhibitors. Given this information, it was decided to retreat the patient with ipilimumab 1 mg/kg along with continued nivolumab 3 mg/kg every 3 weeks. A partial response was demonstrated on imaging after two additional doses of ipilimumab plus nivolumab, with all but one lesion shrinking by more than 50 per cent. The patient remained on combined immune checkpoint blockade therapy for a total of 9 months with stable disease before treatment was discontinued due to grade 3 fatigue, arthralgias and progression of disease in the right ventricle alone.", "qa_list": [{"question": "List all the cancer diagnoses of the patient, separated by comma. If unknown, return NA.", "answer": "Renal cell carcinoma, metastatic renal cell carcinoma.", "justification": ["renal cell carcinoma", "patient\u2019s retroperitoneal and abdominal wall metastases"]}, {"question": "If so, list all therapies that have been administered for each diagnosis, separated by comma. If unknown, return NA.", "answer": "Left radical nephrectomy, ipilimumab, nivolumab", "justification": ["The patient underwent a left radical nephrectomy", "ipilimumab 1 mg/kg along with continued nivolumab"]}]}
{"id": 271, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03957876", "criterion": "Major surgery within 2 weeks prior to study enrollment.", "note_date": "2021-07-09", "note": "Pt admitted to M/SICU from PACU after going to CT Scan of head due to pt slow to wake after surgery. CT was normal.\r\nPt had been admitted for same day surgery for resection of her R facial melanoma. Pt had a previous surgery in 2021-5-4 but then METS to the R parotid. Surgery lasted about 3 hours.\r\nPt came to ICU on vent settings of : CMV FIO2 40% vT 500 Rate 12 PEEP 5.\r\nIncision is open to air with staples intact, there is a JP drain present.\r\nPt is spanish speaking but has sons with her who speak fluent english.\r\nH.O. is writing orders for this admission.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient undergone any surgeries?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["same day surgery", "had a previous surgery"]}, {"question": "If so, list the type of each surgery separated by semicolon if unknown return NA in output", "answer": "Resection of R facial melanoma; NA", "justification": ["resection of her R facial melanoma", "NA"]}, {"question": "If so, list the corresponding date of each surgery separated by semi colon, if unknown return NA in output", "answer": "2021-07-09; 2021-5-4", "justification": ["same day surgery", "2021-07-09", "previous surgery in 2021-5-4"]}]}
{"id": 270, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "Current therapy with any endocrine therapy such as raloxifene (Evista\u00ae), tamoxifen, or other selective estrogen receptor modulators (SERMs), either for osteoporosis or breast cancer prevention. (Short course endocrine therapy of < 6 weeks duration is acceptable post core biopsy pre surgery if the Oncotype DX Recurrence Score is assessed on the biopsy core and is less than or equal to 18.)", "note_date": "2020-05-12", "note": "A 40-year-old woman in May 2018 developed left breast cancer, ductal infiltrating carcinoma with signet ring cells G2 ER 90% PR 35% Ki-67 15% HER2 negative, diagnosed with Tru-cut biopsy; in addition, ultrasound showed 2 pathologic lymph nodes in the left axilla; at this time a colonscopy, performed for rectal bleeding, showed a substenosis 7 cm from the anal margin, biopsies diagnosed metastasis from breast cancer, moderately differentiated (G2) carcinoma, with partial aspects of signet ring cells, ER 85% PR 30% HER2 negative. Chest X-ray, abdominal ultrasound, and bone scan showed absence of metastases.\r\nShe was treated with epirubicin (75 mg/m\u00b2) and docetaxel (75 mg/m\u00b2) days 1\u201321, 6 cycles, with stable disease.\r\nIn November 2018 endocrine therapy with tamoxifen 20 mg/day and LH-RH analogue 11.25 mg every 3 months was started, and symptomatic radiotherapy on the rectum was planned.\r\nTen months later, patient showed progression in the rectum and liver and was treated with liposomal doxorubicin (50 mg day 1\u201321) and carboplatin (AUC 5 = 300 mg day 1\u201321). After 3 cycles she showed disease progression, and chemotherapy with oxaliplatin, folinic acid and 5-fluorouracil was initiated.\r\nAfter 12 cycles of chemotherapy she showed gradual improvement with partial response. Patient is now well, with stable disease, and is treated with endocrine therapy, tamoxifene 20 mg/day.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Is the patient currently receiving treatment for osteoporosis or prophylaxis for breast cancer?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, list all therapies that the patient is currently receiving for the abformentioned indications and the starting date of each therapy, separated by semicolon. If unknown, return NA in the outcome.", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, list all values of the Oncotype DX Recurrence Score of the patient. If unknown, return NA in the output.", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 267, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "Active collagen vascular disease, specifically dermatomyositis with a CPK level above normal or with an active skin rash, systemic lupus erythematosis, or scleroderma.", "note_date": "2021-05-21", "note": "2021-5-21 2:23 PM\r\nVIDEO OROPHARYNGEAL SWALLOW \r\nReason: 31 year old woman with Sjogrens syndrome, complaing of difficulty swallowing.\r\nAdmitting Diagnosis: CSF LEAK\r\nMEDICAL CONDITION:\r\n31 year old woman with Sjogrens syndrome, complaing of difficulty swallowing.\r\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION:\r\n31 year old woman with Sjogrens syndrome, complaing of difficulty swallowing.\r\nFINAL REPORT\r\nINDICATION:  Sjogren syndrome, difficulty swallowing.\r\nSWALLOWING VIDEO FLUOROSCOPY:  Oropharyngeal swallowing video fluoroscopy was\r\nperformed in conjunction with the speech and swallow division.  Multiple\r\nconsistencies of barium were administered. Barium passes freely through the\r\noropharynx without evidence of obstruction although there is brief collection\r\non the vallecula and within the piriform sinuses, promptly clearing with\r\npharyngeal swallow. There is no residue. No aspiration or penetration is seen.\r\nA barium tablet passes freely through the oropharynx and esophagus to the\r\nstomach.\r\nIMPRESSION:  Brief collection of barium on the vallecula and piriform sinuses,\r\nclearing with pharyngeal swallow.\r\nFor details, please refer to speech and swallow note in OMR.", "qa_list": [{"question": "List all the collagen vascular diseases that the patient has been diagnosed with. If none, return NA in the output.", "answer": "Sjogrens syndrome", "justification": ["Sjogrens syndrome"]}, {"question": "If so, list all CPK values of the patient and the respective dates of measurement, separated by semicolon. If unknown, return NA in the output.", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, has the patient an active skin rush?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 266, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "Active collagen vascular disease, specifically dermatomyositis with a CPK level above normal or with an active skin rash, systemic lupus erythematosis, or scleroderma.", "note_date": "2021-07-02", "note": "2021-7-2 3:35 PM\r\nCHEST (PRE-OP PA & LAT)\r\nReason: preop cabg\r\nMEDICAL CONDITION:\r\n69 year old man with cad\r\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION:\r\npreop cabg\r\nFINAL REPORT\r\nPA AND LATERAL CHEST:\r\nINDICATION:  CAD, Preop for CABG.\r\nThere is no prior study for comparison.\r\nFINDINGS:  The pulmonary vasculature is normal.  The mediastinal and hilar\r\ncontours are unremarkable.  There is a coarse reticular pattern in the mid and\r\nlower lung zones, with peripheral predominance.  No pleural plaques are seen.\r\nThere are no effusions.  No pneumothorax.  There is degenerative change of the\r\nthoracic spine.  Flattening of the diaphragms is consistent with underlying\r\nemphysema. Right-sided apical pleural thickening is also noted.\r\nIMPRESSION:\r\n1)  No radiographic evidence of cardiac failure or pneumonia.\r\n2)  Coarse reticular interstitial pattern seen in the mid and lower lung zones\r\nwith peripheral distribution.  The findings are consistent with a usual\r\ninterstitial pneumonia pattern. Diagnostic possibilities for this\r\npattern include IPF, collagen vascular disease, drug reaction and less likely,\r\nasbestosis as no pleural plaques are seen.  A high resolution CT scan is\r\nrecommended along with correlation with pulmonary function tests for better\r\nassessment.", "qa_list": [{"question": "List all the collagen vascular diseases that the patient has been diagnosed with. If none, return NA in the output.", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, list all CPK values of the patient and the respective dates of measurement, separated by semicolon. If unknown, return NA in the output.", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, has the patient an active skin rush?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 265, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "Prior breast or thoracic RT for any condition.", "note_date": "2021-10-23", "note": "2021-10-23 11:17 AM\r\nMR W& W/O CONTRAST\r\nReason: Please scan from C6 through T2, 1 mm slices, T2 images, and\r\nContrast: MAGNEVIST Amt: 18\r\nMEDICAL CONDITION:\r\n62 year old man with met prostate to C7 and T1, with prior RT to T2 and below.\r\nNow for CyberKnife planning.\r\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION:\r\nPlease scan from C6 through T2, 1 mm slices, T2 images, and T1 with GAD, Field\r\nof View to cover the entire vertebral bodies, and soft tissue disease seen on\r\nprior MRI, 2021-10-19, only.\r\nNo contraindications for IV contrast\r\nFINAL REPORT\r\nCERVICAL SPINE MRI WITH AND WITHOUT CONTRAST, 2021-10-23.\r\nINDICATION:  Metastatic prostate cancer with C7 and T1 metastases.  Prior\r\nradiotherapy to T2 and below.  Please scan from C6 through T2 for radiotherapy\r\nplanning.\r\nCOMPARISON:  Cervical spine MRI with and without contrast performed six days\r\nearlier on 2021-10-17.  Thoracic spine MRI with and without contrast\r\ndated 2021-9-7.\r\nTECHNIQUE:  Sagittal T1-weighted spin echo images were obtained from the\r\ncraniocervical junction through the T5 vertebra, before and after intravenous\r\ngadolinium administration.  Pre-contrast axial T1- and T2-weighted, and\r\npost-contrast axial T1-weighted images were obtained from C6 through T2.\r\nAxial MP-RAGE images were obtained following intravenous gadolinium\r\nadministration from C5 through T3, with multiplanar reformatted images.\r\nFINDINGS:  A comprehensive evaluation of the imaged spine is not performed\r\nwith this exam, which is specifically targeted for radiotherapy planning.\r\nOsseous metastases are again demonstrated within the C7 vertebral body, right\r\npedicle, right facet, right lamina, and probably also right transverse\r\nprocess, as well as within the T1 vertebral body and right pedicle.  There is\r\nan associated soft tissue mass centered in the right neural foramen, which\r\nalso slightly narrows the right lateral epidural space and extends slightly\r\ninto the right anterior paravertebral soft tissues.  These findings are\r\nunchanged compared to six days earlier (2021-10-17).  The C7 and T1 vertebral\r\nbodies maintain normal height.\r\nMetastatic disease is again seen within the T4 vertebral body, without loss of\r\nheight, as well as within the right posterior elements of T4.  Laminectomies\r\nare again seen from T3 through T5.  The previously noted small right epidural\r\nmass at T4 is not assessed in the absence of axial images through this level.\r\nIMPRESSION:\r\n1.  Osseous and soft tissue metastatic disease at the C7 and T1 level is again\r\ndemonstrated for radiotherapy planning.\r\n(Over)\r\n2021-10-23 11:17 AM\r\nMR Potter W& W/O CONTRAST\r\nReason: Please scan from C6 through T2, 1 mm slices, T2 images, and\r\nContrast: MAGNEVIST Amt: 18\r\nFINAL REPORT\r\n(Cont)\r\n2.  Metastatic disease at the T4 level is imaged in the sagittal plane only\r\nand is not adequately assessed.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient undergone breast or thoracic radiotherapy?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 264, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "Prior breast or thoracic RT for any condition.", "note_date": "2021-03-20", "note": "HPI:\r\n67 y/o F with h/o lung CA with brain mass\r\nPMH: lung ca s/p radiotherapy, left DVT, breast Ca, s/p radiotherapy\r\nfor brain mass, dermatomyositis, h/o tobacco 40years (quit 3 years ago)\r\nPSH:LLL wedge resection, right mastectomy, IVC filter placed after DVT\r\nDexamethasone 2mg, Fluoxetine 20mg QD, Percocet 5/325mg Q6H\r\nprn, Warfarin, ativan 0.5mg prn, keppra 500mg PO BID, ranitidine 150mg\r\nPO BID\r\nallergies: vicodin - rash\r\nChief complaint:\r\ngait disturbance and weakness\r\nPMHx:\r\nPMH: lung ca s/p radiotherapy, left DVT, breast Ca, s/p radiotherapy\r\nfor brain mass, dermatomyositis, h/o tobacco 40years (quit 3 years ago)\r\nPSH:LLL wedge resection, right mastectomy, IVC filter placed after DVT\r\nProblem\r\ns/p posterior fossa craniotomy with open biopsy\r\nAssessment:\r\nPatient is alert and orientated X3 lungs clear , heart rate 50-60\r\nsystolic b/p < 140, foley patent draining clear yellow urine, + bowel\r\nsounds + flatus no bm, incision clean dry intact. Pain 5 out of 10.\r\nAction:\r\nMRI done this am, a-line dc\r\nd advanced diet to regular , neuro exam\r\nchanged to from q1 to q2, IVF  stopped. IV pain medication changed  to\r\npo.\r\nResponse:\r\nPatient neuro exam is unchanged tolerating diet . Patient tolerating po\r\npain medication with 2 out of 10 on pain scale.\r\nPlan:\r\nContinue with current plan of care, provide comfort and support.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient undergone breast or thoracic radiotherapy?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["lung ca s/p radiotherapy"]}, {"question": "If so, when?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 263, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04187833", "criterion": "Prior anti-cancer therapy for melanoma less than 14 days prior to first dose of study drug.", "note_date": "2021-07-10", "note": "2021-7-10 3:36 PM\r\nCHEST PORT. LINE PLACEMENT PORT\r\nReason: s/p central venous catheter, hx metastatic melanoma\r\nAdmitting Diagnosis: MELANOMA\\CHEMOTHERAPY\r\nMEDICAL CONDITION:\r\n44 year old man with\r\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION:\r\ns/p central venous catheter, hx metastatic melanoma\r\nPLEASE CALL WET READ TO NURSING\r\nThanks\r\nFINAL REPORT\r\nINDICATION:  History of metastatic melanoma.  Status post venous line\r\nplacement.\r\nCOMPARISON:  2021-6-18.\r\nFINDINGS:  There is a right subclavian central venous catheter with the tip\r\nterminating in the SVC.  There is no evidence of pneumothorax.  The heart and\r\nmediastinal contours are unremarkable.  There are faint bilateral lower lobe\r\nnodules, better assessed on the recent CT chest and consistent with the\r\npatient's known history of metastatic melanoma.  Note is also made of a healed\r\nright seventh posterior rib fracture.\r\nIMPRESSION:\r\n1.  Satisfactory placement of right subclavian central venous catheter with no\r\nevidence of pneumothorax.\r\n2.  Bilateral pulmonary nodules consistent with patient's known history of\r\nmetastatic melanoma.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with melanoma?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Admitting Diagnosis: MELANOMA\\CHEMOTHERAPY"]}, {"question": "If so, has the patient received anti-cancer therapy for melanoma?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, what is the date of the most recent dose of chemotherapy for melanoma administered, on a date relative to the clinical note?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 262, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03957876", "criterion": "Calculated creatinine clearance value of > 30ml/min AND a serum creatinine < 1.5mg/dL", "note_date": "2022-03-03", "note": "On 2020-03-01 a kidney biopsy was performed in a 37-year-old man with proteinuria of 2.1 g/day, serum creatinine of 2.48 mg/dl and a glomerular filtration rate of 44 ml/min. Optic microscopy revealed focal and segmental glomerulosclerosis. The patient was started on meprednisone 40 mg/day, valsartan 320 mg/day and a gradual increase in aliskiren dose until 300 mg/day were reached. Low-sodium diet compliance was followed with urinary sodium excretion. One month later, serum creatinine increased to 2.7 mg/dl and proteinuria decreased to 0.8 g/day. Three months later, the steroid dose was tapered and the creatinine clearance improved to 54 ml/min and proteinuria remained steady for the following months (0.6\u20131 g/day). Twenty months later, while on dual blockade (valsartan had been lowered to 160 mg/day due to hypotension) and meprednisone 4 mg/day, proteinuria increased to 1.9 g/day. Steroids were restarted but proteinuria worsened to 6.8 g/day and creatinine clearance increased to 56 ml/min. A new kidney biopsy was performed and a test for \u03b1-galactosidase levels displayed low levels (0.7 ng/ml). A mutation [c.98A>G (D33G)] was identified in the gene of \u03b1-galactosidase A, diagnosed by sequential analysis. The kidney biopsy was consistent with secondary focal and segmental glomerulosclerosis and suggested Fabry's disease. Electron microscopy and genetic studies confirmed the diagnosis. The patient was started on agalsidase \u03b2 intravenously at 1 mg/kg body weight every fortnight and steroids gradually decreased, while the dual blockade was unchanged. Two months after diagnosis, his proteinuria decreased to 2.7 g/day, his creatinine clearance was 46 ml/min and steroids were discontinued. One month later, his proteinuria increased to 3 g/day and the creatinine clearance was 40 ml/min. As adjuvant therapy, meprednisone 10 mg was restarted and added to the regime. Proteinuria decreased to 2 g/day and creatinine clearance was 37 ml/min.", "qa_list": [{"question": "List all values of creatinine of the patient, separated by semicolon", "answer": "2.48 mg/dl; 2.7 mg/dl", "justification": ["creatinine of 2.48 mg/dl", "serum creatinine increased to 2.7 mg/dl"]}, {"question": "List the date of measurement of these values separated by semicolon, if unknown return NA in output", "answer": "2020-03-01; 2020-04", "justification": ["On 2020-03-01", "serum creatinine of 2.48 mg/dl", "One month later, serum creatinine increased to 2.7 mg/dl"]}, {"question": "List all values of creatinine clearance of the patient, separated by semicolons", "answer": "54 ml/min; 56ml/min; 46 ml/min; 40ml/min; 37 ml/min", "justification": ["creatinine clearance improved to 54 ml/min", "creatinine clearance increased to 56 ml/min", "creatinine clearance was 46 ml/min", "creatinine clearance was 40 ml/min", "creatinine clearance was 37 ml/min"]}, {"question": "List the dates of measurement of these values, separated by semicolon, if unknown return NA in output", "answer": "2020-06;  2022-02; NA; NA; NA", "justification": ["Three months later", "creatinine clearance improved to 54 ml/min", "Twenty months later", "creatinine clearance increased to 56 ml/min.", "NA"]}]}
{"id": 261, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04187833", "criterion": "Prior anti-cancer therapy for melanoma less than 14 days prior to first dose of study drug.", "note_date": "2022-07-22", "note": "T/SICU NSG Admission Note \r\n54 yo male S/P left craniotomy, on 7-22 with resection of tumor (metastatic melanoma involving the meningies (leptomenigeal). Patient overnighted in PACU for management of HTN with nipride drip. Patient started on po meds but was unable to wean from nipride drip. Hydralizine iv was given; patient had episode of reflexive tachycardia with ischemia- c/o chest pressure with ST changes. Episode resolved with lopressor 5mg ivp. Cardiology consult was obtained. Plan includes beta-blockers (lopressor), ace inhibitor (lisinopril), treat pain & anxiety(prn pain and anti anxietals available), avoid nipride and hydralizine, follow serial enzymes & EKG, ASA when ok with neurosurgical team, and give IVF if hypotension occurs. PMH: recently diagnosed with melanoma by biopsy of scalp lesion in 2021-12-30. Neck swelling bx also positive for melanoma. Pt had left modified neck dissection in 2022-2-28 with diagnosis of stage IIIC melanoma. Patient developed seizures ~ 3 weeks ago, described as right arm shaking, asphasia, and with right face twitching with most recent seizure activity on 2022-7-20. Keppra therapy was started. MRI revealed a bleed in left frontoparietal area with underlying lesion. HTN diagnosed in 2003 but not treated LVH patient states 'murmur' since childhood \r\nfamily history of melanoma: mother and 2 sisters. \r\nMEDS: keppra 1500mg, labetalol 100mg, decadron (since 2022-7-20 4mg TID (weaning doses) fish oil qd \r\nALLERGIES: no known allergies patient states he has a gluten intolerance but denies formal diagnosis of such. \r\nSOCIAL- patient is divorced father of 2 grown children(son & daughter). lives with son in is self employed as a landscaper; worked up until admission for surgery. See careview for objective data. NEURO- awake, alert, oriented x3; MAE's and follows commands consistently. Normal strength in all extremities except RUE which he can lift & hold but exhibit weak grasp and some pronator drift. Patient denies sensory deficit. Perrl at 3mm/brisk with left pupil asymmetrical(reported as baseline). Speech is clear and coherant. No seizure activity noted, keppra dosing continues. + cough/gag. States incisional discomfort 2022-3-2 without change following 2 percocets but improved following ativan .5mg po. Patient exhibiting moderate anxiety- improved following ativan dose.(per family report: patient has baseline anxiety- untreated) Decadron therapy. Awaiting Post-op MRI. CVS- SB in 50 range without ectopy. EKG reveals T wave inversion in L1 &L & V, depression. Blood pressure goal per cardiology is ~ 130 systolic. Initial troponin negative with second serial specimen pending. Arterial line has fling artifact; NBP ranges less than 130 at this time. Lopressor dosing continues. No complaint of chest pressure. RENAL- adequate output per hour, IVF infusing at 80cc/hour GI- tolerating regular diet(gluten free). PPI therapy. Abdomeen soft with bowel sounds. Bowel regimen", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with melanoma?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["recently diagnosed with melanoma"]}, {"question": "If so, has the patient received anti-cancer therapy for melanoma?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, is the patient currently receiving anti-cancer therapy for melanoma?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 260, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04844749", "criterion": "Patients receiving full dose warfarin therapy are not eligible for study.", "note_date": "2021-02-08", "note": "2021-2-8 7:18 AM\r\nCHEST (PORTABLE AP)                                            \r\nReason: Pls eval for interval change of pleural effusion, e/o acute\r\nAdmitting Diagnosis: FALLS\r\n MEDICAL CONDITION:\r\n74 year old woman with h/o lung cancer, laryngeal cancer, chronic trach, and\r\nmultiple DVTs on warfarin\r\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION:\r\nPls eval for interval change of pleural effusion, e/o acute process\r\nFINAL REPORT\r\nPORTABLE AP CHEST ON 2021-2-8 AT 7:31\r\nCLINICAL INDICATION:  74-year-old with history of lung cancer, laryngeal\r\ncancer, chronic trach, multiple DVTs.  Evaluate for interval change of pleural\r\neffusion.  Question acute process.\r\nComparison to prior study 2021-2-5 at 13:24.\r\nA single portable upright chest film on 2021-2-8 at 7:31 is submitted.\r\nIMPRESSION:\r\n1.  Postoperative appearance to left hemithorax is stable.  There is a patchy\r\nopacity at the right base which could reflect a combination of a layering\r\neffusion with atelectasis, although an acute infectious process cannot be\r\nexcluded.  Overall, however, there is not significant interval change since\r\n2021-2-5.  No pneumothorax.  Cardiac and mediastinal contours is difficult to\r\nassess due to the postoperative state of the patient as well as patient\r\npositioning on the current examination.  No evidence of pulmonary edema.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Is the patient being treated with warfarin?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["on warfarin"]}, {"question": "If so what is the dose?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 259, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04844749", "criterion": "Patients receiving full dose warfarin therapy are not eligible for study.", "note_date": "2022-03-05", "note": "Progress Note  7p-7a\r\nPatient stable overnight with no episodes of A fib.  Amiodarone off at 2230 after po amio given. Heparin gtt continues for left femoral DVT, now at 950 units/hr (ptt 47.2).  Ptt done at 0415, results pending at time of writing. Has been febrile overnight.\r\nNeuro:  A&O x 3, no deficits.  received Ambian 5 mg at bedtime with good results.\r\nCV:  Normotensive and in NSR all night.  Heparin as above.  will start warfarin for afib.  Periperal pulses present. Labs pending for the morning\r\nResp:  Currently on RA, but needed 2 L NC when fast asleep, sats dropping to mid 80's.  Lungs clear to diminished to bases.\r\nGU: Aneuric,  On HD.\r\nGI:  HS snack of crackers and P.Butter, Needing Insulin at hs for B sugar 203.\r\nPlan : C/O to floor\r\n Start warfarin for A fib", "qa_list": [{"question": "Is the patient currently on anticoagulant therapy?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Heparin gtt continues"]}, {"question": "Is the patient currently being treated with of warfarin?", "answer": "No", "justification": ["will start warfarin"]}, {"question": "If so what is the dose of warfarin?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 258, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04871529", "criterion": "Participants must not have received prior systemic chemotherapy, immunotherapy or radiotherapy for the treatment of muscle invasive bladder cancer (MIBC) or upper tract urothelial carcinoma (UTUC). Other prior pelvic radiotherapy is allowed if it does not preclude surgery (radical cystectomy, nephroureterectomy or ureterectomy, based on location of primary tumor). Prior intravesical therapy is allowed", "note_date": "2021-02-21", "note": "In April 2019, a 50-year-old man with a 10-year smoking history and a family history of lung and colorectal cancer experienced intermittent macrohematuria. Pelvic computed tomography (CT) revealed an irregular mass measuring 3.0 cm \u00d7 2.1 cm located at the anterior wall of the bladder . Diagnostic transurethral resection of bladder tumor (TURBt) indicated that the tumor was cauliflower-like with broad base. The pathology revealed that the tumor was MIBC. As the chest/abdominal/pelvic CT scans indicated that the perivesical fat was invaded, the patient was diagnosed with clinical stage III-A (cT3bN0M0) bladder cancer.\r\nThe tissue sample collected during TURBt had a purity of 65% and was submitted for next-generation sequencing (NGS) analysis using a 642-gene panel. The tumor mutation burden (TMB) was 19.10 Mutants/Mb and the microsatellite state was stable (MSS). Furthermore, inactivating mutation in the RB1 gene was detected. The immunohistochemistry showed that the combined positive score (CPS) of the PD-L1 expression level was <1, as determined by using a monoclonal mouse anti-human PD-L1 clone (22C3) antibody, and the frequency of infiltrating CD8+ T cells was 2%.\r\nConsidering the promising efficacy of anti-PD-1 immunotherapy for patients with advanced bladder cancer and the high pCR rate in MIBC-related research, the patient strongly requested neoadjuvant chemotherapy combined with immunotherapy.\r\nSince May 14, 2019, the patient received the neoadjuvant treatment, which included four cycles of gemcitabine and cisplatin (GC) plus concurrent pembrolizumab. The regimen consisted of gemcitabine (1,000 mg/m2) on days 1 and 8, cisplatin (60 mg/m2) on day 2, and pembrolizumab (200 mg) on day 2. As a grade 3 adverse event of bone marrow suppression arose, the gemcitabine and cisplatin doses were decreased to 850 mg/m2 and 50 mg/m2 in the following cycles. After two cycles of neoadjuvant therapy, pelvic MRI showed that the thickness of the anterior wall of the bladder was lessened, and the thickest area was only 0.5 cm. The patient was considered to have achieved a partial response.\r\nOn July 28, 2019, pelvic MRI was repeated after the fourth cycle of neoadjuvant therapy. The imaging results showed that light thickening of anterior wall was persisting, but no node or obvious tumor was shown, and the result of urine cytology analysis was negative. Given these results, the patient strongly preferred bladder-sparing treatment.\r\nOn July 30, 2019, the patient received the second TURBt and randomized biopsies by cystoscopy. The pathological analysis showed inflammation and interstitial edema without any tumor in the bladder and the stage was downgraded to T0.\r\nConcurrent chemoradiotherapy started 1 month after the second TURBt. The regimen consisted of image-guided intensity-modulated conformal radiotherapy to the true pelvis with 45 Gy in 25 fractions plus the local lesion with 20 Gy in 10 fractions and concurrent cisplatin (40 mg/m2, once per week for 5 cycles). The side effects during chemoradiotherapy included second-degree fatigue and leukopenia. However, the patient recovered after symptomatic treatments. To evaluate the effect of chemoradiotherapy, the patient received pelvic MRI plus chest/abdominal CT on January 7 and cystoscopy on January 10, 2020. The results revealed that the bladder was normal with no sign of tumor recurrence. During this period, the patient received concurrent pembrolizumab (200 mg per 21 days). Finally, the patient achieved bladder preservation.\r\nIn addition, to monitor the status of the disease, urine tumor DNA sequencing analysis was carried out three times by a 642-gene panel from October 2019 to August 2020. The results showed that the mutation frequency of RB1 decreased significantly. On February 20, 2021, MRI results showed that there was still no tumor in the bladder. Cystoscopy and urine cytology analyses were also negative. The patient had maintained cancer-free status and excellent bladder function for 19 months at the end of follow-up.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with muscle invasive bladder cancer or upper tract urothelial carcinoma?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["The pathology revealed that the tumor was MIBC"]}, {"question": "If so, has the patient received radiotherapy?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["conformal radiotherapy to the true pelvis"]}, {"question": "If so, has the patient undergone surgery for MIBC or UTUC, defined as radical cystectomy, nephroureterectomy or ureterectomy?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 257, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04871529", "criterion": "Participants must not have received prior systemic chemotherapy, immunotherapy or radiotherapy for the treatment of muscle invasive bladder cancer (MIBC) or upper tract urothelial carcinoma (UTUC). Other prior pelvic radiotherapy is allowed if it does not preclude surgery (radical cystectomy, nephroureterectomy or ureterectomy, based on location of primary tumor). Prior intravesical therapy is allowed", "note_date": "2021-02-20", "note": "In April 2019, a 50-year-old man with a 10-year smoking history and a family history of lung and colorectal cancer experienced intermittent macrohematuria. Pelvic computed tomography (CT) revealed an irregular mass measuring 3.0 cm \u00d7 2.1 cm located at the anterior wall of the bladder . Diagnostic transurethral resection of bladder tumor (TURBt) indicated that the tumor was cauliflower-like with broad base. The pathology revealed that the tumor was MIBC. As the chest/abdominal/pelvic CT scans indicated that the perivesical fat was invaded, the patient was diagnosed with clinical stage III-A (cT3bN0M0) bladder cancer.\r\nThe tissue sample collected during TURBt had a purity of 65% and was submitted for next-generation sequencing (NGS) analysis using a 642-gene panel. The tumor mutation burden (TMB) was 19.10 Mutants/Mb and the microsatellite state was stable (MSS). Furthermore, inactivating mutation in the RB1 gene was detected. The immunohistochemistry showed that the combined positive score (CPS) of the PD-L1 expression level was <1, as determined by using a monoclonal mouse anti-human PD-L1 clone (22C3) antibody, and the frequency of infiltrating CD8+ T cells was 2%.\r\nConsidering the promising efficacy of anti-PD-1 immunotherapy for patients with advanced bladder cancer and the high pCR rate in MIBC-related research, the patient strongly requested neoadjuvant chemotherapy combined with immunotherapy.\r\nSince May 14, 2019, the patient received the neoadjuvant treatment, which included four cycles of gemcitabine and cisplatin (GC) plus concurrent pembrolizumab. The regimen consisted of gemcitabine (1,000 mg/m2) on days 1 and 8, cisplatin (60 mg/m2) on day 2, and pembrolizumab (200 mg) on day 2. As a grade 3 adverse event of bone marrow suppression arose, the gemcitabine and cisplatin doses were decreased to 850 mg/m2 and 50 mg/m2 in the following cycles. After two cycles of neoadjuvant therapy, pelvic MRI showed that the thickness of the anterior wall of the bladder was lessened, and the thickest area was only 0.5 cm. The patient was considered to have achieved a partial response.\r\nOn July 28, 2019, pelvic MRI was repeated after the fourth cycle of neoadjuvant therapy. The imaging results showed that light thickening of anterior wall was persisting, but no node or obvious tumor was shown, and the result of urine cytology analysis was negative. Given these results, the patient strongly preferred bladder-sparing treatment.\r\nOn July 30, 2019, the patient received the second TURBt and randomized biopsies by cystoscopy. The pathological analysis showed inflammation and interstitial edema without any tumor in the bladder and the stage was downgraded to T0.\r\nConcurrent chemoradiotherapy started 1 month after the second TURBt. The regimen consisted of image-guided intensity-modulated conformal radiotherapy to the true pelvis with 45 Gy in 25 fractions plus the local lesion with 20 Gy in 10 fractions and concurrent cisplatin (40 mg/m2, once per week for 5 cycles). The side effects during chemoradiotherapy included second-degree fatigue and leukopenia. However, the patient recovered after symptomatic treatments. To evaluate the effect of chemoradiotherapy, the patient received pelvic MRI plus chest/abdominal CT on January 7 and cystoscopy on January 10, 2020. The results revealed that the bladder was normal with no sign of tumor recurrence. During this period, the patient received concurrent pembrolizumab (200 mg per 21 days). Finally, the patient achieved bladder preservation.\r\nIn addition, to monitor the status of the disease, urine tumor DNA sequencing analysis was carried out three times by a 642-gene panel from October 2019 to August 2020. The results showed that the mutation frequency of RB1 decreased significantly. On February 20, 2021, MRI results showed that there was still no tumor in the bladder. Cystoscopy and urine cytology analyses were also negative. The patient had maintained cancer-free status and excellent bladder function for 19 months at the end of follow-up.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with muscle invasive bladder cancer or upper tract urothelial carcinoma?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["The pathology revealed that the tumor was MIBC."]}, {"question": "If so, did the patient receive treatment for the MIBC or UTUC diagnosis?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["the patient received the neoadjuvant treatment, which included four cycles of gemcitabine and cisplatin (GC) plus concurrent pembrolizumab."]}, {"question": "If so, list all medications or procedures that the patient was administered to treat MICB or UTUC, separated by comma. If no medications are noted, return NA in the output.", "answer": "Gemcitabine, cisplatin, pembrolizumab, TURBt, radiotherapy", "justification": ["gemcitabine and cisplatin (GC) plus concurrent pembrolizumab.", "the patient received the second TURBt", "radiotherapy to the true pelvis", "concurrent cisplatin", "concurrent pembrolizumab"]}]}
{"id": 256, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04134260", "criterion": "Serum potassium >= 3.5 mmol/L within 90 days prior to registration", "note_date": "2022-06-23", "note": "19:00-07:00 ON 6-23.\r\nNO SIGNIFICANT EVENTS OVERNIGHT.PT IS CALLED OUT.AWAITING BED\r\nNEURO:REMAINS CONFUSED,ORIENTED X1,RESPONDS TO YES/NO QUESTIONS.CAN MAKE NEED KNOWN.MOVING ALL FOUR LIMBS.PEARL.\r\nPULM:REMAINS ON O2 4L VIA NC.SAO2>95%. RR 10-25.NEBS GIVEN 6HRLY.LUNGS SOUND DIMINISHED AT THE BASE BUT OTHERWISE CLEAR.HAS GOT WEAK COUGH,DOES NOT EXPECTORATE.\r\nCVS:IN AFIB WITH HR 80-110 WITH OCCASIOANAL PVC'S.BP SYSTOLIC 90-120,OMITTED METOPROLOL THIS AM.HAD LASIX 40 MG.AIMING FOR NEG BALANCE\r\nGI:BOWEL MOVEMENT TWICE OVERNIGHT FOR BLACK LOOSE STOOL.BS POS. SOFT.\r\nGU:PASSING URINE 40-240 MLS/HR.POST LASIX 500 MLS.\r\nID:AFEBRILE.NOT ON ANTIBIOTICS\r\nLABS:HAD 40MEQ POTASSIUM FOR K OF 3.6.POTASSIUM THIS AM WAS 3.3.PT IS FOR FURTHER 40MEQ POTASSIUM THIS AM.1ST UNIT INFUSING.SODIUM 144.HCT 26.4.\r\nSOCIAL:NO PHONE ENQUIRIES OVERNIGHT.\r\nPLAN:MONITOR POTASSIUM AND SODIUM LEVELS.CENTRAL LINE TO BE TAKEN OUT AFTER THE SECOND POTASSIUM BAG.", "qa_list": [{"question": "List all the serum potassium levels of this patient separated by comma, if no potassium levels are detected return NA in the output", "answer": "3.3, 3.6", "justification": ["K OF 3.6", "THIS AM WAS 3.3"]}, {"question": "List the date at which these values were measured, if time is not mentioned return NA in the output?", "answer": "2022-06-23, 2022-06-23", "justification": ["Date of the note: 2022-06-23", "THIS AM"]}]}
{"id": 255, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "pT2 - pT4 tumors including inflammatory breast cancer", "note_date": "2023-01-09", "note": "A 44-year-old woman presented with left periareolar pain for several months. Mammography revealed left subareolar asymmetry, periareolar skin thickening and axillary lymph node hypertrophy. Sonography shows a 2.2\u00d71.7-cm ill defined mass with an irregular shape, heterogeneous echogenicity and posterior enhancement. FNAB was performed to differentiate this from inflammatory breast cancer, but malignant cells were not found. The symptoms were improved after administering antibiotics, and we formed a clinical impression of breast abscess. One year later, the patient presented again with yellowish discharge of the left nipple. On the follow up mammogram, the density of the left subareolar asymmetry and skin thickening was decreased, but it was still observed, and no significant change was observed in the left axillary lymph nodes. On sonography, the previously observed mass showed decreased size (1.5\u00d71.5-cm) and echogenicity. One month after antibiotic administration, the mass disappeared and an irregularly shaped hypoechogenicity was seen on the follow-up sonogram. About seven months later, the patient presented with a heat sensation and pain on the same area. The previous hypoechogenicity area changed to a 1.1\u00d70.8-cm mass on sonography and a recurrent abscess was suspected. The mass was excised and pathologically confirmed as a ruptured epidermal inclusion cyst.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with inflammatory breast cancer?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 253, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "Bilateral mammogram or MRI within 6 months prior to study entry.", "note_date": "2021-12-26", "note": "2021-12-26 10:50 AM\r\nBILAT DIAGNOSTIC MAMMOGRAM\r\nReason: s/p bilateral breast cancer.  annual mammogram\r\nMEDICAL CONDITION:\r\n92-year old woman with\r\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION:\r\ns/p bilateral breast cancer.  annual mammogram\r\nFINAL REPORT\r\nINDICATION:  History of bilateral breast cancer with left breast cancer in\r\n2014 and 2017.  Right breast cancer in 2014.\r\nBILATERAL FILM DIAGNOSTIC MAMMOGRAM:  The breasts are predominantly fatty\r\nreplaced.  There are expected postsurgical changes in the left breast, new\r\nfrom 2021-5-12.  There are unchanged postsurgical changes in both breasts\r\ncompared to that prior exam.  There is no new or spiculated mass, suspicious\r\nclustered microcalcifications, or skin thickening.\r\nIMPRESSION: No evidence of new or recurrent malignancy.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient undergone bilateral mammogram?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["BILAT DIAGNOSTIC MAMMOGRAM"]}, {"question": "If so, when?", "answer": "2021-12-26", "justification": ["2021-12-26 10:50 AM\r\nBILAT DIAGNOSTIC MAMMOGRAM"]}]}
{"id": 252, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04134260", "criterion": "Prior radiotherapy to the region of the study cancer that would result in overlap of radiation therapy fields", "note_date": "2021-04-14", "note": "2021-4-14 9:29 AM MR ENTEROGRAPHY\r\nSBFT; MR 3D RENDERING W/POST PROCESSING ON \r\nReason: small bowel pathology \r\nAdmitting Diagnosis: ABDOMINAL PAIN Contrast: MAGNEVIST Amt: 15 \r\nMEDICAL CONDITION: 66-year-old man with severe abdominal pain (especially LLQ) without etiology \r\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION: small bowel pathology \r\nNo contraindications for IV contrast \r\nFINAL REPORT HISTORY: 66-year-old male with history of Cyberknife radiotherapy for prostate cancer now with lower abdominal pain. \r\nCOMPARISON: CT abdomen and pelvis 2021-4-11 \r\nTECHNIQUE: Multiplanar T1- and T2-weighted images of the abdomen and pelvis acquired on a 1.5 Tesla magnet including 3-D dynamic imaging acquired prior to, during, and after 0.1 mmol/kg gadolinium DTPA. The 3D dynamic series was sent to an independent workstation for creation of multiplanar reformatted and subtracted images. Prior to the examination two bottles of oral Volumen contrast were administered. After acquisition of the initial T2- weighted dynamic images, 1.0 mg intramuscular glucagon was administered to minimize peristaltic motion artifact. \r\nMR ENTEROGRAPHY: The appearance of the abdomen is overall similar to the recent CT of 2021-4-11. On the initial dynamic T2- weighted images small bowel peristalsis is demonstrated however there is minimal passage of ingested Volumen oral contrast which remains in the distended stomach. Jejunum and proximal ileum are dilated up to 4.5 cm. The distal ileum is collapsed. Small bowel caliber change is noted in the central pelvis where there is a tethered appearance of small bowel loops likely explained by adhesions. No enhancing obstructing mass is detected. Fluid and gas are present in the colon, evidence that obstruction is partial. There is a small amount of free intraperitoneal fluid. There are a few small bilateral renal cysts up to 15-mm on the left. The included portion of the liver, spleen, gallbladder, pancreas and adrenal glands are unremarkable. There is diffuse atherosclerotic change of the abdominal arteries. There is no short interval change in fusiform aneurysmal dilatation of the infrarenal aorta to 3.5 cm. Susceptibility artifact is noted of the prostate gland related to fiducial markers for cyberknife radiotherapy.\r\nIMPRESSION: 1. Partial bowel obstruction likely explained by adhesions which could be due to prior prostate radiotherapy in 2019 (Over)\r\n2021-4-14 9:29 AM MR ENTEROGRAPHY \r\nSBFT; MR 3D RENDERING W/POST PROCESSING ON INDEPENDENT WSClip \r\nReason: small bowel pathology Admitting Diagnosis: ABDOMINAL PAIN Contrast: MAGNEVIST Amt: 15 FINAL REPORT 2. Bilateral renal cysts. 3. Atherosclerosis with 3.5 cm infrarenal aortic aneurysm.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient received radiation therapy in the past?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["prior prostate radiotherapy"]}, {"question": "If so, did the radiation therapy target the pelvis or the prostate?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["prior prostate radiotherapy in 2019"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the last dose of radiotherapy, on a date relative to the clinical note?", "answer": "2019", "justification": ["prior prostate radiotherapy in 2019"]}]}
{"id": 251, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04134260", "criterion": "Prior radiotherapy to the region of the study cancer that would result in overlap of radiation therapy fields", "note_date": "2023-03-12", "note": "A 54-year-old Caucasian male presented with a 1.5 mm Breslow malignant melanoma on his left shin in February 2018 and was managed with wide local excision. At 16 months follow-up, recurrence in the left inguinal lymph nodes was detected. The patient underwent groin dissection, and all 8 lymph nodes showed either partial or complete replacement by metastatic melanoma on histology with extracapsular extension. No necrosis was seen in either the skin or the lymph node specimens at this stage. Surgery was followed by adjuvant high-dose interferon-\u03b12a therapy, consisting of 1 month of intravenous interferon 5 days a week followed by 11 months of subcutaneous lower-dose interferon 3 days a week. Progression was documented at 6 months by computed tomography (CT), which confirmed a large metastasis in the spleen, left iliac lymphadenopathy, and 2metastases in the liver. The patient enrolled into a randomized phase II clinical trial in which he was treated with the toll-like receptor 9 agonist PF-3512676 (formerly known as CPG 7909), a synthetic cytosine-phosphorothioate-guanine rich oligodeoxynucleotide. PF-3512676 induces activation of plasmacytoid dendritic cells and enhances cell surface expression of costimulatory molecules (eg, B7) and is hypothesized to promote an antitumor immune response by enhancing antigen presentation to T cells and promoting proliferation of antigen-specific cytotoxic T lymphocytes. CT scanning was performed during the study initially 6 weekly for 6 months, then at 8 weekly intervals. The patient achieved stable disease over a 20-month period. Thereafter, disease progression, according to RECIST radiological parameters, was documented at all disease sites. It is worth noting that during the therapy period, the patient experienced grade 1 cutaneous reaction (minor erythema) at the site of the excised primary lesion, the left shin. In view of the indolent disease biology and the absence of new metastatic lesions during treatment, tumor metastasectomy was undertaken. Initial left iliac lymphadenectomy and splenectomy was followed by adjuvant pelvic radiotherapy. During a second procedure, the patient underwent staging laparoscopy followed by liver resection of segments V and VI with cholecystectomy. Surgical clearance was confirmed by whole body PET scanning at 1 month and 6 months after liver resection, indicating no disease activity. Following up imaging is currently being performed with 3 monthly alternating CT and PET scanning.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient received radiation therapy in the past?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["adjuvant pelvic radiotherapy."]}, {"question": "If so, did the radiation therapy target the pelvis or the prostate?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["adjuvant pelvic radiotherapy."]}, {"question": "If so, when was the last dose of radiotherapy, on a date relative to the clinical note?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 250, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04134260", "criterion": "Patients with inflammatory bowel disease", "note_date": "2021-12-30", "note": "2021-12-30 8:41 AM\r\nCT ABDOMEN W/CONTRAST; CT PELVIS W/CONTRAST\r\nReason: stricture versus abscess, please eval anastamosis site as\r\nAdmitting Diagnosis: SMALL BOWEL OBSTRUCTION;CROHNS DISEASE\r\nContrast: OPTIRAY Amt: 130\r\nMEDICAL CONDITION:\r\n29 year old man with Crohn's disease s/p colectomy and ileosigmoid anastamosis,\r\nadmitted for flareup\r\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION:\r\nstricture versus abscess, please eval anastamosis site as well\r\nNo contraindications for IV contrast\r\nFINAL REPORT\r\nCT ABDOMEN AND PELVIS WITH IV CONTRAST\r\nINDICATION:  29-year-old man with Crohn disease status post colectomy and\r\nileosigmoid anastomosis admitted for flareup stricture versus abscess.  Please\r\nevaluate anastomotic site.\r\nCT OF THE ABDOMEN AND PELVIS WITH IV CONTRAST\r\nTECHNIQUE:  Multidetector scanning is performed from the diaphragm through the\r\nsymphysis during dynamic injection of 130 cc of Optiray.  Comparison is made\r\nto prior examination of 2021-12-2.\r\nCT OF THE ABDOMEN WITH IV CONTRAST:  The lung bases are clear.  The liver is\r\nwithout focal lesions.  The gallbladder, spleen, pancreas, adrenal glands, and\r\nkidneys are unremarkable.  There is no retroperitoneal lymphadenopathy.\r\nCT OF THE PELVIS WITH IV CONTRAST:  Again noted is extensive wall thickening\r\nat the ileosigmoid anastomosis with proximal dilatation of the small bowel.\r\nThe phlegmon surrounding the anastomosis has decreased in size however now\r\nthere are several tracks containing oral contrast and air pockets identified\r\nwithin the phlegmon.  The phlegmon extends to the roof of the bladder however\r\nno air is seen within the bladder.\r\nOn bone windows, there is a small sclerotic focus in the left ilium consistent\r\nwith a bone island.  No concerning osteolytic or osteosclerotic lesions are\r\nseen.\r\nIMPRESSION:\r\n1.  Marked wall thickening at the ileosigmoid anastomosis consistent with\r\nCrohn disease.  There is extensive perianastomotic phlegmon.  While the\r\noverall extent of the phlegmon has decreased, there are now sinus tracts\r\nidentified one of which extends to the bladder roof but no communication with\r\nthe bladder is demonstrated.\r\n2.  Small-bowel obstruction, unchanged.\r\n(Over)\r\nFINAL REPORT", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with inflammatory bowel disease?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["29 year old man with Crohn's disease"]}, {"question": "If so, when?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 249, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04134260", "criterion": "Patients with inflammatory bowel disease", "note_date": "2021-11-04", "note": "2021-11-4 10:05 AM\r\nCHEST (PORTABLE AP)\r\nReason: please verify left picc tip placement\r\nAdmitting Diagnosis: ULCERATIVE COLITIS\r\nMEDICAL CONDITION:\r\n74 year old woman with ulcerative colitis\r\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION:\r\nplease verify left picc tip placement\r\nFINAL REPORT\r\nHISTORY:  Left PICC placement.  Ulcerative colitis.\r\nPORTABLE AP CHEST, ONE VIEW:  Comparison 2021-10-26.  Since the prior study the\r\nright PICC has been removed and a left PICC has been placed with tip in the\r\nregion of the brachiocephalic vein/upper SVC junction.  There is no\r\npneumothorax.  The heart is normal in size and the lungs are clear.  There are\r\nno pleural effusions.  There is deformity of the right lateral upper-to-mid\r\nribs, unchanged, consistent with rib fractures, age indeterminate.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with inflammatory bowel disease?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Admitting Diagnosis: ULCERATIVE COLITIS"]}, {"question": "If so, when?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 248, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04134260", "criterion": "Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)-infected patients on effective anti-retroviral therapy with undetectable viral load within 6 months are eligible for this trial and have a CD4 count >= 200 cells/microliter within 30 days prior to registration. Note: HIV testing is not required for eligibility for this protocol", "note_date": "2022-06-14", "note": "On 04-2022, a 20-year-old HIV infected male with a baseline CD4 count of 17 cells/mm3 was referred with cholestatic jaundice. He had recently commenced a fixed dose combination of emtricitabine, tenofovir DF, and efavirenz and was well prior to initiating ART. He developed jaundice two weeks after initiating these drugs. The ART drugs were discontinued by the referring physician as drug induced liver injury was suspected. He was asymptomatic prior to initiating ART. On examination he was emaciated, had yellow sclera and pale conjunctiva, and had a liver span of 18 cm and splenomegaly measuring 5 cm below the costal margin.\r\nHis baseline and follow-up blood investigations are shown in . Hepatitis A, B, and C serologies were negative. The chest radiograph was normal. Ultrasound of the abdomen showed an enlarged \u201cfatty\u201d liver and splenic hypodensities suggestive of granulomas.\r\nThe liver ultrasound failed to detect biliary obstruction and a liver biopsy was undertaken to rule out an infiltrative cause of the cholestatic jaundice such as mycobacterial, fungal, or nonbenign infiltration. A gastroscope was performed to investigate the normocytic, normochromic anaemia, and the suspicious lesions noted at gastroscopy were biopsied. In view of the bicytopenia and the absence of a plausible cause, a bone marrow aspiration and biopsy were also performed. The liver biopsy showed multiple acid fast bacilli; however the SD Bioline MPT64 TB Antigen Rapid was negative.\r\nThe duodenal biopsy and bone marrow trephine biopsy also showed AFBs. The TB culture was negative for mycobacteria tuberculosis, and microscopy was suggestive of Mycobacteria avium complex; however polymerase chain reaction was unable to identify the species. shows clumping of acid fast bacilli seen in the liver biopsy sample. shows a poorly formed granuloma commonly seen in nontuberculous mycobacteria infection.\r\nHe was commenced on rifampicin, isoniazid, ethambutol, pyrazinamide, and clarithromycin because a definitive microbiological diagnosis of TB or NTM was difficult to attain. After a two-month period of treatment, the patient showed significant clinical improvement.\r\nThe baseline HIV viral load was not done; however his viral load at 2 weeks of ART and following discontinuation of the drug for suspected drug induced hepatitis was 227 226 copies/mL. A HIV viral load, after 5 months of antiretrovirals, in June 2022 was 756 copies/mL.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with HIV?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["20-year-old HIV infected male"]}, {"question": "If so, is the patient under anti-retroviral therapy?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["A HIV viral load, after 5 months of antiretrovirals, in June 2022"]}, {"question": "If so, what is the most recent CD4 count of the patient?", "answer": "17 cells/mm3", "justification": ["a baseline CD4 count of 17 cells/mm3"]}, {"question": "If so, when was that CD4 count measured?", "answer": "04-2022", "justification": ["On 04-2022, a 20-year-old HIV infected male with a baseline CD4 count of 17 cells/mm3"]}]}
{"id": 247, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04134260", "criterion": "Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)-infected patients on effective anti-retroviral therapy with undetectable viral load within 6 months are eligible for this trial and have a CD4 count >= 200 cells/microliter within 30 days prior to registration. Note: HIV testing is not required for eligibility for this protocol", "note_date": "2023-01-12", "note": "The patient was a 46-year-old African American female with a past medical history of AIDS, gastro-esophageal reflux disease (GERD), obstructive sleep apnea, and mild intermittent asthma who presented with diffuse lymphadenopathy and fever. She was diagnosed with human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) 20 years ago but was not compliant with her antiretroviral therapy (ART) for the past two years and restarted ART three weeks prior to presentation. On presentation, her HIV viral load was 61,918,000 copies/mL and CD4 count was 15 cells/uL (2%) (advanced AIDS). Computed tomography (CT) imaging of thorax, abdomen, and pelvis showed pulmonary nodules and retroperitoneal, iliac, inguinal, mediastinal, hilar, and axillary lymphadenopathy, respectively. CT neck showed a right-sided cystic mass, as well as a heterogeneous cystic mass in the nasopharynx. Her right inguinal lymph node biopsy was consistent with a high-grade B-cell lymphoma, most likely PBL, respectively. Lymphoplasmacytic infiltration was detected in the node with mild CD138 staining and CD20 negativity. Her bone marrow biopsy was negative for lymphoma involvement, respectively. She was staged as a stage IIIB with an International Prognostic Index of 2.\r\nShe was started on treatment with the V-EPOCH regimen with intrathecal chemotherapy. Her ART was changed from Genvoya to dolutegravir, lamivudine, and tenofovir to optimize chemotherapy for future cycles and avoid interactions with chemotherapy. Following Cycle 3, imaging findings were consistent with a near-complete response (CR); CT thorax showed that several of her pulmonary nodules had decreased in size and one had completely resolved. CT abdomen and pelvis showed resolution of retroperitoneal and pelvic adenopathy, and CT neck no longer showed the nasopharyngeal mass nor necrotic right lymph node. One month after Cycle 4, CD4 count was at 66 cells/uL and HIV viral load was undetectable. She went on to complete Cycles 5 and 6 with the V-EPOCH regimen. Repeat positron emission tomography (PET) after Cycle 6 showed a complete response with no PET-avid fluorodeoxyglucose (FDG) uptake anywhere.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with HIV?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["She was diagnosed with human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)"]}, {"question": "If so, is the patient under anti-retroviral therapy?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["ART was changed from Genvoya to dolutegravir, lamivudine, and tenofovir"]}, {"question": "If so, what is the most recent viral load of the patient?", "answer": "Undetectable viral load", "justification": ["HIV viral load was undetectable"]}, {"question": "If so, when was that viral load measured?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 246, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04134260", "criterion": "Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)-infected patients on effective anti-retroviral therapy with undetectable viral load within 6 months are eligible for this trial and have a CD4 count >= 200 cells/microliter within 30 days prior to registration. Note: HIV testing is not required for eligibility for this protocol", "note_date": "2023-01-17", "note": "Here we report on a case of low plasmatic concentration of ARV drugs, with persistent detectable viral load despite regimen intensification, in a pregnant 26-year-old Brazilian woman with HIV-1 infection.\r\nThe first diagnosis of HIV was made in August 2016; at diagnosis, her CD4 count was 60 cells/mm3 and plasmatic viral load was 7,060,000 copies/mL. No drug resistance was reported at the baseline test. She did not report any alcohol or drug addiction, neither was she under any medical treatment. She was hence immediately started on ARV therapy. In accordance with the national Italian guidelines, a cART with abacavir/lamivudine/dolutegravir (DTG) (600/300/50 mg) once daily was introduced, which seemed to be well tolerated. Despite a significant reduction in the viral load (1650, 143, 58 copies/mL after 1, 2, and 4 months respectively), she never achieved plasmatic undetectability (HIV-ribonucliec acid (RNA) < 50 copies/mL) at follow-up. When asked, she reported poor adherence to the therapeutic regimen in spite of good tolerability.\r\nIn February 2017 she got pregnant. She was married and had adequate social and familial support and thus decided to go through with her pregnancy. The viral load at the beginning of pregnancy was 77 copies/mL with a CD4 count of 219 cells/mm3. After 1 month, the viral load was lower but still detectable (53 copies/mL). It was thus decided to implement the ongoing therapy with darunavir (DRV)-ritonavir (800/100 mg) once daily. Two months later, plasmatic HIV-RNA was 11,400 copies/mL in a context of reported good adherence. Furthermore, our patient did not report any flu-like illness or alterations of her general status which could have contributed to the increase in the viral load. Anticipating that bioavailability of DTG would be further reduced in the second and third trimesters, an additional dose of DTG (50 mg) was therefore included in the regimen. At the following control, 4 weeks later, plasmatic HIV-RNA was 252 copies/mL.\r\nIn order to maximize our patient\u2019s adherence to the ARV therapy, the frequency of controls was increased to a monthly basis; when interviewed, she appeared motivated to adhere to the treatment and to follow any medical advice in order to preserve her health and the baby\u2019s health. The actual intake of the pills was assessed by an electronic monitoring system of withdrawn drug boxes. In addition, at 23 weeks of gestation we collected a blood sample to determine the effective plasmatic concentration of DTG and DRV and to consequently better document plasmatic levels of ARV drugs. Trough plasma concentration (Ctrough) was measured by validated liquid chromatography\u2013mass spectrometry (LC-MS/MS). For both drugs, analysis revealed a Ctrough of 379 ng/mL (DTG) and 152 ng/mL (DRV), which were lower than expected in non-pregnant adults.\r\nAlong with controls at our HIV clinic, our patient underwent regular gynecologic follow-up. In addition to HIV infection, the physiology of her pregnancy was considered. The fetus showed normal growth and no major abnormalities were detected at ultrasound examinations.\r\nAt 34 weeks of gestation, the viral load dropped again to 81 copies/mL with a CD4 count of 177 cells/mm3; in accordance with the Italian guidelines, a cesarean section was thus recommended. Two weeks later, our patient delivered a healthy baby; there were no subsequent obstetric complications.\r\nOn review at 8 weeks, mother and baby were well; the baby\u2019s T and B cell numbers were normal, and HIV-RNA was undetectable. She is thus far uninfected.\r\nOn 10/2022, ten weeks after delivery, DTG and DRV concentrations in maternal blood were again examined. The Ctroughs were 3042 ng/mL (DTG) and 1748 ng/mL (DRV), showing a normal level of bioavailability for a non-pregnant adult. Our patient\u2019s regimen was then de-intensified to abacavir/lamivudine/DTG (600/300/50 mg) once daily. Her viral load declined to 38 copies/mL with a CD4 count of 248 cells/mm3, 1 month after treatment modification. After another 2 months, her CD4 cell count rose to 398 cells/mm3 and HIV-RNA was < 20 copies/ml.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with HIV?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["woman with HIV-1 infection"]}, {"question": "If so, is the patient under anti-retroviral therapy?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["abacavir/lamivudine/DTG (600/300/50 mg) once daily"]}, {"question": "If so, what is the most recent viral load of the patient?", "answer": "38 copies/mL", "justification": ["Her viral load declined to 38 copies/mL"]}, {"question": "If so, when was that viral load measured?", "answer": "01/2023", "justification": ["On 10/2022", "1 month", "After another 2 months"]}]}
{"id": 237, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT05223673", "criterion": "Participants must have received at least 2 prior regimens of standard chemotherapy for mCRC and had demonstrated progressive disease or intolerance to their last regimen", "note_date": "2020-01-17", "note": "A 73-year-old male patient diagnosed with mCRC was admitted to our hospital in September 2019. He had been diagnosed with colorectal cancer in March 2012 and had been treated with surgery and chemotherapy at that time. In September 2019, the patient was diagnosed with colorectal cancer with multiple metastatic nodules in the right and left lungs and multiple metastatic lymph nodes in both the supraclavicular area and the mediastinum. After the diagnosis, he was treated with FOLFIRI chemotherapy along with Panax ginseng and Cordyceps sinensis herbal pharmacopuncture (HP) treatment. FOLFIRI chemotherapy is a commonly used cocktail combination of three chemotherapeutic agents: fluorouracil, leucovorin, and irinotecan. Immediately after starting chemotherapy, the patient was admitted to our hospital to be treated with HP therapy. When he first presented to our hospital, he had some side effects caused by FOLFIRI chemotherapy such as fatigue, stomatitis, nausea, and headache.\r\nThe patient was treated with FOLFIRI chemotherapy eight times every 2 weeks, with intravenous HP treatment three times per week. Specifically, the side effects caused by FOLFIRI chemotherapy were treated with oral herbal medicine, and the symptoms were mitigated. The decrease of symptoms caused by chemotherapy was assessed using a visual analogue scale (VAS). However, after each chemotherapy treatment, some side effects that had diminished after oral intake of herbal medicine recurred. \r\nCT images were obtained three times during the course of treatment: in September 2019, October 2019, and finally in January 2020. The tumor sizes were found to have decreased at each CT imaging session. Compared to his first CT image in September 2019, the one in January 2020 showed significant decreases in both the pulmonary and lymph node areas.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with mCRC", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["the patient was diagnosed with colorectal cancer with multiple metastatic nodules"]}, {"question": "If so, has the patient received at least 2 regimens of chemotherapy for mCRC", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, what was the most recent regimen that the patient received to treat mCRC, relative to the date of the note?", "answer": "FOLFIRI chemotherapy", "justification": ["The patient was treated with FOLFIRI chemotherapy eight times every 2 weeks"]}, {"question": "If so, did the patient demonstrate intolerance or progressive disease after receiving the last regimen for mCRC", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 235, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04844749", "criterion": "Histologic identification of small cell carcinoma of the prostate or neuroendocrine pathology in either biopsy or prostatectomy tissue.", "note_date": "2023-01-12", "note": "A 68-year-old male patient visited the urology clinic in another hospital because of acute urinary retention. His medical history included hypertension without any specific family history. His prostate-specific antigen (PSA) level and prostate volume as measured at the initial visit were 1.19 mg/ml and 53 g, respectively. The hard prostate was palpated by digital rectal examination, without any palpable masses, and there were no abnormal findings except for a white blood cell (WBC) count of 3-5/high power field (HPF) and a red blood cell (RBC) count of 3-5/HPF in the urine analysis. No abnormal findings were reported for the complete blood cell count, biochemistry indexes, and simple radiologic exam. In May 2009, TURP was performed on this patient, and abdominal pelvic computed tomography (CT), chest CT, and whole-body bone scan were also performed because the pathology results indicated small cell cancer. In the abdominal pelvic CT, multiple lymphadenopathies that were assumed to be metastatic lesions were observed near the bilateral iliac chain. No metastatic lesions were found on the chest CT or whole-body bone scan. To treat the primary small cell carcinoma of the prostate, the patient was admitted for robot-assisted laparoscopic radical prostatectomy with adjuvant chemotherapy after transfer to the urology clinic in our hospital. We performed magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) in order to check the cancer stage. In the prostate MRI, the malignant lesion of the prostate was observed to invade the right capsule and seminal vesicles. In July 2009, the patient underwent robot-assisted laparoscopic radical prostatectomy and extended pelvic lymph node dissection; the bilateral nerves were not saved. The total operative time was 240 minutes, and the amount of blood loss was 250 cc. The drainage tube was removed on day 3 after surgery, and the patient was discharged without any postoperative complications on day 4. The pathologic results showed small cell carcinoma invading the capsule of the prostate and also metastasis of carcinoma in the right external iliac lymph nodes and right obturator lymph nodes. The weight of the prostate was 57 g, and the intraglandular tumor volume was 21 cc. The tumor involved both lobes, but the resection margin was not involved by the tumor. On postoperative day 7, the catheter was removed in the urology clinic. After brain MRI confirmed no metastatic lesions, adjuvant chemotherapy was started with VP-16 100 mg/m2 and cisplatin 80 mg/m2 on day 30. Adjuvant chemotherapy has been performed 8 times for 9 months since the operation. The multiple lymphadenopathies that had been observed before the surgery improved and there is currently no evidence of remnant disease.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with small cell carcinoma of the prostate", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["The pathologic results showed small cell carcinoma invading the capsule of the prostate"]}, {"question": "If so, has the diagnosis been histologically confirmed", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["The pathologic results showed small cell carcinoma invading the capsule of the prostate"]}]}
{"id": 199, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-11-13", "note": "Date of encounter: 11/13/2020\r\nCC: Oligometastatic castrate-sensitive prostate cancer\r\n \r\nHistory of Present Illness:\r\nMr. XXXX is a 72 year-old man with a history of HTN, HLD, and metastatic prostate cancer who is here for further management. He was found to have an elevated PSA around 11.4 in 2013 but deferred biopsy at that time. His PSA was 8.1 in 3/2016 and most recently 48.9 in 6/2018. He underwent a prostate biopsy on 7/12/18 which showed gleasion 4+5=9 with PNI. Prostate MRI shows a 3.1 cm lesion. He had a bone scan which showed activity in the left acetabulum (both anterior and posterior), sacrum at 3 different foci, suspicious for osseous metastasis. CT abdomen and pelvis showed lytic bony lesions involving the posterior left acetabulum and the bilateral sacrum concerning for metastatic disease. \r\n \r\nTREATMENT HISTORY:\r\n9/4/18: Lupron 3 months\r\n9/10/18: Cycle 1 docetaxel, PSA 69.9\r\n10/1/18: Cycle 2 docetaxel, stopped early due to side effects\r\n12/3/18: Lupron 3 months deferred\r\n5/10/19: Lupron 3 months\r\n9/20/19: Lupron 3 months\r\n12/13/19: Lupron 4 months\r\n5/15/20: Lupron 3 months\r\n8/14/20: Lupron 3 months \r\n\r\nImpression and Recommendations:\r\nXXXX is a 74 y.o. male with a history of HTN, HLD, and metastatic castrate-sensitive prostate cancer with bone involvement. His initial PSA is 70. He is currently asymptomatic. \r\n \r\n# Oligometastatic castrate-sensitive prostate cancer. \r\nHe has received 2 cycles of docetaxel chemotherapy and stopped due to side effects. PSA started rising with testosterone recovery and he has started back on ADT alone. He has deferred zytiga.  \r\n- I previously discussed consideration of low-dose radiation to the primary prostate based on the STAMPEDE data as well as MDT to his bony lesions. Referred to radiation oncolgoy for further discussion. He has deferred both for now. \r\n- Defer Lupron for 2 months given severe side effects per patient and him wanting to prioritize QoL over life span. \r\n- Check Testosterone and PSA monthly (12/2020, 1/2021)\r\n- Next Lupron in 1/2021\r\n \r\n#Osteoporosis \r\n- DEXA shows osteoporosis, 8/14/20. Patient to obtain dental evaluation and then will start fosamax\r\n- Continue calcium and vitamin D\r\n \r\nReturn to clinic:\r\n1/15/21\r\n \r\nOrders:\r\n\t\r\nOrders Placed This Encounter\r\n\u2022\tPSA,Free & Total Profile\r\n\u2022\tTestosterone", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient ever received chemotherapy?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["He has received 2 cycles of docetaxel chemotherapy"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the last dose of chemotherapy administered to the patient?", "answer": "10/1/2018", "justification": ["10/1/18: Cycle 2 docetaxel, stopped early due to side effects"]}]}
{"id": 245, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04134260", "criterion": "Hemoglobin >= 9.0 g/dL, independent of transfusion and/or growth factors (within 90 days prior to registration)", "note_date": "2023-01-12", "note": "A 65-year-old male chronic smoker presented with multiple painful swellings on his face, chest, and the left thigh that had developed over the duration of a month. On enquiry, he gave a history of an episode of gross painless hematuria with amorphous clots in the previous month that had not been evaluated. He had also suffered significant loss of weight. On examination, he was poorly nourished, pale and had multiple tender cutaneous nodules. Abdominal examination was unremarkable; on rectal examination an irregular firm mass was palpable above the prostate. On evaluation, he was anemic with a hemoglobin 7 g/dl, other routine blood investigations were within normal limits. Urine analysis confirmed hematuria. A contrast enhanced computed tomography (CECT) of the abdomen revealed a well-defined heterogeneously enhancing growth measuring 4.9 cm \u00d7 4.1 cm \u00d7 3.9 cm in the left lateral wall of the bladder with extravesical extension. Multiple pelvic and para-aortic lymph node enlargement were evident on the CECT. A fine-needle aspiration of one of the cutaneous lesions was taken which showed plenty of scattered atypical cells in a background mixed with lymphocytes and apoptotic debris. The atypical cells had pleomorphic oval irregular nuclei with elongated cytoplasm having flattened ends, a typical morphology of \u201ccercariform cells\u201d suggesting a metastasis from urothelial carcinoma. We proceeded with a cystoscopic biopsy of the bladder growth that revealed a high-grade urothelial carcinoma that was positive for both cytokeratin (CK) and vimentin on immunohistochemistry (IHC) suggesting a diagnosis of sarcomatoid carcinoma. The patient was counseled regarding his disease, he refused active therapy, and was referred for palliative care.", "qa_list": [{"question": "What is the patient's hemoglobin value?", "answer": "7 g/dl", "justification": ["with a hemoglobin 7 g/dl"]}, {"question": "If so, when was this value measured?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 244, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04134260", "criterion": "Hemoglobin >= 9.0 g/dL, independent of transfusion and/or growth factors (within 90 days prior to registration)", "note_date": "2023-02-13", "note": "Assessment and Plan Mr. James is a 91-year old gentleman who is a DNR/DNI with a PMH significant for CAD, COPD on 2L nc at night, PE on coumadin, mild AS (valve area 1.2-1.9cm2), and DM 2 transferred to the CCU for unresponsiveness. Patient presented to the OSH for an episode of unresponsiveness and had a carotid doppler study which showed severe bilateral carotid stenosis. He was transferred to Beth Israel for potential b/l carotid artery stenting. Pt had episode of unresponsiveness w/ jerking motions which did not appear tonic-clonic. Neurology was consulted and patient was transferred to CCU for further care. While in CCU, decision was made not to surgically act upon carotid stenoses (based upon cardiology & neurology decision); patient's right lower extremity had revascularization procedure done on 9-29.\r\nUnresponsiveness: Neurology was consulted, and after speaking to the daughter, believes episode was most likely anxiety attack and hyperventilation as patient reportedly has episodes of labored tachypnea at home. Pt receives 0.5mg Ativan qAM at home, which he had not received. Also possibly Ativan withdrawal, despite small dose. Also possible is LLL collapse seen on CXR leading to transient hypoxia in setting of bilateral carotid occlusive disease with supply/demand mismatch. TIA and seizure are unlikely. From an obstructive lung disease standpoint, he appears to be at baseline. No further episodes of unresponsiveness while here in the CCU. - Chest PT, mucolytics - Continue albuterol and ipratropium nebs. - Continue prednisone burst and azithromycin for presumed COPD exacerbation as contributor - Continue home Ativan qAM - f/u EEG results, neuro recs - Continue ASA 81 mg daily. Carotid stenosis: Patient transferred for carotid intervention, will not have carotid artery stenosis stenting for now, will undergo lower extremity revascularization first. Continue ASA 81 and atorvastatin. Continue to hold coumadin, continue heparin gtt (more for PE than for carotid artery stenosis) Respiratory: Patient with known COPD on supplemental overnight O2, although this appears to be stable. Based on physical exam, admission CXR, and elevated BNP, he likely also has an element of volume overload secondary to cardiogenic pulmonary edema. In addition, he was noted to have elevated filling pressures on cardiac catheterization in 6-23. Lasix prn with goal even to -500cc today. - Albuterol and ipratropium nebs. - Chest PT and mucolytics as above  CAD: Patient with brief <1min complaint of chest pain this morning, no acute EKG changes, resolved spontaneously and resembles pt s chronic chest/axillary pressure which he has when waking up in the mornings. Currently asymptomatic. Admission ECG with new TWI, but low suspicion for ACS at this time.  Continue metoprolol, ASA, statin, imdur. Pump: Patient with preserved LVEF on last echo, although with signs of volume overload currently. Continue metoprolol, lasix as above for goal even to -500cc today. Rhythmn: Sinus with 1:1 conduction. Monitor on telemetry. Anemia: Unclear baseline, although patient received 1 unit PRBC on 2022-08-10 prior to transfer for hemoglobin 10. Patient with iron studies consistent with anemia of chronic disease. Guiac positive on admission but brown non-bloody stool, hct stable since admission except for 2.5 point drop since yesterday s procedure believed appropriate. Check pm Hct today - Trend Hct daily, transfuse for hct<21 - Guaiac stools - Call PCP and assess colonoscopy history. Pulmonary embolism: Patient with history of PE in 4-23 on coumadin. Unclear based on review of records if there was an inciting event and need for continued anticoagulation. INR 1.3 today - Until clarified, will cover with heparin gtt for INR<2, although patient may not require continued anticoagulation. - Now post-procedure, can restart coumadin, and bridge with heparin gtt. DM: Hold home Glipizide. Continue HISS and accuchecks. 1 bottle + peptostrepto on OSH culture - f/u OSH sensitivities FEN: Diabetic, cardiac diet. Replete electrolytes prn. Access: PIV PPx: Heparin gtt, restarting coumadin. Code: DNR/DNI confirmed on admission. Will plan on reversing prior to interventions.", "qa_list": [{"question": "What is the patient's hemoglobin value?", "answer": "10", "justification": ["hemoglobin 10."]}, {"question": "If so, when was this value measured?", "answer": "On 2022-08-10", "justification": ["2022-08-10 prior to transfer for hemoglobin 10."]}]}
{"id": 243, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04134260", "criterion": "Hemoglobin >= 9.0 g/dL, independent of transfusion and/or growth factors (within 90 days prior to registration)", "note_date": "2022-09-23", "note": "2022-9-23 1:19 PM\r\n4 ICU nursing progress note:\r\nRespiratory: Wearing 100% nrb+6l nc sats 78-92%. Pt appearing more fatiqued. Sob with acitivity and dramatic desats. Team decided to bronch pt..much difficulty..requireing increased sedation and desated to 70's. Pt quickly intubated by anesthesia..without traums. Sats have remained in high 80's with po2 60-70. Increased peep to 15/100%/600/16. No spont rr. In order to ventilate/oxygenate pt needed to heavily sedate at this time. see note below.\r\nOf note..per attending..felt. high met-hemoglobin d/t use of hurricane spray..levels 18-20..given 80mgm meth. blue in hopes of decreasing met-hemoglobin..and increasing sats/po2\r\nPt has been suctioned for mod amts thick white secretions..ns lavage.\r\nNeuro: Has required large amts of versed/propofol to maintain adequate oxygenation..Currently on Fent gtt 75mi  Versed 3mgm and Propofol 29mic/kg/min. With any stimulation pt will grimace. Hands are restrainded.\r\nVolume status: Decrease in u/o noted at 1700..had recieved 500ns bolus prior for low bp. 1000ns bolus being given now. Prior to intubation pt c/o thirst. now on dry side.\r\nID: Low grade temp..wbc lower..continues on levo and flagyl.\r\nCardiac: Brief episodes of hypotension when given boluses of propofol..responded well to fluid bolus. Hr 70-120 nsr/st\r\nBP 90-118/60-70\r\nGI: NPO..if remains intubated. ng tube.\r\nSkin: Insciion sites clean and dry..discoloration around hip area..urology resident in to see.\r\nSocial: Husband in early am..called later and spoke with HO.", "qa_list": [{"question": "What is the patient's hemoglobin value?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when was this value measured?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 242, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04134260", "criterion": "Detectable PSA after radical prostatectomy. Detectable PSA is defined as serum PSA > 0 ng/mL at least 30 days after prostatectomy and within 180 days of registration and before start of GnRH agonist/antagonist", "note_date": "2021-09-27", "note": "2021-9-27 7:16 PM\r\nCHEST (PORTABLE AP) \r\nReason: verify tube placement\r\nAdmitting Diagnosis: PROSTATE CA/SDA\r\nMEDICAL CONDITION:\r\n61 year old man with 4500L bleeding after radical prostatectomy, currently intubated.\r\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION:\r\nverify tube placement\r\nFINAL REPORT\r\nINDICATION:  61-year-old man with 4,500 cc bleeding after radical\r\nprostatectomy.  Patient is status post intubation.  Evaluate tube placement.\r\nCOMPARISON:  None.\r\nAP SUPINE PORTABLE CHEST X-RAY:  A nasogastric tube is coiled within the\r\nstomach.  An endotracheal tube is seen 2 cm above the carina.  The cardiac\r\nsilhouette, mediastinal, and hilar contours are within normal limits.  The\r\npulmonary vasculature appears prominent, most likely related to patient\r\npositioning.  Both lungs are clear without consolidations or effusions.  The\r\nsurrounding soft tissue and osseous structures are unremarkable.\r\nIMPRESSION:\r\n1.  Endotracheal tube 2 cm above the carina.\r\n2.  Nasogastric tube coiled within the stomach body.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient had a radical prostatectomy?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["61 year old man with 4500L bleeding after radical prostatectomy"]}, {"question": "If so, when?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, can you list the PSA values of the patient after the radical prostatectomy and the corresponding dates of measurement of those values, separated by semicolon ? If there is no date of measurement in the note, return NA instead of the date", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 228, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04187833", "criterion": "Inability to swallow capsules or known intolerance to talazoparib or its excipients.", "note_date": "2022-12-28", "note": "Paramedics found this 59-year-old female with dyspnea and an oxygenation of 65% on room air and performed immediate tracheal intubation. Moderate ARDS with reduced lung compliance was diagnosed and treated with deep sedation, neuromuscular blocking agents, and prone positioning.\r\nOn day 14, a trial of sitting on the edge-of-bed (SOEB) was performed, while she was still intubated and under pressure support ventilation. SOEB required 3 physical therapists to maintain the position, but resulted in a significant increase in her level of consciousness and collaborative state. The next day, she was able to hold her head and sit for about 15 minutes with 2 therapists. Her muscle strength indicated ICU-acquired weakness, with a Medical Research Council sum-score (MRC-SS) of 40/60; still she continued with small but consistent improvements and started to participate actively in physical therapy sessions. She was encouraged to mobilize herself with exercises against gravity and was actively transferred to a chair each day with the help of 2 physical therapists. She was successfully extubated, but presented postextubation dysphagia. The physical therapy team closely monitored her for secretion management and cough stimulation and continued her physical rehabilitation. On day 19, she started to walk with a walking aid, although at this point oxygen desaturation during exercise training became evident (89% with 3 L/min of oxygen). After 25 days, she was transferred to the institution\u2019s rehabilitation facilities, where a battery of tests indicated persistent physical function impairment (MRC-SS 52/60, physical function ICU test score17 9/12, Timed Up & Go 23 seconds, short physical performance battery 4/12).", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient ever had a hypersensitivity reaction to one or more of the following ingredients : silicified microcrystalline cellulose, HPMC, yellow iron oxide, red iron oxide, titanium dioxide, shellac, black iron oxide, potassium hydroxide, ammonium hydroxide, propylene glycol", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 213, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2022-04-05", "note": "INTERVAL HISTORY\r\nPatient is here for follow up for his prostate cancer and worsening right leg pain. Was previously feeling great. Thinks the Lu177 has improved his pain overall. However in the past couple weeks has had increased pain in right leg. Described as muscle spasms and tightness in right buttocks and upper leg. Associated with low back pain. The pain limits ability to walk on right leg. No numbness, saddle anesthesia, bowel/bladder incontinence. Taking Norco, ibuprofen, and methocarbamol which relieves pain but it comes back within a few hours. He went to ED at St. John's where CT did not show any urgent findings. Overall feels more fatigued. Eating well, maintaining weight. Hypertensive in clinic.\r\n \r\nREVIEW OF SYSTEMS\r\nA 14 point Review of Systems was obtained and was negative unless mentioned otherwise in HPI and Interval History above.\r\n \r\nALLERGIES \t\t\r\nAllergies\r\nAllergen\tReactions\r\n\u2022\tVenlafaxine\t \r\n \r\nMEDICATIONS\r\n\r\nCurrent Outpatient Medications: \r\n\u2022  abiraterone 250 mg tablet, Take 4 tablets (1,000 mg total) by mouth daily., Disp: 120 tablet, Rfl: 5\r\n\u2022  acetaminophen 500 mg tablet, Take 2 tablets (1,000 mg total) by mouth every six (6) hours as needed for Pain., Disp: 100 tablet, Rfl: 2\r\n\u2022  amLODIPine 5 mg tablet, Take 1 tablet (5 mg total) by mouth daily., Disp: 90 tablet, Rfl: 3\r\n\u2022  atorvastatin 20 mg tablet, Take 1 tablet (20 mg total) by mouth daily., Disp: 90 tablet, Rfl: 2\r\n\u2022  gabapentin 300 mg capsule, Take 1 capsule (300 mg total) by mouth three (3) times daily. (Patient taking differently: Take 300 mg by mouth daily .), Disp: 270 capsule, Rfl: 3\r\n\u2022  GINSENG PO, Take 1,500 mg by mouth daily., Disp: , Rfl: \r\n\u2022  HYDROcodone-acetaminophen 5-325 mg tablet, Take 1 tablet by mouth every four (4) hours as needed for Moderate Pain (Pain Scale 4-6) or Severe Pain (Pain Scale 7-10). Max Daily Amount: 6 tablets, Disp: 30 tablet, Rfl: 0\r\n\u2022  leuprolide, 3 month, (LUPRON DEPOT) 22.5 mg injection, Inject 22.5 mg into the muscle every three (3) months., Disp: , Rfl: \r\n\u2022  lidocaine 5% patch, Place 1 patch onto the skin every twelve (12) hours 12 hours on 12 hours off.., Disp: 30 patch, Rfl: 0\r\n\u2022  methocarbamol 500 mg tablet, Take 0.5 tablets (250 mg total) by mouth three (3) times daily as needed., Disp: 60 tablet, Rfl: 0\r\n\u2022  polyethyl glycol-propyl glycol (SYSTANE) 0.4-0.3% ophthalmic solution, Place 1 drop into both eyes as needed for., Disp: , Rfl: \r\n\u2022  predniSONE 5 mg tablet, Take 5 mg by mouth daily., Disp: , Rfl: \r\n\u2022  QUERCETIN PO, Take 1,000 mg by mouth daily., Disp: , Rfl: \r\n\u2022  senna-docusate 8.6-50 mg tablet, Take 1 tablet by mouth two (2) times daily as needed for Constipation., Disp: 60 tablet, Rfl: 5\r\n\u2022  spironolactone 25 mg tablet, Take 0.5 tablets (12.5 mg total) by mouth daily., Disp: 90 tablet, Rfl: 2\r\n\u2022  tamsulosin 0.4 mg capsule, Take 1 capsule (0.4 mg total) by mouth at bedtime., Disp: 90 capsule, Rfl: 5\r\n\u2022  traMADol 50 mg tablet, Take 1 tablet (50 mg total) by mouth every six (6) hours as needed for Moderate Pain (Pain Scale 4-6) or Severe Pain (Pain Scale 7-10). Max Daily Amount: 200 mg, Disp: 10 tablet, Rfl: 0\r\n \r\nCurrent Facility-Administered Medications: \r\n\u2022  lidocaine PF 1% inj 2 mL, 2 mL, Intra-articular, Once, Regan-Rainey, Margaret A., NP\r\n\u2022  methylPREDNISolone acetate 40 mg/mL inj 40 mg, 40 mg, Intra-articular, Once,  \r\n \r\nFacility-Administered Medications Ordered in Other Visits: \r\n\u2022  pegfilgrastim-jmdb (Fulphila) 6 mg/0.6 mL inj 6 mg, 6 mg, Subcutaneous, Once,  \r\n \r\nPAST MEDICAL HISTORY\r\nDiagnosis\tDate\r\n\u2022\tAsthma\t \r\n\u2022\tDepression\t \r\n\u2022\tGERD (gastroesophageal reflux disease)\t \r\n\u2022\tHigh cholesterol\t \r\n\u2022\tProstate cancer (HCC/RAF)\t \r\n\u2022\tSenile cataract\t11/24/2021\r\n\u2022\tSleep apnea\t \r\n \r\nPAST SURGICAL HISTORY\t\t\t\r\nPast Surgical History:\r\nProcedure\tLaterality\tDate\r\n\u2022\tTONSILLECTOMY\t \t \r\n \r\nSOCIAL HISTORY\r\n \r\nSocial Hx (Click to Expand/Collapse)\r\nSocial History\t\t\t\r\nSocioeconomic History\r\n\u2022\tMarital status:\tMarried\r\n \t \tSpouse name:\tNot on file\r\n\u2022\tNumber of children:\tNot on file\r\n\u2022\tYears of education:\tNot on file\r\n\u2022\tHighest education level:\tNot on file\r\nOccupational History\r\n\u2022\tNot on file\r\nTobacco Use\r\n\u2022\tSmoking status:\tNever Smoker\r\n\u2022\tSmokeless tobacco:\tNever Used\r\nSubstance and Sexual Activity\r\n\u2022\tAlcohol use:\tYes\r\n\u2022\tDrug use:\tNever\r\n\u2022\tSexual activity:\tNot on file\r\nOther Topics\tConcern\r\n\u2022\tNot on file\r\nSocial History Narrative\r\n \tHe is drinking 1-2 glasses of wine up to 5-6 times a week\r\n \tHe used cocaine in his 20s.  Denies any illicit drug use or marijuana use\r\n \t \r\nSocial Determinants of Health \r\nPhysical Activity: Not on file\r\nStress: Not on file\r\nFinancial Resource Strain: Not on file", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient ever received chemotherapy", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the first dose of chemotherapy administered to the patient", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 241, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04134260", "criterion": "History/physical examination within 90 days prior to registration", "note_date": "2021-03-07", "note": "2021-3-7 12:41 AM\r\nCT SINUS W/ & W/O CONTRAST\r\nReason: Please assess for areas of occult infection -- do not need c\r\nAdmitting Diagnosis: MULTIPLE MYELOMA;DIARRHEA\r\nMEDICAL CONDITION:\r\n61 year old man with multiple myeloma, acute GVHD of gut, on a variety of\r\nimmunosuppressants, now presenting with fevers to 101.9.\r\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION:\r\nPlease assess for areas of occult infection -- do not need contrast if unnecessary.\r\nNo contraindications for IV contrast\r\nPROVISIONAL FINDINGS IMPRESSION (PFI): RSRc SAT 2021-3-76:11 AM\r\nIncrease in left maxillary sinus opacification, with aerosolized\r\nsecretions, and possible interval obstruction of the left osteomeatal complex.\r\nDecrease in right maxillary sinus opacification.  No definite osseous\r\ndestruction results, but there is again widespread change of multiple myeloma.\r\nFINAL REPORT\r\nHISTORY:  61-year-old male with multiple myeloma, acute graft versus host\r\ndisease, on immunosuppressants, fever to 101.9.  Evaluate for occult\r\ninfection.\r\nCOMPARISON:  CT facial bones one month prior.\r\nTECHNIQUE:  Axial imaging was performed through the facial bones without IV\r\ncontrast.  Multiplanar reformations were provided.\r\nCT FACIAL BONES WITHOUT IV CONTRAST:  Acute on chronic inflammatory disease\r\ninvolving the left maxillary sinus has increased, with increased opacification\r\nand aerosolized secretions.  However, there has been decrease in opacification\r\nof the right maxillary sinus.  There is no evidence of frank bone destruction.\r\nThere may be interval obstruction of the left ostiomeatal complex.\r\nThe bony nasal septum is midline and no other anatomic abnormality is\r\nidentified. There is partial opacification of the anterior ethmoid air cells\r\nas on the prior study.\r\nThere is diffuse osteopenia with numerous lytic foci and accompanying\r\nendosteal scalloping, as in the prior study, likely related to multiple\r\nmyeloma.\r\nIMPRESSION:\r\n1.  Acute on chronic inflammatory disease, increased in the left maxillary\r\nsinus, and decreased in the right maxillary sinus.\r\n2.  Apparent interval obstruction of the left ostiomeatal complex.\r\n3.  No definite bone destruction.\r\n4.  Multiple myeloma widespread changes.\r\n(Over)\r\n2021-3-7 12:41 AM\r\nAdmitting Diagnosis: MULTIPLE MYELOMA;DIARRHEA\r\nFINAL REPORT", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with multiple myeloma", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["61 year old man with multiple myeloma"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the last physical examination of the patient performed", "answer": "On 2021-03-07", "justification": ["2021-3-7 12:41 AM"]}]}
{"id": 240, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2021-05-02", "note": "2021-5-2  2:52 PM\r\nCT ABDOMEN W/O CONTRAST; CT PELVIS W/O CONTRAST\r\nReason: Please evalute for evidence of mass/lymphoma.\r\nAdmitting Diagnosis: PNEUMONIA\r\nMEDICAL CONDITION:\r\n90 year old woman with hypoxemia s/p tap of left pleural effusion.  Prelim\r\nconcerning for lymphoma.  Please evalute for evidence of mass/lymphoma.\r\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION:\r\nPlease evalute for evidence of mass/lymphoma.\r\nCONTRAINDICATIONS for IV CONTRAST:\r\nCKD;CKD\r\nPFI REPORT\r\nPFI:  No masses or lymphadenopathy to suggest source of B-cell lymphoma.\r\nSmall-to-moderate left pleural effusion with left basilar atelectasis.\r\nHypodense pancreatic tail indeterminate etiology without IV contrast is\r\nunlikely to be source of B-cell lymphoma.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with B-cell lymphoma", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 239, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2021-10-06", "note": "2021-10-6 12:09 PM\r\nLIVER OR GALLBLADDER US (SINGLE ORGAN)\r\nReason: CHOLANGIOCARCINOMA, ASSESS RUQ MASS\r\nAdmitting Diagnosis: CHOLANIOCARCINOMA - PAIN CONTROL\r\nMEDICAL CONDITION:\r\n61 year old man with cholangiocarcinoma, s/p resection of part of liver\r\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION:\r\nassess ruq mass\r\nWET READ: JCCJ SUN 2021-10-6 12:42 PM\r\nno obvious mass, no duct dilatation, no free fluid\r\nFINAL REPORT\r\nINDICATION:  A 61-year-old man status post resection for cholangiocarcinoma.\r\nPresenting with intractable pain, localized to the incision site.\r\nCOMPARISON:  CT scan of the abdomen and pelvis 2021-9-23.\r\nFINDINGS:  The patient is status post right hepatic lobectomy.  The left\r\nhepatic lobe is hypertrophied, as expected.  No focal parenchymal\r\nabnormalities are seen.  There is no intrahepatic ductal dilatation.  The\r\nportal vein is open, and flow is hepatopetal.  There is no free abdominal\r\nfluid.\r\nIMPRESSION:  Unremarkable post right lobectomy appearance of the liver.  No\r\nfree fluid or focal abnormality identified.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient ever been tested for hepatitis B virus surface antigen", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, has the patient tested positive for HBsAg", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 238, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2021-02-17", "note": "2021-2-17 8:45 AM\r\nLIVER OR GALLBLADDER US (SINGLE ORGAN)\r\nReason: RESECTION FOR CHOLANGIOCARCINOMA, WITH INCREASED LFT'S AND ITCHING, ASSESS DUCTS\r\nMEDICAL CONDITION:\r\n75 year old man with cholangioca\r\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION:\r\nassess ducts\r\nFINAL REPORT\r\nINDICATION:  History of cholangiocarcinoma with resection 1 year ago.\r\nIncreasing LFTs and itching.  Question biliary ductal dilatation.\r\nFINDINGS:  The liver has normal size and echotexture.  There is intrahepatic\r\nbiliary ductal dilatation, which extends to the area of the hepatic hilum.\r\nBeyond this region, biliary ductal dilatation cannot be seen.  Additionally,\r\nit is difficult to assess the area of hepatic hilum, which appears slightly\r\nhyperechoic with irregular borders compared to the remainder of the hepatic\r\nparenchyma.  The patient is status post cholecystectomy.  Intraabdominal\r\ncatheter is demonstrated.\r\nIMPRESSION:\r\nIntrahepatic biliary ductal dilatation, with history of cholangiocarcinoma and\r\nresection may represent stricture or recurrent obstructing disease.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with prostate cancer", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, has the prostate cancer metastasized to the bones", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 236, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT05223673", "criterion": "Participants must have received at least 2 prior regimens of standard chemotherapy for mCRC and had demonstrated progressive disease or intolerance to their last regimen", "note_date": "2020-05-28", "note": "Patient 1, a 52-year-old female, was admitted to our hospital in Jun 2018, due to \u201cblood-stained stool for 2 years\u201d. Colonoscopy revealed a mass in rectum, and preoperative pathological diagnosis was adenocarcinoma. On July, 2018, the loop sigmoid colostomy was performed, which revealed about 300 mL bloody ascites in pelvis. A 9\u00d78\u00d76 cm mass was found in segment IV of liver, and some pale nodules were distributed in the abdominal cavity and right ovary, which were diagnosed as pelvic mucinous adenocarcinoma planting metastasis (by intraoperative frozen section examination). The diagnosis was rectal adenocarcinoma with diffused pelvic and liver metastasis (T4N2M1 stage IV). No gene mutations were detected in RAS and BRAF. Because our department was conducting clinical research comparing the efficacy of raltitrexed versus fluoropyrimidine in treating mCRC at that time when the patient was admitted to our hospital, we enrolled the patient in our research and administered the patient \u201coxaliplatin + raltitrexed\u201d for three cycles (Jul 2018 to Sep 2018). Unfortunately, her follow-up computed tomography (CT) scans indicated progressive disease (PD). Concerning the patient\u2019s poor response, and severe gastrointestinal symptoms, we recommended the patient use S-1, which is an oral 5-FU prodrug that has slight gastrointestinal toxicity. Her treatment was then altered for three cycles of \u201coxaliplatin + S-1\u201d regimen, as the second-line chemotherapy (Oct 2018\u2013Dec 2018). The therapeutic evaluation was stable disease (SD). Then, she was administered S-1 orally as a maintenance treatment for six cycles (Jan 2015 to Jun 2015) until the patient obtained PD on CT scans. The patient\u2019s condition deteriorated with increased ascites and aggravated gastrointestinal symptoms. Afterward, \u201cCisplatin + Endostatin\u201d hyperthermia peritoneal perfusion chemotherapy was applied three times to treat massive ascites in Jul 2018. The patient obtained PD on CT scans after the termination of chemotherapy. Trifluridine/tipiracil (TAS-102) and regorafenib were not approved in China at that time, and there were no suitable clinical trials of mCRC in our hospital. The patient refused to consult in other hospitals or purchase expensive targeted agents. Apatinib went on the market at that time with a favorable policy for purchasing. After signing informed consent, the patient started taking apatinib (850 mg/day) in Oct 2019. Because of the side effects of hand\u2013foot syndrome (HFS) (grade 2) and proteinuria (grade 2), the patient had a short-time drug withdrawal, and recovered from the side effects with symptomatic treatment during apatinib treatment. Four months later, the follow-up CT scan indicated an SD by Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST 1.1) with a 22.2% decrease of liver target lesions compared with the baseline of Oct 2015. However, due to severe abdominal distension and loss of appetite, we had to terminate the use of apatinib, and we gave the patient immediate and appropriate care in Mar 2020.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with mCRC", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["The diagnosis was rectal adenocarcinoma with diffused pelvic and liver metastasis"]}, {"question": "If so, has the patient received at least 2 regimens of chemotherapy for mCRC", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["administered the patient \u201coxaliplatin + raltitrexed\u201d for three cycles (Jul 2018 to Sep 2018).", "Her treatment was then altered for three cycles of \u201coxaliplatin + S-1\u201d regimen, as the second-line chemotherapy (Oct 2018\u2013Dec 2018)"]}, {"question": "If so, what was the last regimen that the patient received to treat mCRC", "answer": "Apatinib", "justification": ["after signing informed consent, the patient started taking apatinib (850 mg/day) in Oct 2019."]}, {"question": "If so, did the patient demonstrate intolerance or progressive disease after receiving the last regimen for mCRC", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["However, due to severe abdominal distension and loss of appetite, we had to terminate the use of apatinib"]}]}
{"id": 234, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2021-12-08", "note": "10/7/21: Patient established with Dr. XXXX for management of transformation of MGUS to IgG Kappa Multiple Myeloma, confirmed on BM biopsy 9/30/21. \r\nHere to discuss treatment options. He lives in Long Beach and preference is to receive treatment in Torrance. \r\nFeels in his normal state of health with the exception of: \r\n-He reports right sided posterior cervical and supraclavicular lymph nodes, stable in size. \r\n-He does get occasional R sided nerve pain that radiates from his right scapula down his right arm. \r\nPatient denies fevers, chills, night sweats, fatigue, loss of appetite, nausea, swelling, or skin changes. \r\n \r\n10/13/21: He is scheduled to receive his first dose of bortezomib on 10/15/21.  He reports pain in his right neck and posterior ribs.  He is taking tylenol and ibuprofen and feels hesitant to take pain medications. His PET/CT scan was today.  No fevers.  \r\n \r\n10/20/21: He is cycle 1 day 7 of RVD.\r\n \r\n11/10/21: He is s/p cycle 1 day 22 of RVD. C/o significant cramping and hands and legs; went to ED yesterday due to significant calf pain, DVT studies negative. Intermittent burning sensation of R arm, but otherwise denies numbness/tingling. Some constipation. He is working with the transplant team to schedule mobilization. \r\nPSA elevated to 8.0. PCP referred to urology. \r\n \r\n12/8/21: Patient is s/p C3 RVD given at Torrance. Reports tolerating well. \r\nPatient was seen by urologist, Dr. XXXX, who ordered an MRI and biopsy to evaluate up-trending PSA. \r\nHe meet with XXXX today to discuss ASCT. \r\nECOG performance status: 0", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient ever received dexamethasone", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["He is cycle 1 day 7 of RVD."]}, {"question": "If so, when did the patient start treatment with dexamethasone", "answer": "On 2021/10/15", "justification": ["10/20/21: He is cycle 1 day 7 of RVD."]}, {"question": "If so, is the patient currently under dexamethasone treatment", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["12/8/21: Patient is s/p C3 RVD given at Torrance.", "Date of the note: 2021-12-08"]}]}
{"id": 233, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04844749", "criterion": "ECOG performance status <2.", "note_date": "2021-12-08", "note": "10/7/21: Patient established with Dr. XXXX for management of transformation of MGUS to IgG Kappa Multiple Myeloma, confirmed on BM biopsy 9/30/21. \r\nHere to discuss treatment options. He lives in Long Beach and preference is to receive treatment in Torrance. \r\nFeels in his normal state of health with the exception of: \r\n-He reports right sided posterior cervical and supraclavicular lymph nodes, stable in size. \r\n-He does get occasional R sided nerve pain that radiates from his right scapula down his right arm. \r\nPatient denies fevers, chills, night sweats, fatigue, loss of appetite, nausea, swelling, or skin changes. \r\n \r\n10/13/21: He is scheduled to receive his first dose of bortezomib on 10/15/21.  He reports pain in his right neck and posterior ribs.  He is taking tylenol and ibuprofen and feels hesitant to take pain medications. His PET/CT scan was today.  No fevers.  \r\n \r\n10/20/21: He is cycle 1 day 7 of RVD.\r\n \r\n11/10/21: He is s/p cycle 1 day 22 of RVD. C/o significant cramping and hands and legs; went to ED yesterday due to significant calf pain, DVT studies negative. Intermittent burning sensation of R arm, but otherwise denies numbness/tingling. Some constipation. He is working with the transplant team to schedule mobilization. \r\nPSA elevated to 8.0. PCP referred to urology. \r\n \r\n12/8/21: Patient is s/p C3 RVD given at Torrance. Reports tolerating well. \r\nPatient was seen by urologist, Dr. XXXX, who ordered an MRI and biopsy to evaluate up-trending PSA. \r\nHe meet with XXXX today to discuss ASCT. \r\nECOG performance status: 0", "qa_list": [{"question": "What is the most recent ECOG performance status of the patient, on a date relative to the clinical note date", "answer": "ECOG performance status: 0", "justification": ["ECOG performance status: 0"]}, {"question": "If so, when was that ECOG performance status recorded", "answer": "On 12/8/21", "justification": ["12/8/21", "ECOG performance status: 0"]}]}
{"id": 232, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04844749", "criterion": "Patients should be excluded if they have a positive test for hepatitis B virus surface antigen (HBV sAg) or hepatitis C virus ribonucleic acid (HCV antibody) indicating acute or chronic infection.", "note_date": "2021-06-09", "note": "2021-6-9 7:29 PM\r\nDUPLEX DOPP ABD/PEL; LIVER OR GALLBLADDER US (SINGLE ORGAN)\r\nReason: eval liver for blood flow and ascites.\r\nAdmitting Diagnosis: HEPATITIS\r\nMEDICAL CONDITION:\r\n52 year old woman with autoimmune hepatitis, hepatorenal syndrome.\r\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION:\r\neval liver for blood flow and ascites.\r\nWET READ: ENYa TUE 2021-6-9 10:53 PM\r\n1. Major intrahepatic vasculature patent and normal in flow direction.\r\n2. Coarsened and echogenic liver compatible with known autoimmune hepatitis.\r\nFINAL REPORT\r\nHISTORY:  52-year-old woman, with autoimmune hepatitis.  Question about\r\nhepatorenal syndrome.\r\nCOMPARISON:  2021-5-25.\r\nRIGHT UPPER QUADRANT ULTRASOUND WITH DOPPLER:  The liver is diffusely\r\ncoarsened and echogenic.  There is no focal lesion.  No intrahepatic or\r\nextrahepatic biliary ductal dilatation is noted.  The CBD measures 5 mm in\r\ndiameter.  The patient is status post cholecystectomy.  There is no\r\nperihepatic fluid.  The enlarged spleen measures 15 cm.  There are bilateral\r\npleural effusions.\r\nAssessment of the hepatic vasculature is slightly limited by patient's\r\nintubation status and respiratory variation due to ventilation.  Allowing for\r\nthese limitations, major intrahepatic vasculature is patent with expected\r\ndirection of flow assessed by Doppler.\r\nIMPRESSION:\r\n1.  Major intrahepatic vasculature patent with normal direction of flow.\r\n2.  Slightly coarsened and echogenic liver compatible with the history of\r\nautoimmune hepatitis.  No intrahepatic or extrahepatic biliary ductal\r\ndilatation.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient ever been tested for HCV RNA", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, was the HCV RNA test positive", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 231, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04844749", "criterion": "Patients should be excluded if they have a positive test for hepatitis B virus surface antigen (HBV sAg) or hepatitis C virus ribonucleic acid (HCV antibody) indicating acute or chronic infection.", "note_date": "2021-01-12", "note": "An 82-year-old woman was in November 2019 admitted to Kobe Asahi Hospital for the treatment of HCC with molecular targeted therapy such as Lenvatinib (LEN) (8 mg/d).\r\nShe had overcome hepatitis C virus infection (HCV) 10 years earlier with interferon treatment, but still retained Child A liver cirrhosis.\r\nShe has suffered from chronic obstructive pulmonary disease for 20 years.\r\nNothing particular.\r\nShe had no hepatomegaly and no splenomegaly.\r\nLaboratory examinations at admission revealed the following: Total protein 7.3 g/dL (normal 6.5-8.3), albumin 3.6 g/dL (3.8-5.3), aspartate aminotransferase 92 IU/L (10-40), alanine aminotransferase 172 IU/L (5-40), gamma-glutamyl transpeptidase 90 IU/L (< 35), alkaline phosphatase 422 IU/L (115-359), T-bil 1.3 mg/dL (0.2-1.2), NH3 163 \u03bcg/dL (< 130), pertussis toxin 88.3% (70-130), white blood cell 67 \u00d7 103/\u03bcL (36-90), Hb 13.6 g/dL (11.5-15.0), platelets 32.0 \u00d7 104/\u03bcL (13.4-34.9), hepatitis B surface antigen (-), HCVAb (+), HCV RNA (-), tumor markers were as follows: Alpha-fetoprotein (AFP) 30332.7 ng/mL (< 10.0), PIVKA-\u2161 1395 mAU/mL (< 40).\r\nImaging examination 1: At admission imaging studies including Gadolinium-ethoxybenzyl-diethylenetriamine pentaacetic acid-enhanced magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) showed multiple HCC nodules in both right and left lobes. Gastrointestinal fiberscope revealed atrophic gastritis.\r\nImaging examination 2: Brain MRI revealed high intensity in the bilateral globus pallidus on T2-weighted images (T2WI), ascribed to elevated serum ammonia (163 \u03bcg/dL), but no findings in the cavernous sinus or Meckel\u2019s cave, and marrow in the petrous bone was intact.\r\nImaging examination 3: Brain MRI revealed a low intensity mass around the right Meckel\u2019s cave on T2WI and loss of normal fatty bone marrow signal intensity in the right petrous bone on T1-weighted images (T1WI).\r\nImaging examination 4: MRI revealed a low intensity mass around the right cavernous node, the right Meckel's cave, and the right petrous bone on T2WI. Based on MRI findings, the rapid increase in the size of the lesions over 1 mo and the onset of neurologic dysfunction, such as impairment of right trigeminal and abducens nerves, were most likely due to the metastasizing HCC.\r\nUltrasound guided biopsy of the left lobe revealed moderately differentiated HCC.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient ever been tested for HCV RNA", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["HCV RNA (-)"]}, {"question": "If so, has the patient been tested positive for HCV RNA", "answer": "No", "justification": ["HCV RNA (-)"]}]}
{"id": 230, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04844749", "criterion": "Patients should be excluded if they have a positive test for hepatitis B virus surface antigen (HBV sAg) or hepatitis C virus ribonucleic acid (HCV antibody) indicating acute or chronic infection.", "note_date": "2020-12-13", "note": "Patient 2 was a 28-year-old woman. She had been a sexual worker since 2017. She complained about mild fatigue and consulted our hospital in 2018. Her ALT level was 44 IU/L and she was positive for HBsAg, HBeAg, and HBV-DNA. Her ALT level was within the normal range, and HBsAg and HBeAg were positive thereafter. HBV-DNA was consistently >8 LC/mL. She had been diagnosed with chronic hepatitis with mild activity or asymptomatic HBV carrier status (i.e., the immune-tolerant phase); therefore, IgM-type anti-HBc and anti-HBc were not tested in 2018. However, in 2009, it was proven later that she had been negative for HBsAg when she gave birth to her daughter. Although the daughter did not receive HBV vaccine after birth, she was negative for HBsAg and anti-HBc in 2020. The patient was suspected to have had acute HBV infection with mild hepatitis, which was considered an unapparent infection. She was infected with HBV genotype C.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient ever been tested for hepatitis B virus surface antigen", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["she was positive for HBsAg, HBeAg, and HBV-DNA"]}, {"question": "If so, has the patient tested positive for HBsAg", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["she was positive for HBsAg, HBeAg, and HBV-DNA"]}, {"question": "If so, when", "answer": "In 2018", "justification": ["She complained about mild fatigue and consulted our hospital in 2018. Her ALT level was 44 IU/L and she was positive for HBsAg, HBeAg, and HBV-DNA."]}]}
{"id": 229, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04187833", "criterion": "Inability to swallow capsules or known intolerance to talazoparib or its excipients.", "note_date": "2022-05-13", "note": "A 55-year-old lady, a college professor, presented to us with a history of persistent itching, erythema, oozing and crusting over the nipple, areola and periareolar region on the left breast of more than 6 months duration. The lesions had been localized to the nipple and immediate periareolar region initially but had started extending recently. She had been using various topical medications for the same including steroids of varying potency. The patient had good response to topical steroids initially but on further use the lesion appeared to be getting worse. The patient had no other significant co-morbidity and was in otherwise good health. On examination we found an ill-defined area of scaling, erythema and minimal crusting over the over the nipple, areola and peri-areolar region on the left breast. There was minimal induration over the nipple and immediate peri-areolar area and no significant tenderness or bleeding on touch. Patient had no significant lymphadenopathy. The unilateral nature of the central lesions and the apparent lack of response to topical steroids made us consider a possibility of mammary Paget's disease, for which the patient was evaluated. Routine blood and urine investigation were within normal limits. Potassium hydroxide smears and cytology findings were normal. Mammography showed no evidence of any micro calcification or significant breast tissue involvement suggestive of malignancy. A skin biopsy was taken form two sites and both the specimens showed features of a dermatitis with spongiosis and moderate lymphocytic infiltration. Based on the investigation results we ruled out the possibility of Paget's disease and considered an alternative possibility of a primary non-specific dermatitis with a persistent contact dermatitis to topical applications. We initially patch tested the patient with the commercial products she was using, including brands of fluticasone and betamethasone. Interestingly all the products showed a strong positive reaction after 48h. We then patch-tested the patient with multiple antigens including topical antibiotics, preservatives and bases. The patch tests showed a strongly positive reaction to propylene glycol, parabens and chlorocresol and a moderate reaction to both neomycin and gentamycin. We also carried out an intradermal test with hydrocortisone and betamethasone solutions in saline, which gave a negative result. Based on the patch test findings we asked the patient to stop all topical preparations and started the patient on saline compresses and plain Vaseline along with a short course of systemic steroids. The lesions improved and by the end of two weeks had subsided almost entirely with only a mild residual hyperpigmentation.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient ever presented hypersensitivity reaction to one or more of the following ingredients : silicified microcrystalline cellulose, HPMC, yellow iron oxide, red iron oxide, titanium dioxide, shellac, black iron oxide, potassium hydroxide, ammonium hydroxide, propylene glycol", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["The patch tests showed a strongly positive reaction to propylene glycol"]}, {"question": "If so, when", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 227, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04187833", "criterion": "Inability to swallow capsules or known intolerance to talazoparib or its excipients.", "note_date": "2022-12-20", "note": "XXXX is a 59 y.o. male with h/o paraganglioma s/p resection on 5/17/18, HTN and osteoporosis. He has been under the care of Dr. XXXX for MGUS surveillance since September 2019, now here for consultation regarding transformation to IgG Kappa Multiple Myeloma, confirmed on biopsy 9/30/21.\r\n \r\n9/19/19- initial consult with Dr. XXXX. Notes he constantly gets shingles infections, typically q4-6m.o, onset ~30yrs; not taking any medication, just using a topical cream when needed. Denies taking any steroids. No recent fractures or hospitalizations. Fhx includes osteoporosis in mom. Pt works full time at an orthotics and prosthetics company in Torrance. \r\n \r\n10/21/19-f/u. CT skull (10/1) with no e/o hemorrhage, mass or osseous lesions. Lab work up notable for elevated Kappa Light chain at 33.90, K/L free chains at 52.15, IgG at 2,270, monoclonal protein at 88.6 and low IgM at 41. SPEP 1.2g/dl.  Today in clinic, he is overall well. Here to discuss next steps. Denies constitutional symptoms, bone pain.  Started prolia with Dr. XXXXX and tolerated it well.\r\n \r\n3/10/2020- f/u. Pt is doing overall well today. Recently got over shingles flare up. No new issues to report. \r\n \r\n9/14/20- F/U + discuss lab results.  Lab work up notable for elevated Kappa Light chain at 1,143.67, K/L free chains at 257.58, IgG at 1,970, monoclonal protein at 1.0  and low IgM at 26 SPEP 7.9 g/dl. Denies any new symptoms. Saw Dr. Harari on 8/14 which patient suggest he was concern with the elevated norepinephrine and dopamine levels. He will be following back in Dec 2020. Pt is doing well overall. \r\n \r\n12/22/20- F/U + discuss lab results-Lab work up notable for elevated Kappa Light chain at 2067.39, K/L free chains at 504.24, IgG at 1,770, monoclonal protein at 1.0  and low IgM at 22 SPEP 7.9 g/dl. Is doing well, having some hard time during the pandemic. During the interim, patient states he had some problems when collecting labs. Additionally he reports PET/CT appt is on the 30th of this month ordered by NP Isorena. Denies any new symptoms. Has been walking every morning for 2 miles. Still on a restrictive diet, but denies any weight loss or weight gain.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Did the patient ever have dysphagia", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, does the patient currently have dysphagia", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 226, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04187833", "criterion": "Inability to swallow capsules or known intolerance to talazoparib or its excipients.", "note_date": "2022-12-20", "note": "XXXX is a 59 y.o. male with h/o paraganglioma s/p resection on 5/17/18, HTN and osteoporosis. He has been under the care of Dr. XXXX for MGUS surveillance since September 2019, now here for consultation regarding transformation to IgG Kappa Multiple Myeloma, confirmed on biopsy 9/30/21.\r\n \r\n9/19/19- initial consult with Dr. XXXX. Notes he constantly gets shingles infections, typically q4-6m.o, onset ~30yrs; not taking any medication, just using a topical cream when needed. Denies taking any steroids. No recent fractures or hospitalizations. Fhx includes osteoporosis in mom. Pt works full time at an orthotics and prosthetics company in Torrance. \r\n \r\n10/21/19-f/u. CT skull (10/1) with no e/o hemorrhage, mass or osseous lesions. Lab work up notable for elevated Kappa Light chain at 33.90, K/L free chains at 52.15, IgG at 2,270, monoclonal protein at 88.6 and low IgM at 41. SPEP 1.2g/dl.  Today in clinic, he is overall well. Here to discuss next steps. Denies constitutional symptoms, bone pain.  Started prolia with Dr. XXXXX and tolerated it well.\r\n \r\n3/10/2020- f/u. Pt is doing overall well today. Recently got over shingles flare up. No new issues to report. \r\n \r\n9/14/20- F/U + discuss lab results.  Lab work up notable for elevated Kappa Light chain at 1,143.67, K/L free chains at 257.58, IgG at 1,970, monoclonal protein at 1.0  and low IgM at 26 SPEP 7.9 g/dl. Denies any new symptoms. Saw Dr. Harari on 8/14 which patient suggest he was concern with the elevated norepinephrine and dopamine levels. He will be following back in Dec 2020. Pt is doing well overall. \r\n \r\n12/22/20- F/U + discuss lab results-Lab work up notable for elevated Kappa Light chain at 2067.39, K/L free chains at 504.24, IgG at 1,770, monoclonal protein at 1.0  and low IgM at 22 SPEP 7.9 g/dl. Is doing well, having some hard time during the pandemic. During the interim, patient states he had some problems when collecting labs. Additionally he reports PET/CT appt is on the 30th of this month ordered by NP Isorena. Denies any new symptoms. Has been walking every morning for 2 miles. Still on a restrictive diet, but denies any weight loss or weight gain.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient ever received talazoparib", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, did the patient present any hypersensitivity symptoms after talazoparib administration", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 225, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2021-10-22", "note": "2021-10-22 4:15 AM\r\nCHEST (PORTABLE AP)\r\nReason: Interval change in pulmonary status?\r\nAdmitting Diagnosis: ACUTE RENAL FAILURE;METASTATIC OVARIAN CANCER\r\nMEDICAL CONDITION:\r\n74 year old woman with metastatic ovarian cancer, malignant pleural effusion\r\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION:\r\nInterval change in pulmonary status?\r\nPROVISIONAL FINDINGS IMPRESSION (PFI): JRld WED 2021-10-22 1:12 PM\r\nUnchanged small bilateral pleural effusions, greater on the left side, with\r\nassociated atelectasis.\r\nFINAL REPORT\r\nREASON FOR EXAM:  Metastatic ovarian cancer, malignant pleural effusion.\r\nET tube tip is 2.3 cm above the carina.  NG tube and left IJ catheter remain\r\nin place as is the right pleural pigtail catheter.  Small bilateral pleural\r\neffusions, greater on the left side, associated with atelectasis are\r\nunchanged.  Of note, the left lateral CP angle was not included on the film.\r\nCardiomediastinal contours are unchanged.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient received radiation therapy", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 224, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-04-30", "note": "Impression and Recommendations:\r\n \r\n68 y.o. female with Small cell/urothelial bladder cancer, post neoadjuvant chemotherapy, cystectomy/LN dissection and adjuvant pembrolizumab from 2/2019 till 4/2020. PS 1 \r\n \r\n# Urothelial cancer \r\n- She completed 15 months of adjuvant immunotherapy with pembrolizumab and treatment was stopped due to adrenal insufficiency and arthritis.\r\n \r\nTODAY: \r\n- Reviewed and discussed  imaging with patient and spouse no evidence of recurrent disease. \r\n- She denies any cancer related symptoms. Clinically she is doing well wo progressive disease symptoms. \r\n- Repeat CT NCAP wo contrast 4/2022\r\n- Repeat MRI brain 4/2022\r\n \r\n#Adrenal Insufficiency: \r\n- Taking 15 mg qAM and 5mg qnoon as of 1/21/22\r\n- Patient will discuss with Dr. L  regarding lower BP (90s-100s/50-60s) and fatigue and whether alterations of steroids would be necessary\r\n- Placed referral to cardio-oncology on 1/21/22\r\n \r\n# Left ankle fracture\r\nSlid in mud while going downstairs 12/30/21. Saw Dr. F  on 1/4/22. MRI of left ankle on 1/12/22 with sprain and non-displaced fracture in posterior malleolus. \r\n- Following Dr. F \r\n- DXA scan ordered \r\n \r\n# Bladder spasm s/p neobladder surgery\r\n- With urine leakage with catheterization \r\n- s/p urethral debulking with improvement in incontinence in between catheterization \r\n-  To continue to follow with Dr.N \r\n- May seek a second urologic opinion \r\n \r\n# Infectious disease\r\n- See ID for recommendations on antibiotic choice given history of cdiff and multiple infection seen on scans. \r\n- Has fidaxomicin as needed \r\n \r\n# Hypothyroid on thyroid supplement\r\n- TSH normal \r\n-Continue fu with Endocrinology \r\n \r\n# Eye pain/headache \r\n- biopsy negative for temporal arteritis\r\n- MRI Brain negative 6/2021\r\n- On memantine \r\n \r\n#Left leg lymphedema related to cancer \r\n- On lymphedema on her own device at home.\r\n- Stable, continue to monitor. \r\n \r\n# GI symptoms/diverticulitis/celiac \r\n- to follow with Dr. S  \r\n \r\n# Sciatica, L leg\r\n- Referred to Dr. Sacks for consultation on epidural injection\r\n- Ordered duloxetine 60 mg qdaily for pain\r\n- Continue gabapentin 300 mg BID\r\n- Will order oxycodone 5 mg q6h PRN for breakthrough pain (patient is traveling next week and needs something fast-acting)", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient ever been treated with a TKI", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 223, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-04-30", "note": "REASON FOR VISIT/CC: \r\nFollow up for pT3bN2 urothelial carcinoma of the bladder cancer with micropapillary features (surgery 1/2019; patient also has small cell feature history) s/p 14 mo of adjuvant Pembrolizumab therapy currently in surveillance without progressive disease \r\n \r\nONCOLOGY HISTORY\r\n- 12/2016 - (University of Chicago) Diagnosed with T1 urothelial cancer with small cell features.         Treated with TURBT and BCG\r\n- May 17, 2017 - (MD Anderson)  CT chest showed nonspecific bilateral pulmonary nodules          that were stable, MRI urogram showed stable hyperintense lesions on the right lobe of the liver, no residual recurrence of the bladder. \r\n- 5/18/2017: Cystourethroscopy, TURBT and EUA, no masses or lesions, pathology negative.\r\n- June 2018 - Developed a submucosal mass that could not be biopsied effectively \r\n- June 2018 - Started cisplatin/etoposide * 2\r\n- Jan 8, 2019 - Cystectomy with LN dissection and pathology finding ypT3bN2 disease with urothelial with >75% micropapillary, no small cell component.\r\n- Feb 21, 2019 - Started ADJUVANT pembrolizumab. Has mutations in TP53, RB1, TERT, ARID1A, AKT1, BRCA2, TC 5% PD-L1 positive (DAKO 22C3), MMR stable.  Stopped 04/2020 due to adrenal insufficiency and completed 2 years therapy. \r\n-1/19/21: CT NCAP with NED. Stable bilateral inguinal inguinal and external iliac LN. \r\n- 04/2021 Due to headache underwent MRI brain negative for cancer\r\n- 05/2021 CT CAP NED \r\n- 09/2021 CT NCAP NED \r\n- 12/2021: CT NCAP wo contrast NED\r\n \r\nTREATMENT HISTORY:\r\n- TURBT and BCG- 2/2017 to 4/2018\r\n- Etopsoside/cisplatin  2018 for small cell \r\n- Cystectomy  With + BPLN with urothelial +1/8/19\r\n- Adjuvant Pembrolizumab Cycle 1:  2/2019; 6/14/19 - 04/2020:Pemprolizumab at UCLA.D/C due to adrenal insufficiency\r\n \r\nInterval History:\r\nHere for follow up for her bladder cancer. Was seen recently but  In interim with fall leading to left ankle fracture. Now in boot for ~6-10 weeks and will take ~3 months to fully heal. She continues to have issues with her neobladder (leaking during catheterization) and had a recent urethral debulking procedure. Also doing poorly with fatigue and borderline low BP. \r\n \r\nReview of Systems:\r\n14 point ROS negative unless otherwise stated above.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient ever been treated with immunotherapy", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Started ADJUVANT pembrolizumab."]}, {"question": "If so, when did the immunotherapy treatment started", "answer": "On Feb 21, 2019", "justification": ["Feb 21, 2019"]}, {"question": "If so, when did the patient receive the last dose of immunotherapy", "answer": "On 04/2020", "justification": ["Stopped 04/2020 due to adrenal insufficiency"]}]}
{"id": 222, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-04-30", "note": "REASON FOR VISIT/CC: \r\nFollow up for pT3bN2 urothelial carcinoma of the bladder cancer with micropapillary features (surgery 1/2019; patient also has small cell feature history) s/p 14 mo of adjuvant Pembrolizumab therapy currently in surveillance without progressive disease \r\n \r\nONCOLOGY HISTORY\r\n- 12/2016 - (University of Chicago) Diagnosed with T1 urothelial cancer with small cell features.         Treated with TURBT and BCG\r\n- May 17, 2017 - (MD Anderson)  CT chest showed nonspecific bilateral pulmonary nodules          that were stable, MRI urogram showed stable hyperintense lesions on the right lobe of the liver, no residual recurrence of the bladder. \r\n- 5/18/2017: Cystourethroscopy, TURBT and EUA, no masses or lesions, pathology negative.\r\n- June 2018 - Developed a submucosal mass that could not be biopsied effectively \r\n- June 2018 - Started cisplatin/etoposide * 2\r\n- Jan 8, 2019 - Cystectomy with LN dissection and pathology finding ypT3bN2 disease with urothelial with >75% micropapillary, no small cell component.\r\n- Feb 21, 2019 - Started ADJUVANT pembrolizumab. Has mutations in TP53, RB1, TERT, ARID1A, AKT1, BRCA2, TC 5% PD-L1 positive (DAKO 22C3), MMR stable.  Stopped 04/2020 due to adrenal insufficiency and completed 2 years therapy. \r\n-1/19/21: CT NCAP with NED. Stable bilateral inguinal inguinal and external iliac LN. \r\n- 04/2021 Due to headache underwent MRI brain negative for cancer\r\n- 05/2021 CT CAP NED \r\n- 09/2021 CT NCAP NED \r\n- 12/2021: CT NCAP wo contrast NED\r\n \r\nTREATMENT HISTORY:\r\n- TURBT and BCG- 2/2017 to 4/2018\r\n- Etopsoside/cisplatin  2018 for small cell \r\n- Cystectomy  With + BPLN with urothelial +1/8/19\r\n- Adjuvant Pembrolizumab Cycle 1:  2/2019; 6/14/19 - 04/2020:Pemprolizumab at UCLA.D/C due to adrenal insufficiency\r\n \r\nInterval History:\r\nHere for follow up for her bladder cancer. Was seen recently but  In interim with fall leading to left ankle fracture. Now in boot for ~6-10 weeks and will take ~3 months to fully heal. She continues to have issues with her neobladder (leaking during catheterization) and had a recent urethral debulking procedure. Also doing poorly with fatigue and borderline low BP. \r\n \r\nReview of Systems:\r\n14 point ROS negative unless otherwise stated above.", "qa_list": [{"question": "What is the stage of the tumor of the patient", "answer": "Stage 3B", "justification": ["pT3bN2"]}, {"question": "If so, has the tumor spread to lymph nodes", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["pT3bN2"]}, {"question": "If so, has the patient presented metastases to other organs", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 221, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2021-12-15", "note": "REASON FOR VISIT/CC: \r\nFollow up for pT3bN2 urothelial carcinoma of the bladder cancer with micropapillary features (surgery 1/2019; patient also has small cell feature history) s/p 14 mo of adjuvant Pembrolizumab therapy currently in surveillance without progressive disease \r\n \r\nONCOLOGY HISTORY\r\n- 12/2016 - (University of Chicago) Diagnosed with T1 urothelial cancer with small cell features.         Treated with TURBT and BCG\r\n- May 17, 2017 - (MD Anderson)  CT chest showed nonspecific bilateral pulmonary nodules          that were stable, MRI urogram showed stable hyperintense lesions on the right lobe of the liver, no residual recurrence of the bladder. \r\n- 5/18/2017: Cystourethroscopy, TURBT and EUA, no masses or lesions, pathology negative.\r\n- June 2018 - Developed a submucosal mass that could not be biopsied effectively \r\n- June 2018 - Started cisplatin/etoposide * 2\r\n- Jan 8, 2019 - Cystectomy with LN dissection and pathology finding ypT3bN2 disease with urothelial with >75% micropapillary, no small cell component.\r\n- Feb 21, 2019 - Started ADJUVANT pembrolizumab. Has mutations in TP53, RB1, TERT, ARID1A, AKT1, BRCA2, TC 5% PD-L1 positive (DAKO 22C3), MMR stable.  Stopped 04/2020 due to adrenal insufficiency and completed 2 years therapy. \r\n-1/19/21: CT NCAP with NED. Stable bilateral inguinal inguinal and external iliac LN. \r\n- 04/2021 Due to headache underwent MRI brain negative for cancer\r\n- 05/2021 CT CAP NED \r\n- 09/2021 CT NCAP NED \r\n- 12/2021: CT NCAP wo contrast NED\r\n \r\nTREATMENT HISTORY:\r\n- TURBT and BCG- 2/2017 to 4/2018\r\n- Etopsoside/cisplatin  2018 for small cell \r\n- Cystectomy  With + BPLN with urothelial +1/8/19\r\n- Adjuvant Pembrolizumab Cycle 1:  2/2019; 6/14/19 - 04/2020:Pemprolizumab at UCLA.D/C due to adrenal insufficiency\r\n \r\nInterval History:\r\nHere for follow up for her bladder cancer. Was seen recently but  In interim with fall leading to left ankle fracture. Now in boot for ~6-10 weeks and will take ~3 months to fully heal. She continues to have issues with her neobladder (leaking during catheterization) and had a recent urethral debulking procedure. Also doing poorly with fatigue and borderline low BP. \r\n \r\nReview of Systems:\r\n14 point ROS negative unless otherwise stated above.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with urothelial carcinoma", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Diagnosed with T1 urothelial cancer"]}, {"question": "If so, has the patient undergone trans urethral removal of bladder tumor", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Treated with TURBT and BCG"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the patient treated with TURBT", "answer": "On 12/2016", "justification": ["12/2016 - (University of Chicago) Diagnosed with T1 urothelial cancer with small cell features. Treated with TURBT and BCG"]}]}
{"id": 178, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2023-02-02", "note": "A 41-year-old female presented with pelvic pain, profuse menorrhagia, and severe symptomatic anemia (near syncope and shortness of breath). She underwent total abdominal hysterectomy with bilateral salpingo-oophorectomy (TAH/BSO) as the continuous bleeding was not responding to conservative measures and the patient had no further desire of fertility. Biopsy showed an infiltrate in the endomyometrium, fallopian tubes, and cervix of mature-appearing plasma cells that stained positive for CD56, CD38, CD79A, and MUM1 with lambda light chain restriction, consistent with plasmacytosis. Bone marrow (BM) biopsy demonstrated a hypercellular marrow and atypical plasmacytosis (25%) with lambda restriction. BM flow cytometry was positive for CD38, CD138, and CD19 and negative for CD56, CD20, and CD45 consistent with plasma cell neoplasm. FISH showed 46, female karyotype, positive for three copies of 1q21 including CKS1B gene. Free kappa and lambda light chain levels in urine were 39.9 (reference range 1.35\u201324.19) and 1.59 (0.24\u20136.66) with a kappa/lambda ratio of 25.09 (2.04\u201310.37). Free kappa and lambda light chains in serum were 12.6 (3.3\u201319.4) and 16.5 (5.7\u201326.3) with a kappa/lambda ratio of .76 (0.26\u20131.65). No M protein was detected in the SPEP or UPEP. The albumin level was 3.6, beta-2 microglobulin was 1.347 mg/L, and LDH was 163. The patient was diagnosed on 10th of December 2020 with nonsecretory multiple myeloma with extramedullary plasmacytoma (ISS stage I).\r\nAround the time of TAH/BSO, the patient also reported progressively painful swelling on the left side of her neck accompanied with odynophagia, dysphagia, and hoarseness. CT of neck showed a left thyroid mass (7 \u00d7 5 \u00d7 7 cm) with irregular borders and a multinodular thyroid enlargement. Diagnostic incision biopsy demonstrated a very friable, irregular, malignant-appearing mass in the left lobe. A portion of the mass was removed and sent for analysis. Biopsy confirmed lambda-restricted plasma cell neoplasm involving the strap muscles. The neoplastic plasma cells were positive for CD138, CD79a, CD45 (dim), MUM1, VS38C, and CD56. The patient remained clinically and biochemically euthyroid.\r\nWhole body FDG-PET scan showed FDG uptake in a 4.4 \u00d7 4.7 cm mass with central necrosis within the left thyroid lobe along with mild FDG uptake within two right breast nodules. Breast U/S and mammography confirmed the nodules on the PET scan and showed other multiple bilateral nodules. Excision biopsy of the right breast nodule also showed lambda-restricted plasma cell neoplasm ( and ) positive for CD 56, CD138, CD79a, and VS38C. The patient also started complaining of lower extremity bone pain, but skeletal survey was negative.\r\nThe patient was started on bortezomib (Velcade), cyclophosphamide, and dexamethasone (VCD). After the first cycle, lenalidomide (Revlimid) was added to the regimen (RVCD). The patient completed a total of 1 cycle of VCD and 4 cycles of RVCD. Follow-up PET-CT scan done 6 weeks after the 5th cycle showed no evidence of active lesions. The patient had a clinical complete response (CR), so she proceeded with autologous stem cell transplantation (ASCT) 8 weeks after the 5th cycle of chemotherapy with high-dose melphalan conditioning. The patient tolerated the treatment well. She will be continued indefinitely on daily lenalidomide and alternate weekly bortezomib maintenance therapy and will be followed up with PET-CT scans.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient ever been diagnosed with nonsecretory multiple myeloma", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["The patient was diagnosed on 10th of December 2020 with nonsecretory multiple myeloma"]}, {"question": "If so, when", "answer": "On 2020/12/10", "justification": ["The patient was diagnosed on 10th of December 2020 with nonsecretory multiple myeloma"]}]}
{"id": 220, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2022-01-21", "note": "PLAN\r\n# Localized prostate cancer, node positive\r\n- 09/08/21 PSA 13.1 on 09/08/2021. \r\n- 09/10/21 MRI prostate demonstrated  PI-RADS 5 lesion at right right posterolateral and posteromedial peripheral midgland with the suggestion of seminal vesicle involvement as well as an additional PI-RADS 4 lesion at midline posterior peripheral apical midgland. \r\n- 09/17/21 GS 4+3=7 prostate cancer diagnosed via MRI-US fusion prostate biopsy with Dr. A on 09/17/2021. 5/6 cores. 1 core 3+4 = 7 \r\n- 10/08/21 PSMA PET-CT demonstrated uptake in the prostate as well as bilateral proximal seminal vesicles suggesting possible seminal vesicle involvement and prominent right common and right external iliac lymph nodes suspicious for metastatic disease. \r\n- 10/19/21: Robot-assisted laparoscopic radical prostatectomy and extended bilateral pelvic lymph node dissection with Dr. C. pT3bN1\r\n- We discussed case at GU tumor board and discussed final recommendations. No radiation at this time. Based on PSA decide on ADT only for now and consider if at all radiation in 6 months \r\n \r\nToday\r\n- PSA trending up suggestive of biochemical recurrence vs mCSPC\r\n- Repeat restaging scan with PSMA-PET/CT (will reach out to Dr. C to see if candidate to get this on study)\r\n- Afterwards will start Lupron q3 month and Zytiga \r\n- Consideration radiation in future pending scans. Follow-up with Dr. K after PSA-PET/CT scan\r\n- Follow-up with Dr. C on 1/27/22\r\n \r\n# Bone health\r\n- Plan for ADT, which raises risk for bone density loss\r\n- Baseline DEXA scan - will be done locally through PCP\r\n- Start calcium and vitamin D\r\n \r\n# Urosepsis, resolved\r\nHad a severe UTI requiring IV antibiotics for 4 weeks (completed day after Thanksgiving).\r\n- Now recovered \r\n \r\n# Cardiovascular risk\r\n# HTN\r\nGiven history of smoking, active HTN, and plans to start Zytiga will refer to cardio-oncology for co management. \r\n- Referral to Dr. H placed 1/21/22 \r\n \r\n# Genetics\r\n- Went over Tempus results including germline mutation detected for which we will refer to genetics. \r\n- referred to genetics 12/8/21\r\n \r\n# Chronic back pain \r\n- We will repeat scans in the future so can evaluate again these areas and if needed add MRI as well. \r\n \r\n# Emotional support\r\n- Continues on duloxetine  \r\n- Referral to Simms Mann placed 1/21/22\r\n\r\n# Nutrition and lifestyle modifications\r\n- Encouraged to continue to eat healthy well balanced diet. \r\n- Needs to continue to exercise and remain in shape. \r\n- Limit alcohol intake\r\n- Avoid smoking \r\n \r\n# Follow up. \r\n- If possible, plan restaging PSMA-PET/CT, first dose of Lupron with us, and follow-up with Dr. K all in one visit\r\n \r\n Based on PSA decide on ADT only for now and consider if at all radiation in 6 months \r\n \r\nToday\r\n- PSA trending up suggestive of biochemical recurrence vs mCSPC\r\n- Repeat restaging scan with PSMA-PET/CT (will reach out to Dr. C to see if candidate to get this on study)\r\n- Afterwards will start Lupron q3 month and Zytiga \r\n- Consideration radiation in future pending scans. Follow-up with Dr. K after PSA-PET/CT scan\r\n- Follow-up with Dr. C on 1/27/22\r\n \r\n# Bone health\r\n- Plan for ADT, which raises risk for bone density loss\r\n- Baseline DEXA scan - will be done locally through PCP\r\n- Start calcium and vitamin D\r\n \r\n# Urosepsis, resolved\r\nHad a severe UTI requiring IV antibiotics for 4 weeks (completed day after Thanksgiving).\r\n- Now recovered \r\n \r\n# Cardiovascular risk\r\n# HTN\r\nGiven history of smoking, active HTN, and plans to start Zytiga will refer to cardio-oncology for co management. \r\n- Referral to Dr. H placed 1/21/22 \r\n \r\n# Genetics\r\n- Went over Tempus results including germline mutation detected for which we will refer to genetics. \r\n- referred to genetics 12/8/21\r\n \r\n# Chronic back pain \r\n- We will repeat scans in the future so can evaluate again these areas and if needed add MRI as well. \r\n \r\n# Emotional support\r\n- Continues on duloxetine  \r\n- Referral to Simms Mann placed 1/21/22\r\n\r\n# Nutrition and lifestyle modifications\r\n- Encouraged to continue to eat healthy well balanced diet. \r\n- Needs to continue to exercise and remain in shape. \r\n- Limit alcohol intake\r\n- Avoid smoking \r\n \r\n# Follow up. \r\n- If possible, plan restaging PSMA-PET/CT, first dose of Lupron with us, and follow-up with Dr. K all in one visit", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient undergone prostatectomy", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Robot-assisted laparoscopic radical prostatectomy"]}, {"question": "If so, when", "answer": "On 10/19/2021", "justification": ["10/19/21: Robot-assisted laparoscopic radical prostatectomy"]}, {"question": "If so, did the patient receive ADT", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 219, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2022-01-21", "note": "PLAN\r\n# Localized prostate cancer, node positive\r\n- 09/08/21 PSA 13.1 on 09/08/2021. \r\n- 09/10/21 MRI prostate demonstrated  PI-RADS 5 lesion at right right posterolateral and posteromedial peripheral midgland with the suggestion of seminal vesicle involvement as well as an additional PI-RADS 4 lesion at midline posterior peripheral apical midgland. \r\n- 09/17/21 GS 4+3=7 prostate cancer diagnosed via MRI-US fusion prostate biopsy with Dr. A on 09/17/2021. 5/6 cores. 1 core 3+4 = 7 \r\n- 10/08/21 PSMA PET-CT demonstrated uptake in the prostate as well as bilateral proximal seminal vesicles suggesting possible seminal vesicle involvement and prominent right common and right external iliac lymph nodes suspicious for metastatic disease. \r\n- 10/19/21: Robot-assisted laparoscopic radical prostatectomy and extended bilateral pelvic lymph node dissection with Dr. C. pT3bN1\r\n- We discussed case at GU tumor board and discussed final recommendations. PLAN\r\n \r\n# Localized prostate cancer, node positive\r\n- 09/08/21 PSA 13.1 on 09/08/2021. \r\n- 09/10/21 MRI prostate demonstrated  PI-RADS 5 lesion at right right posterolateral and posteromedial peripheral midgland with the suggestion of seminal vesicle involvement as well as an additional PI-RADS 4 lesion at midline posterior peripheral apical midgland. \r\n- 09/17/21 GS 4+3=7 prostate cancer diagnosed via MRI-US fusion prostate biopsy with Dr. A on 09/17/2021. 5/6 cores. 1 core 3+4 = 7 \r\n- 10/08/21 PSMA PET-CT demonstrated uptake in the prostate as well as bilateral proximal seminal vesicles suggesting possible seminal vesicle involvement and prominent right common and right external iliac lymph nodes suspicious for metastatic disease. \r\n- 10/19/21: Robot-assisted laparoscopic radical prostatectomy and extended bilateral pelvic lymph node dissection with Dr. C. pT3bN1\r\n- We discussed case at GU tumor board and discussed final recommendations. No radiation at this time. Based on PSA decide on ADT only for now and consider if at all radiation in 6 months \r\n \r\nToday\r\n- PSA trending up suggestive of biochemical recurrence vs mCSPC\r\n- Repeat restaging scan with PSMA-PET/CT (will reach out to Dr. C to see if candidate to get this on study)\r\n- Afterwards will start Lupron q3 month and Zytiga \r\n- Consideration radiation in future pending scans. Follow-up with Dr. K after PSA-PET/CT scan\r\n- Follow-up with Dr. C on 1/27/22\r\n \r\n# Bone health\r\n- Plan for ADT, which raises risk for bone density loss\r\n- Baseline DEXA scan - will be done locally through PCP\r\n- Start calcium and vitamin D\r\n \r\n# Urosepsis, resolved\r\nHad a severe UTI requiring IV antibiotics for 4 weeks (completed day after Thanksgiving).\r\n- Now recovered \r\n \r\n# Cardiovascular risk\r\n# HTN\r\nGiven history of smoking, active HTN, and plans to start Zytiga will refer to cardio-oncology for co management. \r\n- Referral to Dr. H placed 1/21/22 \r\n \r\n# Genetics\r\n- Went over Tempus results including germline mutation detected for which we will refer to genetics. \r\n- referred to genetics 12/8/21\r\n \r\n# Chronic back pain \r\n- We will repeat scans in the future so can evaluate again these areas and if needed add MRI as well. \r\n \r\n# Emotional support\r\n- Continues on duloxetine  \r\n- Referral to Simms Mann placed 1/21/22\r\n\r\n# Nutrition and lifestyle modifications\r\n- Encouraged to continue to eat healthy well balanced diet. \r\n- Needs to continue to exercise and remain in shape. \r\n- Limit alcohol intake\r\n- Avoid smoking \r\n \r\n# Follow up. \r\n- If possible, plan restaging PSMA-PET/CT, first dose of Lupron with us, and follow-up with Dr. K all in one visit\r\n \r\n Based on PSA decide on ADT only for now and consider if at all radiation in 6 months \r\n \r\nToday\r\n- PSA trending up suggestive of biochemical recurrence vs mCSPC\r\n- Repeat restaging scan with PSMA-PET/CT (will reach out to Dr. C to see if candidate to get this on study)\r\n- Afterwards will start Lupron q3 month and Zytiga \r\n- Consideration radiation in future pending scans. Follow-up with Dr. K after PSA-PET/CT scan\r\n- Follow-up with Dr. C on 1/27/22\r\n \r\n# Bone health\r\n- Plan for ADT, which raises risk for bone density loss\r\n- Baseline DEXA scan - will be done locally through PCP\r\n- Start calcium and vitamin D\r\n \r\n# Urosepsis, resolved\r\nHad a severe UTI requiring IV antibiotics for 4 weeks (completed day after Thanksgiving).\r\n- Now recovered \r\n \r\n# Cardiovascular risk\r\n# HTN\r\nGiven history of smoking, active HTN, and plans to start Zytiga will refer to cardio-oncology for co management. \r\n- Referral to Dr. H placed 1/21/22 \r\n \r\n# Genetics\r\n- Went over Tempus results including germline mutation detected for which we will refer to genetics. \r\n- referred to genetics 12/8/21\r\n \r\n# Chronic back pain \r\n- We will repeat scans in the future so can evaluate again these areas and if needed add MRI as well. \r\n \r\n# Emotional support\r\n- Continues on duloxetine  \r\n- Referral to Simms Mann placed 1/21/22\r\n\r\n# Nutrition and lifestyle modifications\r\n- Encouraged to continue to eat healthy well balanced diet. \r\n- Needs to continue to exercise and remain in shape. \r\n- Limit alcohol intake\r\n- Avoid smoking \r\n \r\n# Follow up. \r\n- If possible, plan restaging PSMA-PET/CT, first dose of Lupron with us, and follow-up with Dr. K all in one visit", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient received radiation therapy", "answer": "No.", "justification": ["No radiation at this time."]}, {"question": "If so, when", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 218, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2021-10-09", "note": "IMAGING\r\nMr Prostate Wo+w Contrast\r\nResult Date: 9/10/2021\r\nIMPRESSION: 1. Focal findings suspicious for neoplasia as above with PIRADS 5/5 lesion in the right posterolateral and posteromedial peripheral midgland extending into the right seminal vesicle and a PIRADS 4/5 lesion in the midline posterior peripheral apical midgland. 2. Capsular margin: suggestion of seminal vesicle involvement. Overall PI-RADS Category: 5/5 \r\n \r\nPetct With Diagnostic Ct Of The Neck-chest-abd-pelvis W/iv Contrast; Psma (68ga-psma, Piflufolastat F18)\r\nResult Date: 10/9/2021\r\n 1. History of newly diagnosed prostate cancer with focal moderate uptake involving the right basal to mid peripheral zone with probable capsular/extracapsular extension compatible with known prostate cancer. Additional focus of moderate uptake in the left posterolateral prostate peripheral zone that is nonspecific. Bilateral proximal seminal vesicle mild to moderate uptake that may suggest seminal vesicle involvement. 2. Prominent right common iliac and right external iliac lymph nodes with moderate and intense uptake, respectively, suspicious for nodal metastatic disease. 3. Left lower lobe 4 mm subpleural partially calcified nodule that may represent a calcified granuloma. Recommend attention on follow-up. 4. Right apical area of traction bronchiectasis and architectural distortion that likely represents postinfectious fibrotic change. Recommend attention on follow-up. \r\n\r\nIMPRESSION\r\na 61 y.o. year old male with GS 4+ 3 = 7 prostate adenocarcinoma PI-RADS 5 lesion on MRI and now PSMA positive right common and external iliac nodes suspicious for metastatic disease.  PS 1", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with prostate cancer", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["newly diagnosed prostate cancer"]}, {"question": "If so, has the prostate cancer metastasized to the bones", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 217, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2022-01-22", "note": "REASON FOR VISIT/CHIEF COMPLAINT: \r\nFollow-up after prostatectomy showing pT3bN1 disease and SDHAF2 germline mutation, rising PSA\r\n \r\nONCOLOGY HISTORY\r\nW is a 61 y.o. with oncology history as follows:\r\n \r\n- 7/27/2016 PSA 4.1  \r\n- 08/25/2017 PSA 2.6 \r\n- 04/18/2019 PSA 5.0 \r\n- 01/28/2020 PSA 3.9\r\n- 07/21/2021 PSA 9.3. Wife encouraged him to come to UCLA for 2nd opinion. \r\n- 08/30/21 Consultation with Dr. D \r\n- 09/07/2021 PSA 13.1 \r\n- 09/10/2021 MRI Prostate - Focal findings suspicious for neoplasia as above with PIRADS 5/5 lesion in the right posterolateral and posteromedial peripheral midgland extending into the right seminal vesicle and a PIRADS 4/5 lesion in the midline posterior peripheral apical midgland. 2. Capsular margin: suggestion of seminal vesicle involvement. Overall PI-RADS Category: 5/5\r\n- 09/17/2021 Biopsy GS 4+3=7 \r\n- 10/8/21: PSMA PET with local and right common iliac and right external iliac nodal metastatic disease. No distant metastatic disease. \r\n- 10/19/21: Robot-assisted laparoscopic radical prostatectomy and extended bilateral pelvic lymph node dissection with Dr. C. Dominant tumor, 2.8 cm. Gleason score: 4+5=9 (Grade Group 5. 4/30 right pelvic LN positive and 1/8 left pelvic LN positive. pT3bN1\r\n- 12/6/21: PSA 1.3\r\n- 1/20/22: PSA trending up to 1.9\r\n \r\nINTERVAL HISTORY\r\n1/21/2022: \r\nNow recovering from a severe sepsis/ UTI requiring IV antibiotics for 4 weeks (completed day after Thanksgiving). Had COVID a few days after Christmas (had congestion and headache). Overall slowly improving towards his pre-operative baseline. Still has some residual soreness in stomach since his surgery. Some mild incontinence requiring pads and improving. Erectile function improving. Emotional distress during holidays that lead to smoking and alcohol. Using nicotine patch weekly. Hypertensive, poorly controlled in clinic.\r\n \r\nREVIEW OF SYSTEMS\r\nReview of Systems: A detailed 14 point review of systems was ascertained today and negative unless otherwise noted in interval history. \r\n \r\nMEDICATIONS\r\nCurrent Outpatient Medications: \r\n\u2022  CITRULLINE PO, Take 1,500 mg by mouth two (2) times daily., Disp: , Rfl: \r\n\u2022  DULoxetine 60 mg DR capsule, Take 60 mg by mouth daily., Disp: , Rfl: \r\n\u2022  lisinopril 20 mg tablet, Take 20 mg by mouth daily ., Disp: , Rfl: \r\n\u2022  multivitamin tablet, Take 1 tablet by mouth daily., Disp: , Rfl: \r\n\u2022  nicotine 21 mg/24 hr patch, Place 1 patch onto the skin daily., Disp: , Rfl: \r\n\u2022  sildenafil 100 mg tablet, Take 100 mg by mouth daily as needed for Erectile Dysfunction ., Disp: , Rfl: \r\n\u2022  simvastatin 20 mg tablet, Take 20 mg by mouth daily ., Disp: , Rfl: \r\n\u2022  tadalafil (CIALIS) 5 mg tablet, Take 1 tablet (5 mg total) by mouth daily., Disp: 90 tablet, Rfl: 3", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with prostate cancer", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Biopsy GS 4+3=7", "pT3bN1"]}, {"question": "If so, what is the tumor stage of the patient", "answer": "Stage 3B", "justification": ["pT3bN1"]}, {"question": "If so, has the patient received ADT", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 216, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2022-01-07", "note": "REASON FOR VISIT/Chief Complaint:  \r\nFollow up for metastatic prostate cancer post chemotherapy on abiraterone, lupron and LU177, worsening right leg pain\r\n \r\nInterval History Illness \r\n62 y.o. male oncology history as follows:\r\n \r\n- Patient has been followed by local Urology for over a decade for BPH.  He was doing overall well without any significant urinary symptoms while on Flomax and finasteride.  \r\n- During fall of 2020 he had a fall where he hit his back.  He was undergoing physical therapy but with persistent severe low back pain and eventually had an MRI of the pelvis for ongoing back pain that revealed multiple bone metastases.  \r\n- Around the same time he had repeat PSA checked that was rising\r\n- Prostate biopsy 1st week of January 2021 confirmed prostate cancer with a Gleason Score 9. \r\n- 2/18/21: Axumin PET/CT with mild-moderate tracer in prostate consistent with primary, tracer within sclerotic osseous structures consistent with widespread osseous metastases\r\n-  05/11/21 Axumin PET - IMPRESSION: History of prostate cancer with heterogeneous tracer activity throughout the prostate, significantly decreased in activity in comparison to prior study. Grossly stable/slightly increasing sclerosis in osseous structures as described above, with areas of decreased tracer activity suggestive of improvement. Evaluation of the skeleton partially limited due to high underlying bone marrow uptake as a result of treatment. Correlation with PSA is recommended.\r\n- 05/11 to 5/21 Radiation to prostate per patient preference. \r\n \r\nPRIOR TREATMENT\r\n1/7/21 Degarelix, casodex for a few weeks\r\n2/11/21 Lupron 22.5 mg\r\n2/25/21: Docetaxel C1D1\r\n03/18/21: Docetaxel C2D1\r\n4/8/21: Docetaxel C3D1\r\n4/29/21: Docetaxel C4D1 \r\n5/11/21, 5/18/21, 5/24/21: SBRT (2 more left 6/1/21, 6/8/21)\r\n5/12/21 Lupron 22.5 / xgeva 120mg plan for q3mo treatment\r\n5/26/21: Docetaxel C5D1 \r\n6/8/2021: Completed SBRT \r\n6/2021: Docetaxel C6\r\n7/23/2021: Started on abiraterone 4 tabs daily, prednisone 5 mg daily\r\n08/12/21 Lupron 3 month dose and Xgeva \r\n11/12/2021: LU177 treatment initiated (6 total treatments, every 6 weeks, last treatment in 06/2022)\r\n11/18/2021: Lupron 3 month dose and Xgeva \r\n12/17/2021: Lu177-PSMA dose 2\r\n \r\nPSA HISTORY\r\n  \r\n09/30/21 PSA 106.0\r\n10/27/21 PSA 100.0\r\n11/01/21 PSA 101.0\r\n11/18/21 PSA 169.0\r\n11/29/21 PSA 124.0\r\n12/16/21 PSA 172.9\r\n01/07/22 PSA 167.0", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with prostate cancer", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Prostate biopsy 1st week of January 2021 confirmed prostate cancer"]}, {"question": "If so, when", "answer": "The first week of January 2021", "justification": ["1st week of January 2021 confirmed prostate cancer"]}, {"question": "If so, list all PSA values of the patient in the order that are mentioned in the note, separated by comma", "answer": "106.0, 100.0, 101.0, 169.0, 124.0, 172.9, 167.0", "justification": ["09/30/21 PSA 106.0\r\n10/27/21 PSA 100.0\r\n11/01/21 PSA 101.0\r\n11/18/21 PSA 169.0\r\n11/29/21 PSA 124.0\r\n12/16/21 PSA 172.9\r\n01/07/22 PSA 167.0"]}, {"question": "If so, list all corresponding dates of measurement of the PSA levels listed above, separated by comma", "answer": "09/30/21, 10/27/21, 11/01/21, 11/18/21, 12/16/21, 01/07/22", "justification": ["09/30/21 PSA 106.0\r\n10/27/21 PSA 100.0\r\n11/01/21 PSA 101.0\r\n11/18/21 PSA 169.0\r\n11/29/21 PSA 124.0\r\n12/16/21 PSA 172.9\r\n01/07/22 PSA 167.0"]}]}
{"id": 215, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2022-01-12", "note": "ASSESSMENT & PLAN\r\nMr.  B a pleasant 62 y.o. male metastatic castration resistant prostate cancer on Lupron and Zytiga, now s/p 2 doses of Lu177-PSMA. PS 1 due to anxiety and pain. \r\n \r\n#Metastatic castrate resistant prostate cancer:\r\n- Rising PSA in the setting of castration with lupron consistent with de-novo castration resistant prostate cancer. \r\n- Started Lupron 2/11/21\r\n- C1D1 docetaxel 2/25/21 completed 6 cycles on  6/17/21 \r\n- TEMPUS testing, initial XF consistent with tp53 \r\n- He received radiation to prostate due to patient preference (SBRT on 5/11/21, 5/18/21, 5/24/21, 6/1/21, 6/8/21)\r\n- Started Zytiga on 7/23/21\r\n- Underwent PSMA Imaging 10/15/21 + PSMA expression in preparation for future LU177 therapy via EAP program \r\n- 08/24/21 - 09/30/21 PSA starting to rise and some worsening bone pain. \r\n- 11/12/2021 - Patient started LU177 treatment. Bone pain improved after first dose and worsening again prior to second dose. PSA rose on 11/18 but downtrending 11/29 and now increasing again\r\n \r\nToday: \r\n- Worsening low back and right leg pain, together with rising PSA is concerning for progression. He will go to ED for rapid evaluation of his symptoms (see below).\r\n- Will work with Nuc Med to expedite PSMA scan to next week if possible. Scheduled for next dose of Lu177-PSMA on 1/28 but if marked progression on imaging will need to reconsider.\r\n- PSA check today \r\n- Xgeva today, next Lupron next month (2/2022)\r\n- Continue Zytiga\r\n- Will obtain authorization for cabazitaxel for next line of therapy\r\n- He is interested in CAR trial, encouraged him to reach out to COH to get eligibility process started\r\n- Given worsening pain and functional status, and concern for progressive disease, will discuss with Palliative Care enrolling in home Pall Care, optimizing pain regimen\r\n \r\n# Low back pain, right leg pain\r\n- Possible tumor impingement on RLE nerve from progressive tumor, less likely cord compression but needs to be ruled out.\r\n- Advised patient to go to ED for STAT MRI spine evaluation, discussed with ED charge RN\r\n- Gave dexamethasone 8mg in clinic, would likely benefit from short course of steroids pending MRI results\r\n- Will discuss MRI findings with Rad Onc for consideration of RT\r\n \r\n# Bone metastases \r\n- Xgeva q 3 months started 5/12/21 to prevent skeletal events and treat osteoporosis.\r\n- Continue calcium and vitamin D\r\n- CTM \r\n \r\n# Fatigue\r\nSecondary to cancer and therapy\r\n \r\n# SOB\r\nLikely side effect of LU177. Improved. \r\n \r\n# Cancer Pain, \r\n- Bone pain worse after LU177 administration, improved then worse again\r\n- Sleeping in a recliner with improvement in back pain\r\n- Tylenol, Advil, norco prn\r\n- Scans as above \r\n \r\n# Hot flashes\r\n- Tolerable at this time.\r\n- Encouraged use of sage \r\n \r\n# Neuropathy, intermittent \r\n- Stable, on gabapentin qday\r\n \r\n# RUE weakness\r\nImproved with steroid injections.\r\n- Followed by ortho\r\n- MRI brain negative, MRI C spine negative.\r\n \r\n# Osteoporosis \r\n- DEXA noting osteoporosis of left total hip and femoral neck T-score 2/25/21 \r\n- Continue xgeva \r\n- Continue calcium and vitamin D. \r\n \r\n# OSA\r\n- Followed by pulmonary\r\n- Sleep study results Mild OSA\r\n- Not using CPAP currently as he is fearful that the machine may stop working in his sleep and that the mask without air flow would be suffocating. Has used CPAP in the past.\r\n \r\n# Tachy-brady syndrome\r\n- Follow up with cardiology for stress echo on 4/5/21 (negative for ischemia)\r\n- Referred to EP by primary cardiologist \r\n- understands importance of calcium replacement and risk of arrhythmia if not well controlled within range.\r\n \r\n# Adjustment disorder\r\n- Referral to Simm Mann clinic seen in the past, he will consider going back. \r\n \r\n# Follow up \r\n- 1 week", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with castration resistant prostate cancer", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Mr.  B a pleasant 62 y.o. male metastatic castration resistant prostate cancer"]}, {"question": "If so, when", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, list all PSA values of the patient in the order that are mentioned in the note, separated by comma", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 214, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2022-01-12", "note": "ASSESSMENT & PLAN\r\nMr.  B a pleasant 62 y.o. male metastatic castration resistant prostate cancer on Lupron and Zytiga, now s/p 2 doses of Lu177-PSMA. PS 1 due to anxiety and pain. \r\n \r\n#Metastatic castrate resistant prostate cancer:\r\n- Rising PSA in the setting of castration with lupron consistent with de-novo castration resistant prostate cancer. \r\n- Started Lupron 2/11/21\r\n- C1D1 docetaxel 2/25/21 completed 6 cycles on  6/17/21 \r\n- TEMPUS testing, initial XF consistent with tp53 \r\n- He received radiation to prostate due to patient preference (SBRT on 5/11/21, 5/18/21, 5/24/21, 6/1/21, 6/8/21)\r\n- Started Zytiga on 7/23/21\r\n- Underwent PSMA Imaging 10/15/21 + PSMA expression in preparation for future LU177 therapy via EAP program \r\n- 08/24/21 - 09/30/21 PSA starting to rise and some worsening bone pain. \r\n- 11/12/2021 - Patient started LU177 treatment. Bone pain improved after first dose and worsening again prior to second dose. PSA rose on 11/18 but downtrending 11/29 and now increasing again\r\n \r\nToday: \r\n- Worsening low back and right leg pain, together with rising PSA is concerning for progression. He will go to ED for rapid evaluation of his symptoms (see below).\r\n- Will work with Nuc Med to expedite PSMA scan to next week if possible. Scheduled for next dose of Lu177-PSMA on 1/28 but if marked progression on imaging will need to reconsider.\r\n- PSA check today \r\n- Xgeva today, next Lupron next month (2/2022)\r\n- Continue Zytiga\r\n- Will obtain authorization for cabazitaxel for next line of therapy\r\n- He is interested in CAR trial, encouraged him to reach out to COH to get eligibility process started\r\n- Given worsening pain and functional status, and concern for progressive disease, will discuss with Palliative Care enrolling in home Pall Care, optimizing pain regimen\r\n \r\n# Low back pain, right leg pain\r\n- Possible tumor impingement on RLE nerve from progressive tumor, less likely cord compression but needs to be ruled out.\r\n- Advised patient to go to ED for STAT MRI spine evaluation, discussed with ED charge RN\r\n- Gave dexamethasone 8mg in clinic, would likely benefit from short course of steroids pending MRI results\r\n- Will discuss MRI findings with Rad Onc for consideration of RT\r\n \r\n# Bone metastases \r\n- Xgeva q 3 months started 5/12/21 to prevent skeletal events and treat osteoporosis.\r\n- Continue calcium and vitamin D\r\n- CTM \r\n \r\n# Fatigue\r\nSecondary to cancer and therapy\r\n \r\n# SOB\r\nLikely side effect of LU177. Improved. \r\n \r\n# Cancer Pain, \r\n- Bone pain worse after LU177 administration, improved then worse again\r\n- Sleeping in a recliner with improvement in back pain\r\n- Tylenol, Advil, norco prn\r\n- Scans as above \r\n \r\n# Hot flashes\r\n- Tolerable at this time.\r\n- Encouraged use of sage \r\n \r\n# Neuropathy, intermittent \r\n- Stable, on gabapentin qday\r\n \r\n# RUE weakness\r\nImproved with steroid injections.\r\n- Followed by ortho\r\n- MRI brain negative, MRI C spine negative.\r\n \r\n# Osteoporosis \r\n- DEXA noting osteoporosis of left total hip and femoral neck T-score 2/25/21 \r\n- Continue xgeva \r\n- Continue calcium and vitamin D. \r\n \r\n# OSA\r\n- Followed by pulmonary\r\n- Sleep study results Mild OSA\r\n- Not using CPAP currently as he is fearful that the machine may stop working in his sleep and that the mask without air flow would be suffocating. Has used CPAP in the past.\r\n \r\n# Tachy-brady syndrome\r\n- Follow up with cardiology for stress echo on 4/5/21 (negative for ischemia)\r\n- Referred to EP by primary cardiologist \r\n- understands importance of calcium replacement and risk of arrhythmia if not well controlled within range.\r\n \r\n# Adjustment disorder\r\n- Referral to Simm Mann clinic seen in the past, he will consider going back. \r\n \r\n# Follow up \r\n- 1 week", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient undergone genetic testing for cancer", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["TEMPUS testing, initial XF consistent with tp53"]}, {"question": "If so, what was the result of the genetic test", "answer": "Present TP53 mutation", "justification": ["consistent with tp53"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the test performed", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 212, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2022-01-20", "note": "REASON FOR VISIT/CC: \r\nFollow up for metastatic urothelial cancer in CR, lynch syndrome currently in surveillance and off therapy consent for clinical trial for single subject IND to continue Durvalumab. \r\n \r\nONCOLOGY HISTORY:\r\nMr. B is a 63 y.o. gentleman who in October of 2017 experienced some abdominal right flank pain once at night for 3 nights in a row. He took pain medications for that pain that caused pain from constipation that led for him to be seen by his physician who ordered imaging given his family history of urothelial cancer. Following that, he was found to have a right kidney lesion. He underwent resection but there was a concern about the margins given the presentation of the tumor. The patient recovered from surgery; however, 2 days postop, he developed left leg swelling. He had imaging that revealed superficial DVT, and he started anti-inflammatories. He has family history of urothelial cancer both brother and father. He has had complete recovery from the surgery\r\n \r\nTREATMENT:\r\n- 12/11/17: Right Nephrectomy\r\n- 1/11/18 - 4/27/2018 Completed 6 cycles cisplatin/gemcitabine\r\n- 2/2/18: Cycle 2. Ureteroscopy by Dr. C confirmed the lesion and so underwent soft tissue near right nephrectomy bed on December 11, 2017. During surgery, was found to have drop metastasis in regional area.\r\n- 9/2018- 10/5/2018: Recurrent disease Cycle 1 Durvalumab. \r\n- 11/6/18: Robot-assisted laparoscopic excision of metastatic retroperitoneal lesion (Size: 2 cm). Pathology was benign with treatment effect.\r\n- 11/15/18: Resumed therapy cycle 4  \r\n- 11/29/18: C5 HELD, due to elevated CK but restarted and remains on treatment ever since. \r\n- 6/2020: Patient was diagnosed with MSH2-related Lynch syndrome. \r\n-10/22/2021 Last dose of Durvalumab. FDA removed approval and insurance no longer covers treatment. \r\n- Restarted 12/20/21 Durvalumab 1500mg monthly \r\n- 1/20/22 Durvalumab 1500mg monthly", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient received immunotherapy on a date relative to the clinical note date", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Recurrent disease Cycle 1 Durvalumab."]}, {"question": "If so, when did the patient started the immunotherapy treatment", "answer": "On 09/2018", "justification": ["9/2018- 10/5/2018: Recurrent disease Cycle 1 Durvalumab."]}, {"question": "If so, is the patient currently receiving the immunotherapy treatment", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["1/20/22 Durvalumab 1500mg monthly"]}]}
{"id": 211, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2022-01-20", "note": "REASON FOR VISIT/CC: \r\nFollow up for metastatic urothelial cancer in CR, lynch syndrome currently in surveillance and off therapy consent for clinical trial for single subject IND to continue Durvalumab. \r\n \r\nONCOLOGY HISTORY:\r\nMr. B is a 63 y.o. gentleman who in October of 2017 experienced some abdominal right flank pain once at night for 3 nights in a row. He took pain medications for that pain that caused pain from constipation that led for him to be seen by his physician who ordered imaging given his family history of urothelial cancer. Following that, he was found to have a right kidney lesion. He underwent resection but there was a concern about the margins given the presentation of the tumor. The patient recovered from surgery; however, 2 days postop, he developed left leg swelling. He had imaging that revealed superficial DVT, and he started anti-inflammatories. He has family history of urothelial cancer both brother and father. He has had complete recovery from the surgery\r\n \r\nTREATMENT:\r\n- 12/11/17: Right Nephrectomy\r\n- 1/11/18 - 4/27/2018 Completed 6 cycles cisplatin/gemcitabine\r\n- 2/2/18: Cycle 2. Ureteroscopy by Dr. C confirmed the lesion and so underwent soft tissue near right nephrectomy bed on December 11, 2017. During surgery, was found to have drop metastasis in regional area.\r\n- 9/2018- 10/5/2018: Recurrent disease Cycle 1 Durvalumab. \r\n- 11/6/18: Robot-assisted laparoscopic excision of metastatic retroperitoneal lesion (Size: 2 cm). Pathology was benign with treatment effect.\r\n- 11/15/18: Resumed therapy cycle 4  \r\n- 11/29/18: C5 HELD, due to elevated CK but restarted and remains on treatment ever since. \r\n- 6/2020: Patient was diagnosed with MSH2-related Lynch syndrome. \r\n-10/22/2021 Last dose of Durvalumab. FDA removed approval and insurance no longer covers treatment. \r\n- Restarted 12/20/21 Durvalumab 1500mg monthly \r\n- 1/20/22 Durvalumab 1500mg monthly", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient undergone any surgical procedure", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Right Nephrectomy"]}, {"question": "If so, when", "answer": "On 12/11/17", "justification": ["12/11/17: Right Nephrectomy"]}, {"question": "If so, did the patient have post-operative complications", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["2 days postop, he developed left leg swelling. He had imaging that revealed superficial DVT"]}]}
{"id": 210, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2022-01-25", "note": "Reason for Visit: \r\nPreparation for cycle 4 day 8 (1/25/2022)  Eribulin for Metastatic breast cancer to liver and bone (ER+/PR+ and HER2 negative breast cancer ) s/p multiple lines of therapy, cough, sob \r\n\r\nONCOLOGY HISTORY\r\n6/2014: start on anastrazole (AI), elevated baseline CA-125 in the 100s (responding to hormonal therapy)\r\n9/29/14: start exemastane ( AI) (due to intolerance of anastrazole due to body aches)\r\n12/2016: plan to begin palbociclib (CDK inhibitor) 125mg 21d on, 7 d off and fulvestrant 500mg on day 1, 15, 29 and then monthly  \r\n3/17/17: started on fulvestrant - stopped 3/26\r\n4/16/20 started on xeloda \r\n7/29/2 biopsy of R adnexal mass consistent with breast primary, ER 95% PR 30%\r\n9/2020: STOPPED XELODA\r\n10/13/2020: Clinical trial enrollment ARV-471 on protocol. 11/05/20 progression on ct \r\n12/16/2020: Started on Everolimus + Exemestane. \r\n12/22/2020: Foundation report MS-stable, no PIK3A mutation identified \r\n3/25/2021 - 05/06: Completed 2 cycles of weekly taxol 80mg/m2 3 wks on, 1 wk off \r\n6/18/2021- Patient presents at JS UOA for f/u on age related macular degeneration and possible Lucentis injection-both eyes. No new vision changes. \r\n6/16/21: signed consent for Cytomx trial, screen failed for occular comorbidities specific to Cytomx trial\r\n06/23/2021-9/1/21: Tamoxifen 20mg, progression in liver but stable lung findings\r\n11/16/21 Started cycle 1 Eribulin \r\n\r\nTreatments to date\r\nAnastrazole\r\nExemestane\r\nPalbociclib/Fulvestrant\r\nXeloda\r\nEverolimus/Exemestane\r\nTaxol\r\nTamoxifen\r\nEribulin\r\n\r\nINTERVAL HISTORY\r\nPatient is here for follow up and next dose of treatment. She reports overall feels well. No change in symptoms. Nausea well controlled. Using medication for this 2-3 times per week. Cough is better with morphine. She has no worsening pain some pain at area of back but reports stable. She denies any fever or chills. Denies any diarrhea. She has constipation but using ducosate and miralax daily with benefit.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with breast cancer", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Preparation for cycle 4 day 8 (1/25/2022)  Eribulin for Metastatic breast cancer"]}, {"question": "If so, what is the HER2 status of the tumor", "answer": "HER2 negative", "justification": ["HER2 negative"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the diagnosis established", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 209, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2022-01-25", "note": "Reason for Visit: \r\nPreparation for cycle 4 day 8 (1/25/2022)  Eribulin for Metastatic breast cancer to liver and bone (ER+/PR+ and HER2 negative breast cancer ) s/p multiple lines of therapy, cough, sob \r\n\r\nONCOLOGY HISTORY\r\n6/2014: start on anastrazole (AI), elevated baseline CA-125 in the 100s (responding to hormonal therapy)\r\n9/29/14: start exemastane ( AI) (due to intolerance of anastrazole due to body aches)\r\n12/2016: plan to begin palbociclib (CDK inhibitor) 125mg 21d on, 7 d off and fulvestrant 500mg on day 1, 15, 29 and then monthly  \r\n3/17/17: started on fulvestrant - stopped 3/26\r\n4/16/20 started on xeloda \r\n7/29/2 biopsy of R adnexal mass consistent with breast primary, ER 95% PR 30%\r\n9/2020: STOPPED XELODA\r\n10/13/2020: Clinical trial enrollment ARV-471 on protocol. 11/05/20 progression on ct \r\n12/16/2020: Started on Everolimus + Exemestane. \r\n12/22/2020: Foundation report MS-stable, no PIK3A mutation identified \r\n3/25/2021 - 05/06: Completed 2 cycles of weekly taxol 80mg/m2 3 wks on, 1 wk off \r\n6/18/2021- Patient presents at JS UOA for f/u on age related macular degeneration and possible Lucentis injection-both eyes. No new vision changes. \r\n6/16/21: signed consent for Cytomx trial, screen failed for occular comorbidities specific to Cytomx trial\r\n06/23/2021-9/1/21: Tamoxifen 20mg, progression in liver but stable lung findings\r\n11/16/21 Started cycle 1 Eribulin \r\n\r\nTreatments to date\r\nAnastrazole\r\nExemestane\r\nPalbociclib/Fulvestrant\r\nXeloda\r\nEverolimus/Exemestane\r\nTaxol\r\nTamoxifen\r\nEribulin\r\n\r\nINTERVAL HISTORY\r\nPatient is here for follow up and next dose of treatment. She reports overall feels well. No change in symptoms. Nausea well controlled. Using medication for this 2-3 times per week. Cough is better with morphine. She has no worsening pain some pain at area of back but reports stable. She denies any fever or chills. Denies any diarrhea. She has constipation but using ducosate and miralax daily with benefit.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient ever received capecitabine", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["4/16/20 started on xeloda"]}, {"question": "If so, is the patient currently on capecitabine", "answer": "No", "justification": ["STOPPED XELODA"]}]}
{"id": 208, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2022-02-07", "note": "REASON FOR VISIT:  \r\nPreparation for next cycle, Cycle 8 day 8 of Enfortumab Vedotin for metastatic urothelial cancer with colon thickening and lymph node involvement  \r\n \r\nONCOLOGY HISTORY:\r\nMr. S  is a 80 y.o. male with newly diagnosed MIBC. \r\n \r\nHas been seen by UCLA urology for PSA monitoring last 20 years. PSA 6 and went up to 12, Dec 2019 MRI showing prostatomegaly and thickening of bladder and colon. Sp first cysto T1 disease more recently TURBT 3/10/20 revealed high grade papillary urothelial carcinoma with micropapillary and pleomorphic giant cell carcinoma component of glandular differentiation seen on surface and muscle invasion. CT CAP on 3/17/2020 without evidence of metastasis to chest. CT A/P showing thickening in region of left ureterovesicular junction resulting in moderate hydronephrosis. Prostatomegaly. Unchanged mesorectal LN. Being seen by Dr. W for workup of hyperplastic polyps in colon, sigmoid and thickened rectum. EUS and biopsy revealed metastatic cancer to rectum and regional lymph nodes.\r\n \r\nHe went on to receive chemoradiation completed 04/2020 - 8/14/2020.\r\n04/30/2021 CT shows new colonic thickening and enlargement in nodes\r\n05/12/2021 Colonscopy confirmed  metastatic urothelial cancer \r\n05/19/21 Consent for Morpheus trial \r\n08/10/21 CT - PD on SG + Atezo clinical trial \r\n\r\nRecurrent disease \r\n- 05/28/21 C1D1 Sacituzumab + Atezolizumab \r\n- 06/04/21 C1D8 Sacituzumab + Atezolizumab \r\n- 06/21/21 C2D1 Sacituzumab + Atezolizumab  \r\n- 06/28/21 C2D8 Sacituzumab + Atezolizumab  \r\n- 07/12/21 C3D1 Sacituzumab + Atezolizumab  \r\n- 07/19/21 C3D8 Sacituzumab + Atezolizumab  \r\n- 08/02/21 C4D1 Sacituzumab + Atezolizumab\r\n- 08/09/21 C4D8 Sacituzumab + Atezolizumab\r\n \r\nSecond line of therapy \r\n- 08/23/21 Enfortumab cycle 1 1mg/kg \r\n- 08/30/21 Enfortumab cycle 1 day 8 \r\n- 09/13/21 Enfortumab cycle 2 day 1 full dose. \r\n- 09/20/21 Enfortumab cycle 2 day 8 \r\n- 10/04/21 Enfortumab cycle 3 day 1 \r\n- 10/11/21 Enfortumab cycle 3 day 8 \r\n- 10/25/21 Enfortumab Cycle 4 day 1 \r\n- 11/01/21 Enfortumab Cycle 4 day 8 \r\n- 11/15/21 Cycle 5 day 1 \r\n- 11/22/21 Cycle 5 day 8\r\n- 12/6/21 Cycle 6 day 1\r\n- 12/13/21 Cycle 6 day 8\r\n- 12/27/21 Cycle 7 day 1 \r\n- 01/03/22 Cycle 7 day 8 \r\n- 1/18/22 Cycle 8 day 1\r\n- 1/24/22 Cycle 8 day 8 \r\n \r\nINTERVAL HISTORY:\r\nPatient is here in follow up and for next dose of treatment. He has No pain. No falls. No major dizziness.  Mostly out of chair or bed. Neuropathy feels worse up to knees.  No constipation.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with bladder cancer", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Mr. S  is a 80 y.o. male with newly diagnosed MIBC"]}, {"question": "Has the patient received chemotherapy for bladder cancer", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["went on to receive chemoradiation completed", "Sacituzumab", "Enfortumab"]}, {"question": "If so, is the patient currently receiving chemotherapy", "answer": "yes", "justification": ["REASON FOR VISIT:   Preparation for next cycle, Cycle 8 day 8 of Enfortumab Vedotin"]}]}
{"id": 207, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2022-02-07", "note": "REASON FOR VISIT:  \r\nPreparation for next cycle, Cycle 8 day 8 of Enfortumab Vedotin for metastatic urothelial cancer with colon thickening and lymph node involvement  \r\n \r\nONCOLOGY HISTORY:\r\nMr. S  is a 80 y.o. male with newly diagnosed MIBC. \r\n \r\nHas been seen by UCLA urology for PSA monitoring last 20 years. PSA 6 and went up to 12, Dec 2019 MRI showing prostatomegaly and thickening of bladder and colon. Sp first cysto T1 disease more recently TURBT 3/10/20 revealed high grade papillary urothelial carcinoma with micropapillary and pleomorphic giant cell carcinoma component of glandular differentiation seen on surface and muscle invasion. CT CAP on 3/17/2020 without evidence of metastasis to chest. CT A/P showing thickening in region of left ureterovesicular junction resulting in moderate hydronephrosis. Prostatomegaly. Unchanged mesorectal LN. Being seen by Dr. W for workup of hyperplastic polyps in colon, sigmoid and thickened rectum. EUS and biopsy revealed metastatic cancer to rectum and regional lymph nodes.\r\n \r\nHe went on to receive chemoradiation completed 04/2020 - 8/14/2020.\r\n04/30/2021 CT shows new colonic thickening and enlargement in nodes\r\n05/12/2021 Colonscopy confirmed  metastatic urothelial cancer \r\n05/19/21 Consent for Morpheus trial \r\n08/10/21 CT - PD on SG + Atezo clinical trial \r\n\r\nRecurrent disease \r\n- 05/28/21 C1D1 Sacituzumab + Atezolizumab \r\n- 06/04/21 C1D8 Sacituzumab + Atezolizumab \r\n- 06/21/21 C2D1 Sacituzumab + Atezolizumab  \r\n- 06/28/21 C2D8 Sacituzumab + Atezolizumab  \r\n- 07/12/21 C3D1 Sacituzumab + Atezolizumab  \r\n- 07/19/21 C3D8 Sacituzumab + Atezolizumab  \r\n- 08/02/21 C4D1 Sacituzumab + Atezolizumab\r\n- 08/09/21 C4D8 Sacituzumab + Atezolizumab\r\n \r\nSecond line of therapy \r\n- 08/23/21 Enfortumab cycle 1 1mg/kg \r\n- 08/30/21 Enfortumab cycle 1 day 8 \r\n- 09/13/21 Enfortumab cycle 2 day 1 full dose. \r\n- 09/20/21 Enfortumab cycle 2 day 8 \r\n- 10/04/21 Enfortumab cycle 3 day 1 \r\n- 10/11/21 Enfortumab cycle 3 day 8 \r\n- 10/25/21 Enfortumab Cycle 4 day 1 \r\n- 11/01/21 Enfortumab Cycle 4 day 8 \r\n- 11/15/21 Cycle 5 day 1 \r\n- 11/22/21 Cycle 5 day 8\r\n- 12/6/21 Cycle 6 day 1\r\n- 12/13/21 Cycle 6 day 8\r\n- 12/27/21 Cycle 7 day 1 \r\n- 01/03/22 Cycle 7 day 8 \r\n- 1/18/22 Cycle 8 day 1\r\n- 1/24/22 Cycle 8 day 8 \r\n \r\nINTERVAL HISTORY:\r\nPatient is here in follow up and for next dose of treatment. He has No pain. No falls. No major dizziness.  Mostly out of chair or bed. Neuropathy feels worse up to knees.  No constipation.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with prostate cancer", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, has the prostate cancer metastasized to the bones", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 206, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2021-12-03", "note": "2021-12-3 2:23 PM\r\nLIVER OR GALLBLADDER US (SINGLE ORGAN) PORT\r\nReason: evaluate for hepatobiliary pathology\r\nAdmitting Diagnosis: SEPSIS\r\nMEDICAL CONDITION:\r\n63 year old woman with elevated LFTs of unknown etiology, is s/p\r\ncholecystectomy\r\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION:\r\nevaluate for hepatobiliary pathology\r\nWET READ: IPf MON 2021-12-3 5:09 PM\r\nNo intrahepatic biliary duct dilatation.\r\nNo abnormality at the gallbladder fossa.\r\nCBD measures up to 8 mm in a post-cholecystectomy patient.\r\nMain portal vein patent.\r\nFINAL REPORT\r\nHISTORY:  63-year-old woman with elevated LFTs of unknown etiology status post\r\ncholecystectomy.  Evaluate for hepatobiliary pathology.\r\nTECHNIQUE:  Liver gallbladder ultrasound.\r\nCOMPARISON:  Compared to liver gallbladder ultrasound from 2021-11-25\r\nand CT torso 2021-11-28.\r\nFINDINGS:  Suboptimal study due to difficulty in patient positioning and body\r\nhabitus.  Liver is diffusely echogenic compatible with fatty infiltration.  No\r\nfocal hepatic lesions are seen.\r\nPatient is status post remote cholecystectomy (per history).  There is no\r\nintrahepatic biliary duct dilatation.  CBD measures up to 8 mm in a post-\r\ncholecystectomy patient.  The main portal vein is patent.  Suboptimal\r\nevaluation of pancreas due to body habitus, and air in the bowel.\r\nIMPRESSION:\r\n1.  Diffusely echogenic liver compatible with fatty infiltration.  Other forms\r\nof liver disease and more advanced liver disease cannot be excluded.\r\n2.  No abnormality at the gallbladder fossa.\r\n3.  No intrahepatic biliary duct dilatation.  CBD measures up to 8 mm in a\r\npost-cholecystectomy patient.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient undergone any surgical procedure", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["63-year-old woman with elevated LFTs of unknown etiology status post\r\ncholecystectomy."]}, {"question": "If so, what was the type of the surgical procedure", "answer": "Cholecystectomy", "justification": ["63-year-old woman with elevated LFTs of unknown etiology status post\r\ncholecystectomy."]}, {"question": "If so, when was the surgical procedure performed", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 205, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2021-12-27", "note": "A 54-year-old Hispanic female with a past medical history of type 2 diabetes mellitus, unvaccinated for COVID-19 presented with shortness of breath, cough, and pleuritic chest pain for four days. Upon initial evaluation in the emergency room, vital signs were as follows: BP was 118/63 mmHg, HR was 80 bpm, temperature was 103.1\u00b0F, and oxygen saturation was 91% on room air. Lab work showed nasopharyngeal swab positive for SARS-CoV-2, leukopenia (WBC: 3.8x103/uL), elevated D-dimer (514 ng/mL), hyperglycemia (126 mg/dL), elevated liver enzymes (AST: 224 U/L, ALT: 175 U/L), elevated c-reactive protein (CRP) (129.8 mg/L), and elevated respiratory procalcitonin (0.26 ng/mL). Chest x-ray showed patchy bilateral lung opacities. CT chest with contrast showed moderate bilateral pulmonary infiltrates. The patient was admitted to the telemetry unit and started on ceftriaxone, azithromycin, and dexamethasone. EKG on admission showed normal sinus rhythm with HR of 80 bpm (Figure ). The day following admission, the patient was started on remdesivir. After two doses of remdesivir, the patient developed severe sinus bradycardia with HR of 30-40 bpm, and remdesivir was discontinued. She continued to have bradycardia with HR of 45-60 bpm persistently throughout the hospitalization. Potassium and magnesium levels stayed within normal limits for this patient throughout the hospital stay.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient undergone any surgical procedure", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, what was the type of the surgical procedure", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the surgical procedure performed", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 204, "trial": "https://example.com/", "criterion": "Shoulder biopsy at a certain point in time", "note_date": "2021-08-21", "note": "The patient was a 62-year-old male with a past medical history of liver cirrhosis secondary to hepatitis C, tobacco use, and post-stent coronary artery disease, who initially came to the hospital for elective left and right heart catheterization as a pre-transplant evaluation. Physical examination showed abdominal distension and diffuse tenderness with the presence of prominent superficial abdominal veins. A computed tomography (CT) scan of the abdomen with contrast was obtained immediately. The CT showed an occlusive thrombus of the IVC extending from the renal veins to the level of the cavoatrial junction. Thrombus was also observed in the portal vein, and multiple subcutaneous varicosities were found. Initially, a plan was made to start the patient on anticoagulation, but because of the patient\u2019s history of advanced cirrhosis, large esophageal varices on recent endoscopy, and thrombocytopenia, we concluded that the patient was not a candidate for anticoagulation. Given that the patient had significant abdominal distention with pain that did not improve even after therapeutic paracentesis; we inserted a stent in the IVC to relieve the patient\u2019s pain as a palliative procedure to improve his quality of life.\r\nRight internal jugular (IJ) and right femoral vein accesses were obtained for the procedure. A 6F pigtail diagnostic catheter was advanced from the right IJ to the right atrium, and contrast was injected into the right atrium that showed an occluded IVC at the junction of the right atrium. Another pigtail catheter was advanced through the right femoral vein and an inferior venogram was performed that showed the IVC was 100% occluded 2 cm above the renal veins.\r\nA Glidewire advantage was advanced through the right femoral vein but was unable to cross the 100% occluded IVC. Then, a 7-French Swan-Ganz catheter was tried and was successfully advanced through the IVC all the way to the right atrium. A Swan wire was inserted through the Swan-Ganz catheter. Then, a multipurpose catheter was advanced over the Swan wire into the right atrium, and the Swan-Ganz wire was successfully replaced with a Glidewire Advantage. Initially, a 9 \u00d7 80 Mustang balloon was used to perform the IVC ballooning; after IVC ballooning; however, the inferior venogram showed no flow to the IVC, which was still 100% occluded. Then, a 22 \u00d7 70 mm Wallstent was advanced via the right femoral vein to the right atrial side. The stent was deployed with a considerable waist in the mid area. After stent placement, an 18 \u00d7 60 Boston Scientific esophageal balloon was successfully used to post-dilate the stent.\r\nThe final venogram and digital subtraction imaging mode showed excellent flow in the IVC to the right atrium. Small clots floating around at the lower edge of the stent above the renal artery were successfully removed with a 7-Fr snare. Usually, if IVC occlusion is of thrombosis in etiology anticoagulation is advised after venous stent placement, since our patient had an advanced liver failure with elevated INR, anticoagulation was not started.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient received immunotherapy on a date relative to the clinical note date", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, what is the most recent date of immunotherapy administration, relative to the clinical note date", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 203, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04844749", "criterion": "Participation in another clinical study with an investigational product during the last 6 months prior to randomization into this study.", "note_date": "2020-09-16", "note": "A 66-year-old male started to present symptoms of fever, dyspnea, coughing, asthenia, lack of appetite, nausea, and vomiting. He was admitted to the acute care unit for observation and oxygen therapy, but his oxygen requirements constantly increased due to moderate ARDS. After 12 days of deep sedation, neuromuscular blocking agents, and proning with daily passive range of motion, the patient finally started to initiate active movements and was passively transferred to a chair. However, due to a persisting difficult weaning status, probably related to respiratory muscle weakness, tracheostomy was performed [ventilator settings: pressure support 10 cmH2O, positive end-expiratory pressure (PEEP) 8 cmH2O]. Subsequently, the patient showed significant improvement in his physical functions with active SOEB, chair-transfer with the help of 2 physical therapists, and active in-bed cycling against resistance for 20 minutes. The strategy was to increase pressure support (by 5 cmH2O) during efforts to reinforce exercise training effects, unloading respiratory muscles. This strategy along with a highly collaborative patient culminated in his rapid improvement in physical function (MRC-SS 58/60, physical function ICU test score 10/12, walking distance 10 m), although he was still experiencing fatigue, inspiratory muscle weakness (maximal inspiratory pressure of \u221245 cmH2O) and dysphagia upon his transfer to a step-down unit.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient participated in a clinical trial with an investigational product, on a date relative to the date of the clinical note", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the last time of administration of the investigational drug, on a date relative to the date of the clinical note", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 202, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04844749", "criterion": "Participation in another clinical study with an investigational product during the last 6 months prior to randomization into this study.", "note_date": "2021-08-31", "note": "ID/CHIEF COMPLAINT: 74 y.o. old female with h/o HTN, osteoporosis and glaucoma who p/w symptomatic hypercalcemia due to new Dx diffuse large B-cell lymphoma. \r\n \r\nHEMATOLOGIC/ONCOLOGIC HISTORY, THERAPY, RESPONSE & SIDE EFFECTS\r\n1. Diffuse large B-cell lymphoma, Dx 12/21/20. Stage IV with bone involvement. Non-GCB. + double expressor\r\n12/24/20 C1D1 R-CHOP\r\n1/14/21 C2D1 R-CHOP\r\n2/4/21 C3D1 R-CHOP          \r\n2/19/21 PET/CT: complete response \r\n2/25/21 C4D1 R-CHOP\r\n3/17/21 C5D1 R-CHOP\r\n4/8/21 C6D1 R-CHOP\r\n5/3/21: C1 HD-MTX 3.5g/m2\r\n6/1/21  C2 HD-MTX 3.5g/m2\r\n7/21/21 biopsy proven relapsed disease\r\n9/20/21 C1D1 of GenMab 3013-02 Arm 4 trial with R-DHAC + epcoritamab\r\nC1D1 (9/21) - R-DHAC with Epcoritmab SubQ 0.16mg (priming dose). \r\nC1D8 (9/28) - Epcoritmab 0.8mg SubQ (priming dose) \r\nC1D15 (10/5) - Epcoritmab 48mg SubQ (Full dose) \r\n10/12/21 C2 of GenMab 3013-02 Arm 4 trial with R-DHAC + epcoritamab\r\n11/1/21 - 11/4/21 C2 of GenMab 3013-02 Arm 4 trial with R-DHAC + epcoritamab\r\n \r\nDISEASE STATUS: Relapsed/refractory disease\r\n \r\nECOG PERFORMANCE STATUS\r\nThe patient's overall ECOG performance status is 0\r\n \r\nHISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS\r\nRegarding our shared patient, XXX is a very pleasant 74 y.o. old female with h/o HTN, osteoporosis and glaucoma who p/w symptomatic hypercalcemia due to new Dx diffuse large B-cell lymphoma. \r\n \r\nShe was quite healthy with an excellent performance status until Late Nov/early Dec 2020 when she developed lethargy, weakness, anorexia and wt loss around 10 lbs and night sweats. Palpable LAD in bilateral inguinal stations noted. Her PCP checked labs, which showed significant anemia, hypercalcemia and hyperferritinemia. Following a consult with Ventura/UCLA heme/ONC XXX, she underwent a BMBx, which showed a mildly hypocellular bone marrow with erythroid preponderance and slightly increased megakaryopoiesis.  No excess blasts, dysplasia or HLH, cytogenetics/molecular analysis all normal. Amyloid negative, small monoclonal paraprotein on SPEP, viscosity NL. Outpt CT A/P workup showed diffuse abdominal and pelvic lymphadenopathy.  She was admitted to SBCH for progressive weakness for expedited w/u, received zoledronate x1 on 12/18/20, and excisional LN Bx of groin 12/21/20 showed DLBCL, non-GCB, double expressor. Started C1D1 R-CHOP 12/24/20. Was discharged from SBCH 12/26/20. Has had significant decrease in lymphadenopathy in neck & groin. \r\n \r\nPatient was admitted on 6/1/21 - 6/5/21 for C2 of HD methotrexate.\r\nHer post thx scan showed suspicious focal splenic lesions, however on biopsy there was no DLBCL.\r\nA repeat PET/CT showed resolution of the splenic activity but new PET+ LAP. She has now biopsy proved relapsed DLBCL.\r\n \r\nPatient was admitted from 9/20/21 - 9/23/21 for GenMab-02 Trial R-DHAC + Epcoritamab. Patient admitted for cycle 2 of Genmab-02 trial with R-DHAX + Epcoritamab regimen: Arm 4, C2D2 10/13/21. Patient was admitted from 11/1/21 - 11/4/21 for C3D1 GenMab 3013-02 Arm 4 trial with R-DHAC + epcoritamab. Patient tolerated her treatment well and her admission was uncomplicated without any CRS.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient participated in a clinical trial with an investigational product, on a date relative to the date of the clinical note", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Patient was admitted from 9/20/21 - 9/23/21 for GenMab-02 Trial"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the last time of administration of the investigational drug, on a date relative to the date of the clinical note", "answer": "On 01/11/2021", "justification": ["Patient was admitted from 11/1/21 - 11/4/21 for C3D1 GenMab"]}]}
{"id": 201, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2021-08-31", "note": "ID/CHIEF COMPLAINT: 74 y.o. old female with h/o HTN, osteoporosis and glaucoma who p/w symptomatic hypercalcemia due to new Dx diffuse large B-cell lymphoma. \r\n \r\nHEMATOLOGIC/ONCOLOGIC HISTORY, THERAPY, RESPONSE & SIDE EFFECTS\r\n1.         Diffuse large B-cell lymphoma, Dx 12/21/20. Stage IV with bone involvement. Non-GCB. + double expressor\r\n12/24/20 C1D1 R-CHOP\r\n1/14/21 C2D1 R-CHOP\r\n2/4/21 C3D1 R-CHOP          \r\n2/19/21 PET/CT: complete response \r\n2/25/21 C4D1 R-CHOP\r\n3/17/21 C5D1 R-CHOP\r\n4/8/21 C6D1 R-CHOP\r\n5/3/21: C1 HD-MTX 3.5g/m2\r\n6/1/21  C2 HD-MTX 3.5g/m2\r\n7/21/21 biopsy proven relapsed disease\r\n9/20/21 C1D1 of GenMab 3013-02 Arm 4 trial with R-DHAC + epcoritamab\r\nC1D1 (9/21) - R-DHAC with Epcoritmab SubQ 0.16mg (priming dose). \r\nC1D8 (9/28) - Epcoritmab 0.8mg SubQ (priming dose) \r\nC1D15 (10/5) - Epcoritmab 48mg SubQ (Full dose) \r\n10/12/21 C2 of GenMab 3013-02 Arm 4 trial with R-DHAC + epcoritamab\r\n11/1/21 - 11/4/21 C2 of GenMab 3013-02 Arm 4 trial with R-DHAC + epcoritamab\r\n \r\nDISEASE STATUS: Relapsed/refractory disease\r\n \r\nECOG PERFORMANCE STATUS\r\nThe patient's overall ECOG performance status is 0\r\n \r\nHISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS\r\nRegarding our shared patient, XXX is a very pleasant 74 y.o. old female with h/o HTN, osteoporosis and glaucoma who p/w symptomatic hypercalcemia due to new Dx diffuse large B-cell lymphoma. \r\n \r\nShe was quite healthy with an excellent performance status until Late Nov/early Dec 2020 when she developed lethargy, weakness, anorexia and wt loss around 10 lbs and night sweats. Palpable LAD in bilateral inguinal stations noted. Her PCP checked labs, which showed significant anemia, hypercalcemia and hyperferritinemia. Following a consult with Ventura/UCLA heme/ONC XXX, she underwent a BMBx, which showed a mildly hypocellular bone marrow with erythroid preponderance and slightly increased megakaryopoiesis.  No excess blasts, dysplasia or HLH, cytogenetics/molecular analysis all normal. Amyloid negative, small monoclonal paraprotein on SPEP, viscosity NL. Outpt CT A/P workup showed diffuse abdominal and pelvic lymphadenopathy.  She was admitted to SBCH for progressive weakness for expedited w/u, received zoledronate x1 on 12/18/20, and excisional LN Bx of groin 12/21/20 showed DLBCL, non-GCB, double expressor. Started C1D1 R-CHOP 12/24/20. Was discharged from SBCH 12/26/20. Has had significant decrease in lymphadenopathy in neck & groin. \r\n \r\nPatient was admitted on 6/1/21 - 6/5/21 for C2 of HD methotrexate.\r\nHer post thx scan showed suspicious focal splenic lesions, however on biopsy there was no DLBCL.\r\nA repeat PET/CT showed resolution of the splenic activity but new PET+ LAP. She has now biopsy proved relapsed DLBCL.\r\n \r\nPatient was admitted from 9/20/21 - 9/23/21 for GenMab-02 Trial R-DHAC + Epcoritamab. Patient admitted for cycle 2 of Genmab-02 trial with R-DHAX + Epcoritamab regimen: Arm 4, C2D2 10/13/21. Patient was admitted from 11/1/21 - 11/4/21 for C3D1 GenMab 3013-02 Arm 4 trial with R-DHAC + epcoritamab. Patient tolerated her treatment well and her admission was uncomplicated without any CRS.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient ever received chemotherapy", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["R-CHOP", "MTX", "R-DHAC"]}, {"question": "If so, has the patient ever received cyclophosphamide", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["R-CHOP"]}, {"question": "If so, when did the patient stop receiving cyclophosphamide", "answer": "On 2021/04/08", "justification": ["4/8/21 C6D1 R-CHOP"]}]}
{"id": 200, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2021-09-30", "note": "XXXX is a 59 y.o. male with h/o paraganglioma s/p resection on 5/17/18, HTN and osteoporosis. He has been under the care of Dr. XXXX for MGUS surveillance since September 2019, now here for consultation regarding transformation to IgG Kappa Multiple Myeloma, confirmed on biopsy 9/30/21.\r\n \r\n9/19/19- initial consult with Dr. XXXX. Notes he constantly gets shingles infections, typically q4-6m.o, onset ~30yrs; not taking any medication, just using a topical cream when needed. Denies taking any steroids. No recent fractures or hospitalizations. Fhx includes osteoporosis in mom. Pt works full time at an orthotics and prosthetics company in Torrance. \r\n \r\n10/21/19-f/u. CT skull (10/1) with no e/o hemorrhage, mass or osseous lesions. Lab work up notable for elevated Kappa Light chain at 33.90, K/L free chains at 52.15, IgG at 2,270, monoclonal protein at 88.6 and low IgM at 41. SPEP 1.2g/dl.  Today in clinic, he is overall well. Here to discuss next steps. Denies constitutional symptoms, bone pain.  Started prolia with Dr. XXXXX and tolerated it well.\r\n \r\n3/10/2020- f/u. Pt is doing overall well today. Recently got over shingles flare up. No new issues to report. \r\n \r\n9/14/20- F/U + discuss lab results.  Lab work up notable for elevated Kappa Light chain at 1,143.67, K/L free chains at 257.58, IgG at 1,970, monoclonal protein at 1.0  and low IgM at 26 SPEP 7.9 g/dl. Denies any new symptoms. Saw Dr. Harari on 8/14 which patient suggest he was concern with the elevated norepinephrine and dopamine levels. He will be following back in Dec 2020. Pt is doing well overall. \r\n \r\n12/22/20- F/U + discuss lab results-Lab work up notable for elevated Kappa Light chain at 2067.39, K/L free chains at 504.24, IgG at 1,770, monoclonal protein at 1.0  and low IgM at 22 SPEP 7.9 g/dl. Is doing well, having some hard time during the pandemic. During the interim, patient states he had some problems when collecting labs. Additionally he reports PET/CT appt is on the 30th of this month ordered by NP Isorena. Denies any new symptoms. Has been walking every morning for 2 miles. Still on a restrictive diet, but denies any weight loss or weight gain. \r\n \r\n7/26/2021-f/u + reviewed/discussed lab results -- ESR elevated at 90 on 7/1/2021. He notes blood abnormalities occurred after he received the COVID vaccine. Pt reports some chest pain since he has been working out more. He was seen in the ER and was seen by a pulmonologist. Pt complete CT angiogram of the chest and found to have mild aortic ectasia. No PE or bony lesions noted. No change in weight/energy or appetite. No new pain otherwise.\r\n \r\n9/22/21 presented to Dr. XXXX where in-clinic US demonstrated right level 4 and level 5 multiple, probably greater than 12, abnormal-appearing lymph nodes of various sizes, One was 8 mm; one was 1 cm x 1.2 cm; one was 1.4 cm. The largest was just superior to his clavicle in the right posterior neck of level 5, which was 1.7 cm\r\n \r\n9/27/21 US and lymph node biopsy demonstrated plasmacytoma with sheets of plasma cells CD138+ CD38+ and positive for kappa light chains with Ki67 of <5%\r\n \r\n9/30/21 seen in person in Dr. XXXX clinic, feels well. Only symptomatology in the last year was the inflammation he experienced after both his COVID vaccinations, which manifested as persistent body pain/ache that worsened with exercise. Rheumatology workup was reportedly negative per patient.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with multiple myeloma", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["transformation to IgG Kappa Multiple Myeloma, confirmed on biopsy"]}, {"question": "If so, list all the M protein lab results of the patient in the order that they are presented in the text, separated by comma", "answer": "88.6, 1.0, 1.0", "justification": ["monoclonal protein at 88.6", "monoclonal protein at 1.0", "monoclonal protein at 1.0"]}, {"question": "If so, list the corresponding time of measurement of the above M protein lab results, separated by comma", "answer": "10/21/19, 9/14/20, 12/22/20", "justification": ["10/21/19-f/u. CT skull (10/1) with no e/o hemorrhage, mass or osseous lesions. Lab work up notable for elevated Kappa Light chain at 33.90, K/L free chains at 52.15, IgG at 2,270, monoclonal protein at 88.6", "9/14/20- F/U + discuss lab results.  Lab work up notable for elevated Kappa Light chain at 1,143.67, K/L free chains at 257.58, IgG at 1,970, monoclonal protein at 1.0", "12/22/20- F/U + discuss lab results-Lab work up notable for elevated Kappa Light chain at 2067.39, K/L free chains at 504.24, IgG at 1,770, monoclonal protein at 1.0"]}]}
{"id": 198, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2021-07-01", "note": "Chief Complaint:  Follow-up Metastatic Castration-Resistant Prostate Cancer, Bone Metastases\r\nHistory of Present Illness: XXXXX is a 63 y.o. Caucasian male with h/o high-risk prostate adenocarcinoma s/p radical prostatectomy (12/2014, Gleason 5+4=9, pT3N0), metastatic melanoma (in remission, s/p Keytruda x 48 cycles, last in 6/2019), referred for metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer with bone metastases. He developed a biochemical recurrence of his prostate cancer in late 2016, around the time he was diagnosed with metastatic melanoma, that included a brain metastasis in the Right occipital lobe s/p excision (7/2016, +V600E). In the context of his competing malignancy, he was started on Lupron monotherapy. He subsequently developed metastatic disease with numerous bony lesions seen on PSMA PET (10/2018 - mi T0 N0 M1b(diss)) and Xtandi was added. He had a biochemical response to Xtandi until this year when PSA has started to increase again, 2.1 (6/3/20) -> 4.2 (9/2/20) -> 5.6 (10/14/2020) -> 9.3 (11/23/2020)", "qa_list": [{"question": "List all PSA levels of the patient in the order that they are mentioned in the note, separated by comma", "answer": "2.1, 4.2, 5.6, 9.3", "justification": ["PSA has started to increase again, 2.1 (6/3/20) -> 4.2 (9/2/20) -> 5.6 (10/14/2020) -> 9.3 (11/23/2020)"]}, {"question": "If so, list the corresponding dates of measurement of the listed PSA levels. If a date is not mentioned, respond NA", "answer": "6/3/20, 9/2/20, 10/14/2020, 11/23/2020", "justification": ["PSA has started to increase again, 2.1 (6/3/20) -> 4.2 (9/2/20) -> 5.6 (10/14/2020) -> 9.3 (11/23/2020)"]}]}
{"id": 197, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-06-03", "note": "Mark XXXX is a 62-year-old white male with a history of melanoma treated successfully with immunotherapy and has currently been off medications for 1 year. He also has a history of metastatic prostate cancer for which he has been treated with denosumab and intermittent Lupron for which he is currently doing extremely well. His most recent PSA in February was 1.3, which is down slightly from previous value. Labs are drawn today. The patient, other than mild decrease in his energy level, has no urinary complaints, no bone pains. Weight is stable and has otherwise good performance status. He is given his Lupron today. He got his Xgeva in Long Beach, which he gets on a monthly basis and labs are drawn today. We did have a further discussion about his need for a Hemaport and since he gets nothing through it and it is not in use, as long as he remains NAD, I see no reason to continue it. He will discuss that with his medical oncologists. He is also on enzalutamide, which I failed to mention previously. So, metastatic prostate cancer in good control at the present time. Will return in 3 months. Three-month Lupron is given today.\r\n\r\nImpression and Recommendations:\r\n \r\n# Metastatic melanoma\r\n- Metastatic melanoma in lung, bone and liver, BRAF mutant, in a patient with a history of prostate cancer s/p prostatectomy Dec 2014. Started on dabrafenib + trametinib within S1320. Had to stop due to prostate cancer but also with evidence of a new brain lesion. Switched to Keytruda and radiation.\r\n- Progression in MRI of brain lesion s/p craniotomy, hospitalized  for seizure, resolved.\r\n-  MRI of brain stable.  Recent CT CAP with bone mets , some stable , some enlarged, and likely from prostate cancer since pt had PET/cT PSMA (scan specific for prostate cancer) showing uptake on bone mets. \r\n- Stopped pembrolizumab 6/19 after a total of 3+ years.\r\n- Plan CT chest/abd/pelvis q6 mo with MRIs of brain with every other scan.\r\n \r\n#Transient auras and afasia\r\n- Evaluate by neurologist\r\n- May be related to prior neurosurgery and SRS, and lowering seizure threshold with Xtandi/enzalutamide.\r\n \r\n# Erosive gastritis\r\n- Developed 3-4 months after last dose of pembro\r\n- Treat with prilosec and budesonide with continued improvement.\r\n \r\n#Brain metastasis\r\n- Had sterotactic radiation of brain mets.\r\n- Keppra dc'ed\r\n- Long term control.\r\n \r\n#Prostate cancer, metastatic to bone\r\n- Had prostatectomy in Dec 2014 but declined adjuvant XRT (prior notes were wrong on this point).\r\n- Had PET/cT PSMA showing uptake on bone metastasis\r\n- On Xtandi with slight increase in PSA.\r\n- On Lupron\r\n \r\n# Unclear neurologic symptoms\r\n- patient describes episodes of \"aura\", ?dizziness\r\n- recent brain MRI with NED\r\n- perhaps partial seizure activity with xtandi\r\n- Dr. XXXX was emailed on 6/15/20\r\n \r\n#Bone mets\r\n- confirmed from prostate cancer wth recent PET/CT PSMA.\r\n-  Xgeva every 4-6 weeks supportive treatment for bone mets; currently receiving at Long Beach will ask Dr. XXXX, prostate cancer physician.\r\n-  Vitamin D 1000iu  And Calcium 1000mg daily\r\n-  Normalization of PSA with Xtandi and continuing on lupron\r\n \r\n#  Vision changes\r\n- no peripheral vision  since craniotomy, slightly improved\r\n- Under care of neuro opthalmologist nearer home\r\n \r\n#  Multiple thyroid nodules \r\n- under endocrinology care\r\n- ultrasound and biopsy done, NED.\r\n \r\n# Apendicitis and spontaneous splenic rupture\r\n- Happened  incidentally when traveling in Africa.\r\n \r\n#  Psychosocial:\r\n-   He has several life stressors:  Changing jobs after 30+ years . Daugher undergoing divorce.  Sudden death from accident of his brother in law.  \r\n-  He has strong family support.\r\n \r\n#  Elevated blood pressure\r\n- monitor.\r\n- it has improved.\r\n \r\nRTC 6 months with labs and scans prior", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with melanoma", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Mark XXXX is a 62-year-old white male with a history of melanoma"]}, {"question": "If so, has the patient ever been treated with immunotherapy for melanoma", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Switched to Keytruda"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the last dose of immunotherapy for melanoma administered", "answer": "On June 2019", "justification": ["Stopped pembrolizumab 6/19"]}]}
{"id": 195, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-03-06", "note": "Mark XXXX is a 62-year-old white male with a history of melanoma treated successfully with immunotherapy and has currently been off medications for 1 year. He also has a history of metastatic prostate cancer for which he has been treated with denosumab and intermittent Lupron for which he is currently doing extremely well. His most recent PSA in February was 1.3, which is down slightly from previous value. Labs are drawn today. The patient, other than mild decrease in his energy level, has no urinary complaints, no bone pains. Weight is stable and has otherwise good performance status. He is given his Lupron today. He got his Xgeva in Long Beach, which he gets on a monthly basis and labs are drawn today. We did have a further discussion about his need for a Hemaport and since he gets nothing through it and it is not in use, as long as he remains NAD, I see no reason to continue it. He will discuss that with his medical oncologists. He is also on enzalutamide, which I failed to mention previously. So, metastatic prostate cancer in good control at the present time. Will return in 3 months. Three-month Lupron is given today.\r\n\r\nImpression and Recommendations:\r\n \r\n# Metastatic melanoma\r\n- Metastatic melanoma in lung, bone and liver, BRAF mutant, in a patient with a history of prostate cancer s/p prostatectomy Dec 2014. Started on dabrafenib + trametinib within S1320. Had to stop due to prostate cancer but also with evidence of a new brain lesion. Switched to Keytruda and radiation.\r\n- Progression in MRI of brain lesion s/p craniotomy, hospitalized  for seizure, resolved.\r\n-  MRI of brain stable.  Recent CT CAP with bone mets , some stable , some enlarged, and likely from prostate cancer since pt had PET/cT PSMA (scan specific for prostate cancer) showing uptake on bone mets. \r\n- Stopped pembrolizumab 6/19 after a total of 3+ years.\r\n- Plan CT chest/abd/pelvis q6 mo with MRIs of brain with every other scan.\r\n \r\n#Transient auras and afasia\r\n- Evaluate by neurologist\r\n- May be related to prior neurosurgery and SRS, and lowering seizure threshold with Xtandi/enzalutamide.\r\n \r\n# Erosive gastritis\r\n- Developed 3-4 months after last dose of pembro\r\n- Treat with prilosec and budesonide with continued improvement.\r\n \r\n#Brain metastasis\r\n- Had sterotactic radiation of brain mets.\r\n- Keppra dc'ed\r\n- Long term control.\r\n \r\n#Prostate cancer, metastatic to bone\r\n- Had prostatectomy in Dec 2014 but declined adjuvant XRT (prior notes were wrong on this point).\r\n- Had PET/cT PSMA showing uptake on bone metastasis\r\n- On Xtandi with slight increase in PSA.\r\n- On Lupron\r\n \r\n# Unclear neurologic symptoms\r\n- patient describes episodes of \"aura\", ?dizziness\r\n- recent brain MRI with NED\r\n- perhaps partial seizure activity with xtandi\r\n- Dr. XXXX was emailed on 6/15/20\r\n \r\n#Bone mets\r\n- confirmed from prostate cancer wth recent PET/CT PSMA.\r\n-  Xgeva every 4-6 weeks supportive treatment for bone mets; currently receiving at Long Beach will ask Dr. XXXX, prostate cancer physician.\r\n-  Vitamin D 1000iu  And Calcium 1000mg daily\r\n-  Normalization of PSA with Xtandi and continuing on lupron\r\n \r\n#  Vision changes\r\n- no peripheral vision  since craniotomy, slightly improved\r\n- Under care of neuro opthalmologist nearer home\r\n \r\n#  Multiple thyroid nodules \r\n- under endocrinology care\r\n- ultrasound and biopsy done, NED.\r\n \r\n# Apendicitis and spontaneous splenic rupture\r\n- Happened  incidentally when traveling in Africa.\r\n \r\n#  Psychosocial:\r\n-   He has several life stressors:  Changing jobs after 30+ years . Daugher undergoing divorce.  Sudden death from accident of his brother in law.  \r\n-  He has strong family support.\r\n \r\n#  Elevated blood pressure\r\n- monitor.\r\n- it has improved.\r\n \r\nRTC 6 months with labs and scans prior", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient ever received immunosuppressive medications", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 196, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-03-06", "note": "Mark XXXX is a 62-year-old white male with a history of melanoma treated successfully with immunotherapy and has currently been off medications for 1 year. He also has a history of metastatic prostate cancer for which he has been treated with denosumab and intermittent Lupron for which he is currently doing extremely well. His most recent PSA in February was 1.3, which is down slightly from previous value. Labs are drawn today. The patient, other than mild decrease in his energy level, has no urinary complaints, no bone pains. Weight is stable and has otherwise good performance status. He is given his Lupron today. He got his Xgeva in Long Beach, which he gets on a monthly basis and labs are drawn today. We did have a further discussion about his need for a Hemaport and since he gets nothing through it and it is not in use, as long as he remains NAD, I see no reason to continue it. He will discuss that with his medical oncologists. He is also on enzalutamide, which I failed to mention previously. So, metastatic prostate cancer in good control at the present time. Will return in 3 months. Three-month Lupron is given today.\r\n\r\nImpression and Recommendations:\r\n \r\n# Metastatic melanoma\r\n- Metastatic melanoma in lung, bone and liver, BRAF mutant, in a patient with a history of prostate cancer s/p prostatectomy Dec 2014. Started on dabrafenib + trametinib within S1320. Had to stop due to prostate cancer but also with evidence of a new brain lesion. Switched to Keytruda and radiation.\r\n- Progression in MRI of brain lesion s/p craniotomy, hospitalized  for seizure, resolved.\r\n-  MRI of brain stable.  Recent CT CAP with bone mets , some stable , some enlarged, and likely from prostate cancer since pt had PET/cT PSMA (scan specific for prostate cancer) showing uptake on bone mets. \r\n- Stopped pembrolizumab 6/19 after a total of 3+ years.\r\n- Plan CT chest/abd/pelvis q6 mo with MRIs of brain with every other scan.\r\n \r\n#Transient auras and afasia\r\n- Evaluate by neurologist\r\n- May be related to prior neurosurgery and SRS, and lowering seizure threshold with Xtandi/enzalutamide.\r\n \r\n# Erosive gastritis\r\n- Developed 3-4 months after last dose of pembro\r\n- Treat with prilosec and budesonide with continued improvement.\r\n \r\n#Brain metastasis\r\n- Had sterotactic radiation of brain mets.\r\n- Keppra dc'ed\r\n- Long term control.\r\n \r\n#Prostate cancer, metastatic to bone\r\n- Had prostatectomy in Dec 2014 but declined adjuvant XRT (prior notes were wrong on this point).\r\n- Had PET/cT PSMA showing uptake on bone metastasis\r\n- On Xtandi with slight increase in PSA.\r\n- On Lupron\r\n \r\n# Unclear neurologic symptoms\r\n- patient describes episodes of \"aura\", ?dizziness\r\n- recent brain MRI with NED\r\n- perhaps partial seizure activity with xtandi\r\n- Dr. XXXX was emailed on 6/15/20\r\n \r\n#Bone mets\r\n- confirmed from prostate cancer wth recent PET/CT PSMA.\r\n-  Xgeva every 4-6 weeks supportive treatment for bone mets; currently receiving at Long Beach will ask Dr. XXXX, prostate cancer physician.\r\n-  Vitamin D 1000iu  And Calcium 1000mg daily\r\n-  Normalization of PSA with Xtandi and continuing on lupron\r\n \r\n#  Vision changes\r\n- no peripheral vision  since craniotomy, slightly improved\r\n- Under care of neuro opthalmologist nearer home\r\n \r\n#  Multiple thyroid nodules \r\n- under endocrinology care\r\n- ultrasound and biopsy done, NED.\r\n \r\n# Apendicitis and spontaneous splenic rupture\r\n- Happened  incidentally when traveling in Africa.\r\n \r\n#  Psychosocial:\r\n-   He has several life stressors:  Changing jobs after 30+ years . Daugher undergoing divorce.  Sudden death from accident of his brother in law.  \r\n-  He has strong family support.\r\n \r\n#  Elevated blood pressure\r\n- monitor.\r\n- it has improved.\r\n \r\nRTC 6 months with labs and scans prior", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with prostate cancer", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["He also has a history of metastatic prostate cancer"]}, {"question": "If so, has the prostate cancer been metastasized to the bones", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Prostate cancer, metastatic to bone"]}, {"question": "If so, has the patient received chemotherapy to treat bone metastases", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 194, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04844749", "criterion": "Patients are excluded if they have known brain metastases or leptomeningeal metastases.", "note_date": "2017-09-18", "note": "CHIEF COMPLAINT: Discussion of treatment options\r\nIDENTIFYING DATA: XXXXX is a 61 y.o. male with likely oligometastatic prostate cancer (NaF-18 and C-11 acetate positive lesions in the bilateral inferior pubic rami and posterolateral left third rib). He initially was found to have high-risk prostate cancer (iPSA 9.9, GS 4+4=8, cT2a) in late 2012, s/p cryoablation to a palpable and radiographically visible focus in the right midgland. He had an intermediate PSA response, with recent rise in PSA from nadir to 3.77 in March 2015 to 8.8 currently. The C-11 acetate PET/CT did show a metabolically active focus in the left apex of the prostate; he did have a biopsy of a left base lesion in 2014 that showed fibrous tissue.\r\nMedication\r\n\u2022\tamlodipine (NORVASC) 5 mg tablet by mouth.\r\n\u2022\teszopiclone (LUNESTA) 2 mg tablet by mouth.\r\n\u2022\thydrochlorothiazide 25 mg tablet\t \r\n\u2022\tsimvastatin 20 mg tablet\t \r\n\u2022\tazithromycin 250 mg tablet\t \r\n\u2022\tlevofloxacin 500 mg tablet\t \r\n\u2022\tVIAGRA 100 MG tablet\t \r\nPlan/ Recommendation:\r\nWe reviewed the patient\u2019s detailed clinical history and imaging. His original pathology reports are not available for review, both multiple outside record notes mention a prior biopsy showing Gleason 8 disease.\r\nThe C11 acetate and 18NaF PET/CT scans are reasonably specific and sensitive, and with evidence of new lesions concordant with a rising PSA and no definitive treatment for his original primary disease (i.e., partial cryo alone in 2012), all available evidence suggests that he has oligometastatic disease. The patient would like to think more about systemic therapy options (specifically, he is interested in triple therapy with Lupron, Zytiga, and Taxotere).", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with prostate cancer", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["61 y.o. male with likely oligometastatic prostate cancer"]}, {"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with brain or leptomeningeal metastases", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 193, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04844749", "criterion": "Known hypersensitivity or allergy to colchicine.", "note_date": "2021-09-12", "note": "A 30-year-old male was admitted to our hospital with the complaints of fever, nausea, vomiting, and generalized myalgia, and weakness for 15 days. The day after hospitalization, the patient had abdominal pain. Approximately a month before, the patient was treated with a diagnosis of urinary tract infection with similar complaints. There was no family history of recurrent fevers. His physical examination showed a high temperature (39.2\u00b0C) with widespread abdominal tenderness, and rebound and defense positivity. To rule out an acute abdomen due to appendicitis, abdominal ultrasonography and computed tomography were performed; radiological findings did not suggest appendicitis. Laboratory findings were as follows: hemoglobin: 11.2 g/dL, white blood cell count: 7500/mm3, C-reactive protein (CRP): 141 mg/dL (0\u20135 mg/dL), erythrocyte sedimentation rate (ESR): 88 mm/h, fibrinogen: 508 mg/dL (200\u2013400 mg/dL), d-dimer: 0.9 \u00b5g/mL, serum amyloid A (SAA): 4205 mg/L, serum creatinine 0.89 mg/dL, serum albumin: 4.17 g/dL, serum Fe: 17 \u00b5g/dL (32\u2013193), serum iron-binding capacity: 180 mg/dL, and haptoglobulin: 498 mg/dL. Antinuclear antibody, antineutrophil cytoplasmic antibody, rheumatoid factor, and Brucella agglutination tests were negative. There were 225 erythrocytes/hpf and 3 leukocytes/hpf on urine analysis; the 24 h urinary protein was 708 mg/dL and the 24 h urinary microalbumin was 291 mg/dL. MEFV gene mutation analysis revealed homozygosity for the R202Q mutation.\r\nFMF was considered in the patient due to the presence of recurrent febrile serositis attacks and R202Q homozygous mutation in the FMF gene analyses. Colchicine was started 3\u00d70.5 mg/day by consulting rheumatology on day 8 of admission. The patient\u2019s symptoms were successfully controlled by administration of colchicine. On the 7th day of the treatment, the patient was discharged with colchicine treatment. After the colchicine treatment, there was a marked improvement in his complaints and the inflammatory markers returned to normal levels. At his follow-up visit at 6 months, the patient remained asymptomatic. The patient provided written informed consent to have the case details published.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient ever received colchicine", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Colchicine was started 3\u00d70.5 mg/day by consulting rheumatology"]}, {"question": "If so, has the patient presented any allergies or hypersensitivity reaction to colchicine", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 192, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04844749", "criterion": "Known hypersensitivity or allergy to colchicine.", "note_date": "2019-05-30", "note": "A 64-year-old man presented with a prostate-specific antigen (PSA) level of 25.78 ng/mL. After diagnosis of metastatic prostate cancer (cT4N1M1b) with Gleason score 7 (4 + 3), he was started on combined androgen blockade (CAB) with degarelix and bicalutamide in January 2018. For local control, he underwent intensity-modulated radiation therapy (IMRT) for the prostate (66 Gy/33 fractions). Although the patient initially responded well to treatment (PSA nadir of 0.039 ng/mL), he was diagnosed with CRPC when we found that his PSA levels had increased 9 months after starting CAB. Abiraterone and prednisolone were administered and resulted in a 50% reduction of PSA. However, despite the reduction of PSA, the disease progressed. He had frequent repeated episodes of severe anemia, and bone marrow aspiration showed a bone marrow metastasis. In April 2019, the patient presented with a severe headache and nausea. Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) showed multiple brain metastases with major lesions in the left middle cranial fossa. We administered mannitol, furosemide, and dexamethasone to reduce intracranial pressure and subsequently started WBRT. However, the patient wanted to stop WBRT (the total radiation dose was 9 Gy/3 fractions) and died 1 month after diagnosis of his brain metastasis.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient ever received colchicine", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, has the patient presented any allergies or hypersensitivity reaction to colchicine", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 191, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04134260", "criterion": "Androgen deprivation therapy (ADT) prior to radical prostatectomy", "note_date": "2020-06-15", "note": "A 66-year-old man was diagnosed with castration-resistant prostate cancer (CRPC) and treated with enzalutamide followed by six cycles of docetaxel chemotherapy. However, his serum prostate specific antigen level increased to 899 ng/mL, so he was diagnosed as docetaxel resistant CRPC. Figure shows bone metastases. The patient was treated for bone metastases with 37.5 Gy/15 fr to the thoracic spine (Th 7) as a local radiotherapy from February 2019 to March 2019. The radiation induced only mild dermatitis as an adverse event. Moreover, internal fixation of the left femur was performed to prevent pathological fractures due to metastasis to the left femur on August 2016. He also received six cycles of intravenous injections of radium-223 (50 kBq/kg) once every 4 weeks from September 2019 to January 2020.\r\nOn admission in April 20th 2020, the patient was started on cabazitaxel at 22.5 mg/m2 with proactive management of adverse events, including the use of a prophylactic long-acting granulocyte colony stimulating factor (G-CSF) and an oral empirical broad-spectrum antimicrobial agent (sitafloxacin hydrate, a new-generation, broad-spectrum oral fluoroquinolone that is very active against many Gram-positive, Gram-negative and anaerobic bacteria) to prevent febrile neutropenia. On day 10, grade 4 neutropenia and febrile neutropenia were observed. He was treated with an intravenous broad-spectrum antimicrobial agent (cefepime, a broad-spectrum cephalosporin with enhanced coverage against Gram-positive and Gram-negative bacteria), which resulted in cessation of the fever and increased neutrophil count, although sputum and blood cultures revealed negative. On day 18, he developed a secondary fever of 38 \u00b0C again despite neutrophil count of 3000/\u03bcL, so antimicrobial administration (cefepime) was restarted due to a suspected infection. Three days later, he complained of dyspnea and had a pulse oximetric saturation (SpO2) of 80% while breathing room air. The serum Krebs von den Lungen-6 (KL-6) and surfactant protein (SP-D) levels were 744 U/mL and 147 ng/mL (normal ranges, < 500 U/ml and < 100 ng/ml, respectively). The serum levels of procalcitonin, endotoxin concentration and (1,3)-beta-D-glucan were not elevated. Chest X-ray showed interstitial opacities indicative of inflammation in the irradiated field of the both lungs. Chest computed tomography (CT) showed interstitial lung disease with ground glass opacities in the irradiated field of both lungs. These characteristic image findings could have been associated with drug toxicity, due to the treatment of thoracic radiation therapy followed by cabazitaxel.\r\nOn 15/05/2020 the intravenous steroid pulse therapy was started at a methylprednisolone of 1000 mg a day for 3 days, followed by prednisolone at 1.0 mg/kg of body mass per day for a week. The patient improved and dyspnea disappeared. SpO2 showed 95% while breathing room air. The ground-glass opacities had also improved. The dosage of prednisolone was gradually reduced every week. The follow-up observation is still ongoing.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Did the patient ever undergo prostatectomy", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, did the patient receive ADT on a date relative to the date of the clinical note", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 190, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2022-02-15", "note": "2022-2-15 7:45 PM\r\nMR L SPINE W/O CONTRAST\r\nReason: sacral bone metastasis right sciatica\r\nMEDICAL CONDITION:\r\n59 year old woman with metastatic breast cancer with headache and vertigo.\r\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION:\r\nsacral bone metastasis right sciatica\r\nFINAL REPORT\r\nINDICATION:  59-year-old woman with metastatic breast cancer with headache and\r\nvertigo, sacral bone metastasis, right sciatica, to evaluate the lumbar spine.\r\nSTUDY DATE:  2022-2-15.\r\nThis is a redictation of the report as the original report was lost before\r\ntranscription.  However, the findings on the study were discussed with Dr. Holmes.\r\nPRIOR STUDY:  MR of the lumbar spine done on 2022-4-14.\r\nTECHNIQUE:  Multiplanar T1- and T2-weighted imaging of the lumbar spine was\r\nperformed without contrast.  Contrast was not given due to misinterpretation\r\nof the protocol, at the time of performing the study.\r\nFINDINGS:\r\nThere are several areas of altered signal intensity in the lumbar vertebral\r\nbodies, consistent with metastatic involvement.  There is also involvement of\r\nthe sacral body and the right hemi-sacrum by metastasis, with extension\r\nthrough the sacral foramina.  This is however better evaluated on the MRI of\r\nthe hip done the day before, on 2022-2-14.\r\nAxial sections were obtained from L2-S1 level.\r\nThe metastatic lesions are better seen on the axial T1-weighted images than\r\naxial T2-weighted images, which are limited by some motion.\r\nAt L4-5 level, there is a 2.1 cm area of altered signal intensity in the right\r\nside of the superior part of the L5 vertebral body, including the posterior\r\nmargin with possible extension into the spinal canal at this level.  In\r\naddition, there is a 1.3 x 0.7-cm focus in the right lateral recess, which\r\nappears to be contiguous with the above-mentioned metastatic focus in the L5\r\nvertebral body.  However, this was seen on the prior study on 2022-4-14, and\r\ninterpreted as disc protrusion.  On the present study, due to lack of IV\r\ncontrast, it is difficult to ascertain whether this represents disc material\r\nor tumor.  There is possible impingement/encasement of the traversing right L5\r\nnerve root at this level.  No pre- or para-vertebral soft tissue masses are\r\nnoted. The spinal cord ends at T12-L1 level.  The roots of the cauda equina\r\nare unremarkable.\r\nThe spinal canal at the T11 level, included on the uppermost aspect of the\r\nfield of view, appears unremarkable on the T1-weighted images and increased\r\n(Over)\r\n2022-2-15 7:45 PM\r\nMR L SPINE W/O CONTRAST  \r\nReason: sacral bone metastasis right sciatica\r\nFINAL REPORT\r\n(Cont)\r\nsignal within the spinal canal on the sagittal T2-weighted images could be\r\nartifactual.\r\nIMPRESSION:\r\n1.  Extensive metastatic involvement of the lumbar vertebral bodies, body of\r\nthe sacrum and the right hemi-sacrum with extension through the sacral\r\nforamina.\r\n2.  L4-5:  1.4-cm focus in the right lateral recess, which could represent\r\neither disc material (as reported on  prior scans) or superimposed tumor. The\r\npatient should return for contrast-enhanced study, for further\r\ncharacterization.\r\nCOMMENT: Findings were discussed with Dr. Holmes", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient undergone an MRI", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["MR L SPINE W/O CONTRAST", "MRI of the hip done"]}, {"question": "If so, did the MRI present any metastases", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["FINDINGS: There is also involvement of the sacral body and the right hemi-sacrum by metastasis", "The metastatic lesions are better seen on the axial T1-weighted images than\r\naxial T2-weighted images"]}]}
{"id": 189, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04844749", "criterion": "Serum PSA progression of two consecutive increases in PSA over a previous reference value within 6 months of first study treatment, each measurement at least 2 weeks apart.", "note_date": "2023-01-04", "note": "71-year-old male with metastatic CRPC. In March 2013, he presented with a Gleason score 4+4 adenocarcinoma (cT3aN0M0) and was treated with ADT plus external beam radiation therapy following radical prostatectomy. In June 2018, he was diagnosed with CRPC, right after PSA levels increased to 11.8 ng/ml and received docetaxel 70 mg/m2 with prednisone 10 mg daily. In October 2018, after 16 cycles of docetaxel, the patient presented with biochemical failure, indicated by an elevated PSA level of 40.2 ng/ml. In 01/2022, abiraterone was given at the standard dose of 1000 mg once daily with prednisone 5 mg twice daily. Two weeks after treatment with abiraterone was initiated, the patient was transferred to our department, with a chief complaint of convulsive seizures. His blood pressure level was 90/65 and no abnormalities were noted on brain CT. Routine laboratory and endocrinology tests revealed mild liver dysfunction (AST 57 IU/L, ALT 68 IU/L) and decreased levels of potassium 2.1 mEq/l and cortisol 3.0pg/ml. The levels of serum potassium before abiraterone therapy were 4.5mEq/l. We determined that the convulsive seizure occurred as a result of hypokalemia associated with abiraterone therapy. He received potassium supplementation and increased the dose of prednisone to 25 mg/d following discontinuation of abiraterone. Furthermore, furosemide, which was used for a prolonged period because of protracted lower extremity edema, was also interrupted. Seven days after the supplementation therapy, the levels of serum potassium and plasma cortisol were normalized (5.0 mEq/l and 7.5 pg/ml, respectively). He was discharged today and was prescribed oral prednisone (20 mg/d).", "qa_list": [{"question": "List all the PSA levels of the patient separated by comma", "answer": "11.8 ng/ml, 40.2 ng/ml", "justification": ["PSA levels increased to 11.8 ng/ml", "elevated PSA level of 40.2 ng/ml"]}, {"question": "If so, list the corresponding time of each PSA level measurement presented, separated by comma. If there is no date associated with the PSA level, return NA", "answer": "June 2018, October 2018", "justification": ["In June 2018, he was diagnosed with CRPC, right after PSA levels increased to 11.8 ng/ml", "October 2018, after 16 cycles of docetaxel, the patient presented with biochemical failure, indicated by an elevated PSA level of 40.2 ng/ml"]}]}
{"id": 188, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04844749", "criterion": "Subjects who have metastatic castration resistant prostate cancer that have maintained or have previously been treated with ADT (while on-study, patients must receive continuous ADT. Either chemical or surgical castration by bilateral orchiectomy is acceptable)", "note_date": "2022-05-18", "note": "71-year-old male with metastatic CRPC. In March 2013, he presented with a Gleason score 4+4 adenocarcinoma (cT3aN0M0) and was treated with ADT plus external beam radiation therapy following radical prostatectomy. In June 2018, he was diagnosed with CRPC, after PSA levels increased to 11.8 ng/ml and received docetaxel 70 mg/m2 with prednisone 10 mg daily. After 16 cycles of docetaxel, the patient presented with biochemical failure, indicated by an elevated PSA level of 40.2 ng/ml. In 01/2022, abiraterone was given at the standard dose of 1000 mg once daily with prednisone 5 mg twice daily. Two weeks after treatment with abiraterone was initiated, the patient was transferred to our department, with a chief complaint of convulsive seizures. His blood pressure level was 90/65 and no abnormalities were noted on brain CT. Routine laboratory and endocrinology tests revealed mild liver dysfunction (AST 57 IU/L, ALT 68 IU/L) and decreased levels of potassium 2.1 mEq/l and cortisol 3.0pg/ml. The levels of serum potassium before abiraterone therapy were 4.5mEq/l. We determined that the convulsive seizure occurred as a result of hypokalemia associated with abiraterone therapy. He received potassium supplementation and increased the dose of prednisone to 25 mg/d following discontinuation of abiraterone. Furthermore, furosemide, which was used for a prolonged period because of protracted lower extremity edema, was also interrupted. Seven days after the supplementation therapy, the levels of serum potassium and plasma cortisol were normalized (5.0 mEq/l and 7.5 pg/ml, respectively). He was discharged today and was prescribed oral prednisone (20 mg/d).", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with castration resistant prostate cancer", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["he was diagnosed with CRPC"]}, {"question": "If so, when", "answer": "In June 2018", "justification": ["In June 2018, he was diagnosed with CRPC"]}, {"question": "If so, has the patient ever received androgen deprivation therapy", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["was treated with ADT"]}, {"question": "If so, when", "answer": "In March 2013", "justification": ["In March 2013 he presented with a Gleason score 4+4 adenocarcinoma (cT3aN0M0) and was treated with ADT"]}]}
{"id": 187, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04844749", "criterion": "Subjects who have metastatic castration resistant prostate cancer that have maintained or have previously been treated with ADT (while on-study, patients must receive continuous ADT. Either chemical or surgical castration by bilateral orchiectomy is acceptable)", "note_date": "2022-03-23", "note": "2022-2-15 7:45 PM\r\nMR L SPINE W/O CONTRAST\r\nReason: sacral bone metastasis right sciatica\r\nMEDICAL CONDITION:\r\n59 year old woman with metastatic breast cancer with headache and vertigo.\r\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION:\r\nsacral bone metastasis right sciatica\r\nFINAL REPORT\r\nINDICATION:  59-year-old woman with metastatic breast cancer with headache and\r\nvertigo, sacral bone metastasis, right sciatica, to evaluate the lumbar spine.\r\nSTUDY DATE:  2022-2-15.\r\nThis is a redictation of the report as the original report was lost before\r\ntranscription.  However, the findings on the study were discussed with Dr. Holmes.\r\nPRIOR STUDY:  MR of the lumbar spine done on 2021-4-14.\r\nTECHNIQUE:  Multiplanar T1- and T2-weighted imaging of the lumbar spine was\r\nperformed without contrast.  Contrast was not given due to misinterpretation\r\nof the protocol, at the time of performing the study.\r\nFINDINGS:\r\nThere are several areas of altered signal intensity in the lumbar vertebral\r\nbodies, consistent with metastatic involvement.  There is also involvement of\r\nthe sacral body and the right hemi-sacrum by metastasis, with extension\r\nthrough the sacral foramina.  This is however better evaluated on the MRI of\r\nthe hip done the day before, on 2022-2-14.\r\nAxial sections were obtained from L2-S1 level.\r\nThe metastatic lesions are  better seen on the axial T1-weighted images than\r\naxial T2-weighted images, which are limited by some motion.\r\nAt L4-5 level, there is a 2.1 cm area of altered signal intensity in the right\r\nside of the superior part of the L5 vertebral body, including the posterior\r\nmargin with possible extension into the spinal canal at this level.  In\r\naddition, there is a 1.3 x 0.7-cm focus in the right lateral recess, which\r\nappears to be contiguous with the above-mentioned metastatic focus in the L5\r\nvertebral body.  However, this was seen on the prior study on 2022-4-14, and\r\ninterpreted as disc protrusion.  On the present study, due to lack of IV\r\ncontrast, it is difficult to ascertain whether this represents disc material\r\nor tumor.  There is possible impingement/encasement of the traversing right L5\r\nnerve root at this level.  No pre- or para-vertebral soft tissue masses are\r\nnoted. The spinal cord ends at T12-L1 level.  The roots of the cauda equina\r\nare unremarkable.\r\nThe spinal canal at the T11 level, included on the uppermost aspect of the\r\nfield of view, appears unremarkable on the T1-weighted images and increased\r\n(Over)\r\n2022-2-15 7:45 PM\r\nMR L SPINE W/O CONTRAST  \r\nReason: sacral bone metastasis right sciatica\r\nFINAL REPORT\r\n(Cont)\r\nsignal within the spinal canal on the sagittal T2-weighted images could be\r\nartifactual.\r\nIMPRESSION:\r\n1.  Extensive metastatic involvement of the lumbar vertebral bodies, body of\r\nthe sacrum and the right hemi-sacrum with extension through the sacral\r\nforamina.\r\n2.  L4-5:  1.4-cm focus in the right lateral recess, which could represent\r\neither disc material (as reported on  prior scans) or superimposed tumor. The\r\npatient should return for contrast-enhanced study, for further\r\ncharacterization.\r\nCOMMENT: Findings were discussed with Dr. Holmes", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with castration resistant prostate cancer", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, has the patient ever received androgen deprivation therapy", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 186, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04844749", "criterion": "Histological or cytologic proof of adenocarcinoma of the prostate not including the diagnosis of small cell carcinoma of the prostate of neuroendocrine pathology.", "note_date": "2020-09-23", "note": "The patient was a 65-year-old male with a history of radical prostatectomy for prostate cancer. Following a positive faecal occult blood test, a total colonoscopy was performed at a previous hospital in 2008 and a sigmoid colon lesion was identified. He was referred to our hospital for more precise examination and treatment. Colonoscopy revealed a 12 mm type 0-Is lesion in the sigmoid colon. We diagnosed the lesion as an adenoma or an intramucosal cancer and tried to remove this lesion by en bloc EMR. However, as a result the lesion was removed by piecemeal resection (2-pieces). The post-resection defect was closed using metallic endoclips.\r\nHistopathological examination revealed a well differentiated adenocarcinoma with low grade atypia, and the depth of invasion was intramucosa without lymphovascular invasion, cut end margin negative. We considered the treatment to be a curative resection. Follow up colonoscopy was performed 1 and 3 years after endoscopic resection. The EPMR scar was recognized without any residual or recurrent lesion in the follow up. Follow up colonoscopy was scheduled at 5 years after treatment, but cancelled for personal reasons.\r\nIn 2017, the third follow up colonoscopy revealed a protruding submucosal tumor (SMT), 20 mm in size at the site of the 2008 EPMR. The biopsy specimen from the colonic mucosa did not demonstrate any malignancy. Therefore, we planned a follow up colonoscopy 6 months later. The follow up colonoscopy revealed that the SMT-like lesion had grown to a large size, with a reddish surface pitted with crater-like irregularities. Histopathological diagnosis confirmed an adenocarcinoma, and a laparoscopic-assisted sigmoidectomy with D3 lymph node resection was performed in 2017. Histopathological analysis of the resected lesion revealed a moderately differentiated adenocarcinoma, and the depth of invasion was subserosa with lymph node metastasis, lymphovascular invasion, venous invasion and perineural invasion.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with prostate cancer", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["The patient was a 65-year-old male with a history of radical prostatectomy for prostate cancer"]}, {"question": "If so, has the patient been diagnosed with adenocarcinoma of the prostate", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, was the diagnosis confirmed by biopsy", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 185, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT05020912", "criterion": "Known hypersensitivity to 5-aminolevulinic acid (ALA)", "note_date": "2021-09-06", "note": "A 69-year-old male was admitted to our hospital upon incidental finding of calcification in the left temporal lobe during a computed tomography scan. Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) revealed a 2.4\u00d73.0\u00d72.5 cm mass located deeply in the left Sylvian fissure extending into the left temporal lobe. On both T2 and T1-weighted images, it was mainly iso- or hypointense, and enhanced brightly with contrast. The lesion appeared closely associated with the MCA and was surrounded by moderate edema. Preoperative diagnosis favored an intra-axial tumor, most likely a high-grade oligodendroglioma, which prompted the decision to utilize 5-ALA-induced tumor fluorescence as per standard.\r\nFour hours before the induction of anesthesia, 20 mg/kg of 5-ALA was administered orally. A left fronto-temporal craniotomy was performed, using intraoperative evoked potential monitoring. In order to ensure no interference, the entire operative field was initially assessed for fluorescence with a Leica M720 OH5 microscope equipped with FL400 Fluorescence Module. After dissecting the Sylvian fissure, a firm mass was exposed and its red fluorescence under the violet-blue excitation light was confirmed. It was not well demarcated from the surrounding brain parenchyma. The main mass was grossly removed using a cavitron ultrasonic surgical aspirator under white light illumination. Guided by red fluorescence of the remaining tumor tissue, safe excision was achieved, while small areas of neoplasm with calcified portions were preserved due to their strong adherence to the MCA and the sylvian vein. The fluorescence in tumor was of helpful to delineate tumors from vessels which adjoined under same arachnoid membrane and enabled the safe resection without vessel injury.\r\nPostoperative MRI demonstrated the aforementioned unresected MCA-adherent neoplastic areas with calcification. Pathological examination of the fluorescent tumor specimen revealed a benign meningioma (WHO grade I) of psammomatous type. The patient recovered uneventfully without neurological deficits.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient ever received 5-aminolevulinic acid", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Four hours before the induction of anesthesia, 20 mg/kg of 5-ALA was administered orally."]}, {"question": "If so, did the patient present any hypersensitivity reaction following the administration of 5-aminolevulinic acid", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 184, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-11-09", "note": "An 80-year-old woman with a past medical history of recurrent right cheek nodular melanoma and new lung metastasis previously on immunotherapy presented for worsening dysphagia and odynophagia for one month.\r\nThe patient initially developed dysphagia, odynophagia and associated malnutrition after 6 cycles of pembrolizumab. Immunotherapy was discontinued, and patient was started on prednisone slow taper with initial improvement of symptoms. However, after 2 mo, the patient developed throat swelling with hoarseness and new oxygen requirement.\r\nThe patient initially had a right cheek skin pigmented lesion diagnosed as nodular melanoma in July 2017. She subsequently underwent tumor resection, and sentinel lymph node biopsy showed 0/4 positive lymph nodes. She was then started on active surveillance. In December 2018, the patient noticed a lump near the right parotid gland, and positron emission tomography/computed tomography (PET/CT) showed 1 cm fluorodeoxyglucose (FDG) avid nodule in the subcutaneous tissue of her right lower cheek consistent with malignancy and a new 1 cm FDG avid right upper lobe lung nodule with a standardized uptake value (SUV) max of 4.5. Fine needle aspiration (FNA) of right lower cheek subcutaneous nodule revealed metastatic melanoma. The patient underwent right superficial parotidectomy, modified radical neck dissection, and excision of the right subcutaneous peri-mandibular facial mass in January 2019. In February 2019, local radiation therapy and adjuvant Ipilimumab immunotherapy were started. However, the patient developed severe diarrhea and rash after 2 doses of ipilimumab, so ipilimumab was discontinued, and she resumed active surveillance again. In March 2020, PET/CT showed an increased right upper lobe lung mass of 3.5 cm \u00d7 3 cm with SUV max of 17.3, pembrolizumab and radiation therapy to right lung were initiated. Near resolution of right lung metastatic lesion was noted after 3 doses.\r\nIn October 2020, PET scan revealed metabolic activity in the right supraglottic area. The patient was hospitalized and underwent direct laryngoscopy with biopsy which showed a developed posterior supraglottic mass with inflamed mucosa encroached over posterior supraglottic airway and generalized inflamed mucosa throughout lower pharynx. Biopsy showed friable purulent debris with focal multinucleated giant cells without any evidence of fungal, bacterial, acid fast organisms or melanoma cells, indicating a diagnosis of immunotherapy associated mucositis. Pembrolizumab was held and patient was started on prednisone 40 mg oral daily with improvement of symptoms, and she was discharged home with prednisone slow taper.\r\nPast medical history was significant for depression, diabetes mellitus type 2, hypertension.\r\nHeight: 5\u20194.9\u201d (165 cm); Weight 199.3 Lbs (90.4 kg); Body Mass Index 33.2 kg/m2. Physical examination detected copious amount of thick mucus in the oropharynx.\r\nCT neck showed near complete occlusion of the airway due to tissue thickening of epiglottis and larynx.\r\nDirect laryngopharyngoscopy with biopsies of pharyngeal, supraglottic, and glottic mucosa showed impending airway obstruction with massive swelling of posterior supraglottic larynx and diffuse inflamed granular mucosa involving majority of supraglottic larynx and lower larynx.\r\nHistologic analysis of tissue biopsies demonstrated fibrinopurulent exudate and granulation tissue with acute and chronic inflammation in left and right arytenoid tissues of the larynx and also epiglottic tissue.\r\nTissue culture with Periodic acid-Schiff (PAS), Grocott-Gomori\u2019s methenamine silver (GMS) stain, gram stain, Fite, Kinyoun, and Wright-Giemsa stains were negative for typical and atypical bacteria, acid-fast bacteria (AFB), and fungi.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient undergone PET/CT scan", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["and positron emission tomography/computed tomography (PET/CT) showed 1 cm fluorodeoxyglucose (FDG) avid nodule", "PET scan revealed metabolic activity in the right supraglottic area", "PET/CT showed an increased right upper lobe lung mass of 3.5 cm \u00d7 3 cm"]}, {"question": "If so, when", "answer": "In December 2018, March 2020 and October 2020", "justification": ["In December 2018, the patient noticed a lump near the right parotid gland, and positron emission tomography/computed tomography (PET/CT)", "In March 2020, PET/CT showed an increased right upper lobe lung mass of 3.5 cm \u00d7 3 cm", "In October 2020, PET scan revealed metabolic activity in the right supraglottic area."]}, {"question": "If so, did the PET/CT scan reveal colorectal cancer", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 182, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-11-09", "note": "An 80-year-old woman with a past medical history of recurrent right cheek nodular melanoma and new lung metastasis previously on immunotherapy presented for worsening dysphagia and odynophagia for one month.\r\nThe patient initially developed dysphagia, odynophagia and associated malnutrition after 6 cycles of pembrolizumab. Immunotherapy was discontinued, and patient was started on prednisone slow taper with initial improvement of symptoms. However, after 2 mo, the patient developed throat swelling with hoarseness and new oxygen requirement.\r\nThe patient initially had a right cheek skin pigmented lesion diagnosed as nodular melanoma in July 2017. She subsequently underwent tumor resection, and sentinel lymph node biopsy showed 0/4 positive lymph nodes. She was then started on active surveillance. In December 2018, the patient noticed a lump near the right parotid gland, and positron emission tomography/computed tomography (PET/CT) showed 1 cm fluorodeoxyglucose (FDG) avid nodule in the subcutaneous tissue of her right lower cheek consistent with malignancy and a new 1 cm FDG avid right upper lobe lung nodule with a standardized uptake value (SUV) max of 4.5. Fine needle aspiration (FNA) of right lower cheek subcutaneous nodule revealed metastatic melanoma. The patient underwent right superficial parotidectomy, modified radical neck dissection, and excision of the right subcutaneous peri-mandibular facial mass in January 2019. In February 2019, local radiation therapy and adjuvant Ipilimumab immunotherapy were started. However, the patient developed severe diarrhea and rash after 2 doses of ipilimumab, so ipilimumab was discontinued, and she resumed active surveillance again. In March 2020, PET/CT showed an increased right upper lobe lung mass of 3.5 cm \u00d7 3 cm with SUV max of 17.3, pembrolizumab and radiation therapy to right lung were initiated. Near resolution of right lung metastatic lesion was noted after 3 doses.\r\nIn October 2020, PET scan revealed metabolic activity in the right supraglottic area. The patient was hospitalized and underwent direct laryngoscopy with biopsy which showed a developed posterior supraglottic mass with inflamed mucosa encroached over posterior supraglottic airway and generalized inflamed mucosa throughout lower pharynx. Biopsy showed friable purulent debris with focal multinucleated giant cells without any evidence of fungal, bacterial, acid fast organisms or melanoma cells, indicating a diagnosis of immunotherapy associated mucositis. Pembrolizumab was held and patient was started on prednisone 40 mg oral daily with improvement of symptoms, and she was discharged home with prednisone slow taper.\r\nPast medical history was significant for depression, diabetes mellitus type 2, hypertension.\r\nHeight: 5\u20194.9\u201d (165 cm); Weight 199.3 Lbs (90.4 kg); Body Mass Index 33.2 kg/m2. Physical examination detected copious amount of thick mucus in the oropharynx.\r\nCT neck showed near complete occlusion of the airway due to tissue thickening of epiglottis and larynx.\r\nDirect laryngopharyngoscopy with biopsies of pharyngeal, supraglottic, and glottic mucosa showed impending airway obstruction with massive swelling of posterior supraglottic larynx and diffuse inflamed granular mucosa involving majority of supraglottic larynx and lower larynx.\r\nHistologic analysis of tissue biopsies demonstrated fibrinopurulent exudate and granulation tissue with acute and chronic inflammation in left and right arytenoid tissues of the larynx and also epiglottic tissue.\r\nTissue culture with Periodic acid-Schiff (PAS), Grocott-Gomori\u2019s methenamine silver (GMS) stain, gram stain, Fite, Kinyoun, and Wright-Giemsa stains were negative for typical and atypical bacteria, acid-fast bacteria (AFB), and fungi.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been received immunotherapy for metastatic melanoma", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["In February 2019, local radiation therapy and adjuvant Ipilimumab immunotherapy were started.", "Fine needle aspiration (FNA) of right lower cheek subcutaneous nodule revealed metastatic melanoma"]}, {"question": "If so, when did the patient receive immunotherapy for metastatic melanoma", "answer": "In February 2019", "justification": ["In February 2019, local radiation therapy and adjuvant Ipilimumab immunotherapy were started."]}, {"question": "If so, does the immunotherapy that the patient received belong to anti-CTLA-4 monoclonal antibodies category", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Ipilimumab immunotherapy were started"]}]}
{"id": 183, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-11-09", "note": "An 80-year-old woman with a past medical history of recurrent right cheek nodular melanoma and new lung metastasis previously on immunotherapy presented for worsening dysphagia and odynophagia for one month.\r\nThe patient initially developed dysphagia, odynophagia and associated malnutrition after 6 cycles of pembrolizumab. Immunotherapy was discontinued, and patient was started on prednisone slow taper with initial improvement of symptoms. However, after 2 mo, the patient developed throat swelling with hoarseness and new oxygen requirement.\r\nThe patient initially had a right cheek skin pigmented lesion diagnosed as nodular melanoma in July 2017. She subsequently underwent tumor resection, and sentinel lymph node biopsy showed 0/4 positive lymph nodes. She was then started on active surveillance. In December 2018, the patient noticed a lump near the right parotid gland, and positron emission tomography/computed tomography (PET/CT) showed 1 cm fluorodeoxyglucose (FDG) avid nodule in the subcutaneous tissue of her right lower cheek consistent with malignancy and a new 1 cm FDG avid right upper lobe lung nodule with a standardized uptake value (SUV) max of 4.5. Fine needle aspiration (FNA) of right lower cheek subcutaneous nodule revealed metastatic melanoma. The patient underwent right superficial parotidectomy, modified radical neck dissection, and excision of the right subcutaneous peri-mandibular facial mass in January 2019. In February 2019, local radiation therapy and adjuvant Ipilimumab immunotherapy were started. However, the patient developed severe diarrhea and rash after 2 doses of ipilimumab, so ipilimumab was discontinued, and she resumed active surveillance again. In March 2020, PET/CT showed an increased right upper lobe lung mass of 3.5 cm \u00d7 3 cm with SUV max of 17.3, pembrolizumab and radiation therapy to right lung were initiated. Near resolution of right lung metastatic lesion was noted after 3 doses.\r\nIn October 2020, PET scan revealed metabolic activity in the right supraglottic area. The patient was hospitalized and underwent direct laryngoscopy with biopsy which showed a developed posterior supraglottic mass with inflamed mucosa encroached over posterior supraglottic airway and generalized inflamed mucosa throughout lower pharynx. Biopsy showed friable purulent debris with focal multinucleated giant cells without any evidence of fungal, bacterial, acid fast organisms or melanoma cells, indicating a diagnosis of immunotherapy associated mucositis. Pembrolizumab was held and patient was started on prednisone 40 mg oral daily with improvement of symptoms, and she was discharged home with prednisone slow taper.\r\nPast medical history was significant for depression, diabetes mellitus type 2, hypertension.\r\nHeight: 5\u20194.9\u201d (165 cm); Weight 199.3 Lbs (90.4 kg); Body Mass Index 33.2 kg/m2. Physical examination detected copious amount of thick mucus in the oropharynx.\r\nCT neck showed near complete occlusion of the airway due to tissue thickening of epiglottis and larynx.\r\nDirect laryngopharyngoscopy with biopsies of pharyngeal, supraglottic, and glottic mucosa showed impending airway obstruction with massive swelling of posterior supraglottic larynx and diffuse inflamed granular mucosa involving majority of supraglottic larynx and lower larynx.\r\nHistologic analysis of tissue biopsies demonstrated fibrinopurulent exudate and granulation tissue with acute and chronic inflammation in left and right arytenoid tissues of the larynx and also epiglottic tissue.\r\nTissue culture with Periodic acid-Schiff (PAS), Grocott-Gomori\u2019s methenamine silver (GMS) stain, gram stain, Fite, Kinyoun, and Wright-Giemsa stains were negative for typical and atypical bacteria, acid-fast bacteria (AFB), and fungi.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Did the patient receive PD-1 inhibition therapy", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["pembrolizumab and radiation therapy to right lung were initiated"]}, {"question": "If so, what is the most recent date that PD-1 inhibition therapy was administered on a date relative to the clinical note date", "answer": "In October 2020.", "justification": ["In October 2020, PET scan revealed metabolic activity in the right supraglottic area.", "Pembrolizumab was held"]}]}
{"id": 181, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2022-04-17", "note": "A 66-years-old Vietnamese female patient acutely presented today with severe pain and no light perception in the right eye. The symptoms began 2 months ago, with progressive loss of vision, haloes, and ipsilateral headache. Her medical and family history was noncontributory.\r\nExamination of the right eye revealed vision of no perception of light, diffuse conjunctival injection, corneal edema, shallow anterior chamber, fixed dilated right pupil, no RAPD, elevated intraocular pressure of 30 mm Hg, age-related nuclear cataract, and 360\u00b0 retinal detachment (kissing configuration). Left eye examination was normal. B-scan ultrasonography revealed a right superior intraocular mass arising from the choroid and ciliary body and with a poorly defined scleral margin.\r\nThe clinical diagnosis was right angle-closure crisis secondary to uveal tumor and complete retinal detachment. As the right eye was blind and painful, an enucleation was performed. There was an intraocular, 1.2 cm, black mass arising from the choroid on macroscopic examination. Histopathologic examination revealed a type A spindle cell melanoma with an occluded iridocorneal angle, total serous retinal detachment. There was no tumor necrosis, epithelioid cells, scleral, or optic nerve infiltration.", "qa_list": [{"question": "What is the patient's diagnosis", "answer": "Right angle-closure crisis secondary to uveal tumor and complete retinal detachment", "justification": ["The clinical diagnosis was right angle-closure crisis secondary to uveal tumor and complete retinal detachment."]}, {"question": "If so, when was the diagnosis established", "answer": "On 2022/04/17", "justification": ["A 66-years-old Vietnamese female patient acutely presented today", "Note date: 2022-04-17"]}]}
{"id": 180, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2021-10-04", "note": "2021-10-4 10:13 AM\r\nCHEST (PORTABLE AP)\r\nReason: aspiration\r\nAdmitting Diagnosis: ETOH WITHDRAWAL SEIZURES\r\nMEDICAL CONDITION:\r\n61 year old man with seizures, copious secretions\r\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION:\r\naspiration\r\nFINAL REPORT\r\nREASON FOR EXAMINATION:  Seizures, copious secretions.\r\nPortable AP radiograph of the chest was reviewed in comparison to 2021-10-3.\r\nThe NG tube tip passes below the diaphragm terminating in the stomach.  The\r\nheart size is top normal.  Mediastinum is normal.  Lungs are essentially\r\nclear, except for right lower lobe opacity, new and might potentially reflect\r\natelectasis (most likely), aspiration or developing infection would be another\r\npossibility.  Attention on the subsequent radiograph is recommended to this\r\narea.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient history of seizures", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Admitting Diagnosis: ETOH WITHDRAWAL SEIZURES"]}, {"question": "If so, when did the seizures present", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, has the patient been diagnosed with epilepsy on a date relative to the clinical note date", "answer": "No", "justification": ["ETOH WITHDRAWAL SEIZURES"]}]}
{"id": 179, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-11-23", "note": "2020-11-23 7:57 PM\r\nMR HEAD W/O CONTRAST\r\nReason: structural abnormality to explain seizures.\r\nAdmitting Diagnosis: STATUS EPILEPTICUS\r\nMEDICAL CONDITION:\r\n41 year old man with newly-diagnosed IDDM who presented from OSH with new onset\r\nseizures.  Please do seizure protocol. Please have study be non-contrast given\r\nsCr=2.8\r\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION:\r\nstructural abnormality to explain seizures.\r\nCONTRAINDICATIONS for IV CONTRAST:\r\nrenal function serum Cr 2.8\r\nYes to Choyke questions.\r\nFINAL REPORT\r\nINDICATION:  A 41-year-old man with newly diagnosed IDDM presents with new\r\nonset seizures.\r\nCOMPARISON:  None.\r\nTECHNIQUE:  Multiplanar, multisequence MRI of the brain was obtained without\r\ncontrast per department protocol.  The study was requested without contrast in\r\nview of the high serum creatinine values.\r\nFINDINGS:  There is no acute intracranial hemorrhage or infarction, edema,\r\nmass or mass effect seen.  No diffusion abnormalities are seen.  No foci of\r\nabnormal susceptibility are seen.  Ventricles and sulci appear age\r\nappropriate.  Structural abnormalities identified.  Major intracranial flow\r\nvoids are preserved.  There are few scattered T2/FLAIR hyperintensities seen\r\nin bilateral periventricular, subcortical and deep white matter which are\r\nnon-specific, may be related to the seizures, or result from prior infectious/\r\ninflammatory process.\r\nThere is mucosal thickening involving bilateral maxillary sinuses, ethmoidal\r\nair cells and sphenoid sinuses. There is mild diffuse opacification of right\r\nmastoid air cells.\r\nIMPRESSION:\r\n1.  No acute intracranial abnormality.  No abnormality identified on the MRI\r\nto explain the patient's seizures.\r\n2.  Bilateral maxillary, ethmoid and sphenoid sinus disease.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient undergone a brain MRI", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Multiplanar, multisequence MRI of the brain was obtained"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the MRI obtained", "answer": "On 2020-11-23", "justification": ["2020-11-23 7:57 PM\r\nMR HEAD W/O CONTRAST"]}, {"question": "If so, was an MRI contrast agent used", "answer": "No", "justification": ["MRI of the brain was obtained without contrast per department protocol"]}]}
{"id": 177, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04641351", "criterion": "Injection with corticosteroid into affected knee in past 12 weeks", "note_date": "2021-10-21", "note": "2021-10-21 7:17 PM\r\nKNEE (2 VIEWS) RIGHT                                          \r\nReason: evaluate for fracture\r\nAdmitting Diagnosis: ENDOCARDITIS\r\nMEDICAL CONDITION:\r\n69 year old man with pain in right knee, mild swelling\r\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION:\r\nevaluate for fracture\r\nWET READ: JXKc WED 2021-10-21 9:32 PM\r\nTricompartmental osteoarthritis with severe osteoarthritis involving the\r\nlateral compartment of the knee, with near complete loss of articular\r\ncartilage.  No discrete fx identified.  No dislocation.  Joint effusion\r\npresent.\r\nFINAL REPORT\r\nHISTORY:  Right knee mild swelling, evaluate fracture.\r\nRIGHT KNEE TWO VIEWS. No oblique views available, decreasing sensitivity for\r\nfracture detection.\r\nA preliminary report was issued by the Radiology resident Dr. Bond as follows\r\n\"tricompartmental osteoarthritis with severe osteoarthritis involving the\r\nlateral compartment of the knee, with near-complete loss of articular\r\ncartilage.  No discrete fracture detected.  No dislocation.  Joint effusion\r\npresent\".\r\nFinal staff as follows:  There is diffuse osteopenia. There is\r\ntricompartmental osteoarthritis, most pronounced in the lateral compartment,\r\nwhere there is moderately severe joint space narrowing.  There does appear to\r\nbe faint chondrocalcinosis along the lateral aspect of the lateral\r\ncompartment.  Small-to-moderate joint effusion is present.  Scattered vascular\r\ncalcification is present.  Increased soft tissue density anterior to the\r\ninferior patella is noted.\r\nIMPRESSION:\r\n1.  No acute fracture detected.\r\n2.  Joint effusion.\r\n3.  Osteoarthritis.\r\n4.  Chondrocalcinosis -- differential diagnosis include CPPD.\r\n5.  Prepatellar soft tissue edema.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with osteoarthritis of the knee", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Tricompartmental osteoarthritis with severe osteoarthritis involving the\r\nlateral compartment of the knee"]}, {"question": "If so, which one is the affected knee", "answer": "The right knee.", "justification": ["KNEE (2 VIEWS) RIGHT"]}, {"question": "If so, has the patient received corticosteroid injection in the affected knee", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 176, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04641351", "criterion": "Injection with corticosteroid into affected knee in past 12 weeks", "note_date": "2022-06-15", "note": "A 70-year-old female patient, suffering from right gonarthrosis, was examined at our Dermatology Unit for intense pruritus on inferior limbs, intense erythema and desquamation on the right knee, and secondary identical lesions on the left inferior limb. Dermatological examination revealed a large desquamating erythematous lesion, well delineated, associated with slight edema and scratch signs on the right knee. Scattered erythematous papules coved by scales and diffuse erythema were noticed on the left knee and left lower leg (Fig. ). She described DSTG 1% gel application only on the right knee for 5 consecutive days. First complaints were noticed on the right knee, followed by occurrence of the same lesions on the left knee and left lower limb. The presumed mechanism of occurrence of the skin lesions on the other leg is transfer of DSTG 1% gel from right knee to other knee and id reaction. The application of DSTG was discontinued. The patient was treated with topical corticosteroid ointment (betamethasone) twice daily for 7 days resulting in complete regression of lesions. Clinical diagnosis of ACD to diclofenac sodium was confirmed by positive patch. A patch test was performed 5 weeks later and was positive only to the patient\u2019s own DSTG 1% gel (++/+++) and 1% diclofenac sodium in petrolatum (++/+++). Readings were done at Day 2 and Day 3. The patient\u2019s Naranjo ADR probability score was calculated (score was 6; ADR is probable).", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with osteoarthritis of the knee", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so which knee was affected from osteoarthritis", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, has the patient received corticosteroid injection in the affected knee", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 175, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2022-09-11", "note": "In September 2019, a 75-year-old, never-smoking female came to the hospital with cough and chest pain. Clinical examination revealed that she was in good overall condition. She also suffered from arterial hypertension and rheumatoid arthritis. A chest X-ray showed right upper lobe infiltration. CT of the chest showed a tumorous lesion in the right upper lobe, 6.5 cm in diameter with multiple bilateral pulmonary nodules, but without lymph node enlargement. A CT scan of the abdomen was without any pathological finding.\r\nBronchoscopy produced no pathological endoscopic finding, and pathohistological examination of TBB from the right upper lobe confirmed lung adenocarcinoma at stage T4N0M1a. EGFR testing confirmed the existence of L858R mutation in exon 21 and T790M mutation in exon 20. Following confirmation of the EGFR mutation status, the patient received first-line treatment with gefitinib at 250 mg. Total treatment with gefitinib was carried out for a period of 16 months, and during that time, RECIST v.1.1-assessed stable disease was achieved. The patient maintained an ECOG performance status of 1 with no significant adverse events.\r\nIn April 2021, the patient started complaining of chest pain with shortness of breath. A CT scan showed progression in terms of right pleural effusion, which was confirmed to be malignant by cytological examination. A cytological examination of the pleural effusion revealed malignant cells (lung adenocarcinoma), and EGFR testing from the cytological sample was negative for any driver mutation. Bronchoscopy with TBB from the right upper lobe was repeated, and histology once more confirmed lung adenocarcinoma. EGFR testing confirmed the L858R mutation in exon 21. At that point, the tumor board recommended liquid biopsy (the cytology test from effusion was completely negative and the tissue EGFR positive for preexisting mutation). The liquid biopsy confirmed the L858R mutation in exon 21 and the T790M mutation in exon 20.\r\nThe patient was administered second-line therapy with osimertinib at a dose of 80 mg/day. During the treatment, the patient showed no major adverse events, and the ECOG performance status was 1. A CT scan after 4 months of therapy revealed a primary tumor in the right upper lobe, 4.7 cm in diameter with multiple bilateral pulmonary nodules, and right pleural effusion without lymph node enlargement. According to the RECIST v.1.1 criteria, this was a partial radiological response.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient ever been diagnosed with breast cancer", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the breast cancer diagnosis established", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 172, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2021-12-11", "note": "2021-12-11 7:46 AM\r\nRENAL U.S.\r\nReason: F/U HYDRONEPHROSIS\r\nAdmitting Diagnosis: SEIZURE\r\nMEDICAL CONDITION:\r\n21 year old woman with lupus nephritis and hydronephrosis on previous scan.\r\nPlease evaluate for interval change in hydronephrosis.\r\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION:\r\nhydronephrosis\r\nPROVISIONAL FINDINGS IMPRESSION (PFI): GWp \r\n2021-12-11 10:47 AM\r\nPFI:\r\n1.  Persistent, but decreased right hydronephrosis.\r\n2.  No significant hydronephrosis on the left.\r\n3.  Persistent echogenic cortex consistent with history of lupus nephritis.\r\n4.  Persistent midline fluid collection.\r\nFINAL REPORT\r\nINDICATION:  Lupus nephritis and hydronephrosis on previous scan.  Please\r\nevaluate for interval change in hydronephrosis.\r\nCOMPARISON:  2021-12-9.\r\nRENAL ULTRASOUND:  scale and color Doppler son images demonstrate\r\nthe kidneys to have persistent increased echogenicity of the cortex consistent\r\nwith a history of lupus nephritis.  The right kidney measures 13.6 cm pole to\r\npole and the left 14.1.  There is persistent, but decreased mild-to-moderate\r\nhydronephrosis on the right.  There is no significant hydronephrosis on the\r\nleft.  There are persistent bilateral pleural effusions.  Limited views of the\r\nliver and gallbladder are unremarkable.  Blood flow to the kidneys is again\r\ndemonstrated.  Again seen is a midline fluid collection (for detailed\r\ndescription see the report from 2021-12-9.  There is no\r\nnephrolithiasis or renal mass.  The spleen is normal in terms of echotexture\r\nand measures 8.6 cm pole to pole.  There is a small amount of perisplenic\r\nfluid.\r\nIMPRESSION:\r\n1.  Decreased right hydronephrosis, now mild-to-moderate and no hydronephrosis\r\non the left.\r\n2. Persistent bilateral echogenic kidneys consistent with provided history of\r\nlupus nephritis.\r\n3.  Persistent bilateral pleural effusions.\r\n4.  Large abdominal fluid collection with low-level echoes consistent with\r\nhemorrhage.\r\n(Over)\r\n2021-12-11 7:46 AM\r\nRENAL U.S.\r\nReason: F/U HYDRONEPHROSIS\r\nAdmitting Diagnosis: SEIZURE\r\nFINAL REPORT", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with lung cancer", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, has the patient undergone testing for EGFR mutations", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the testing for EGFR mutations performed", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 174, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2022-09-11", "note": "In September 2019, a 75-year-old, never-smoking female came to the hospital with cough and chest pain. Clinical examination revealed that she was in good overall condition. She also suffered from arterial hypertension and rheumatoid arthritis. A chest X-ray showed right upper lobe infiltration. CT of the chest showed a tumorous lesion in the right upper lobe, 6.5 cm in diameter with multiple bilateral pulmonary nodules, but without lymph node enlargement. A CT scan of the abdomen was without any pathological finding.\r\nBronchoscopy produced no pathological endoscopic finding, and pathohistological examination of TBB from the right upper lobe confirmed lung adenocarcinoma at stage T4N0M1a. EGFR testing confirmed the existence of L858R mutation in exon 21 and T790M mutation in exon 20. Following confirmation of the EGFR mutation status, the patient received first-line treatment with gefitinib at 250 mg. Total treatment with gefitinib was carried out for a period of 16 months, and during that time, RECIST v.1.1-assessed stable disease was achieved. The patient maintained an ECOG performance status of 1 with no significant adverse events.\r\nIn April 2021, the patient started complaining of chest pain with shortness of breath. A CT scan showed progression in terms of right pleural effusion, which was confirmed to be malignant by cytological examination. A cytological examination of the pleural effusion revealed malignant cells (lung adenocarcinoma), and EGFR testing from the cytological sample was negative for any driver mutation. Bronchoscopy with TBB from the right upper lobe was repeated, and histology once more confirmed lung adenocarcinoma. EGFR testing confirmed the L858R mutation in exon 21. At that point, the tumor board recommended liquid biopsy (the cytology test from effusion was completely negative and the tissue EGFR positive for preexisting mutation). The liquid biopsy confirmed the L858R mutation in exon 21 and the T790M mutation in exon 20.\r\nThe patient was administered second-line therapy with osimertinib at a dose of 80 mg/day. During the treatment, the patient showed no major adverse events, and the ECOG performance status was 1. A CT scan after 4 months of therapy revealed a primary tumor in the right upper lobe, 4.7 cm in diameter with multiple bilateral pulmonary nodules, and right pleural effusion without lymph node enlargement. According to the RECIST v.1.1 criteria, this was a partial radiological response.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient ever been treated with a TKI", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["the patient received first-line treatment with gefitinib at 250 mg", "The patient was administered second-line therapy with osimertinib"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the treatment with TKI started", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "Did the patient experience any severe drug reactions from the TKI received", "answer": "No", "justification": ["Total treatment with gefitinib was carried out for a period of 16 months, and during that time, RECIST v.1.1-assessed stable disease was achieved. The patient maintained an ECOG performance status of 1 with no significant adverse events.", "The patient was administered second-line therapy with osimertinib at a dose of 80 mg/day. During the treatment, the patient showed no major adverse events"]}]}
{"id": 173, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2022-09-11", "note": "In September 2019, a 75-year-old, never-smoking female came to the hospital with cough and chest pain. Clinical examination revealed that she was in good overall condition. She also suffered from arterial hypertension and rheumatoid arthritis. A chest X-ray showed right upper lobe infiltration. CT of the chest showed a tumorous lesion in the right upper lobe, 6.5 cm in diameter with multiple bilateral pulmonary nodules, but without lymph node enlargement. A CT scan of the abdomen was without any pathological finding.\r\nBronchoscopy produced no pathological endoscopic finding, and pathohistological examination of TBB from the right upper lobe confirmed lung adenocarcinoma at stage T4N0M1a. EGFR testing confirmed the existence of L858R mutation in exon 21 and T790M mutation in exon 20. Following confirmation of the EGFR mutation status, the patient received first-line treatment with gefitinib at 250 mg. Total treatment with gefitinib was carried out for a period of 16 months, and during that time, RECIST v.1.1-assessed stable disease was achieved. The patient maintained an ECOG performance status of 1 with no significant adverse events.\r\nIn April 2021, the patient started complaining of chest pain with shortness of breath. A CT scan showed progression in terms of right pleural effusion, which was confirmed to be malignant by cytological examination. A cytological examination of the pleural effusion revealed malignant cells (lung adenocarcinoma), and EGFR testing from the cytological sample was negative for any driver mutation. Bronchoscopy with TBB from the right upper lobe was repeated, and histology once more confirmed lung adenocarcinoma. EGFR testing confirmed the L858R mutation in exon 21. At that point, the tumor board recommended liquid biopsy (the cytology test from effusion was completely negative and the tissue EGFR positive for preexisting mutation). The liquid biopsy confirmed the L858R mutation in exon 21 and the T790M mutation in exon 20.\r\nThe patient was administered second-line therapy with osimertinib at a dose of 80 mg/day. During the treatment, the patient showed no major adverse events, and the ECOG performance status was 1. A CT scan after 4 months of therapy revealed a primary tumor in the right upper lobe, 4.7 cm in diameter with multiple bilateral pulmonary nodules, and right pleural effusion without lymph node enlargement. According to the RECIST v.1.1 criteria, this was a partial radiological response.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with lung cancer", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["pathohistological examination of TBB from the right upper lobe confirmed lung adenocarcinoma at stage T4N0M1a"]}, {"question": "If so, has the patient undergone testing for EGFR mutations", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["EGFR testing confirmed the existence of L858R mutation in exon 21 and T790M mutation in exon 20"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the testing for EGFR mutations performed", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 154, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04844749", "criterion": "Other than metastatic prostate cancer, no evidence (within 5 years) of prior malignancies (except successfully treated basal cell or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin or other cancers treated with curative intent >3 years prior).", "note_date": "2022-11-05", "note": "305265793\r\nFIH\r\n2833679\r\n58208/9t7e\r\n971039\r\n8/5/2022 12:00:00 AM\r\nOVARIAN CANCER , III-C PAPILLARY SEROUS .\r\nUnsigned\r\nDIS\r\nReport Status :\r\nUnsigned\r\nADMISSION DATE :\r\n5-8-22\r\nDISCHARGE DATE :\r\n5-11-22\r\nPRINCIPAL DIAGNOSIS :\r\novarian cancer , III-c papillary serous .\r\nASSOCIATED DIAGNOSIS :\r\nhistory of deep venous thrombosis .\r\nSPECIAL PROCEDURES AND OPERATIONS :\r\nchemotherapy with cisplatin and VP-16 , line one , cycle five .\r\nHISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS :\r\nThe patient is a 71 year old female with III-c papillary serous carcinoma .\r\nThe patient had a mass noted on a barium enema .\r\nAn ultrasound revealed ascites and the question of a pelvic mass .\r\nThe patient was explored by General Surgery .\r\nShe was found to have III-c ovarian cancer .\r\nAt that time , she had an omentectomy and an ileostomy .\r\nThe patient was then admitted for cycle one of chemotherapy , followed by debulking procedure on 5-8-22 .\r\nThe procedure involved total abdominal hysterectomy , bilateral salpingo-oophorectomy , omentectomy , splenectomy , rectosigmoid colectomy , and take-down of ileostomy .\r\nStudies revealed that her chemotherapy was sensitive to cisplatin and VP-16 .\r\nPAST MEDICAL HISTORY :\r\nnotable for a deep venous thrombosis and embolectomy in January of 1992 .\r\nMEDICATIONS ON ADMISSION :\r\nCoumadin , Ativan , Lomotil and Metamucil .\r\nALLERGIES :\r\nThe patient is allergic to Reglan , iodine dye and shellfish .\r\nPHYSICAL EXAMINATION :\r\nOn physical examination on admission , her vital signs were stable , she was afebrile .\r\nThe head , eyes , ears , nose , throat examination was unremarkable .\r\nHer breast examination was benign .\r\nHer lungs were clear to auscultation and percussion .\r\nCardiovascular exam : benign.\r\nThe abdomen was soft , nontender , nondistended , with no hepatosplenomegaly , well healed vertical incision at midline .\r\nThe pelvic examination was unremarkable .\r\nHer rectal examination was guaiac negative .\r\nHer rectovaginal examination revealed smooth walls .\r\nExtremities : right lower extremity medial well healed incision , no cords or edema .\r\nThe neurological examination was grossly nonfocal .\r\nLABORATORY DATA :\r\nsignificant for a white blood count of 6.4 and an absolute neutrophil count of 4.2 .\r\nThe patient 's hematocrit and platelet count were 33 and 480,000 respectively .\r\nHer BUN and creatinine were 29 and 1.5 .\r\nThe magnesium and calcium were 1.4 and 10 respectively .\r\nHOSPITAL COURSE :\r\nThe patient was admitted for line one , cycle five of cisplatin and VP-16 .\r\nHer creatinine was noted to be slightly elevated , however the decision was made not to alter her dose of cisplatin as it had been decreased during her February chemotherapy .\r\nThe patient the chemotherapy well .\r\nOn hospital day three , her BUN and creatinine were 21 and 1.2 respectively .\r\nOn hospital day four , the patient was judged to be stable for discharge to home .\r\nMEDICATIONS ON DISCHARGE :\r\nCoumadin , Ativan , Lomotil , Metamucil , Benadryl and Compazine .\r\nFOLLOWUP :\r\nThe patient will follow up with Dr. Large .\r\nPRINCIPAL DIAGNOSIS :\r\nIII-c papillary serous ovarian cancer .\r\nASSOCIATED DIAGNOSIS :\r\nhistory of deep venous thrombosis .\r\nKITRI CURB , M.D.\r\nDICTATING FOR :\r\nSLAINEAEE S. LARGE , M.D.\r\nTR :\r\nnh / bmot\r\nDD :\r\n5-11-22\r\nTD :\r\n05/12/22\r\nCC :\r\n3 copies to Dr. Large", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with malignancy other than metastatic prostate cancer", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["PRINCIPAL DIAGNOSIS : ovarian cancer , III-c papillary serous"]}, {"question": "If so, what is type of malignancy", "answer": "ovarian cancer", "justification": ["PRINCIPAL DIAGNOSIS : ovarian cancer"]}, {"question": "If so, what was the date of diagnosis", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 159, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2019-08-25", "note": "CHIEF COMPLAINT: Left breast cancer.,\r\nHISTORY: The patient is a 57-year-old female, who I initially saw in the office on 2019/07/12, as a referral from the Tomball Breast Center.  On 2019/07/21, the patient underwent image-guided needle core biopsy of a 1.5 cm lesion at the 7 o'clock position of the left breast (inferomedial).  The biopsy returned showing infiltrating ductal carcinoma high histologic grade.  The patient stated that she had recently felt and her physician had felt a palpable mass in that area prior to her breast imaging.  She prior to that area, denied any complaints.  She had no nipple discharge.  No trauma history.  She has had been on no estrogen supplementation.  She has had no other personal history of breast cancer.  Her family history is positive for her mother having breast cancer at age 48.  The patient has had no children and no pregnancies.  She denies any change in the right breast.  Subsequent to the office visit and tissue diagnosis of breast cancer, she has had medical oncology consultation with Dr. Smith and radiation oncology consultation with Dr. Brown.  I have discussed the case with Dr. Smith and Dr. Brown, who are both in agreement with proceeding with surgery prior to adjuvant therapy.  The patient's metastatic workup has otherwise been negative with MRI scan and CT scanning.  The MRI scan showed some close involvement possibly involving the left pectoralis muscle, although thought to also possibly represent biopsy artifact.  CT scan of the neck, chest, and abdomen is negative for metastatic disease. PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:,  Previous surgery is history of benign breast biopsy in 2015, laparotomy in 2015, 2016, and 2018, right oophorectomy in 2018, and ganglion cyst removal of the hand in 2018. MEDICATIONS:,  She is currently on omeprazole for reflux and indigestion.,ALLERGIES:,  SHE HAS NO KNOWN DRUG ALLERGIES.,REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:,  Negative for any recent febrile illnesses, chest pains or shortness of breath.  Positive for restless leg syndrome.  Negative for any unexplained weight loss and no change in bowel or bladder habits.,FAMILY HISTORY:,  Positive for breast cancer in her mother and also mesothelioma from possible asbestosis or asbestos exposure.,SOCIAL HISTORY:  ,The patient works as a school teacher and teaching high school.,PHYSICAL EXAMINATION,GENERAL:  The patient is a white female, alert and oriented x 3, appears her stated age of 57.,HEENT:  Head is atraumatic and normocephalic.  Sclerae are anicteric.,NECK:  Supple.,CHEST:  Clear.,HEART:  Regular rate and rhythm.,BREASTS:  Exam reveals an approximately 1.5 cm relatively mobile focal palpable mass in the inferomedial left breast at the 7 o'clock position, which clinically is not fixed to the underlying pectoralis muscle.  There are no nipple retractions.  No skin dimpling.  There is some, at the time of the office visit, ecchymosis from recent biopsy.  There is no axillary adenopathy.  The remainder of the left breast is without abnormality.  The right breast is without abnormality.  The axillary areas are negative for adenopathy bilaterally.,ABDOMEN:  Soft, nontender without masses.  No gross organomegaly.  No CVA or flank tenderness.,EXTREMITIES:  Grossly neurovascularly intact.,IMPRESSION: , The patient is a 57-year-old female with invasive ductal carcinoma of the left breast, T1c, Nx, M0 left breast carcinoma.,RECOMMENDATIONS: , I have discussed with the patient in detail about the diagnosis of breast cancer and the surgical options, and medical oncologist has discussed with her issues about adjuvant or neoadjuvant chemotherapy.  We have decided to recommend to the patient breast conservation surgery with left breast lumpectomy with preoperative sentinel lymph node injection and mapping and left axillary dissection.  The possibility of further surgery requiring wider lumpectomy or even completion mastectomy was explained to the patient.  The procedure and risks of the surgery were explained to include, but not limited to extra bleeding, infection, unsightly scar formation, the possibility of local recurrence, the possibility of left upper extremity lymphedema was explained.  Local numbness, paresthesias or chronic pain was explained.  The patient was given an educational brochure and several brochures about the diagnosis and treatment of breast cancers.  She was certainly encouraged to obtain further surgical medical opinions prior to proceeding.  I believe the patient has given full informed consent and desires to proceed with the above.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with breast cancer", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["The biopsy returned showing infiltrating ductal carcinoma high histologic grade"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the patient diagnosed with breast cancer", "answer": "On 2019/07/21", "justification": ["On 2019/07/21, the patient underwent image-guided needle core biopsy", "The biopsy returned showing infiltrating ductal carcinoma high histologic grade."]}, {"question": "Has the patient receive radiation therapy for breast cancer", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 66, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2010-09-02", "note": "Admission Date :\n2010-08-26\nDischarge Date :\n2010-09-02\nDate of Birth :\n1961-06-26\nSex :\nM\nService :\nHISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS :\nMr. Robert Mackey is a 49 year old gentleman with a 22 year history of diabetes mellitus .\nHe has a history of peripheral neuropathy , kidney transplantation in 2003 secondary to diabetic nephropathy , as well as throat cancer in 2004 treated with local resection and radical neck dissection on the left as well as postoperative radiation .\nMr.  Mackey also had signs and symptoms consistent with cervical myelopathy ; a cervical MRI scan showed very impressive disc herniations at C5-C6 , less so at C4-C5 , with clear cut cord compression , particularly on the right side C5-C6 .\nTherefore , he was admitted for C4-C5 and C5-C6 anterior diskectomy with autologous bone graft and instrumented fusion .\nPHYSICAL EXAMINATION :\nPostoperative physical examination demonstrated that he was afebrile at 97 degrees ; blood pressure 145/80 ; pulse 60 ; respiratory rate 10 ; 100% on a non-rebreather .\nHe was awake , alert , uncomfortable secondary to incisional tenderness at neck site as well as right iliac graft site .\nThe wounds were clean , dry and intact , and flat .\nHOSPITAL COURSE :\nWhile in the PACU , Anesthesia was called because the patient became dyspneic and tachypneic and his SAO2 dropped to 89% .\nHis respiratory rate was 30 on face mask .\nInteroperatively , he was positive two liters with a stable blood pressure and heart rate , although requiring some neo-synephrine interoperatively .\nHe responded to intravenous Lasix with 3.2 liters of urine output as well as marked clinical improvement .\nThe etiology for his congestive heart failure was determined likely to be diastolic dysfunction from increased heart rate as well as excess volume .\nNo definite evidence for significant myocardial ischemia , although cardiac enzymes were sent and he ruled out for myocardial infarction .\nHe was admitted to the Surgical Intensive Care Unit where his respiratory and cardiac status was monitored carefully .\nHe was given Lasix to continue to diurese the excess volume .\nHe was also put on Lopressor 150 mg twice a day .\nAlso in the Intensive Care Unit , O2 saturation was closely monitored .\nThe patient became agitated with both tent and Bi-PAP machine , although continued to saturate well .\nHe was transferred to Medicine the morning of 2010-08-30 , for continued medical management post surgery .\nOn the day of transfer , the patient was noted to be confused with waxing and waning sensorium ; thus , a delirium work-up was initiated looking for precipitants .\nHe was febrile in the Intensive Care Unit to 101.0 F. ; yet , chest x-ray , blood cultures , urinalysis and urine cultures were all negative for sources .\nA lumbar puncture was considered , although not performed due to the fact that the cerebrospinal fluid was not breached during the procedure .\nDISPOSITION :\nThe patient was discharged on 09-02 .\nDISCHARGE INSTRUCTIONS :\n\n1. Follow-up with Dr. Williams on Tuesday , 09-07 , at noon .\n2. Follow-up with Dr. Michael , his psychiatrist , on Wednesday , 09-08 .\n3. He was also discharged home with Visiting Nurse Association for Physical Therapy evaluation of home safety .\n\nHe was instructed to hold the following three medications that he took prior to admission :\nNortriptyline 10 mg q. h.s. ; Flomax 0.4 mg q. h.s. ; Neurontin 600 mg three times a day .\nHe was instructed not to restart these until seen by Dr. Ercek .\nDISCHARGE DIAGNOSES :\n\n1. C4-C5 , C5-C6 , anterior microdiscectomy and fusion with right iliac bone graft .\n\nFor completeness , the patient 's complete past medical history :\n\n1. End-stage renal disease secondary to type 1 diabetes mellitus ; status post renal transplant in 2003 .\n2. History of multiple urinary tract infections .\n3. Pyelonephritis .\n4. Creatinine 2.2 to 2.5 .\n5. Right coronary artery stent in 2008 ; ejection fraction 60 to 65% .\n6. Type 1 diabetes mellitus with triopathy , retinopathy , neuropathy , nephropathy .\n7. Benign prostatic hypertrophy status post transurethral resection of the prostate ; self catheterization .\n8. Hypertension .\n9. Hypercholesterolemia .\n10. Hepatitis B .\n11. Throat cancer status post right neck dissection and XRT in 2004 .\n12. Cerebral aneurysm .\n13. Left prosthetic CMED CCU .\n\nALLERGIES :\nGentamicin , and ibuprofen .", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient ever been diagnosed with cancer?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["as well as throat cancer in 2004"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the most recent cancer diagnosis made, relative to the date of the clinical note?", "answer": "2004", "justification": ["as well as throat cancer in 2004"]}, {"question": "If so, what type of cancer was most recently diagnosed, relative to the date of the clinical note?", "answer": "throat cancer", "justification": ["as well as throat cancer in 2004"]}, {"question": "If so, when did the patient receive the most recent treatment for that cancer, relative to the date of the clinical note?", "answer": "right neck dissection and XRT", "justification": ["Throat cancer status post right neck dissection and XRT in 2004"]}]}
{"id": 104, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "The interval between the last surgery for breast cancer (including re-excision of margins) and study entry must be no more than 70 days.", "note_date": "2016-01-07", "note": "2016-1-7 9:53 AM\nReason: surveillence\nBarnes Jewish Hospital\nMEDICAL CONDITION:\nh/o l breast ca, s/p ex & rt, 2005\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION:\nsurveillence\nFINAL REPORT\nBILATERAL DIGITAL DIAGNOSTIC MAMMOGRAM ON 2016-1-7\nCLINICAL INFORMATION: History of left breast cancer, status post lumpectomy\nand radiation therapy in 2005. No current complaints.\nFINDINGS: A wire was placed over the upper outer posterior left breast\nindicating the lumpectomy scar, and routine views of both breasts were\nperformed using GE digital mammography. Additional MLO spot compression and\n90-degree lateral views of the right breast were performed to evaluate an area\nof density. Comparison made with 2012-12-26 and film screen exam from 2009-12-30.\nBoth breasts demonstrate scattered fibroglandular densities. In the superior\nright breast, an area of density is again noted, and was questionably more\nprominent. This likely is due to differences in technique and positioning.\nAdditional views reveal no focal mass, no clustered microcalcifications, and\nno significant architectural distortion. In the posterior lateral left\nbreast, there is stable architectural distortion consistent with post\nlumpectomy/post treatment changes. Vascular calcification is again noted.\nIMPRESSION: No radiographic evidence of new or recurrent malignancy. Annual\nmammography recommended. Results discussed with the patient.\nRush University Medical Center-RADS 2 - benign.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient ever had surgery for breast cancer?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["History of left breast cancer, status post lumpectomy"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the most recent such surgery, relative to the note date?", "answer": "2005", "justification": ["status post lumpectomy and radiation therapy in 2005"]}]}
{"id": 116, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2017-01-08", "note": "CHIEF COMPLAINT: Newly diagnosed mantle cell lymphoma.,HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS: , The patient is a 47-year-old woman who presented with abdominal pain in September 2016. On chest x-ray, she had a possible infiltrate and it was thought she might have pneumonia and she was treated with antibiotics and prednisone. Symptoms improved temporarily, but did not completely resolve. By the end of September, her pain had worsened and she was seen in the emergency room at Beth Israel. Chest x-ray was compatible with pleurisy and she was treated with Percocet. Few days later, she was seen and given a prescription for Ultram because Percocet was causing nausea. Eventually, she was seen by Dr. Ng and noted to have splenomegaly. Repeat ultrasound was done and showed the spleen enlarged at 19 cm. In retrospect, this was not changed in comparison to an ultrasound that was done in September. She underwent positron emission tomography (PET) scanning, which showed diffuse hypermetabolic lymph nodes measuring 1 to 2 cm in diameter, as well as a hypermetabolic spleen that was enlarged.,The patient underwent lymph node biopsy on the right neck on 10/27/2016. Pathology is consistent with mantle cell lymphoma.,On 10/31/2016, she had a bone marrow biopsy. This does show involvement of bone marrow with lymphoma.,She was noted to have circulating lymphoma cells on peripheral smear as well.,Although CBC was normal, MCV was low and the ferritin was assessed and was low at 8, consistent with iron deficiency.,ALLERGIES:, NONE.,MEDICATIONS: ,1. Estradiol/Prometrium. ,2. Ultram p.r.n. ,3. Baby aspirin. ,4. Lunesta for sleep. ,5. She has been started on iron supplements.,PAST MEDICAL HISTORY: ,1. Tubal ligation in 1996.,2. Possible cyst removed from the left neck in 2001.,3. Tonsillectomy.,4. Migraines, which are rare.,SOCIAL HISTORY: , She does not smoke cigarettes and drinks alcohol only occasionally. She is married and has two children, ages 24 and 20. She works as a project administrator.,FAMILY HISTORY: ,Father is deceased. He had emphysema and colon cancer at age 68. Mother has arrhythmia and hypertension. Her sister has hypertension and her brother is healthy.,PHYSICAL EXAMINATION: ,GENERAL: She is in no acute distress.,VITAL SIGNS: Her weight is 168 pounds, and she is afebrile with a normal blood pressure and pulse.,HEENT: The oropharynx is benign.,SKIN: The skin is warm and dry and shows no jaundice.,NECK: There is shotty adenopathy in the neck.,CARDIAC: Regular rate without murmur.,LUNGS: Clear to auscultation bilaterally.,ABDOMEN: Soft and nontender and shows the spleen palpable about 10 cm below the right costal margin.,EXTREMITIES: No peripheral edema is noted.,LABORATORY DATA: , CBC and chemistry panel are pending. CBC was normal last week. PT/INR was normal as well.,IMPRESSION:, Newly diagnosed mantle cell lymphoma, admitted now to start chemotherapy. She will start treatment with hyperfractionated cyclophosphamide, vincristine, doxorubicin, dexamethasone. Toxicities have already been discussed with her including myelosuppression, mucositis, diarrhea, nausea, alopecia, the low risk for cardiac toxicity, bladder toxicity, neuropathy, constipation, etc. Written materials were provided to her last week.,PLAN: , Plan will be to add Rituxan a little later in her course because she has circulating lymphoma cells. She will be started on allopurinol today as well as hydration further to avoid the possibility of tumor lysis syndrome.,Plan will be to have her evaluated for bone marrow transplant in first remission. I will have Dr. Y see her while she is in the hospital.,The patient is anxious, and will be given Ativan as needed. We will discontinue aspirin for now, but continue estradiol/Prometrium.,Iron deficiency will be treated with oral iron supplements and we will follow her counts. She may well have gastrointestinal (GI) involvement, which is not uncommon with mantle cell lymphoma. After she undergoes remission, we will consider colonoscopy for biopsies prior to proceeding to transplant.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Is this patient receiving any hormone therapy medications?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["MEDICATIONS: ,1. Estradiol/Prometrium"]}, {"question": "If so, which?", "answer": "Estradiol/Prometrium", "justification": ["MEDICATIONS: ,1. Estradiol/Prometrium"]}, {"question": "If so, what dosage?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 117, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2017-01-08", "note": "CHIEF COMPLAINT: Newly diagnosed mantle cell lymphoma.,HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS: , The patient is a 47-year-old woman who presented with abdominal pain in September 2016. On chest x-ray, she had a possible infiltrate and it was thought she might have pneumonia and she was treated with antibiotics and prednisone. Symptoms improved temporarily, but did not completely resolve. By the end of September, her pain had worsened and she was seen in the emergency room at Beth Israel. Chest x-ray was compatible with pleurisy and she was treated with Percocet. Few days later, she was seen and given a prescription for Ultram because Percocet was causing nausea. Eventually, she was seen by Dr. Ng and noted to have splenomegaly. Repeat ultrasound was done and showed the spleen enlarged at 19 cm. In retrospect, this was not changed in comparison to an ultrasound that was done in September. She underwent positron emission tomography (PET) scanning, which showed diffuse hypermetabolic lymph nodes measuring 1 to 2 cm in diameter, as well as a hypermetabolic spleen that was enlarged.,The patient underwent lymph node biopsy on the right neck on 10/27/2016. Pathology is consistent with mantle cell lymphoma.,On 10/31/2016, she had a bone marrow biopsy. This does show involvement of bone marrow with lymphoma.,She was noted to have circulating lymphoma cells on peripheral smear as well.,Although CBC was normal, MCV was low and the ferritin was assessed and was low at 8, consistent with iron deficiency.,ALLERGIES:, NONE.,MEDICATIONS: ,1. Estradiol/Prometrium. ,2. Ultram p.r.n. ,3. Baby aspirin. ,4. Lunesta for sleep. ,5. She has been started on iron supplements.,PAST MEDICAL HISTORY: ,1. Tubal ligation in 1996.,2. Possible cyst removed from the left neck in 2001.,3. Tonsillectomy.,4. Migraines, which are rare.,SOCIAL HISTORY: , She does not smoke cigarettes and drinks alcohol only occasionally. She is married and has two children, ages 24 and 20. She works as a project administrator.,FAMILY HISTORY: ,Father is deceased. He had emphysema and colon cancer at age 68. Mother has arrhythmia and hypertension. Her sister has hypertension and her brother is healthy.,PHYSICAL EXAMINATION: ,GENERAL: She is in no acute distress.,VITAL SIGNS: Her weight is 168 pounds, and she is afebrile with a normal blood pressure and pulse.,HEENT: The oropharynx is benign.,SKIN: The skin is warm and dry and shows no jaundice.,NECK: There is shotty adenopathy in the neck.,CARDIAC: Regular rate without murmur.,LUNGS: Clear to auscultation bilaterally.,ABDOMEN: Soft and nontender and shows the spleen palpable about 10 cm below the right costal margin.,EXTREMITIES: No peripheral edema is noted.,LABORATORY DATA: , CBC and chemistry panel are pending. CBC was normal last week. PT/INR was normal as well.,IMPRESSION:, Newly diagnosed mantle cell lymphoma, admitted now to start chemotherapy. She will start treatment with hyperfractionated cyclophosphamide, vincristine, doxorubicin, dexamethasone. Toxicities have already been discussed with her including myelosuppression, mucositis, diarrhea, nausea, alopecia, the low risk for cardiac toxicity, bladder toxicity, neuropathy, constipation, etc. Written materials were provided to her last week.,PLAN: , Plan will be to add Rituxan a little later in her course because she has circulating lymphoma cells. She will be started on allopurinol today as well as hydration further to avoid the possibility of tumor lysis syndrome.,Plan will be to have her evaluated for bone marrow transplant in first remission. I will have Dr. Y see her while she is in the hospital.,The patient is anxious, and will be given Ativan as needed. We will discontinue aspirin for now, but continue estradiol/Prometrium.,Iron deficiency will be treated with oral iron supplements and we will follow her counts. She may well have gastrointestinal (GI) involvement, which is not uncommon with mantle cell lymphoma. After she undergoes remission, we will consider colonoscopy for biopsies prior to proceeding to transplant.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Does this patient have peripheral edema on the date of the note?", "answer": "No", "justification": ["No peripheral edema is noted"]}]}
{"id": 115, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2017-01-08", "note": "CHIEF COMPLAINT: Newly diagnosed mantle cell lymphoma.,HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS: , The patient is a 47-year-old woman who presented with abdominal pain in September 2016. On chest x-ray, she had a possible infiltrate and it was thought she might have pneumonia and she was treated with antibiotics and prednisone. Symptoms improved temporarily, but did not completely resolve. By the end of September, her pain had worsened and she was seen in the emergency room at Beth Israel. Chest x-ray was compatible with pleurisy and she was treated with Percocet. Few days later, she was seen and given a prescription for Ultram because Percocet was causing nausea. Eventually, she was seen by Dr. Ng and noted to have splenomegaly. Repeat ultrasound was done and showed the spleen enlarged at 19 cm. In retrospect, this was not changed in comparison to an ultrasound that was done in September. She underwent positron emission tomography (PET) scanning, which showed diffuse hypermetabolic lymph nodes measuring 1 to 2 cm in diameter, as well as a hypermetabolic spleen that was enlarged.,The patient underwent lymph node biopsy on the right neck on 10/27/2016. Pathology is consistent with mantle cell lymphoma.,On 10/31/2016, she had a bone marrow biopsy. This does show involvement of bone marrow with lymphoma.,She was noted to have circulating lymphoma cells on peripheral smear as well.,Although CBC was normal, MCV was low and the ferritin was assessed and was low at 8, consistent with iron deficiency.,ALLERGIES:, NONE.,MEDICATIONS: ,1. Estradiol/Prometrium. ,2. Ultram p.r.n. ,3. Baby aspirin. ,4. Lunesta for sleep. ,5. She has been started on iron supplements.,PAST MEDICAL HISTORY: ,1. Tubal ligation in 1996.,2. Possible cyst removed from the left neck in 2001.,3. Tonsillectomy.,4. Migraines, which are rare.,SOCIAL HISTORY: , She does not smoke cigarettes and drinks alcohol only occasionally. She is married and has two children, ages 24 and 20. She works as a project administrator.,FAMILY HISTORY: ,Father is deceased. He had emphysema and colon cancer at age 68. Mother has arrhythmia and hypertension. Her sister has hypertension and her brother is healthy.,PHYSICAL EXAMINATION: ,GENERAL: She is in no acute distress.,VITAL SIGNS: Her weight is 168 pounds, and she is afebrile with a normal blood pressure and pulse.,HEENT: The oropharynx is benign.,SKIN: The skin is warm and dry and shows no jaundice.,NECK: There is shotty adenopathy in the neck.,CARDIAC: Regular rate without murmur.,LUNGS: Clear to auscultation bilaterally.,ABDOMEN: Soft and nontender and shows the spleen palpable about 10 cm below the right costal margin.,EXTREMITIES: No peripheral edema is noted.,LABORATORY DATA: , CBC and chemistry panel are pending. CBC was normal last week. PT/INR was normal as well.,IMPRESSION:, Newly diagnosed mantle cell lymphoma, admitted now to start chemotherapy. She will start treatment with hyperfractionated cyclophosphamide, vincristine, doxorubicin, dexamethasone. Toxicities have already been discussed with her including myelosuppression, mucositis, diarrhea, nausea, alopecia, the low risk for cardiac toxicity, bladder toxicity, neuropathy, constipation, etc. Written materials were provided to her last week.,PLAN: , Plan will be to add Rituxan a little later in her course because she has circulating lymphoma cells. She will be started on allopurinol today as well as hydration further to avoid the possibility of tumor lysis syndrome.,Plan will be to have her evaluated for bone marrow transplant in first remission. I will have Dr. Y see her while she is in the hospital.,The patient is anxious, and will be given Ativan as needed. We will discontinue aspirin for now, but continue estradiol/Prometrium.,Iron deficiency will be treated with oral iron supplements and we will follow her counts. She may well have gastrointestinal (GI) involvement, which is not uncommon with mantle cell lymphoma. After she undergoes remission, we will consider colonoscopy for biopsies prior to proceeding to transplant.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient had a bone marrow biopsy?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["she had a bone marrow biopsy"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the most recent such biopsy relative to the date of the note?", "answer": "10/31/2016", "justification": ["On 10/31/2016, she had a bone marrow biopsy"]}]}
{"id": 90, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2017-01-25", "note": "Jack Clarkson is a 43-year-old man who was diagnosed with metastatic prostate cancer (Gleason score 4 + 4) in November 2013. Laboratory data at the time showed that the prostate-specific antigen (PSA) level was 18.6 ng/mL, and digital rectal examination indicated a stony hard mass in the prostate that was suspected to be local advanced prostate cancer. Magnetic resonance imaging revealed a prostate tumor invading the seminal vesicle and a metastasis of the pubic bone. Based on these results, the patient underwent neoadjuvant androgen deprivation and docetaxel therapy, followed by laparoscopic prostatectomy, extended lymphadenenolectomy, and metastatectomy of the pubic bone in March 2014. Pathological examination revealed residual adenocarcinoma in the prostate and pubic bone (pathological T stage 3b, positive surgical margin). After the operation, he received adjuvant radiation therapy (66 Gy) to the pelvic floor. His serum PSA level decreased to < 0.01 ng/mL but gradually increased to 0.14 ng/mL. He was then re-initiated on docetaxel in December 2015, although computed tomography (CT) and bone scan did not show obvious metastatic lesions. His PSA level decreased to < 0.01 ng/mL in April 2016 after 7 cycles of docetaxel chemotherapy but slightly increased to 0.17 ng/mL in July 2016. Positron emission tomography-CT indicated five tiny nodules in the bilateral lungs. Biopsy specimens are difficult to obtain and might not reflect the precise extent of the disease owing to heterogeneity in patients with CRPC. Therefore, we performed liquid biopsy to isolate circulating tumor cells (CTCs) using the ClearCell FX System, which is an automated CTC enrichment system that is powered by a microfluidics biochip. To count the CTCs isolated using this system, we performed immunostaining using the following antibodies: mouse anti-pan human keratin (C11) monoclonal antibody (mAb) (keratin 4, 5, 6, 8, 10, 13, and 18; Cell Signaling, Danvers, MA, USA), mouse anti-human cytokeratin mAb (CK3-6H5, Miltenyi Biotec GmbH, Bergisch Gladbach, Germany), mouse anti-human EpCAM (VU1D9) mAb (Cell Signaling), goat N-terminal androgen receptor (AR; N-10) polyclonal antibody (Santa Cruz Biotechnology, Santa Cruz, CA, USA), and rabbit CD45 (D9M81) mAb (Cell Signaling). Additionally, we performed nuclear staining using 4\u2032,6-diamidino-2-phenylindole. Overall, 156 CTCs were detected per 7.5 mL, and almost all CTCs were AR negative in the nucleus. Therefore, we diagnosed the five tiny nodules as lung metastases from docetaxel-resistant CRPC with few AR-signaling-dependent cancer cells.\nThe patient was initiated on CBZ (25 mg/m2) according to the standard protocol in August 2016, instead of a second-generation AR-targeting agent (enzalutamide or abiraterone). Following 2 cycles of CBZ chemotherapy, the PSA level decreased to < 0.01 ng/mL and the lung metastases completely disappeared, with a reduced CTC count of < 5. To date, the patient has been receiving intermittent CBZ chemotherapy.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient received androgen deprivation therapy?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["the patient underwent neoadjuvant androgen deprivation and docetaxel therapy"]}, {"question": "If so, when did such therapy start?", "answer": "2013", "justification": ["in November 2013", "Laboratory data at the time", "Based on these results, the patient underwent neoadjuvant androgen deprivation and docetaxel therapy"]}]}
{"id": 88, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04844749", "criterion": "The patient has received at least one androgen receptor targeting agent (e.g. abiraterone, enzalutamide, darolutamide, or apalutamide).", "note_date": "2017-01-25", "note": "Jack Clarkson is a 43-year-old man who was diagnosed with metastatic prostate cancer (Gleason score 4 + 4) in November 2013. Laboratory data at the time showed that the prostate-specific antigen (PSA) level was 18.6 ng/mL, and digital rectal examination indicated a stony hard mass in the prostate that was suspected to be local advanced prostate cancer. Magnetic resonance imaging revealed a prostate tumor invading the seminal vesicle and a metastasis of the pubic bone. Based on these results, the patient underwent neoadjuvant androgen deprivation and docetaxel therapy, followed by laparoscopic prostatectomy, extended lymphadenenolectomy, and metastatectomy of the pubic bone in March 2014. Pathological examination revealed residual adenocarcinoma in the prostate and pubic bone (pathological T stage 3b, positive surgical margin). After the operation, he received adjuvant radiation therapy (66 Gy) to the pelvic floor. His serum PSA level decreased to < 0.01 ng/mL but gradually increased to 0.14 ng/mL. He was then re-initiated on docetaxel in December 2015, although computed tomography (CT) and bone scan did not show obvious metastatic lesions. His PSA level decreased to < 0.01 ng/mL in April 2016 after 7 cycles of docetaxel chemotherapy but slightly increased to 0.17 ng/mL in July 2016. Positron emission tomography-CT indicated five tiny nodules in the bilateral lungs. Biopsy specimens are difficult to obtain and might not reflect the precise extent of the disease owing to heterogeneity in patients with CRPC. Therefore, we performed liquid biopsy to isolate circulating tumor cells (CTCs) using the ClearCell FX System, which is an automated CTC enrichment system that is powered by a microfluidics biochip. To count the CTCs isolated using this system, we performed immunostaining using the following antibodies: mouse anti-pan human keratin (C11) monoclonal antibody (mAb) (keratin 4, 5, 6, 8, 10, 13, and 18; Cell Signaling, Danvers, MA, USA), mouse anti-human cytokeratin mAb (CK3-6H5, Miltenyi Biotec GmbH, Bergisch Gladbach, Germany), mouse anti-human EpCAM (VU1D9) mAb (Cell Signaling), goat N-terminal androgen receptor (AR; N-10) polyclonal antibody (Santa Cruz Biotechnology, Santa Cruz, CA, USA), and rabbit CD45 (D9M81) mAb (Cell Signaling). Additionally, we performed nuclear staining using 4\u2032,6-diamidino-2-phenylindole. Overall, 156 CTCs were detected per 7.5 mL, and almost all CTCs were AR negative in the nucleus. Therefore, we diagnosed the five tiny nodules as lung metastases from docetaxel-resistant CRPC with few AR-signaling-dependent cancer cells.\nThe patient was initiated on CBZ (25 mg/m2) according to the standard protocol in August 2016, instead of a second-generation AR-targeting agent (enzalutamide or abiraterone). Following 2 cycles of CBZ chemotherapy, the PSA level decreased to < 0.01 ng/mL and the lung metastases completely disappeared, with a reduced CTC count of < 5. To date, the patient has been receiving intermittent CBZ chemotherapy.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been treated with at least one androgen receptor targeting agent?", "answer": "No", "justification": ["instead of a second-generation AR-targeting agent (enzalutamide or abiraterone)"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the most recent such treatment?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 89, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2017-01-25", "note": "Jack Clarkson is a 43-year-old man who was diagnosed with metastatic prostate cancer (Gleason score 4 + 4) in November 2013. Laboratory data at the time showed that the prostate-specific antigen (PSA) level was 18.6 ng/mL, and digital rectal examination indicated a stony hard mass in the prostate that was suspected to be local advanced prostate cancer. Magnetic resonance imaging revealed a prostate tumor invading the seminal vesicle and a metastasis of the pubic bone. Based on these results, the patient underwent neoadjuvant androgen deprivation and docetaxel therapy, followed by laparoscopic prostatectomy, extended lymphadenenolectomy, and metastatectomy of the pubic bone in March 2014. Pathological examination revealed residual adenocarcinoma in the prostate and pubic bone (pathological T stage 3b, positive surgical margin). After the operation, he received adjuvant radiation therapy (66 Gy) to the pelvic floor. His serum PSA level decreased to < 0.01 ng/mL but gradually increased to 0.14 ng/mL. He was then re-initiated on docetaxel in December 2015, although computed tomography (CT) and bone scan did not show obvious metastatic lesions. His PSA level decreased to < 0.01 ng/mL in April 2016 after 7 cycles of docetaxel chemotherapy but slightly increased to 0.17 ng/mL in July 2016. Positron emission tomography-CT indicated five tiny nodules in the bilateral lungs. Biopsy specimens are difficult to obtain and might not reflect the precise extent of the disease owing to heterogeneity in patients with CRPC. Therefore, we performed liquid biopsy to isolate circulating tumor cells (CTCs) using the ClearCell FX System, which is an automated CTC enrichment system that is powered by a microfluidics biochip. To count the CTCs isolated using this system, we performed immunostaining using the following antibodies: mouse anti-pan human keratin (C11) monoclonal antibody (mAb) (keratin 4, 5, 6, 8, 10, 13, and 18; Cell Signaling, Danvers, MA, USA), mouse anti-human cytokeratin mAb (CK3-6H5, Miltenyi Biotec GmbH, Bergisch Gladbach, Germany), mouse anti-human EpCAM (VU1D9) mAb (Cell Signaling), goat N-terminal androgen receptor (AR; N-10) polyclonal antibody (Santa Cruz Biotechnology, Santa Cruz, CA, USA), and rabbit CD45 (D9M81) mAb (Cell Signaling). Additionally, we performed nuclear staining using 4\u2032,6-diamidino-2-phenylindole. Overall, 156 CTCs were detected per 7.5 mL, and almost all CTCs were AR negative in the nucleus. Therefore, we diagnosed the five tiny nodules as lung metastases from docetaxel-resistant CRPC with few AR-signaling-dependent cancer cells.\nThe patient was initiated on CBZ (25 mg/m2) according to the standard protocol in August 2016, instead of a second-generation AR-targeting agent (enzalutamide or abiraterone). Following 2 cycles of CBZ chemotherapy, the PSA level decreased to < 0.01 ng/mL and the lung metastases completely disappeared, with a reduced CTC count of < 5. To date, the patient has been receiving intermittent CBZ chemotherapy.", "qa_list": [{"question": "What was this patient's most recently measured PSA level?", "answer": "< 0.01 ng/mL", "justification": ["the PSA level decreased to < 0.01 ng/mL"]}, {"question": "When was this measurement obtained?", "answer": "Fall 2016", "justification": ["The patient was initiated on CBZ (25 mg/m2) according to the standard protocol in August 2016\",  \"Following 2 cycles of CBZ chemotherapy, the PSA level decreased to < 0.01 ng/mL"]}]}
{"id": 62, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04641351", "criterion": "Patient must not be pregnant", "note_date": "2017-06-13", "note": "Admission Date :\n2017-06-13\nDischarge Date :\n2017-06-17\nDate of Birth :\n1956-02-17\nSex :\nM\nService :\nCARDIOTHORACIC\nAllergies :\nPatient recorded as having No Known Allergies to Drugs\nAttending:Jordan U Kostohryz , M.D.\nChief Complaint: recent mild angina with exertion\nMajor Surgical or Invasive Procedure :\nemergency CABG X 3 ( 2017-06-13 )( LIMA to LAD , SVG to ramus , SVG to OM )\nHistory of Present Illness :\n61 yo African-American-Hispanic male had abnormal EKG found as part of pre-op eval. for ventral hernia repair .\nHad subsequent abnormal stress test and pefusion imaging showed EF 38% with perfusion defects .\nEcho prior to scheduled cath showed mild LVH , inferior HK , EF 40% , mild MR , mild LAE .\nCath at Kindred/North Shore today showed 80% LM lesion with normal LAD , CX , RCA .\nSevere systolic HTN also noted .\nTransferred in urgently for cabg with Dr. Howard .\nPast Medical History :\nventral hernia\nHTN elev. chol. right facial droop with metal plate secondary to GSW to face right nephrectomy\nSocial History :\ncurrent smoker\nFamily History :\nnot given\nPhysical Exam:\nNot done , taken to OR direct from ambulance transfer .\nPertinent Results:\n2017-06-14 02:06AM BLOOD\nWBC - 9.4 RBC - 3.61* Hgb - 10.4* Hct - 29.9* MCV - 83 MCH - 28.8 MCHC - 34.8 RDW - 14.3 Plt Ct - 154\n2017-06-17 05:14AM BLOOD\nHct - 25.2*\n2017-06-14 02:06AM BLOOD\nPlt Ct - 154\n2017-06-13 08:05PM BLOOD\nPT - 13.6* PTT - 33.3 INR ( PT ) - 1.2*\n2017-06-17 05:14AM BLOOD\nUreaN - 25* Creat - 1.0 K - 3.9", "qa_list": [{"question": "Is the patient pregnant at the time of the clinical note?", "answer": "No", "justification": ["Sex :M"]}, {"question": "If so, what is the gestational age at the time of the note?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 127, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2017-06-17", "note": "HPI:\n35F with apparent liver laceration, no prior history of\ntrauma, with hemoperitoneum and Hct 44.8 \u2192 33.7.\nChief complaint:\nhemorrhage\nPMHx:\nPMH: cervical disc herniation\nPSH: c-section 2 years ago, tubal ligation 2 years ago. eye surgery, Percocet prn neck pain\nPain control (acute pain, chronic pain)\nAssessment:\nPt with acute abdominal pain 2017-6-17.\nAction:\nMedicated with Dilauded\nResponse:\nGood response to medication, pt comfortable for periods, able to sleep\nthis shift.\nPlan:\nMedicate as needed.\nLiver Laceration\nAssessment:\nPt admit with Liver laceration of unknown etiology.\nAction:\nPt to US for scan of liver, Q4hr Hc\nResponse:\nStable Hct\ns, no evidence of bleeding per US.\nPlan:\nContinue to monitor Hct\nPt needs social work consult as recently lost her husband, has small\nchild at home, seems to have needs around coping appropriately.\nDemographics\nAttending MD:\nBehn Jennifer\nAdmit diagnosis:\nABDOMINAL PAIN\nCode status:\nFull code\nHeight:\nAdmission weight:\n49.9 kg\nDaily weight:\nAllergies/Reactions:\nCodeine\nUnknown;\nPrecautions:\nPMH: Anemia, ETOH\nCV-PMH:\nAdditional history: C Section, tubal ligation, 4-19 \"slipped cervical disc\"\nSurgery / Procedure and date:\nLatest Vital Signs and I/O\nNon-invasive BP:\nS:114\nD:66\nTemperature:\n98.1\nArterial BP:\nS:\nD:\nRespiratory rate:\n11 insp/min\nHeart Rate:\n54 bpm\nHeart rhythm:\nSB (Sinus Bradycardia)\nO2 delivery device:\nNone\nO2 saturation:\n98% %\nO2 flow:\n2 L/min\nFiO2 set:\n24h total in:\n1,896 mL\n24h total out:\n1,500 mL\nPertinent Lab Results:\nSodium:\n142 mEq/L\n2016-7-9 12:54 AM\nPotassium:\n3.2 mEq/L\n2016-7-9 12:54 AM\nChloride:\n108 mEq/L\n2016-7-9 12:54 AM\nCO2:\n26 mEq/L\n2016-7-9 12:54 AM\nBUN:\n8 mg/dL\n2016-7-9 12:54 AM\nCreatinine:\n0.5 mg/dL\n2016-7-9 12:54 AM\nGlucose:\n92 mg/dL\n2016-7-9 12:54 AM\nHematocrit:\n32.1 %\n2016-7-9 02:20 PM\nValuables / Signature\nPatient valuables: Glasses\nOther valuables: Cellphone\nClothes: Sent home with:\nWallet / Money:\nNo money / wallet\nCash / Credit cards sent home with:\nJewelry:\nTransferred from: Medstar Union Memorial Hospital\nTransferred to: University of Maryland St. Joseph Medical Center\nDate & time of Transfer: 2016-7-9 20:00", "qa_list": [{"question": "What is the patient\u2019s most recent potassium level, relative to the note date?", "answer": "3.2 mEq/L", "justification": ["Potassium: 3.2 mEq/L"]}, {"question": "When was this level measured?", "answer": "2016-7-9", "justification": ["Potassium: 3.2 mEq/L 2016-7-9 12:54 AM"]}]}
{"id": 124, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2017-06-17", "note": "HPI:\n35F with apparent liver laceration, no prior history of\ntrauma, with hemoperitoneum and Hct 44.8 \u2192 33.7.\nChief complaint:\nhemorrhage\nPMHx:\nPMH: cervical disc herniation\nPSH: c-section 2 years ago, tubal ligation 2 years ago. eye surgery, Percocet prn neck pain\nPain control (acute pain, chronic pain)\nAssessment:\nPt with acute abdominal pain 2017-6-17.\nAction:\nMedicated with Dilauded\nResponse:\nGood response to medication, pt comfortable for periods, able to sleep\nthis shift.\nPlan:\nMedicate as needed.\nLiver Laceration\nAssessment:\nPt admit with Liver laceration of unknown etiology.\nAction:\nPt to US for scan of liver, Q4hr Hc\nResponse:\nStable Hct\ns, no evidence of bleeding per US.\nPlan:\nContinue to monitor Hct\nPt needs social work consult as recently lost her husband, has small\nchild at home, seems to have needs around coping appropriately.\nDemographics\nAttending MD:\nBehn Jennifer\nAdmit diagnosis:\nABDOMINAL PAIN\nCode status:\nFull code\nHeight:\nAdmission weight:\n49.9 kg\nDaily weight:\nAllergies/Reactions:\nCodeine\nUnknown;\nPrecautions:\nPMH: Anemia, ETOH\nCV-PMH:\nAdditional history: C Section, tubal ligation, 4-19 \"slipped cervical disc\"\nSurgery / Procedure and date:\nLatest Vital Signs and I/O\nNon-invasive BP:\nS:114\nD:66\nTemperature:\n98.1\nArterial BP:\nS:\nD:\nRespiratory rate:\n11 insp/min\nHeart Rate:\n54 bpm\nHeart rhythm:\nSB (Sinus Bradycardia)\nO2 delivery device:\nNone\nO2 saturation:\n98% %\nO2 flow:\n2 L/min\nFiO2 set:\n24h total in:\n1,896 mL\n24h total out:\n1,500 mL\nPertinent Lab Results:\nSodium:\n142 mEq/L\n2016-7-9 12:54 AM\nPotassium:\n3.2 mEq/L\n2016-7-9 12:54 AM\nChloride:\n108 mEq/L\n2016-7-9 12:54 AM\nCO2:\n26 mEq/L\n2016-7-9 12:54 AM\nBUN:\n8 mg/dL\n2016-7-9 12:54 AM\nCreatinine:\n0.5 mg/dL\n2016-7-9 12:54 AM\nGlucose:\n92 mg/dL\n2016-7-9 12:54 AM\nHematocrit:\n32.1 %\n2016-7-9 02:20 PM\nValuables / Signature\nPatient valuables: Glasses\nOther valuables: Cellphone\nClothes: Sent home with:\nWallet / Money:\nNo money / wallet\nCash / Credit cards sent home with:\nJewelry:\nTransferred from: Medstar Union Memorial Hospital\nTransferred to: University of Maryland St. Joseph Medical Center\nDate & time of Transfer: 2016-7-9 20:00", "qa_list": [{"question": "Does this patient have a history of alcohol consumption?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["PMH: Anemia, ETOH"]}]}
{"id": 123, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03957876", "criterion": "The patient is surgically sterile", "note_date": "2017-06-17", "note": "HPI:\n35F with apparent liver laceration, no prior history of\ntrauma, with hemoperitoneum and Hct 44.8 \u2192 33.7.\nChief complaint:\nhemorrhage\nPMHx:\nPMH: cervical disc herniation\nPSH: c-section 2 years ago, tubal ligation 2 years ago. eye surgery, Percocet prn neck pain\nPain control (acute pain, chronic pain)\nAssessment:\nPt with acute abdominal pain 2017-6-17.\nAction:\nMedicated with Dilauded\nResponse:\nGood response to medication, pt comfortable for periods, able to sleep\nthis shift.\nPlan:\nMedicate as needed.\nLiver Laceration\nAssessment:\nPt admit with Liver laceration of unknown etiology.\nAction:\nPt to US for scan of liver, Q4hr Hc\nResponse:\nStable Hct\ns, no evidence of bleeding per US.\nPlan:\nContinue to monitor Hct\nPt needs social work consult as recently lost her husband, has small\nchild at home, seems to have needs around coping appropriately.\nDemographics\nAttending MD:\nBehn Jennifer\nAdmit diagnosis:\nABDOMINAL PAIN\nCode status:\nFull code\nHeight:\nAdmission weight:\n49.9 kg\nDaily weight:\nAllergies/Reactions:\nCodeine\nUnknown;\nPrecautions:\nPMH: Anemia, ETOH\nCV-PMH:\nAdditional history: C Section, tubal ligation, 4-19 \"slipped cervical disc\"\nSurgery / Procedure and date:\nLatest Vital Signs and I/O\nNon-invasive BP:\nS:114\nD:66\nTemperature:\n98.1\nArterial BP:\nS:\nD:\nRespiratory rate:\n11 insp/min\nHeart Rate:\n54 bpm\nHeart rhythm:\nSB (Sinus Bradycardia)\nO2 delivery device:\nNone\nO2 saturation:\n98% %\nO2 flow:\n2 L/min\nFiO2 set:\n24h total in:\n1,896 mL\n24h total out:\n1,500 mL\nPertinent Lab Results:\nSodium:\n142 mEq/L\n2016-7-9 12:54 AM\nPotassium:\n3.2 mEq/L\n2016-7-9 12:54 AM\nChloride:\n108 mEq/L\n2016-7-9 12:54 AM\nCO2:\n26 mEq/L\n2016-7-9 12:54 AM\nBUN:\n8 mg/dL\n2016-7-9 12:54 AM\nCreatinine:\n0.5 mg/dL\n2016-7-9 12:54 AM\nGlucose:\n92 mg/dL\n2016-7-9 12:54 AM\nHematocrit:\n32.1 %\n2016-7-9 02:20 PM\nValuables / Signature\nPatient valuables: Glasses\nOther valuables: Cellphone\nClothes: Sent home with:\nWallet / Money:\nNo money / wallet\nCash / Credit cards sent home with:\nJewelry:\nTransferred from: Medstar Union Memorial Hospital\nTransferred to: University of Maryland St. Joseph Medical Center\nDate & time of Transfer: 2016-7-9 20:00", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient undergone a surgical sterilization procedure?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["tubal ligation 2 years ago"]}, {"question": "If so, when?", "answer": "2015", "justification": ["Note Date: 2017-6-17", "tubal ligation 2 years ago"]}]}
{"id": 125, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2017-06-17", "note": "HPI:\n35F with apparent liver laceration, no prior history of\ntrauma, with hemoperitoneum and Hct 44.8 \u2192 33.7.\nChief complaint:\nhemorrhage\nPMHx:\nPMH: cervical disc herniation\nPSH: c-section 2 years ago, tubal ligation 2 years ago. eye surgery, Percocet prn neck pain\nPain control (acute pain, chronic pain)\nAssessment:\nPt with acute abdominal pain 2017-6-17.\nAction:\nMedicated with Dilauded\nResponse:\nGood response to medication, pt comfortable for periods, able to sleep\nthis shift.\nPlan:\nMedicate as needed.\nLiver Laceration\nAssessment:\nPt admit with Liver laceration of unknown etiology.\nAction:\nPt to US for scan of liver, Q4hr Hc\nResponse:\nStable Hct\ns, no evidence of bleeding per US.\nPlan:\nContinue to monitor Hct\nPt needs social work consult as recently lost her husband, has small\nchild at home, seems to have needs around coping appropriately.\nDemographics\nAttending MD:\nBehn Jennifer\nAdmit diagnosis:\nABDOMINAL PAIN\nCode status:\nFull code\nHeight:\nAdmission weight:\n49.9 kg\nDaily weight:\nAllergies/Reactions:\nCodeine\nUnknown;\nPrecautions:\nPMH: Anemia, ETOH\nCV-PMH:\nAdditional history: C Section, tubal ligation, 4-19 \"slipped cervical disc\"\nSurgery / Procedure and date:\nLatest Vital Signs and I/O\nNon-invasive BP:\nS:114\nD:66\nTemperature:\n98.1\nArterial BP:\nS:\nD:\nRespiratory rate:\n11 insp/min\nHeart Rate:\n54 bpm\nHeart rhythm:\nSB (Sinus Bradycardia)\nO2 delivery device:\nNone\nO2 saturation:\n98% %\nO2 flow:\n2 L/min\nFiO2 set:\n24h total in:\n1,896 mL\n24h total out:\n1,500 mL\nPertinent Lab Results:\nSodium:\n142 mEq/L\n2016-7-9 12:54 AM\nPotassium:\n3.2 mEq/L\n2016-7-9 12:54 AM\nChloride:\n108 mEq/L\n2016-7-9 12:54 AM\nCO2:\n26 mEq/L\n2016-7-9 12:54 AM\nBUN:\n8 mg/dL\n2016-7-9 12:54 AM\nCreatinine:\n0.5 mg/dL\n2016-7-9 12:54 AM\nGlucose:\n92 mg/dL\n2016-7-9 12:54 AM\nHematocrit:\n32.1 %\n2016-7-9 02:20 PM\nValuables / Signature\nPatient valuables: Glasses\nOther valuables: Cellphone\nClothes: Sent home with:\nWallet / Money:\nNo money / wallet\nCash / Credit cards sent home with:\nJewelry:\nTransferred from: Medstar Union Memorial Hospital\nTransferred to: University of Maryland St. Joseph Medical Center\nDate & time of Transfer: 2016-7-9 20:00", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient had a decrease in hematocrit levels?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Hct 44.8 \u2192 33.7"]}, {"question": "If so, what was the starting level?", "answer": "44.8", "justification": ["Hct 44.8 \u2192 33.7"]}, {"question": "If so, what was the decreased level?", "answer": "33.7", "justification": ["Hct 44.8 \u2192 33.7"]}, {"question": "If so, when did the decrease occur?", "answer": "2017-6-17", "justification": ["Note Date: 2017-6-17"]}]}
{"id": 97, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2018-02-10", "note": "Record date: 2018-02-10\nREASON FOR VISIT: Followup for diabetic cheiropathy. Rule out other diabetes-related musculoskeletal syndrome. Monitoring of Ultracet therapy and left shoulder injection.\nINTERVAL HISTORY: Left shoulder injection was helpful but only last short time. Just a week or so. Ultracet was relieving pains but was not able to afford it. Feels stable and not worse since last seen. Telling me he is cutting down his medications and he is letting his doctors know about this. No acute swelling or further different joint complaints other than what was described in my previous notes. Rest of review of systems again unchanged.\nMEDICATIONS: The medication file is same as last time, except for addition of Tylenols now.\nPHYSICAL EXAMINATION: BP 100/70. Other VS WNL. Wt. 170lb. Gait: Slow. Cooperative. VSS. HEENT: Halitosis. Poor teeth hygiene. Lungs: Clear. Heart: Unremarkable. Abdomen exam: Slight sensitiveness in epigastrium. A little low-frequency tremor in extremities. Musculoskeletal examination: Both shoulders with limited ROM. Left shoulder active ROM is improved compared to the last description. Hands with prayer's sign present. Elbows again show lesser degree of flexion contracture. Range of motion in both shoulders diminished,\nmore in the left side. Hardening of skin on the palm side of hands. Has atrophy of intrinsic muscles of hands. The rest of joint examination, free of inflammation. Unchanged from last description.\nIMPRESSION: Diabetic cheiropathy. Rule out other diabetes-related musculoskeletal syndrome esp in shoulders. Helped by Ultracet. Osteoarthritis changes of early stage. Status post olecranon bursitis. Elevated creatinine.\nPLANS:\n1. Continue Ultracet up 2 tablets prn once twice a day; Samples given.\n2. May consider low-dose narcotics, given his multiple comorbidity and sensitive renal function to nonsteroidal therapy. 3. Close followup for diabetes care with other physicians.\nDISPOSITION: Followup in 4 months or so.\nVirgil Gregory, M.D.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Was this patient ever diagnosed with diabetes?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["REASON FOR VISIT: Followup for diabetic cheiropathy"]}, {"question": "If so, when was that diagnosis made?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 37, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2018-05-09", "note": "The patient is a 40-year-old woman diagnosed with myelodysplastic syndrome with excess blasts-I (MDS-EB-1; 2016 WHO MDS classification) (chromosome 46, XX (20)) in August 2017. She underwent HSCT in September 2017. The immunosuppressant regimen was cyclosporine (400 mg/day) and prednisolone (20 mg/day). Then, three months after HSCT, she presented with intermittent low-grade fever, progressive nasal blockage, and bloody rhinorrhea.\nNasopharyngoscopy revealed an exophytic mass completely occupying the nasopharynx. The surface of the tumor was necrotic and showed multiple bleeding spots. Computed tomography revealed an ill-defined tumor with heterogeneous enhancement at the nasopharynx. Blood biochemical examination showed that Epstein\u2013Barr viral capsid antigen immunoglobulin G (EB-VCA IgG: 107.0 U/mL; the normal value is less than 20 U/mL) and Epstein\u2013Barr nuclear antigen antibody (EBNA-Ab: 278.0 U/mL > 18 U/mL) display positive reactions, while EB-VCA IgM (10.0 U/mL < 36 U/mL) and EB early antigen antibody (EBEA-Ab: 5.0 U/mL < 9 U/mL) presented negative reactions. The quantitative Polymerase Chain Reaction (q-PCR) measurement of EBV DNA (in-house PCR assay; specimen: 5ml whole blood; target gene: BamHI-W gene, 3-kb repeat sequence contained in the EBV genome; detection limit: 200 copies/mL) showed a positive reaction (255 copies/mL).\nAfter biopsy was performed, hematoxylin\u2013eosin staining revealed diffuse polymorphous infiltrates of lymphoid and plasma cells with scattered mitotic features in the nasopharyngeal mass (A,B). Immunohistochemical staining disclosed that a majority of the lymphoid cells were positive for CD20 (A), CD79A (B), and multiple myeloma 1 (MUM1) (C), partially positive for CD38 (D) and positive for CD30 (E). The lymphoid cells were negative for CD3, CD5, cyclin D1, CD10, Bcl-6, CD56, and CD23. In addition, Epstein\u2013Barr encoding region (EBER) in situ hybridization showed positive results (F), and immunostaining for immunoglobulin light chains (kappa and lambda) was negative. (S1 and S2)\nAfter the patient was diagnosed as having polymorphic PTLD, we used local radiotherapy at a dose of 40 cGy for 20 fractions, and the immunosuppressant regimen was adjusted. At the 3-month follow-up, the nasopharyngeal lesion was in complete remission, and the following EBV DNA also dropped to the normal level (EBV DNA qPCR: 0 copies/mL).", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient been diagnosed with MDS or MDS/MPN according to 2016 WHO criteria?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["diagnosed with myelodysplastic syndrome with excess blasts-I (MDS-EB-1; 2016 WHO MDS classification)"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the diagnosis made?", "answer": "August 2017", "justification": ["diagnosed with myelodysplastic syndrome with excess blasts-I (MDS-EB-1; 2016 WHO MDS classification) (chromosome 46, XX (20)) in August 2017"]}]}
{"id": 74, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04844749", "criterion": "The patient must not have a prior history of a thromboembolic event within the last 6 months.", "note_date": "2018-09-20", "note": "57 y.o.f. s/p MCA/CVA. Pt was found aphasic w/ R hemiplegia this am by husband- time of event unknown. Head CT @ OSH revealed thromboembolic CVA- unable to initiate TPA therapy. Pt s/p L knee arthroscopy 2018-9-10 - MDs believe thrombus formed following procedure immobility. Pt given PR aspirin as only form of tx at this time. Repeate head CT performed at MGH, pt transferred to ICU for Q2H neuro checks. PMH/PSH: Hypothyroidism, HTN, cataracts, hysterectomy, tonsilectomy. Home medications include verapamil, synthroid, asa, & currently ibuprofen/percocet for L knee discomfort after arthroscopy. Allergies: ?sulfa & contrast dye. Pt's code status discussed with family- family stated that pt has requested that if she were to undergo cardiac arrest not to have CPR performed, however pt can be intubated for airway management as long as current status/condition is reversible.\nROS:\nRESP: SV on 2L NC, SpO2 95-97%, RR 12-19, LSCTAB. No secretions/cough noted.\nCVS: NSR w/ no ectopy. HR 74-86, SBP 126-140, NMed will tol SBP < 180. Hct 36.1, WBC 11.5, INR 1. + pedal pulses, cap refill <3sec. Skin intact. PIV x1 for access. SC heparin & venodynes for prophylaxis. Enzymes cycled- first of 3 sent at 1600, CK 62, next enzymes to be drawn at 2400. Pt ordered for Surface ECHO to r/o wall motion abnormality/vascular disease & determine EF functioning. Carotid Duplex US also scheduled as routine.\nNEURO: Doozing for majority of shift, however alert when awake, but unable to assess orientation due to aphasia. Pt occasionally nods head in response to yes/no questions. GCS 11 (e4v1m6). Pt also presenting with R hemiplegia- unable to move extremities to command, however pt will withdraw extremites in response to painful stimuli. Lift/holds LUE & LLE. PERRLA. Reflexes intact- +corneals/gag/cough. Pt denies pain at present- however upon arrival to ICU, pt nodded to having some discomfort to L knee from incision arthroscopy. Pt scheduled for Head MRI at 2011.\nGI/GU: Abd soft NT, ND, hypoactive BS, no BM/flatus. Pt currently NPO. FS 140- did not require insulin per RISS. Foley patent, draining adequate amts c/y/u. UOP 40-85cc/hr. LR infusing at 75 cc/hr. Lytes wnl.\nSOCIAL: Pt has large supportive family. Daughter spokesperson- family at bedside this afternoon, spoke w/ Dr. Sahili & was updated as to pts status & poc.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient had a thromboembolic event?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Head CT @ OSH revealed thromboembolic CVA"]}, {"question": "If so, when did the most recent thromboembolic event occur, relative to the note date?", "answer": "2018-9-20", "justification": ["Pt was found aphasic w/ R hemiplegia this am by husband- time of event unknown. Head CT @ OSH revealed thromboembolic CVA", "Note Date: 2018-9-20"]}]}
{"id": 141, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2019-01-14", "note": "A 57-year-old Japanese woman whose Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) PS was 3, with ALK-positive advanced NSCLC with abdominal lymph node (fluorescence in situ hybridization-positive, ALK iScore 3 by iAEP immunohistochemistry) and pleural effusion was treated with first-line alectinib at a dose of 600 mg daily for 9 months at Tokyo Metropolitan Komagome Hospital, starting on 2018-2-5. CT scan demonstrated primary tumor in right lower lobe, 70 mm in diameter, several mediastinal and abdominal lymph node metastases, and plural effusion. Programmed death-ligand 1 expression was 90% using the 22C3 antibody. After 4 months, she achieved partial response and her PS improved to ECOG-PS 1; however, CT scan 8 months after introducing alectinib revealed growth of primary tumor and mediastinal lymph node.\n\nIn the second line, two cycles of cisplatin (75 mg/m2, day 1, every 3 weeks) and pemetrexed (500 mg/m2, day 1, every 3 weeks) demonstrated a partial response evaluated by thorax\u2013pelvis CT scan every 2 months; however, upon the completion of four cycles of cisplatin and pemetrexed, rapid progression occurred. CT scan showed growth of primary sites and abdominal lymph node, increase of plural effusion, and emerge of pleural dissemination. Prior to the third line of chemotherapy, the patient was weakened with the ECOG-PS 3 because of anorexia, dyspnea, dysphagia, and cachexia. The pleural effusion was negative for malignancy, and she underwent a blood transfusion for grade 3 anemia (Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events Version (CTCAE) version 4.0) due to chronic disorder.\n\nThe patient was treated with 600 mg of ceritinib (Zykadia\u00ae) under the support of oral ramosetron for the first 5 days and 10 mg of olanzapine daily before sleep. In a few weeks, pleural effusion was gradually reduced and PS was improved. A tumor response was obtained. Grade 2 diarrhea and anorexia (CTCAE version 4.0) were exhibited for a week but were manageable with supportive care. The patient was discharged and seen on an outpatient basis. Her PS improved to ECOG-PS 2; however, she discontinued ceritinib at 6 weeks because of grade 3 increased amylase and grade 2 dysgeusia. Abdominal metastatic lymph node also decreased in size and was assessed as showing partial response according to the Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST version 1.1) for at least 2 months.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Did this patient ever receive chemotherapy?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["had been treated with first-line alectinib at a dose of 600 mg daily"]}, {"question": "If so, when did the chemotherapy start?", "answer": "2018-2-5", "justification": ["had been treated with first-line alectinib at a dose of 600 mg daily for 9 months at Tokyo Metropolitan Komagome Hospital, starting on 2018-2-5"]}, {"question": "If so, when did the first line of chemotherapy end?", "answer": "November 2018", "justification": ["had been treated with first-line alectinib at a dose of 600 mg daily for 9 months at Tokyo Metropolitan Komagome Hospital, starting on 2018-2-5"]}, {"question": "If so, how many lines of chemotherapy did the patient receive?", "answer": "3", "justification": ["Prior to the third line of chemotherapy"]}, {"question": "If so, what was the patient\u2019s ECOG score before the first line of chemotherapy?", "answer": "3", "justification": ["A 57-year-old Japanese woman whose Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) PS was 3"]}, {"question": "If so, what was the patient\u2019s ECOG score after the first line of chemotherapy?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 142, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2019-01-14", "note": "A 57-year-old Japanese woman whose Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) PS was 3, with ALK-positive advanced NSCLC with abdominal lymph node (fluorescence in situ hybridization-positive, ALK iScore 3 by iAEP immunohistochemistry) and pleural effusion was treated with first-line alectinib at a dose of 600 mg daily for 9 months at Tokyo Metropolitan Komagome Hospital, starting on 2018-2-5. CT scan demonstrated primary tumor in right lower lobe, 70 mm in diameter, several mediastinal and abdominal lymph node metastases, and plural effusion. Programmed death-ligand 1 expression was 90% using the 22C3 antibody. After 4 months, she achieved partial response and her PS improved to ECOG-PS 1; however, CT scan 8 months after introducing alectinib revealed growth of primary tumor and mediastinal lymph node.\n\nIn the second line, two cycles of cisplatin (75 mg/m2, day 1, every 3 weeks) and pemetrexed (500 mg/m2, day 1, every 3 weeks) demonstrated a partial response evaluated by thorax\u2013pelvis CT scan every 2 months; however, upon the completion of four cycles of cisplatin and pemetrexed, rapid progression occurred. CT scan showed growth of primary sites and abdominal lymph node, increase of plural effusion, and emerge of pleural dissemination. Prior to the third line of chemotherapy, the patient was weakened with the ECOG-PS 3 because of anorexia, dyspnea, dysphagia, and cachexia. The pleural effusion was negative for malignancy, and she underwent a blood transfusion for grade 3 anemia (Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events Version (CTCAE) version 4.0) due to chronic disorder.\n\nThe patient was treated with 600 mg of ceritinib (Zykadia\u00ae) under the support of oral ramosetron for the first 5 days and 10 mg of olanzapine daily before sleep. In a few weeks, pleural effusion was gradually reduced and PS was improved. A tumor response was obtained. Grade 2 diarrhea and anorexia (CTCAE version 4.0) were exhibited for a week but were manageable with supportive care. The patient was discharged and seen on an outpatient basis. Her PS improved to ECOG-PS 2; however, she discontinued ceritinib at 6 weeks because of grade 3 increased amylase and grade 2 dysgeusia. Abdominal metastatic lymph node also decreased in size and was assessed as showing partial response according to the Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST version 1.1) for at least 2 months.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Did the patient receive a second line of chemotherapy?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["In the second line"]}, {"question": "If so, when did the second line start?", "answer": "Around November 2021", "justification": ["was treated with first-line alectinib at a dose of 600 mg daily for 9 months"]}, {"question": "If so, what was the ECOG score after the second line of chemotherapy?", "answer": "2", "justification": ["Her PS improved to ECOG-PS 2"]}]}
{"id": 147, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2019-01-14", "note": "A 57-year-old Japanese woman whose Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) PS was 3, with ALK-positive advanced NSCLC with abdominal lymph node (fluorescence in situ hybridization-positive, ALK iScore 3 by iAEP immunohistochemistry) and pleural effusion was treated with first-line alectinib at a dose of 600 mg daily for 9 months at Tokyo Metropolitan Komagome Hospital, starting on 2018-2-5. CT scan demonstrated primary tumor in right lower lobe, 70 mm in diameter, several mediastinal and abdominal lymph node metastases, and plural effusion. Programmed death-ligand 1 expression was 90% using the 22C3 antibody. After 4 months, she achieved partial response and her PS improved to ECOG-PS 1; however, CT scan 8 months after introducing alectinib revealed growth of primary tumor and mediastinal lymph node.\n\nIn the second line, two cycles of cisplatin (75 mg/m2, day 1, every 3 weeks) and pemetrexed (500 mg/m2, day 1, every 3 weeks) demonstrated a partial response evaluated by thorax\u2013pelvis CT scan every 2 months; however, upon the completion of four cycles of cisplatin and pemetrexed, rapid progression occurred. CT scan showed growth of primary sites and abdominal lymph node, increase of plural effusion, and emerge of pleural dissemination. Prior to the third line of chemotherapy, the patient was weakened with the ECOG-PS 3 because of anorexia, dyspnea, dysphagia, and cachexia. The pleural effusion was negative for malignancy, and she underwent a blood transfusion for grade 3 anemia (Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events Version (CTCAE) version 4.0) due to chronic disorder.\n\nThe patient was treated with 600 mg of ceritinib (Zykadia\u00ae) under the support of oral ramosetron for the first 5 days and 10 mg of olanzapine daily before sleep. In a few weeks, pleural effusion was gradually reduced and PS was improved. A tumor response was obtained. Grade 2 diarrhea and anorexia (CTCAE version 4.0) were exhibited for a week but were manageable with supportive care. The patient was discharged and seen on an outpatient basis. Her PS improved to ECOG-PS 2; however, she discontinued ceritinib at 6 weeks because of grade 3 increased amylase and grade 2 dysgeusia. Abdominal metastatic lymph node also decreased in size and was assessed as showing partial response according to the Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST version 1.1) for at least 2 months.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Did the patient experience any adverse effects from a chemotherapy treatment?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Grade 2 diarrhea and anorexia (CTCAE version 4.0) were exhibited"]}, {"question": "If so, what were the adverse effects?", "answer": "Grade 2 diarrhea and anorexia", "justification": ["Grade 2 diarrhea and anorexia"]}, {"question": "If so, what was the chemotherapy regimen that caused the adverse reactions?", "answer": "600 mg of ceritinib (Zykadia\u00ae) under the support of oral ramosetron and 10 mg of olanzapine daily before sleep", "justification": ["The patient was treated with 600 mg of ceritinib (Zykadia\u00ae) under the support of oral ramosetron for the first 5 days and 10 mg of olanzapine daily before sleep"]}]}
{"id": 140, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2019-01-14", "note": "A 57-year-old Japanese woman whose Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) PS was 3, with ALK-positive advanced NSCLC with abdominal lymph node (fluorescence in situ hybridization-positive, ALK iScore 3 by iAEP immunohistochemistry) and pleural effusion was treated with first-line alectinib at a dose of 600 mg daily for 9 months at Tokyo Metropolitan Komagome Hospital, starting on 2018-2-5. CT scan demonstrated primary tumor in right lower lobe, 70 mm in diameter, several mediastinal and abdominal lymph node metastases, and plural effusion. Programmed death-ligand 1 expression was 90% using the 22C3 antibody. After 4 months, she achieved partial response and her PS improved to ECOG-PS 1; however, CT scan 8 months after introducing alectinib revealed growth of primary tumor and mediastinal lymph node.\n\nIn the second line, two cycles of cisplatin (75 mg/m2, day 1, every 3 weeks) and pemetrexed (500 mg/m2, day 1, every 3 weeks) demonstrated a partial response evaluated by thorax\u2013pelvis CT scan every 2 months; however, upon the completion of four cycles of cisplatin and pemetrexed, rapid progression occurred. CT scan showed growth of primary sites and abdominal lymph node, increase of plural effusion, and emerge of pleural dissemination. Prior to the third line of chemotherapy, the patient was weakened with the ECOG-PS 3 because of anorexia, dyspnea, dysphagia, and cachexia. The pleural effusion was negative for malignancy, and she underwent a blood transfusion for grade 3 anemia (Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events Version (CTCAE) version 4.0) due to chronic disorder.\n\nThe patient was treated with 600 mg of ceritinib (Zykadia\u00ae) under the support of oral ramosetron for the first 5 days and 10 mg of olanzapine daily before sleep. In a few weeks, pleural effusion was gradually reduced and PS was improved. A tumor response was obtained. Grade 2 diarrhea and anorexia (CTCAE version 4.0) were exhibited for a week but were manageable with supportive care. The patient was discharged and seen on an outpatient basis. Her PS improved to ECOG-PS 2; however, she discontinued ceritinib at 6 weeks because of grade 3 increased amylase and grade 2 dysgeusia. Abdominal metastatic lymph node also decreased in size and was assessed as showing partial response according to the Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST version 1.1) for at least 2 months.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Did this patient ever have non-small cell lung cancer?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["advanced NSCLC"]}, {"question": "If so, was that cancer positive for anaplastic lymphoma kinase gene rearrangement?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["ALK-positive advanced NSCLC"]}, {"question": "If so, how was this confirmed?", "answer": "FISH test and iAEP immunohistochemistry", "justification": ["fluorescence in situ hybridization-positive, ALK iScore 3 by iAEP immunohistochemistry"]}, {"question": "If so, did that cancer ever spread to any lymph nodes?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["several mediastinal and abdominal lymph node metastases"]}]}
{"id": 87, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "Palpable or radiographically suspicious ipsilateral or contralateral axillary, supraclavicular, infraclavicular, or internal mammary nodes, unless there is histologic confirmation that these nodes are negative for tumor.", "note_date": "2019-01-23", "note": "81 years old female presented to the Department of Surgery a week ago with a history of right breast erythema and edema associated to breast pain, with over two weeks duration and progressive worsening.\nShe linked the appearance of these signals with an episode of breast trauma and she denied the presence of previous breast nodules, nipple drainage, nipple retraction, fever and constitutional symptoms.\nThe patient was multiparous (three pregnancies and three births) and nursed all children.\nShe had multiple medical co-morbidities but there was no past history of breast pathology or family history of breast malignacy.\nPhysical examination demonstrated mammary asymmetry because right breast was bigger and tender. The outer quadrants and the periareolar region had inflammatory signs with orange peel skin. There was no palpable masses or nipple changes. The left breast was normal.\nShe had the right upper limb swollen and palpable axillar and supraclavicular lymph nodes.\nThe principal suspicion was an inflammatory breast cancer.\nThe ultrasound of the right breast revealed skin thickening and tissue densification involving principally the external quadrants, and it was identified an irregular hypoechoic mass with 8 cm \u00d7 5 cm and multiple axillary and supraclavicular enlarged lymph nodes. The ultrasound of left breast and of left axilla was normal.\nOn 1-20, core needle biopsy of an axillary lymph node and of the breast mass identified morphological and immunophenotypic features consistent with diagnosis of primary non-Hodgkin DLBCL.\nA CT scan of the chest on 1-21 confirmed right breast alterations identified in ultrasound and ipsilateral axillary and supraclavicular lymph node enlargement. No other enlarged lymph nodes were observed. CT scans of the brain, abdomen and pelvis were normal. Bone marrow aspiration was negative. Serum lactate dehydrogenase level was normal.\nAfter confirming diagnosis, the therapy plan will include R-CHOP x8 (Rituximab (375 mg/m2, D1), cyclophosphamide (750 mg/m2, D1), doxorubicin (50 mg/m2, D1), vincristine (1.4 mg/m2, D1), prednisone (50 mg twice a day, D1\u2013D5)). She will also receive radiotherapy (4500 cGY) to the breast and regional lymph nodes with 180 cGY daily fractions.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient been radiographically observed to have enlarged ipsilateral or contralateral axillary or supraclavicular mammary nodes?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["A CT scan of the chest on 1-21 confirmed right breast alterations identified in ultrasound and ipsilateral axillary and supraclavicular lymph node enlargement"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the most recent such observation, relative to the date of the note?", "answer": "2019-01-21", "justification": ["A CT scan of the chest on 1-21 confirmed right breast alterations identified in ultrasound and ipsilateral axillary and supraclavicular lymph node enlargement", "Note Date: 2019-1-23"]}]}
{"id": 52, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04871529", "criterion": "Participants must have a bone scan within 56 days prior to registration if they have bone pain or elevated serum alkaline phosphatase.", "note_date": "2019-06-28", "note": "A 59-year-old man had undergone prostate needle biopsy after a high prostate specific antigen (PSA) level (218.5 ng/mL) was observed, and he was diagnosed with adenocarcinoma of the prostate (Gleason score 4\uff0b5). He underwent pelvic magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) and bone scintigraphy at our hospital. The MRI showed the mass in the right peripheral zone as a low signal intensity on the T2-weighted image and as an abnormal signal intensity on the diffusion-weighted image, reflecting prostate cancer. Bone metastases of the right rib and L2 vertebra were clarified. Therefore, clinical stage was T2aN0M1. He was treated with radiation therapy and androgen deprivation therapy (ADT) including bicalutamide and goserelin and his PSA dropped to 0.053 ng/mL.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient had a bone scan?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["He underwent pelvic magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) and bone scintigraphy at our hospital"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the most recent bone scan performed, relative to the note date?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 34, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2019-06-29", "note": "A 48-year-old Hispanic female with no prior medical history, including sexually transmitted infections, presented on 2019-06-18 as a transfer from an outside hospital for higher level of care due to concerns of sepsis possibly secondary to ascending cholangitis versus bile leak. The patient initially presented to the outside hospital with a diagnosis of acute cholecystitis and underwent a laparoscopic cholecystectomy (Figure ). The tissue pathology confirmed evidence of acute cholecystitis. Her post-operative course was complicated by intermittent fever and tachycardia followed by complaints of 5/10 diffuse abdominal pain without abdominal rebound or guarding by day four. She appeared fatigued with minimal scleral icterus. Her laparoscopic wounds showed no signs of active infection. Chest x-ray did not demonstrate acute airspace disease. Hepatobiliary iminodiacetic acid (HIDA) scan demonstrated surgically absent gallbladder, homogenous uptake throughout the liver and no bile leak. CT of the abdomen and pelvis with contrast demonstrated free fluid adjacent to the right hepatic lobe, likely post-operative free fluid, however no abscess, pancreatitis, or hepatic lesions appreciated. She was started initially on piperacillin-tazobactam and metronidazole antibiotics at the outside hospital without clinical improvement, then switched to vancomycin and meropenem once transferred to the intensive care unit (ICU) at our facility.\nOn presentation to our hospital, she was febrile at 39.2\u00b0C. Laboratory studies conducted on 2019-06-19 showed a leukocytosis of 18.4 x 109 white blood cells (WBC)/L, hemoglobin (Hgb) 7 g/dL, platelets 57x109/L, international normalized ratio (INR) 1.1, albumin 2.3 g/dL, alkaline phosphatase (ALP) 229 units/L (upper limit of normal [ULN] 126 units/L), alanine aminotransferase (ALT) 104 units/L (ULN 50 units/L), aspartate aminotransferase (AST) 67 units/L (ULN 36 units/L), and total bilirubin 1.9 mg/dL (ULN 1.3 mg/dL). D-dimer and fibrinogen were elevated at 6.89 mg/L (ULN 0.59 mg/L) and 445 mg/L (ULN 430 mg/L), respectively. Her viral and autoimmune hepatitis panels were negative. She underwent an endoscopic retrograde cholangiopancreatography (ERCP) which did not demonstrate a bile leak, although sludge and gravel were present. Therefore, an 8.5-French 9-cm stent was placed in the distal common bile duct (CBD) and a 4-French 3-cm single pigtail pancreatic stent was placed to protect against pancreatitis (Figure ). Over the next eight days, she continued to have multiple elevated body temperatures of >38\u00b0C, her leukocytosis did not improve and her transaminases remained persistently elevated. Repeat CT of the abdomen and pelvis with contrast showed an improvement of the gallbladder fossa fluid collection (Figure ). Her blood, urine, and sputum cultures remained negative. The patient started to complain of oral pain to which numerous ulcerated lesions are appreciated on her anterior tongue, soft palate, and lower right lip, which were of presumed HSV infection previously not present on admission. Valacyclovir 1g PO every eight hours (q8h) was started for empiric treatment. Her serologies were highly positive for HSV-1 IgG 46.8 (reference range [RR] negative: <0.91 index) and HSV-1/2 IgM ratio 2.59 (RR positive: >1.09 ratio). Confirmatory HSV-1 DNA polymerase chain reaction (PCR) was positive and negative for HSV-2 and HIV. The patient remained afebrile for two days afterward, during which her leukocytosis improved to 7.7 x 109 WBC/L, liver function test improved with ALP 121 units/L, total bilirubin 0.8 mg/dL, and AST and ALT 43 units/L and 39 units/L, respectively. She was discharged from the hospital with a continued course of valacyclovir. Her outpatient follow-up revealed resolution of oral lesions, abdominal symptoms, and abnormal transaminases.", "qa_list": [{"question": "What is this patient's most recent aspartate aminotransferase measurement?", "answer": "67 units/L", "justification": ["aspartate aminotransferase (AST) 67 units/L (ULN 36 units/L)"]}, {"question": "When was this measurement made?", "answer": "2019-06-19", "justification": ["Laboratory studies conducted on 2019-06-19"]}]}
{"id": 81, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03957876", "criterion": "Patients who are postmenopausal for at least 1 year before the screening visit.", "note_date": "2019-07-14", "note": "A 65-yr-old woman, P8L8, all normal vaginal deliveries, who had menopause 11 yrs back presented to us with chief complaints of pain in lower abdomen and postmenopausal white discharge per vaginum since 7\u20138 months. While her blood counts and urine examination were normal, MRI showed enlarged uterus of 16.1x10.4x13.5 cms with isointense endometrial collection of around 14.4x9.4x12.7 cms, approximately 860 cc. Her cervical biopsy revealed well-differentiated squamous cell carcinoma of cervix. Her chest CT scan and echocardiography were normal. Upon obtaining a valid written consent she was scheduled for pyometra drainage and followed by Wertheim\u2019s hysterectomy. Her uterine specimen along with bilateral adnexa, pelvic lymph nodes were sent for histopathological examination. Histopathology report revealed squamous cell carcinoma in situ of cervix with dysplastic epithelium replacing entire endometrial cavity with bilateral reactive lymph nodes.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient reach menopause?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["A 65-yr-old woman", "who had menopause"]}, {"question": "If so, when did menopause start?", "answer": "11 years back", "justification": ["who had menopause 11 yrs back"]}]}
{"id": 94, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2019-08-15", "note": "A 69-year-old female with HPV-related OPC was referred to our hospital in December 2016. She had been diagnosed with HPV type 16-related cervical cancer at age 58 years and was treated with surgery followed by adjuvant chemoradiotherapy. She had had no recurrence. She was neither a smoker nor a drinker. She felt painless cervical lymph nodes on the right side in August 2016 and visited a local otolaryngologist in December 2016. Fiberoptic laryngoscopy revealed a tumor extending from the tonsil to the soft palate on the right. Biopsy of the oropharyngeal lesion confirmed well-differentiated squamous cell carcinoma of the right soft palate. A magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) scan confirmed a primary lesion of approximately 3 cm extending from the right tonsil to the soft palate on the right with bilateral enlarged cervical and retropharyngeal lymph nodes, from levels II to IV and Vb. Their maximum diameter was approximately 2 cm. There was no evidence of extranodal infiltration. Computed tomography (CT) of the chest, abdomen, and pelvis revealed no abnormalities.\n\nShe was staged as clinical T2N2cM0 (stage IVA, AJCC 7th edition 2010, Stage II, AJCC 8th edition 2018, HPV IHC[+], p16/INK4a gene expression [++], type 16 positive and type 18 positive). At the tumor board meeting, it was decided that she should receive cisplatin (CDDP)-based chemoradiotherapy (CRT). Following the placement of percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy (PEG), CRT (intensity-modulated radiation therapy (IMRT) 70 Gy/35 fractions and CDDP 80 mg/m2 for two cycles) were initiated in February 2017. As she developed Grade 3 neutropenia and leukopenia, chemotherapy was delayed, but she was able to complete radiation therapy without radiation interruption. Radiation dermatitis was Grade 2 and mucositis was Grade 3. After the treatment was completed, she required tube feeding via PEG. Following rehabilitation, she could eat orally after two months. She achieved a complete response and has remained alive since then.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Was this patient ever diagnosed with oropharyngeal cancer?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["A 69-year-old female with HPV-related OPC"]}, {"question": "If so, when was that diagnosis made?", "answer": "December 2016", "justification": ["visited a local otolaryngologist in December 2016. Fiberoptic laryngoscopy revealed a tumor extending from the tonsil to the soft palate on the right. Biopsy of the oropharyngeal lesion confirmed well-differentiated squamous cell carcinoma of the right soft palate"]}]}
{"id": 95, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2019-08-15", "note": "A 69-year-old female with HPV-related OPC was referred to our hospital in December 2016. She had been diagnosed with HPV type 16-related cervical cancer at age 58 years and was treated with surgery followed by adjuvant chemoradiotherapy. She had had no recurrence. She was neither a smoker nor a drinker. She felt painless cervical lymph nodes on the right side in August 2016 and visited a local otolaryngologist in December 2016. Fiberoptic laryngoscopy revealed a tumor extending from the tonsil to the soft palate on the right. Biopsy of the oropharyngeal lesion confirmed well-differentiated squamous cell carcinoma of the right soft palate. A magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) scan confirmed a primary lesion of approximately 3 cm extending from the right tonsil to the soft palate on the right with bilateral enlarged cervical and retropharyngeal lymph nodes, from levels II to IV and Vb. Their maximum diameter was approximately 2 cm. There was no evidence of extranodal infiltration. Computed tomography (CT) of the chest, abdomen, and pelvis revealed no abnormalities.\n\nShe was staged as clinical T2N2cM0 (stage IVA, AJCC 7th edition 2010, Stage II, AJCC 8th edition 2018, HPV IHC[+], p16/INK4a gene expression [++], type 16 positive and type 18 positive). At the tumor board meeting, it was decided that she should receive cisplatin (CDDP)-based chemoradiotherapy (CRT). Following the placement of percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy (PEG), CRT (intensity-modulated radiation therapy (IMRT) 70 Gy/35 fractions and CDDP 80 mg/m2 for two cycles) were initiated in February 2017. As she developed Grade 3 neutropenia and leukopenia, chemotherapy was delayed, but she was able to complete radiation therapy without radiation interruption. Radiation dermatitis was Grade 2 and mucositis was Grade 3. After the treatment was completed, she required tube feeding via PEG. Following rehabilitation, she could eat orally after two months. She achieved a complete response and has remained alive since then.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Was this patient ever diagnosed with cervical cancer?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["A 69-year-old female with HPV-related OPC"]}, {"question": "If so, when was that diagnosis made?", "answer": "2008", "justification": ["A 69-year-old female with HPV-related OPC was referred to our hospital in December 2016. She had been diagnosed with HPV type 16-related cervical cancer at age 58 years"]}]}
{"id": 93, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "The primary tumor must be pT1 according to AJCC 8th edition criteria.", "note_date": "2019-08-15", "note": "A 69-year-old female with HPV-related OPC was referred to our hospital in December 2016. She had been diagnosed with HPV type 16-related cervical cancer at age 58 years and was treated with surgery followed by adjuvant chemoradiotherapy. She had had no recurrence. She was neither a smoker nor a drinker. She felt painless cervical lymph nodes on the right side in August 2016 and visited a local otolaryngologist in December 2016. Fiberoptic laryngoscopy revealed a tumor extending from the tonsil to the soft palate on the right. Biopsy of the oropharyngeal lesion confirmed well-differentiated squamous cell carcinoma of the right soft palate. A magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) scan confirmed a primary lesion of approximately 3 cm extending from the right tonsil to the soft palate on the right with bilateral enlarged cervical and retropharyngeal lymph nodes, from levels II to IV and Vb. Their maximum diameter was approximately 2 cm. There was no evidence of extranodal infiltration. Computed tomography (CT) of the chest, abdomen, and pelvis revealed no abnormalities.\n\nShe was staged as clinical T2N2cM0 (stage IVA, AJCC 7th edition 2010, Stage II, AJCC 8th edition 2018, HPV IHC[+], p16/INK4a gene expression [++], type 16 positive and type 18 positive). At the tumor board meeting, it was decided that she should receive cisplatin (CDDP)-based chemoradiotherapy (CRT). Following the placement of percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy (PEG), CRT (intensity-modulated radiation therapy (IMRT) 70 Gy/35 fractions and CDDP 80 mg/m2 for two cycles) were initiated in February 2017. As she developed Grade 3 neutropenia and leukopenia, chemotherapy was delayed, but she was able to complete radiation therapy without radiation interruption. Radiation dermatitis was Grade 2 and mucositis was Grade 3. After the treatment was completed, she required tube feeding via PEG. Following rehabilitation, she could eat orally after two months. She achieved a complete response and has remained alive since then.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Was this patient ever diagnosed with cancer?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Biopsy of the oropharyngeal lesion confirmed well-differentiated squamous cell carcinoma of the right soft palate"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the most recent such diagnosis made, relative to the date of the note?", "answer": "December 2016", "justification": ["visited a local otolaryngologist in December 2016. Fiberoptic laryngoscopy revealed a tumor extending from the tonsil to the soft palate on the right. Biopsy of the oropharyngeal lesion confirmed well-differentiated squamous cell carcinoma of the right soft palate"]}, {"question": "If so, what was the stage of the cancer according to AJCC 8th edition criteria?", "answer": "Stage II", "justification": ["Stage II, AJCC 8th edition 2018"]}, {"question": "If so, how was the cancer stage determined, via imaging or via pathologic evaluation?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 132, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "Non-epithelial breast malignancies such as sarcoma or lymphoma.", "note_date": "2019-08-30", "note": "A 45-year-old female came to Surgery Outpatient Department with a complaint of progressively increasing ulcerated mass in right breast. Informed consent was taken from the patient. There was no family history of breast cancer. In addition, there was no history of breast trauma or any radiation exposure. On examination, there was a large ulcerated mass involving right breast. X-Ray chest and abdominal scan were normal. Her hemoglobin was 7.5 gm/dl. Fine needle aspiration performed was suggestive of carcinoma breast. Further, Modified radical mastectomy (MRM) was performed and the specimen was sent for histopathological examination. Grossly, we received an MRM specimen measuring 24x15x13 cm along with skin flap measuring 14x9x6 cm. The skin surface showed a large grey-white lobulated and ulcerated growth. On serial sectioning, an ill-defined grey-white growth identified measuring approximately 18x15x12 cm that was involving the skin and appeared approximately 0.8 cm away from resected base. The cut section was solid, grey-white along with necrotic and few cystic areas. Totally, 10 lymph nodes were isolated from the specimen. Microscopic examination revealed numerous haphazardly arranged spindle cells with variation in cellular size along with few benign appearing glands entrapped in between. The cells had round to oval hyperchromatic nuclei with inconspicuous nucleoli and moderate amount of eosinophilic cytoplasm. Multinucleated and bizarre forms were also evident. Mitotic count was 4-5/10hpf. Possibility of soft tissue sarcoma was kept. Thorough sampling of the specimen was done to rule out the possibility of cystosarcoma phylloides. Further, immunohistochemical panel was applied including vimentin, cytokeratin (CK), Myogenin, desmin, SMA, S100, CD68, CD34, CD10, ER, PR, and Her2/neu. Vimentin and CD10 were positive in tumor cells; however, CK and ER were positive in benign epithelial cells. CD34 was positive in endothelial cells of vessels. Desmin, Myogenin, SMA, CD68, S100, PR, and Her2/neu were negative. Lymph nodes isolated showed no evidence of metastatic deposits from tumor. A Final diagnosis of primary stromal breast sarcoma was made.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with breast sarcoma ?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["A Final diagnosis of primary stromal breast sarcoma was made"]}, {"question": "If so, what was the date of the diagnosis?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with breast lymphoma?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, what was the date of the diagnosis?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 135, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03957876", "criterion": "The patient is surgically sterile", "note_date": "2019-09-04", "note": "HPI:\n41 y.o female with hx of pancreatic divisum, acute pancreatitis,\npresents with stabbing epigastric pain and pancreatic pseudocyst on CT.\nCT at MGH 2019-9-3:\nLarge complex cystic structure arising from and and replacing\nmuch of the body of the pancreas, likely a large pseudocyst.\n(16cm X 10cm)\nCT at OSH 2019-8-17:\nFindings consistent with acute pancreatitis with free fluid\nwithin abdomen and pelvis. There is no evidence of abscess or\nfocal fluid collection.\nRUQ U/S: CBD 4mm no stones no cholecystitis\nChief complaint:\nSOB- CP\nPMHx:\nPMH:\npancreas divisum, one episode of pancreatitis 3-4 years ago;\nhysterectomy, duodenal ulcer, tonsillectomy, hypertension,\nhyperlipidemia, hypothyroidism\nPSH: Transvaginal hysterectomy, appendectomy, Tonsillectomy and\nAdenoidectomy, Colonoscopy in 2018-7-8 with polypectomy\nPain control (acute pain, chronic pain)\nAssessment:\nAction:\nResponse:\nPlan:\nPancreatic pseudocyst\nAssessment:\nAction:\nResponse:\nPlan:\nHyperglycemia\nAssessment:\nAction:\nResponse:\nPlan:", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient undergone a surgical sterilization procedure?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["PSH: Transvaginal hysterectomy"]}, {"question": "If so, when?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 133, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "Paget's disease of the nipple.", "note_date": "2019-10-30", "note": "A 39 year old lady was referred to our breast unit on February 2019 with a one week history of a lump in the lateral aspect of the right breast. On examination, a generalized hardness was felt in the right breast together with central retraction of the nipple. Mammography revealed malignant microcalcification affecting the whole breast with core biopsy proving high grade ductal carcinoma in situ (DCIS). Following discussion at the multi disciplinary meeting, she underwent a mastectomy and axillary sampling together with an immediate latissimus dorsi (LD) reconstruction flap. Post-operative recovery was unremarkable and the cosmetic result was good. Histology of the breast revealed 120 mm of high grade DCIS of mixed comedo and solid type. Two separate foci of invasive ductal carcinoma (Grade 1 and Grade 2) were identified. The margins were clear of tumour by 1.3 mm (in-situ disease) and 5.8 mm (invasive component). No evidence of Paget's disease was documented at this time. The axillary sample was negative for tumour. As the tumour demonstrated strong Estrogen/Progesterone positivity, Mrs K.S was started on postoperative Tamoxifen treatment on 2019-03-02 but this was discontinued within 6 months due to adverse side effects. On her second post-operative visit, a small erythematous skin lesion was noted on the superio-medial aspect of the flap adjacent to the scar. A punch biopsy was obtained which revealed foci of atypical cells within the epidermis with Pagetoid spread. Immunostaining showed positivity for CAM 5.2, CEA and EMA, consistent with. Paget's disease. A wide local excision of the lesion was performed and the specimen was sent for a histological second opinion. This showed acanthosis, hyperkeratosis with focal parakeratosis and extensive replacement of the epidermis by pleomorphic epithelial cells with marked pagetoid pattern. Tumour cells extended into adjacent hair follicles and immunohistochemistry on 10/19 confirmed features of Paget's disease . The differential diagnosis was between that of Paget's disease of the breast (although there was no underlying breast tissue or nipple and it was not seen in the original mastectomy specimen) and extra-mammary Paget's disease of the skin. Because of the past history of breast carcinoma, a diagnosis of Paget's disease of the breast was made.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with Paget\u2019s disease of the nipple ?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["a diagnosis of Paget's disease of the breast was made"]}, {"question": "If so, what was the date of the diagnosis?", "answer": "October 2019", "justification": ["immunohistochemistry on 10/19 confirmed features of Paget's disease"]}]}
{"id": 35, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2019-11-01", "note": "A 67-year-old man presented to our hospital on 2019-10-25 with a primary complaint of subcutaneous bleeding in his left thigh and development of purpura, over the last 3 months. It had been pointed out to him that there was a mild anaemia with haemoglobin level of 10.4 g/dL. He had been diagnosed two years previously with myelodysplastic syndromes with multilineage dysplasia (MDS-MLD) considered in the context of the 2016 World Health Organization (WHO) classification criteria. The 46, XY, i(14) (q10) abnormality was detected in 100% of marrow metaphases (). The bone marrow blast was 3.3%. He was categorized as low risk in Revised International Prognostic Scoring System (IPSS-R), and he had not received cytokine therapy or blood transfusion. He had a medical history of hypertension, type 2 diabetes mellitus, spinal canal stenosis, and idiopathic osteonecrosis of the femoral head and underwent right total hip arthroplasty (r-THA).\nPhysical examination showed conjunctival pallor and a swelling on the left thigh with overlying bruising (). Computed tomography revealed a large bleed in the left quadriceps femoris muscle (). Laboratory data showed the following: white blood cell count, 13.6 \u00d7 109/L (normal range 3.5\u20139.7 \u00d7 109/L); monocyte count, 4.6 \u00d7 109/L (monocyte percentage, 33.6%); haemoglobin level, 8.8 g/dL (13.2\u201317.2 g/dL); haematocrit, 28.1% (40\u201352%); and platelet count, 258 \u00d7 109/L (140\u2013370 \u00d7 109/L) (). On review, the monocyte count on three months previously too had been elevated (3.0 \u00d7 109/L). Activated partial thromboplastin time (APTT) was significantly prolonged (85.8 s, normal range 24\u201339 s). Prothrombin time was within the normal range (10.5\u201314 s). Mixing studies demonstrated that the prolongation of APTT was not corrected by the addition of an equal volume of pooled normal plasma either instantaneously or over two hours of incubation, indicating the presence of an inhibitor. When coagulation factors of the intrinsic pathway were measured, FVIII activity was less than 1% (normal range 60\u2013150%), and coagulation factors IX, XI, and XII were also found to be reduced. Further tests did not detect lupus anticoagulant antibody. The inhibitor for FVIII was quantified using the Bethesda method and showed a high level of 166 BU/mL, but there was no inhibitory activity against factor IX inhibitor (). Since the patient's coagulation profile had previously been normal, the current results indicated that he had developed acquired haemophilia A (AHA).", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient been diagnosed with MDS or MDS/MPN according to 2016 WHO criteria?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["He had been diagnosed two years previously with myelodysplastic syndromes with multilineage dysplasia (MDS-MLD) considered in the context of the 2016 World Health Organization (WHO) classification criteria"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the diagnosis made?", "answer": "two years previously", "justification": ["He had been diagnosed two years previously"]}]}
{"id": 36, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2019-11-01", "note": "The patient is a 70-year-old woman who presented with progressive thrombocytopenia that has been present for 8 years, and monocytosis in June 2017. The bone marrow biopsy performed at that time showed a MDS with multilineage dysplasia according to the 2016 WHO classification, with a bone marrow blast count percentage totaled <5%. Cytogenetics revealed a translocation. Therefore the patient falls within the intermediate 1 risk group, according to IPSS. She was started on danazole 400 mg/day which was eventually increased to 600 mg/day, with a low response in platelets count (30\u201340,000/mmc). The treatment was well tolerated, and no major bleeding was observed. After two years on therapy, she again developed worsening thrombocytopenia (10,000/mmc). Repeat bone marrow evaluation revealed MDS with excess blasts type 1 (MDS-EB 1). She was subsequently treated with 5-azacitidine at a dose 75 mg (sqm)/day x 7 days monthly for 15 cycles, for which she achieved a complete hematological response after 4 cycles. The treatment was discontinued in October 2019 for hematological toxicity and evolution of the disease to MDS-EB type 2 (IPSS intermediate 2).", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient been diagnosed with MDS or MDS/MPN according to 2016 WHO criteria?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["The bone marrow biopsy performed at that time showed a MDS with multilineage dysplasia according to the 2016 WHO classification"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the diagnosis made?", "answer": "June 2017", "justification": ["in June 2017", "The bone marrow biopsy performed at that time showed a MDS"]}]}
{"id": 48, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2019-11-01", "note": "The patient is a 70-year-old woman who presented with progressive thrombocytopenia that has been present for 8 years, and monocytosis in June 2017. The bone marrow biopsy performed at that time showed a MDS with multilineage dysplasia according to the 2016 WHO classification, with a bone marrow blast count percentage totaled <5%. Cytogenetics revealed a translocation. Therefore the patient falls within the intermediate 1 risk group, according to IPSS. She was started on danazole 400 mg/day which was eventually increased to 600 mg/day, with a low response in platelets count (30\u201340,000/mmc). The treatment was well tolerated, and no major bleeding was observed. After two years on therapy, she again developed worsening thrombocytopenia (10,000/mmc). Repeat bone marrow evaluation revealed MDS with excess blasts type 1 (MDS-EB 1). She was subsequently treated with 5-azacitidine at a dose 75 mg (sqm)/day x 7 days monthly for 15 cycles, for which she achieved a complete hematological response after 4 cycles. The treatment was discontinued in October 2019 for hematological toxicity and evolution of the disease to MDS-EB type 2 (IPSS intermediate 2).", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient been treated with a nucleoside metabolic inhibitor?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["She was subsequently treated with 5-azacitidine"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the most recent such treatment, relative to the note date?", "answer": "October 2019", "justification": ["The treatment was discontinued in October 2019"]}]}
{"id": 2, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-01-06", "note": "A 63-year-old male presented to us with a complaint of diminution of vision in the right eye (OD) for 2 days. He gave a history of facing complication during the cataract surgery elsewhere of OD 2 days back. His visual acuity at the time of presentation was 20/20 in the left eye (OS) and counting finger at 1-m OD. On slit-lamp examination of OD, there was presence of anterior chamber cell (AC) 2+, AC flare 2+, cortical lens matter in AC, intraocular lens in the sulcus, posterior capsular rupture, and intraocular pressure (IOP) of 21 mmHg. OD fundus could not be examined due to the cortical lens matter obstructing the view. OS anterior segment examination was unremarkable, retina on, and disc pink and vertical cup\u2013disc ratio of 0.5 with IOP of 18 mmHg. Ultrasound B-scan OD showed the presence of echoes in the vitreous cavity and over the posterior pole suggestive of lens matter in the vitreous cavity. The patient was then posted for 23-gauge pars plana vitrectomy. To achieve dilatation of the pupil, tropicamide 1% and phenylephrine 10% eye drops were used. Peribulbar anesthesia with 4 mL lignocaine hydrochloride 2% with adrenaline 1 in 200,000 and hyaluronidase 500 IU was administered by an experienced anesthetist. Anesthesia was satisfactory, and uneventful 23-gauge core vitrectomy was performed with removal of cortical lens matter from vitreous cavity. OD retina was on, and the disc was pink. Immediate postoperative recovery was uneventful. Six hours postsurgery, he reported with complaints of pain and swelling of the right eye. OD examination showed noticeable chemosis, periorbital swelling, redness, tenderness of eyelids, axial proptosis, and a tense orbit []. There was no perception of light OD. The pupil was dilated with sluggish reaction to light and marked restriction of extraocular movement OD. The visual axis was clear with hyperemic disc, and IOP was elevated to 22 mmHg. OS examination showed mild lid edema with unremarkable anterior and posterior segment examination. Systemic symptoms were absent. On further questioning, he gave a history of a similar episode in OS and OD at the time of cataract surgery done previously under peribulbar anesthesia (lignocaine 2% with adrenaline 1 in 200,000). Complete blood count, erythrocyte sedimentation rate, blood glucose levels, electrolyte levels, serum homocysteine, and angiotensin-converting enzyme levels were normal. Venereal disease research laboratory test (VDRL) was nonreactive. Antinuclear antibodies, antiphospholipid antibodies, and blood cultures were negative. Magnetic resonance imaging scan of the brain and orbit was remarkable. Hence, a differential diagnosis of lignocaine hypersensitivity (on the Naranjo's causality assessment scale, the adverse event was 8 indicating a \u201cprobable\u201d reaction to lignocaine) or orbital infection or hemorrhage was made. He was started on intravenous (IV) methylprednisolone 1gm/day, IV amoxicillin, and clavulanic acid 1.2g 2 times/day for 3 days. Over the next 3 days, the ocular condition improved and the IV medications were changed to oral medications []. After 1 week, there was a resolution of proptosis, ocular motility was not restricted, but his visual acuity in OD remained at counting finger at 1 m with relative afferent pupillary defect (RAPD) positive. He was discharged and put on topical brimonidine tartrate 0.2%, timolol maleate 0.25%, prednisolone acetate 1%, and also referred for allergological tests. Subcutaneous injection of lignocaine showed an erythematous reaction at the test site which resolved within 2 h. The rechallenge test with hyaluronidase did not show any erythematous reaction. Two months later, his visual acuity was counting finger at 3 m, RAPD was positive [], IOP was 18 mmHg, fundus examination showed the presence of optic atrophy [Figure and ], visual field analysis showed field loss in three quadrants [Figure and ], and visual evoked potential showed reduced amplitude [] OD. The sequence of events is depicted in .", "qa_list": [{"question": "Can we conclude that this patient is hypersensitive to lignocaine?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["a differential diagnosis of lignocaine hypersensitivity (on the Naranjo's causality assessment scale, the adverse event was 8 indicating a \u201cprobable\u201d reaction to lignocaine) or orbital infection or hemorrhage was made", "Subcutaneous injection of lignocaine showed an erythematous reaction at the test site which resolved within 2 h. The rechallenge test with hyaluronidase did not show any erythematous reaction"]}]}
{"id": 11, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-01-19", "note": "Past Medical History:\n-Afib dx 1 month ago-declined coumadin because of frequent blood draws\n-HTN (not well controlled per daughter)\n-CABG stent x5 (20 y ago)\n-CAD\npatient had 3 stents placed. One stent was placed in 2017 and\nanother stent was placed in 2020\n-breast mass diagnosed in 2022-7-10\n2022-8-10 - breast cancer was resected (lumpectomy) with\nnegative, clear margins\nNo chemo or radiation\n-Bilateral CEA", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient had a lumpectomy?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["breast cancer was resected (lumpectomy)"]}, {"question": "If so, are the margins of the resected specimen or re-excision histologically free of invasive tumor and DCIS?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["with negative, clear margins"]}]}
{"id": 3, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-01-21", "note": "In 2016, a 53-year-old nulligravida woman presented to the Department of Maternal, Infant and Urological Sciences of Policlinico Umberto I (Sapienza University) in Rome for recurrent, advanced ovarian cancer with breast metastasis. Her clinical history started in October 2014 when she underwent primary cytoreductive surgery (total hysterectomy, bilateral salpingo-oophorectomy, omentectomy, pelvic and lomboaortic lymphadenectomy) for high-grade (G3), BRCA wild-type, serous EOC. From November 2014 to March 2015, she received 6 cycles of carboplatin (AUC5) and paclitaxel (175 mg/m2) i.v. every 21 days. Bevacizumab (15 mg/m2) was added during the last 2 cycles and then continued as maintenance therapy for 12 months up to April 2016. Regularly scheduled follow-ups were negative until September 2016 when a total-body computed tomography (CT) scan revealed intraperitoneal spread (carcinosis), left axillary lymphadenopathy and a 3-cm-sized left breast mass in the upper outer quadrant. The patient had no family history of breast cancer and no history of previous breast pathology. The axillary lymph node and breast biopsies confirmed the diagnosis of recurrent, metastatic serous ovarian cancer, with a platinum-free interval of 18 months. The patient did not undergo any breast surgical treatment. From November 2016 to May 2017, she was submitted to 8 cycles of second-line chemotherapy with gemcitabine plus cisplatin (switched from carboplatin from the third cycle because of a hypersensitivity reaction with maculopapular erythematous rush over the neck and trunk). As the post-treatment imaging (positron emission tomography, PET/CT) showed persistence of breast disease, the patient underwent radiation therapy to the left axillary region (50 Gy in 25 fractions) from August to September 2017. In November 2017, a new palpable breast lump appeared in the left breast and an additional biopsy was performed with the same histopathological results. Although an additional breast radiation treatment with a total dose of 35 Gy was performed, a disease progression to homolateral supraclavicular and internal mammary lymph nodes was reported; thus the patient underwent a third-line chemotherapy with 2 cycles of liposomal doxorubicin (30 mg/m2) from March to May 2018. The revaluation with PET/CT scan showed contralateral axillary lymphadenopathy and both neck and mediastinum involvement. Moreover, signs and symptoms of inflammatory and lymphangitic breast cancer appeared, including bilateral edema, erythema and peau d'orange (Fig. ). From June to August 2018, a further line of chemotherapy consisting of 3 cycles of weekly topotecan was administered, again without any clinical benefit. Therefore, in October 2018, the patient was enrolled in the clinical trial BAROCCO [], and she was randomized in the experimental arm with olaparib (300 mg twice daily, 7 days per week) plus cediranib (20 mg daily, 5 days per week). Even if the patient reported some clinical benefits, the total-body CT scan performed after 4 months of treatment revealed progression of disease and the patient abandoned the clinical trial. Our last attempt was to administer weekly paclitaxel (80 mg/m2) and then weekly cisplatin (20 mg/m2). Unfortunately, in September 2019, the patient's general conditions appeared to be significantly compromised and she was referred to palliative care and hormonal therapy with letrozole, before dying a month later (5 years after ovarian cancer diagnosis and 3 years after the diagnosis of the breast metastasis).", "qa_list": [{"question": "Can we conclude that this patient is hypersensitive to carboplatin?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["switched from carboplatin from the third cycle because of a hypersensitivity reaction with maculopapular erythematous rush over the neck and trunk"]}]}
{"id": 19, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-01-29", "note": "A.P.A., a 16-year-old female student born and residing in Jaragu\u00e1 do Sul, SC, Brazil, arrived at the emergency unit after suffering from dry cough and dyspnea for four days, along with hematemesis and bloody diarrhea. She said she had been diagnosed with polycystic kidney disease as a child and that a pediatric nephrologist was treating her. The patient also mentioned that she had been referred for a kidney transplant on account of chronic kidney disease and that she was being treated for systemic hypertension and anemia secondary to renal impairment. Physical examination revealed she was pale, rational, attentive, responsive, and oriented. Her blood pressure (BP) was 140x70 mmHg. Lung auscultation showed she had vesicular breath sounds and basilar crackles on her right lung. Heart auscultation showed a regular rhythm with two sounds and no murmur. She had tachycardia (140 beats per minute), tachypnea (respiratory rate [RR] 20 breaths per minute), a painless abdomen with a palpable spleen, and no edema on her legs. Tests performed three months prior to admission showed her hemoglobin and creatinine levels had been at 8.0 g/dL and 2.5 mg/dL, respectively (creatinine clearance 32.21 mL/min estimated by the Cockroft-Gault formula). Tests performed on admission read as follows: hemoglobin 5.8 g/dL; hematocrit 15.9%; leukocytes 22,500 without a left shift; platelets 122,000; creatinine 5.39 mg/dL (creatinine clearance 14.94 mL/min); urea 158 mg/dL; C-reactive protein 81.8 U/L; serum sodium 141 mEq/L; and serum potassium 3.9 mEq/L. Chest X-ray findings were consistent with consolidation of the right upper lobe and lung infiltration on the left middle and lower zones. She was started on ceftriaxone, hydration, and received two bags of packed red blood cells. Her respiratory pattern deteriorated on the first day of hospitalization. She became more tachypneic (RR: 36 breaths per minute) and presented stertor bilaterally down to the middle zone of her lungs, coffee ground vomitus, and early-stage edema in her lower limbs (2+/4+). She was referred to the ICU and was prescribed clarithromycin, oseltamivir, pantoprazole, and was placed on noninvasive ventilation. Point-of-care ultrasound examination showed B-lines in all lung areas bilaterally, no pleural effusion, and a fixed dilated inferior vena cava with no variation on ventilation. Her echocardiogram showed a left ventricle on the parasternal short axis with good contractility and no significant pericardial effusion on subjective evaluation. She stayed in the ICU for eight days with episodes of melena and hematemesis.", "qa_list": [{"question": "What is the creatinine clearance of this patient according to the Cockroft-Gault equation?", "answer": "32.21 mL/min", "justification": ["creatinine clearance 32.21 mL/min estimated by the Cockroft-Gault formula"]}, {"question": "When was that result obtained?", "answer": "2020-01-29", "justification": ["2020-01-29"]}]}
{"id": 7, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-02-05", "note": "A 68-year-old Japanese postmenopausal woman developed brown vaginal discharge after radical cystectomy for bladder cancer, which was histologically diagnosed as high-grade UC invading up to the superficial muscularis propria without metastasis (pT2a pN0 cM0 [Union for International Cancer Control, 8th edition]) concomitant with focal urothelial carcinoma in situ in the urethra. She had a history of left renal pelvis UC, which was surgically removed after repeated 80-mg/fraction Bacillus Calmette-Gu\u00e9rin injections via a single J stent, resulting in no residual carcinoma 9 months before the radical cystectomy. She was also treated for breast cancer at 47 years of age without postoperative recurrence. Gynecologic examination of the lower genital tract, including the periurethral region, was unremarkable; however, cervical screening cytology demonstrated severely atypical cells suspicious for adenocarcinoma (Fig. a-c). Cervical colposcopy and diagnostic conization revealed no cervical neoplasm. Eleven months post-cystectomy, punch biopsy of the vulva and vagina confirmed intraepithelial UC in the juxtaposed squamous epithelium with pagetoid spread (Fig. a-c). Concurrent invasive malignancy was ruled out, and CO2 laser vaporization of the vulvar and vaginal lesion was performed. The patient remained alive without evidence of invasive malignancy for 14 months after the radical cystectomy for bladder cancer. The CINtec\u00ae PLUS cytology test (Roche Diagnostics, Basel, Switzerland), an immunocytochemical p16/Ki-67 dual staining kit for screening of cervical disease, was negative for p16 labeling (Fig. d). Immunocytochemistry revealed neoplastic cells positive for cytokeratin (CK) 7, CK20, p63, and GATA3 (Fig. e-h). Immunohistochemical examination of the biopsy sample of the vulva and vagina revealed neoplastic cells positive for uroplakin III, thrombomodulin, and uroplakin II (Fig. d-f) but negative for carcinoembryonic antigen (CEA), gross cystic disease fluid protein 15 (GCDFP15), and S100. No high-risk human papillomavirus (HPV) genotype was identified by an automated DNA chip system (Clinichip\u2122 HPV test; Sekisui Medical, Tokyo, Japan) using LBC samples.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Can we conclude that the patient has bladder cancer now?", "answer": "No", "justification": ["the patient had cancer before her radical cystectomy"]}, {"question": "If so, what is the cancer's stage?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 4, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-02-10", "note": "A 55-year-old woman complained of right knee pain off and on for years. The pain was located mainly over the lateral knee and was noted when she bore weight on her right lower limb, such as standing up from bed in the morning, standing for more than 30 minutes for housework, walking, and stair climbing. There was occasional right knee swelling if she walked for a long distance. No resting pain or nocturnal pain was complained. Osteoarthritis of the right knee joint (Kellgren and Lawrence classification grade III) was diagnosed at another clinic. The pain worsened three months before her visit, and she failed to improve with the conservative treatment, including three courses of physical therapy with physical modality and exercise, and acupuncture three times weekly for two months. The visual analog scale (VAS) was 7-8/10 and the Western Ontario and McMaster Universities Arthritis Index (WOMAC) scores were 16/20 for pain, 4/8 for stiffness, 51/68 for physical disability. On physical examination, she had an antalgic gait and a slight reduction of range of motion of the right knee compared to the left (right 5-110 degrees and left 0-120 degrees). There was severe tenderness (VAS 7-8/10) over the lateral part of the tibial plateau, which in fact reproduced the patient\u2019s usual pain when she stepped down on the floor each morning. McMurray test was positive over both the medial and lateral menisci. The US examination revealed signs of lateral and medial meniscus tears with marginal osteophytes and a cortical break over the lateral tibial plateau close to the Gerdy\u2019s tubercle (Figure ). The MRI revealed a general osteoarthritic change and tears of the lateral and medial menisci, and there was a subchondral BML over the lateral tibial plateau (Figure ). After a discussion about the treatment, the patient opted for regenerative injection therapy. We performed a US-assisted intraosseous injection of PRP (Smart Prep II; Harvest Technologies, Belton, TX, USA; 60ml whole blood to 6ml PRP) at the subchondral BML of the lateral tibial plateau by placing a 21-gauge, 1.5-inch needle through the cortical break close to the Gerdy\u2019s tubercle (Figure , Video ). After evaluating the orientation of the opening of the cortical break, the needle was inserted into the apex of the hole and further advanced deeper to the subchondral bone. The contrast (Ominpaque 350) was then injected under fluoroscopy to confirm the needle placement and evaluate the contrast spread (Figure ). The contrast reached the location of the subchondral bone marrow lesion at the lateral tibial plateau and the injection did reproduce the patient\u2019s usual knee pain on weight-bearing. PRP injection (3ml) was then offered to the same region and the displacement of the contrast was observed under fluoroscopy. The patient was kept to have non-weight-bearing to her right knee for two days and when she was allowed to have full-weight bearing walking on the third day, she reported VAS 3/10. Three weeks later, the patient reported significant improvement of her pain with VAS 0-2/10. She could walk 1.5 to two hours over level ground and stand more than 1.5 hours without pain. The WOMAC scores were 4/20 for pain, 0/8 for stiffness, 12/68 for physical disability. The MRI six months after the treatment revealed resolution of the subchondral BML (Figure ).", "qa_list": [{"question": "Does the patient have a knee osteoarthritis Kellgren-Lawrence grade of 3?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Osteoarthritis of the right knee joint (Kellgren and Lawrence classification grade III) was diagnosed"]}]}
{"id": 28, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-02-15", "note": "A 51-year-old male with a history of well-controlled HIV infection on anti-retroviral treatment presented to the rheumatology clinic for the evaluation of a two-month history of symmetric polyarthritis involving bilateral knees, ankles, and feet. The joint was aching, and the pain was present at rest and with activity. The pain is associated with joint swelling and morning stiffness lasting approximately one hour. He was previously treated with a two-week course of prednisone 20 mg daily without any improvement of his symptoms. The patient was diagnosed with HIV at the age of 33 and has been on ART regimen, including efavirenz 600 mg, emtricitabine 200 mg, and tenofovir 300 mg. His most recent CD4 count from December 2019 was 382 with an undetectable HIV viral load.\nThe patient's vital signs were within normal limits. The physical examination was remarkable for tenderness to palpation in his feet and knees. There was ankle synovitis with moderate effusion, limiting the range of motion. Cervical lymph nodes were enlarged, mobile, and non-tender. There was no other lymphadenopathy or hepatosplenomegaly on examination.\nRadiographs of both knees revealed bilateral large suprapatellar effusions. Left knee arthrocentesis was performed and demonstrated a white blood count of 27,900 cells/mm3 (0-200 cells/mm3) with no crystals. Erythrocyte sedimentation rate and C-reactive protein were elevated at 54 mm/hr and 122 mg/L, respectively. Other studies, including synovial fluid gram stain, cultures, antinuclear antibody, rheumatoid factor (RF), cyclic citrullinated peptide antibody, and rapid plasma reagin were all negative. The patient\u2019s symptoms did not improve with a trial of a higher dose of prednisone - 40 mg daily and intramuscular triamcinolone injection. The addition of sulfasalazine and methotrexate did not provide any relief to the patient\u2019s symptoms. He developed progressive swelling of his cervical lymph nodes, decreased appetite, nausea, and recurrent emesis. The patient lost approximately 12 kg (26 lb) over the period of three months. On initial evaluation, the calcium level was normal but eight weeks later, his calcium level increased to 13 mg/dl. Computed tomography revealed extensive lymphadenopathy involving the cervical lymph nodes (Figure ).\nImaging studies also demonstrated further lymphadenopathy in the mediastinum, abdomen, and pelvis with the largest measuring 9.5 x 15 cm, as well as splenomegaly (Figures -). There was no evidence of any bony lytic or sclerotic lesions. The patient gradually developed an altered mental status, requiring hospital admission. Initial admission laboratory studies were significant for a calcium level of 19.3 mg/dL, creatinine of 2.04 mg/dL, and uric acid level of 17.6 mg/dL.\nThe patient\u2019s overall clinical presentation was consistent with tumor lysis syndrome from hematologic malignancy. He was treated in the intensive care unit for severe hypercalcemia and he received intravascular fluids, zoledronic acid, and calcitonin. This resulted in an improvement in renal function and hypercalcemia.\nWorkup for the hypercalcemia showed an elevated parathyroid-hormone-related peptide level of 6.1 pmol/ml (normal level < 2.5), low parathyroid hormone at the level of 6.4 pg/ml (normal 10-65), and normal levels of 1,25-hydroxyvitamin D and 25-hydroxyvitamin D, supporting a paraneoplastic etiology for the hypercalcemia. A right submandibular lymph node biopsy was performed that yielded the effacement of the lymphoid architecture by a diffuse sheet-like proliferation of large lymphoid cells that had enlarged irregular nuclei with vesicular chromatin and prominent nucleoli (Figure ).\nImmunoperoxidase stains showed that the neoplastic cells were strongly and diffusely positive for CD20, CD79A, BCL2, and LCA and negative for CD10, BCL-6, CD5, and cyclin D1. These findings were consistent with diffuse large B-cell lymphoma (DLBCL). Bone marrow biopsy and cerebrospinal fluid cytology excluded bone marrow and central nervous system involvement. Based on these results, our patient was diagnosed with HIV-associated diffuse large B cell lymphoma (DLBCL).", "qa_list": [{"question": "Is this patient on effective anti-retroviral therapy for HIV?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["The patient was diagnosed with HIV at the age of 33 and has been on ART regimen, including efavirenz 600 mg, emtricitabine 200 mg, and tenofovir 300 mg"]}, {"question": "If so, has the patient had an undetectable HIV viral load recently?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["His most recent CD4 count from December 2019 was 382 with an undetectable HIV viral load"]}, {"question": "If so, how recent was the diagnosis of an undetectable HIV viral load?", "answer": "December 2019", "justification": ["His most recent CD4 count from December 2019 was 382 with an undetectable HIV viral load"]}]}
{"id": 30, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-02-25", "note": "The patient is a 21-year-old male without significant medical history. He was admitted in the emergency department for cephalalgia, fever, and frequent easy vomiting lasting 1 week duration. Symptoms were associated to a puffiness of the face and dyspnea of level I according to Sadoul classification. At admission, the patient was conscious with a fever of 39\u00b0C. The blood pressure was 120/70 mmHg with a heart rate of 80 beats/min and a respiratory frequency of 24 cycles/min. The neurological examination objectified signs of meningeal irritation without any motor and sensory deficit. The pleuropulmonary examination found subcutaneous emphysema in the top part of the thorax and upper limbs extending to the cervical region and the face. Associated air effusion syndrome was not evidenced. The initial cerebral computed tomography (CT) scan was normal. Afterward, a lumbar puncture was performed and revealed a blurred liquid with predominant polynuclear neutrophils (80%). The glycorrhachia was 0.40 g/l (with concomitant glycemia of 1.20 g/l); total albumin level was 0.98 g/l, and the classical cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) gram\u2019s stain and culture was negative. The immunochemistry study of lumbar puncture was in favor of meningitis diagnosis, which oriented to start the antibiotherapy. The routine biological and hematological studies included blood cells count and blood culture, ionogram, and sedimentation rate were found to be normal. The hepatic assessment was also without abnormalities. The diagnosis of bacterial meningitis was retained. The patient was treated using adequate antibiotherapy consisting of 2.0 g of ceftriaxone every 12 h. Ceftriaxone dose was maintained at the meningitis rate of 100 mg/kg/day. The thorax X-ray showed a pneumomediastinum in the left paratracheal border along the left edge of the heart; the image also showed subcutaneous emphysema without associated pneumothorax []. Evermore, thorax CT scan confirmed all abnormalities described in the thorax X-ray and revealed the presence of air collection in the spinal canal between C7 and D6 levels []. The laryngoscopy, bronchoscopy, and digestive opacification did not show any abnormality in the respiratory-digestive tracts. These invasive gestures were achieved under general anesthesia without remarkable event. The clinical evolution within 48 h was marked by the occurrence of apyrexia, coupled with disappearance of the subcutaneous emphysema and the meningeal steepness. However, the neurological status of the patient worsened gradually; a paraparesis occurred and was followed by a tetraparesis. The patient started with presenting neurovegetative disorders with hemodynamic instability which was in favor of central affection. The sepsis was discarded since the patient was afebrile. The patient experienced acute respiratory syndrome that required artificial ventilation. Afterward, a spinal magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) was performed and showed a cervical medullary edema extending from C2 to C6 without any sign of spinal cord compression. This result was consistent with a general clinical profile of acute transverse myelitis []. The hemodynamic support consisted initially of administrating vasoactive Drugs and dopamine then adrenaline since nor adrenaline was not available. The patient died within 15 days with a profile of vasoparalysis resistant to vasoactive drugs.", "qa_list": [{"question": "does this patient have imminent or established spinal cord compression?", "answer": "No", "justification": ["Afterward, a spinal magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) was performed and showed a cervical medullary edema extending from C2 to C6 without any sign of spinal cord compression"]}]}
{"id": 9, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-03-28", "note": "A Gleason score of 3 + 3 prostatic adenocarcinoma was detected at 12-quadrant transrectal ultrasound (TRUS)-guided prostate biopsy performed after determination of a serum prostate specific antigen value of 8.1 ng/mL in a 65-year-old man presenting with lower urinary tract symptoms. Prostate volume was calculated at 202 g at TRUS. No lymph node of pathologic size was determined at multiparametric prostate MRI. During RALRP, a 2/0 Vicryl suture was applied on the median lobe for traction to supply a better view for bladder neck and exposure of the large median lobe. We subsequently observed an injury of the left ureter orifice occurred during dissection with monopolar scissors. At inspection, the right ureter orifice was natural in appearance, whereas the left orifice had lost its natural appearance in association with a laceration. However, peristalsis and urinary flow from the area thought to be the left ureter orifice were observed. Online video call was made with experienced colleagues who were in another city (A.F.A. and A.E.C.) and the surgical fields on the screen were presented to them to get advice. Owing to their suggestion, two 4.7F 28 cm Double-J stents were inserted through the assistant port into the abdomen and installed in the both ureteral orifices, and RALRP was completed. The second orifice was also stented to prevent injury. Postoperative prostate weight was measured as 202 g. Estimated blood loss was 250 mL. During control ultrasonography (USG) performed on postoperative day 1, the bilateral kidneys were normal, and no hydronephrosis was observed. Postoperative follow-up was uneventful and the patient was discharged on day 7. Cystography was performed on day 21 that showed no leakage and urethral catheter was removed. Control USG was performed periodically during hospitalization and no hydronephrosis was observed. The pathology report was pT2a with negative surgical margins. The Double-J stents were removed with the assistance of a flexible endoscope on the second month. The ureter orifices remained behind the neck of the bladder with normal appearance.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Does the patient have prostatic adenocarcinoma?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["A Gleason score of 3 + 3 prostatic adenocarcinoma was detected"]}, {"question": "If so, what stage is the cancer?", "answer": "pT2a", "justification": ["The pathology report was pT2a"]}]}
{"id": 99, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "Oncotype DX Recurrence Score of less than or equal to 18 on diagnostic core biopsy or resected specimen.", "note_date": "2020-04-03", "note": "At the end of February 2020, a 49-year-old nonsmoking female patient with no comorbidity and unfamiliar with oncological diseases, underwent a screening mammography x-ray that showed the presence of a nodule of about 2 cm against the external quadrant of the right breast, which was suspected for heteroplasia in the absence of further suspect nodules and/or lymph nodes. The patient was then subjected to an ultrasound examination, which confirmed the presence of a lump with malignant characteristics, and was therefore subjected to true-cut of the breast lump with histological examination positive for invasive ductal carcinoma of the breast.\nIn late March 2020, the patient underwent a quadrantectomy of the right breast with removal of 2 cm neoplastic nodule and three ipsilateral sentinel lymph nodes. The microscopic examination was positive for moderately differentiated invasive ductal carcinoma containing osteoclast-like giant cells (OGCs). According to immunohistochemical analysis, the tumor had the following characteristics: ER: + 100%, PR: + 85%, E-cadherin: positive, Ki67: + 10% and HER2: negative, with a staging category corresponding to pT1c pN0, according to the TNM staging system.\nImmunohistochemically, OGCs are positive for the histiocytic marker CD68 and negative for E-cadherin, an epithelial marker, and for ER, PR and HER2. In addition, they are CD163 positive.\nOn the other hand, cancer cells are negative for CD68 and CD163 for the HER2 but are positive for cadherin E, estrogen receptor (ER: 100%) and progesterone receptor (PR: 85%).\nClinical\u2013instrumental staging tests (blood chemistry tests with tumor markers, abdomen ultrasound, chest CT without bone and bone scan) were negative for distant neoplastic disease.\nFor the negative HER2 hormone-responsive disease, various analysis tests of gene profiles are available and are useful in determining the risk of relapse of disease in early breast cancer, in order to assess the need for chemotherapy in addition to hormone therapy.\nIn this clinical case, the Oncotype Dx test provided was used in our institute on March 30, with a recurrence score of 23. Considering the age of the patient, \u226450 years, the use of chemotherapy was found to correspond to a benefit of approximately 6.5%.\nAfter a multidisciplinary collegial discussion, and considering the age, the absence of comorbidity, the premenopausal state, the rare histotype and the Oncotype Dx report, the patient underwent adjuvant chemotherapy treatment, according to the Docetaxel-Cyclophosphamide q21 scheme, for 4 cycles, followed by hormone therapy with luteinizing hormone-releasing hormone (LHRH) analogue and exemestane.\nThe patient, aware of the benefits and risks related to the aforementioned therapeutic proposal, decided to accept it. After chemotherapy, the patient will also undergo radiotherapy treatment on the residual breast.", "qa_list": [{"question": "What is this patient's Oncotype DX Recurrence Score?", "answer": "23", "justification": ["the Oncotype Dx test provided was used in our institute on March 30, with a recurrence score of 23"]}, {"question": "When was that score computed?", "answer": "March 30, 2020", "justification": ["the Oncotype Dx test provided was used in our institute on March 30", "Note Date: 2020-4-3"]}]}
{"id": 98, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-04-10", "note": "68yo M with h/o oropharyngeal cancer recently admitted with pneumonia\nand now s/p tracheostomy, recently s/p 21 day vancomycin course for\nMRSA pneumonia, who is now admitted with migration of trach into false\nlumen. Now s/p new trach placement by IP, also with fever and\nLeukocytosis.\nWBC down to 22.8 today. PICC and Chest tubes taken out. Pt\ncontinues to have thick copious greenish/yellow secretions via trach\nbut does not seem to have active pulmonary infection. Finished his\ncourse of IV vanco two days ago.\nPlan is for pt to have continued pulmonary toilet here and watch for\n24-48hrs for any signs of worsening infection. Check CXR, Labs and\nvital signs. If stable he may go to  in next day or two. Team\ndoes not want him to go to the floor. He will go directly to pulmonary\nrehab when able. In the meantime he will be encouraged to get OOB. Pt\nrefuses a lot of care and does not like to be turned, washed, given\nmouth care etc. PT has been consulted.\n.H/O cancer (Malignant Neoplasm), Esophageal\nAssessment:\nAction:\nResponse:\nPlan:", "qa_list": [{"question": "Was this patient ever diagnosed with oropharyngeal cancer?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["68yo M with h/o oropharyngeal cancer"]}, {"question": "If so, when was that diagnosis made?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 86, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-04-12", "note": "P Is a 70 yo male, who had been in the nearby Presbyterian hospital a few days ago\nfor treatment of a UTI.  While there, he received 2 doses of SQ\nheparin.  While following up with his PCP, Dr. Sanders had labs drawn and was\nfound to have a hct of 29 ( down from 40 on 4-02).  Arrived to ED,\nNG lavage was negative.  Pt without complaints.    Placed on octrotide\ngtt.  To MICU for further monitoring.\n.H/O gastrointestinal bleed, other (GI Bleed, GIB)\nAssessment:\nHemodynamically stable.  BP 70\ns-80\ns afib with occasional PVCs.  BP\n113-148/51-82.  EGD performed this morning.  Incomplete study secondary\nto food in stomach.  Severe portal gastropathy detected.  No stool this\nshift.\nAction:\nPt transfused 1 unit PRBC.  Octreotide drip infusing at 50mcg/hr.\nResponse:\nRepeat HCT  28.6%.  EGD incomplete study secondary to food in stomach\nPlan:\nContinue to monitor.  EGD in am.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient been diagnosed with portal gastropathy?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Severe portal gastropathy detected."]}, {"question": "If so, when was the most recent diagnosis of portal gastropathy, relative to the date of the note?", "answer": "2020-4-12", "justification": ["EGD performed this morning", "Note Date: 2020-4-12"]}, {"question": "If so, what was the procedure used to arrive at the most recent diagnosis of portal gastropathy, relative to the date of the note?", "answer": "Esophagogastroduodenoscopy", "justification": ["EGD performed this morning"]}]}
{"id": 129, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04187833", "criterion": "Prior treatment with a PARP inhibitor.", "note_date": "2020-04-18", "note": "A 57-year-old Caucasian woman was recently diagnosed with advanced stage ovarian cancer. Otherwise healthy, she had initially consulted her general practitioner simply for abdominal distension. Further investigations [abdominal computed tomography (CT), serum CA125determination and laparoscopy] revealed a peritoneal carcinomatosis. The diagnosis of stage III (FIGO classification) ovarian cancer was established and the patient received a carboplatin-paclitaxel based chemotherapy regimen in a neoadjuvant setting. The indication of a debulking surgery with hyperthermic intraperitoneal chemotherapy (HIPEC) was retained by our institutional tumor board. A CVL was inserted via the right jugular vein into the superior vena cava in prevision of surgery and the appropriate positioning of the catheter was verified by chest x-ray. An implantable central venous catheter (Port-a-Cath) was already in place. The first 48 postoperative hours were marked by difficult pain management, hypotension, and transient hyperlactatemia responding to fluid replacement and norepinephrine. On postoperative day 3, she presented acute onset dyspnea when transferred from the bed to a chair, and a major drop in pulse oxygen saturation (from SpO2 96% to 83%) justified the administration of oxygen (5 L/min) via a nasal cannula. On physical examination, her body temperature was 37.4 \u00b0C, blood pressure 135/81 mmHg, heart rate 122 beats/min, respiratory rate 20/min. No chest pain was reported. Pulmonary examination revealed a bilateral reduction of basal breath sounds with dullness at percussion. Chest x-ray examination showed bilateral pleural effusions that could largely explain patient\u2019s dyspnea and oxygen desaturation. After switching from a nasal cannula to a nonrebreather mask (FiO2 0.40), the patient\u2019s condition seemed to stabilize in supine position. A measurement of the arteriovenous oxygen difference was obtained via sampling through the arterial and central venous line after the patient was again lying in supine position . A sampling error or a wrong positioning of the recent CVL was suspected, but a sample taken from the Port-a-Cath confirmed the venous value. A transthoracic echocardiography (TTE) with bubble test failed to show a right-to-left shunt, atrial septum was intact. No pulmonary hypertension was detected and right ventricle was not dilated. A CT pulmonary angiography (Fig. ) showed large bilateral pleural effusions with atelectasis of both lower lobes, acute pulmonary embolism in the right middle and upper lobe pulmonary arteries, and ultimately an anatomical variant of the left upper pulmonary vein draining into the left innominate vein. Following bilateral chest drainage, the patient was treated with low molecular weight heparin twice daily. There was no evidence for deep venous thrombosis. This was followed by a significant clinical improvement, a disappearance of the platypnea\u2013orthodeoxia complaints and a reduction of oxygen requirement over the following days. At 1-year follow-up, TTE showed no right ventricular dilation and absence of pulmonary hypertension. From an oncological perspective, stability was also observed during her niraparib maintenance therapy, with absence of new lesions at a 1-year follow-up abdominal CT.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient ever received a PARP inhibitor ?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["stability was also observed during her niraparib maintenance therapy"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the PARP inhibitor treatment started?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 18, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-05-07", "note": "A 52-year-old Korean woman presented to our hospital because of edema and dry mouth. Additional complaints include fatigue, weight loss, and nail dystrophy. She had not had any of these symptoms in her medical history before. She started to complain of dry mouth and nail dystrophy 4 months before admission. During that period she lost 4 kg and felt severe fatigue. Two months before admission, she underwent a health screening in another hospital and received a diagnosis of renal dysfunction and hypothyroidism. There was no fever, rash, Raynaud phenomenon, or articular complaints. She had no medical history, and denied tobacco or alcohol abuse. There was no history of renal disease in her family. Her blood pressure was 120/70 mmHg, pulse rate was 62/minute, and her body temperature was 36.8 \u00b0C. Her conjunctiva was pale and her oral cavity was dry. Her nails were flattened and revealed onycholysis. A KOH test showed no fungi in her nails. Her thyroid gland was not enlarged and superficial lymph nodes were not palpable. There was no hepatosplenomegaly. No abnormality was present in the urological findings and neurologic examinations. Laboratory findings disclosed the following: hemoglobin 69 g/L, erythrocyte sedimentation rate 53 mm/hour, serum protein 88 g/L, albumin 26 g/L, serum creatinine 298.8 umol/L, and creatinine clearance 15 ml/minute according to Cockcroft and Gault formula. Urine sediment contained 0\u20132 white blood cells (WBC) and 0\u20132 red blood cells (RBC) per field. Her 24-hour urinary protein excretion was 0.696 g/day. Antinuclear antibodies, antibodies to SSA and SSB, rheumatoid factor, complement fractions, and cryoglobulins were all negative or within the normal range. In a urine protein electrophoresis, the proportion of urine protein was the following: albumin 87.6%, \u03b11-globulin 4.0%, \u03b12-globulin 1.1%, \u00df-globulin 0%, and \u03b3-globulin 7.3%. Serum and urine protein immunofixation electrophoresis showed no abnormal finding. Serum free light chain of kappa and lambda was increased (0.307 g/L and 0.192 g/L, respectively). Serum immunoglobulin G (IgG) was raised at 38.55 g/L (normal 7.0\u201317.0), however, IgA and IgM levels were normal (3.04 g/L and 2.45 g/L, respectively). A slit lamp examination revealed superficial keratoconjunctival erosion in both eyes. A 99mTc pertechnetate scan of her salivary gland showed normal function. A lip biopsy demonstrated amyloid deposition around her salivary ducts, and atrophy of her salivary duct. There was no mononuclear infiltration. A renal ultrasound scan showed increased echogenicity and the size of her right kidney and left kidney was 10.32 cm and 9.42 cm, respectively. A renal biopsy was performed. Light microscopy revealed a glomerular and peripheral capillary wall deposition of eosinophilic amorphous hyaline material. The Congo red stain by birefringence under polarized light showed apple-green staining reaction. Under electron microscopy, we observed non-branching, randomly distributed 10 nm-wide fibrils.", "qa_list": [{"question": "What is the creatinine clearance of this patient according to the Cockroft-Gault equation?", "answer": "15 mL/min", "justification": ["creatinine clearance 15 ml/minute according to Cockcroft and Gault formula"]}]}
{"id": 100, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "Oncotype DX Recurrence Score of less than or equal to 18 on diagnostic core biopsy or resected specimen.", "note_date": "2020-05-10", "note": "A 37-year-old East Asian woman presented a month ago with 3 days of dysphagia and 2 months of bilateral neck swelling. She denied any nausea, vomiting, headache, or gait disturbances.\nThe patient's family history was unknown as she was adopted. The patient's medical history was significant for bipolar disorder. On physical exam, patient was alert and oriented and cranial nerves were found to be intact. Palpable, nontender masses in the anterior neck were appreciated on head and neck examination. A mobile, nontender, 1 cm lump was also present on the left breast.\nCT, MRI, and fine needle aspiration of the thyroid masses performed last month revealed bilateral nonmalignant nodules measuring 1.9 cm and 1.7 cm on the right side and 2.2 cm and 2.3 cm on the left. The nodules abutted the esophagus bilaterally.\nMRI of the head revealed mild hydrocephalus and a right 3.8 cm cerebellar mass with a \"tiger-stripe\" appearance consistent with LDD. Total resection of the lesion was performed and histopathologic evaluation confirmed the diagnosis.\nMammogram, MRI, and core biopsy of the breasts were also performed in late April, which showed bilateral invasive ductal carcinoma. The patient subsequently underwent bilateral mastectomy. Histology revealed a 0.8 cm invasive ductal carcinoma of the right breast (T1bN0), estrogen positive, progesterone positive, and HER2 negative, and a 1.5 cm invasive ductal carcinoma of the left breast (T1cN0), estrogen positive, progesterone positive, and HER2 negative. Her Oncotype DX breast cancer recurrence score was 24 for her left breast carcinoma, corresponding with a 15% risk of distant recurrence over 10 years. She was given 4 doses of Taxotere and Cytoxan. The patient declined tamoxifen therapy.\nGenetic testing results confirmed the presence of the R335X (c.1003C>T) mutation in the PTEN gene and the patient was diagnosed with Cowden syndrome. The patient also chose to undergo risk-reducing thyroidectomy and hysterectomy with bilateral salpingectomy.", "qa_list": [{"question": "What is this patient's Oncotype DX Recurrence Score?", "answer": "24", "justification": ["Her Oncotype DX breast cancer recurrence score was 24"]}, {"question": "When was that score computed?", "answer": "April 2020", "justification": ["Mammogram, MRI, and core biopsy of the breasts were also performed in late April", "Note Date: 2020-5-10"]}]}
{"id": 22, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-05-22", "note": "A 61-year-old male patient presented with a large and deep infiltrating BCC of the left temple. After Mohs surgery, wound healing was unremarkable. However, a combined brow and upper lid ptosis had developed and hampered his lateral view []. On the other hand, he needed his car and so rehabilitative surgery was planned. Since he had a blepharochalasis, we used a combined approach, i.e. blepharoplasty of the upper lid and direct brow lift. The procedures were performed under local anaesthesia. Because there was no prolapse of the adipose tissue, a simple skin resection of the upper lid skin was performed and sutured with 4-0 Prolene (Ethicon, Norderstedt, Germany) sutures. For the brow lift, an elliptical incision on the apical border of the brow was performed []. The height of the incision was measured before by pulling the brow to its intended height and marking the position. After the removal of skin, the deeper layers were carefully removed down to the insertion of the insertions of muscle fibres of the venter frontalis. The vessels including the arteria conjunctivalis posterior were carefully preserved. We deepened the lateral part to the areolar tissue superficial to the periosteum. The skin adjacent to the incision borders was loosened by blunt preparation to ensure a tension-free suturing. The frontalis muscle was resected and the ends were sutured by 4-0 PDS (Ethicon) sutures to position the brow [Figure , ]. Wound closure was done by suturing the subcutaneous tissue with deep knots (4-0 PDS) and final wound closure with cutaneous 4-0 Ethilon (Ethicon) sutures []. After the removal of the suture, we recommended a preventive topical scar treatment (Cicaplast\u00ae; La Roche Posay, Asnieres, France). There was no significant scarring or other late adverse effects. The patient was very pleased with the outcome.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Does this patient have at least two BCC tumors?", "answer": "No", "justification": ["A 61-year-old male patient presented with a large and deep infiltrating BCC of the left temple"]}, {"question": "Are these BCC tumors eligible for removal by Mohs surgery?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["After Mohs surgery, wound healing was unremarkable"]}]}
{"id": 1, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-05-28", "note": "57-year-old male patient (weight: 62 kg) reported with a chief complaint of bleeding gums from the upper back tooth region for 1 month. On examination, a generalized probing depth of 6\u20137 mm with the moderate horizontal bone loss was observed. The oral hygiene of the patient was fair with a moderate amount of supragingival and subgingival deposits. The patient was systemically healthy with no history of any cutaneous skin lesions, drug intake, or allergic reaction to any medication or irritant. A nonsurgical phase one therapy comprising of full mouth oral prophylaxis and root surface debridement was initiated. Ibuprofen 200 mg was prescribed post-treatment in case any pain or discomfort was experienced. The patient was recalled after 2 weeks for re-evaluation and follow-up. However, the patient reported back within 1 h, with the development of a sudden, localized, soft, edematous, non-fluctuant, and nonmovable lobular swelling on the frontal and temporal part of his forehead. The swelling was tender on palpation with slight erythema on its outer surface []. The patient also reported the development of a mild rise in body temperature, lassitude, and malaise. Based on the patient's history and the timing of onset of allergic response, ibuprofen-induced hypersensitivity reaction was suspected. The patient was questioned regarding the onset of any similar incidents in the past. The patient then reported the onset of a similar swelling a few years back (etiology unknown). The patient was immediately referred to a physician, and blood was withdrawn to check for the total and differential blood count delete was done. The blood reports showed increases in the eosinophils (absolute eosinophils count = 9.67 \u00d7 103/\u03bcL (H); differential cell count = 16.5%) suggestive of an allergic reaction []. A local prick skin test with ibuprofen was also performed to confirm the hypersensitivity reaction []. To exclude the cross-reactivity and tolerance to other chemically unrelated NSAIDS, an oral challenge with other COX 1 inhibitors (aspirin) was done. The patient was immediately administered 10\u201320 mg intravenous injection of pheniramine maleate to control the reaction. A drastic reduction in the temporal swelling was observed within 24 h. The patient was kept under observation and was prescribed 10 mg of pheniramine maleate twice a day for 3 days. The patient was instructed not be take any nonselective NSAIDs in the future. The complete resolution of the swelling and urticaria was observed within 72 h. Since the allergic response to ibuprofen was immediately observed in the absence of any previous history of cutaneous lesion, bronchial asthma, respiratory disorders along with cross-reactivity to two or more NSAIDs, a diagnosis of NSAID-induced urticaria/angioedema (NIUA) was established based on the European Academy of Allergy and Clinical Immunology)/WAO nomenclature [].[]", "qa_list": [{"question": "Can we conclude that this patient is allergic to ibuprofen or to acetaminophen?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Since the allergic response to ibuprofen was immediately observed in the absence of any previous history of cutaneous lesion, bronchial asthma, respiratory disorders along with cross-reactivity to two or more NSAIDs, a diagnosis of NSAID-induced urticaria/angioedema (NIUA) was established based on the European Academy of Allergy and Clinical Immunology)/WAO nomenclature [].[]"]}]}
{"id": 25, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-06-18", "note": "A 53-year-old man had history of adenocarcinoma of the lung with liver metastases. He was found to have brain metastasis when he presented with intra-cranial bleeding, which necessitated an excision of the solitary brain metastasis. He presented with hematuria 1 year after the initial diagnosis of his lung cancer. Initial investigations with plain radiographs and mid-stream urine sampling were unrevealing. His urine cytology demonstrated suspicious cells with marked variation of nuclear size, irregularity of nuclear outline, and abnormal chromatin pattern []. He underwent a computed tomographic urography, which revealed a 2.7 cm contrast-enhancing posterior bladder wall mass with transmural involvement. The urogram phase revealed its fungative morphology []. Our patient underwent a flexible cystoscopy, which revealed a 3 cm sessile vascular growth with rugged edges and a central crater at the left lateral wall. The surrounding mucosa appeared distorted and elevated, which was suggestive of a growth beneath the intact bladder mucosa []. Biopsy of the tumor mass revealed adenocarcinoma, favored lung primary. A transurethral resection of bladder tumor was performed to alleviate his hematuria. shows the histological appearance of the brain metastasis. The tumor demonstrated true papillae with fibrovascular cores, features which were diagnostic of adenocarcinoma. The tumor was also diffusely and strongly positive for thyroid transcription factor 1 (TTF1) (mouse monoclonal, 1:100, Dako Denmark), a marker which was positive in majority of primary lung adenocarcinoma.[] shows the histological appearance of the bladder tumor. The tumor was morphologically reminiscent of the brain metastasis. The overlying transitional cell epithelium was intact and benign, whereas the underlying detrusor muscle was extensively infiltrated by the tumor. A directed panel of immunohistochemistry () revealed the tumor cells showed a cytokeratin 7 (CK7) (mouse anti-human, 1:300, Dako Denmark) positive, CK20 (mouse anti-human, 1:100, Dako Denmark) negative and TTF1 positive phenotype, which was most compatible with adenocarcinoma of lung primary.[] It was of note that the residual transitional epithelium retained its CK20 positive property. Our patient had external-beam radiotherapy for his scalp metastasis on June 3, 2020 but decided not for further systemic therapy for his lung cancer. There was no recurrence of gross hematuria as reported by the patient up to the time when this article was prepared (3 months post-transurethral resection). Our trans-urethral resection achieved its palliative role for the patient.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient received external-beam radiotherapy?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Our patient had external-beam radiotherapy for his scalp metastasis"]}, {"question": "If so, when did the patient receive the external-beam radiotherapy?", "answer": "June 3, 2020", "justification": ["on June 3, 2020"]}]}
{"id": 10, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-07-10", "note": "Problems:\nDiabetes mellitus type 2 : Not on any meds.\nDepression\nAnxiety : Given lorazepam in ER.\nsleep disturbance : Insomnia\nSmoking : started 40 years ago.\nHypertension\ntraumatic brain injury s/p MVA : 9/2070.\nHyperlipidemia\ndiabetic foot ulcer on right big toe : Urgent referral to podiatry and put on Keflex.\nProteinuria\nleft upper lobe lung nodule : 3 month follow up CT scan scheduled for 2/4/72.\nNoncompliance\nH/O breast cancer : s/p radiation tx, chemotherapy.Left breast T2 N0 MX invasive ductal carcinoma, LVI-, margins -, ER+PR+, HER 2/neu- s/p lumpectomy and SLN mapping.\ns/p left carotid endarderectomy\nOnychomycosis", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient had a lumpectomy?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["s/p lumpectomy"]}, {"question": "If so, are the margins of the resected specimen or re-excision histologically free of invasive tumor and DCIS?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["margins -"]}]}
{"id": 12, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-07-18", "note": "Past Medical History:\nright breast cancer s/p lumpectomy (clear margins) and radiation\n(2015)\nfibrocystic breast disease\nIrritable bowel syndrome\nfybromyalgia\ngastroesophageal reflux disease", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient had a lumpectomy?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["right breast cancer s/p lumpectomy"]}, {"question": "If so, are the margins of the resected specimen or re-excision histologically free of invasive tumor and DCIS?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["(clear margins)"]}]}
{"id": 21, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-07-19", "note": "A 78-year-old immunocompetent Caucasian male with past medical history of numerous BCCs and malignant melanoma of the right posterior shoulder (0.26 mm Breslow depth treated with wide local excision in 2010) presented with an asymptomatic, crusted, pink plaque of unknown duration on the left parietal scalp measuring 1.5 \u00d7 1.5 cm2. Shave biopsy revealed a nodular and focally infiltrative BCC. He was referred to the Mohs Surgery clinic for treatment. The patient had a past medical history of multiple aggressive scalp BCCs. Five years prior he underwent Mohs surgery for two BCCs on the left and right parietal scalp. The left parietal scalp BCC recurred 18 months later and he was treated at an outside plastic surgery clinic with a wide local excision. He developed a BCC on the vertex scalp 9 months after that which was treated with Mohs surgery. Due to extension to bone, the patient also underwent adjuvant radiation therapy. Mohs surgery was initiated for the most recent recurrent BCC on the vertex of the scalp (). Frozen section analysis revealed diffuse infiltrative BCC in the dermis and subcutaneous fat. In the fifth stage, intravascular tumor cells were noted (), and the patient was still positive in five out of six specimens with a defect measuring 6.5 \u00d7 7.0 cm2 (). Intravascular invasion, with CD31(+) and CD34(+) vascular channels, was confirmed with permanent sections by a board-certified dermatopathologist. No evidence of perineural involvement was seen in the sections examined. Mohs surgery was stopped given the concern for widespread disease of the scalp and inability to attain a clear margin. A positron emission tomography/computed tomography (PET/CT) scan was ordered to evaluate for metastatic disease. The PET/CT scan demonstrated diffuse heterogeneous moderate tracer distribution in the left scalp wound favoring malignant involvement with an overlap of activity into the left parietal bone with erosion of the cortex, favoring osseous involvement. Prominent activity was last noted in the left cervical level IIa nodes, right sacrum, right scapula, and the third left rib, concerning for metastatic disease. A right sacral ala biopsy showed infiltrating nests of basaloid tumor cells in a sclerotic stroma, consistent with metastatic BCC (). After discussion at a multidisciplinary tumor board involving head and neck surgery, radiation oncology, and medical oncology, he started vismodegib 150 mg daily. Repeat PET/CT scan 6 months later showed decrease in the activity of right sacrum metastatic lesions, consistent with response to treatment, and stable cervical IIa nodes. However, there was an interval new subcutaneous focus over the right cheek suggestive of new BCC development, which is being managed with vismodegib at this time.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Does this patient have at least two BCC tumors?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["A 78-year-old immunocompetent Caucasian male with past medical history of numerous BCCs and malignant melanoma of the right posterior shoulder"]}, {"question": "Are these BCC tumors eligible for removal by Mohs surgery?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["He was referred to the Mohs Surgery clinic for treatment"]}]}
{"id": 20, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-07-27", "note": "A 53-year-old woman was referred to a radiologist for performance of a routine computed tomography scan of the head to exclude intracranial hemorrhage after accidental head trauma. The computed tomography imaging detected lamellar calcification of the falx cerebri, which is a pathognomonic feature of GGS (fig. ) []. Meeting the criteria for GGS and considering the pathognomonic feature of the lamellar calcification (major criterion for GGS), the patient was referred to the Department of Dermatology. An examination of the patient's skin showed multiple small lesions clinically resembling basal cell carcinomas (BCCs) on the back, for which shave excisions were carried out. One suspected nodular BCC on the nose was removed by Mohs micrographic surgery. Pathologic examination of the lesions revealed 9 superficial BCCs on the back and 1 nodular BCC on the nose. The patient reported that the first BCC had occurred at the age of 27 years, and subsequently 4 other superficial BCCs had been removed by shave excision until the diagnosis of GGS was established. Furthermore, the patient presented with multiple palmar pits and marked syndactyly of the toes. Therefore, in our case, 2 major criteria [(I) lamellar calcification of falx cerebri, and (II) more than 2 BCCs] and 1 minor criterion (marked syndactyly of digits) were detected []. Additionally, the diagnosis of GGS was confirmed by positive testing for mutations in the tumor suppressor gene PTCH. Taking into account that GGS is an autosomal dominant genetic disease with nearly full penetrance and variable expressivity [], the daughters of our patient were screened for PTCH gene mutations as well. Although they both had no BCCs upon clinical inspection and none recorded in their medical history, one of the daughters tested positive for a PTCH gene mutation.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Does this patient have at least two BCC tumors?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Pathologic examination of the lesions revealed 9 superficial BCCs on the back and 1 nodular BCC on the nose"]}, {"question": "Are these BCC tumors eligible for removal by Mohs surgery?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["One suspected nodular BCC on the nose was removed by Mohs micrographic surgery"]}]}
{"id": 24, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-08-07", "note": "An 86-year-old man presented with syncope on a background of castration resistant metastatic prostate cancer that was diagnosed on Dec. 12, 2018. He had no pre-existing diagnosis of cardiovascular disease and no known intracranial or intracardiac metastases. He was enrolled in the TRITON-2 trial (NCT02952534; PR CO-338-052), receiving oral rucaparib 600 mg twice daily for 9 months prior to the index admission. His only other regular medication was paracetamol. Baseline and serial electrocardiogram (ECG) monitoring was not undertaken during the trial period and pre-existing prolonged QT on an earlier ECG from 2013 (QTc 465 ms) did not preclude him from enrolment in this trial. Left ventricular systolic function was preserved on transthoracic echocardiogram prior to enrolment. Following rucaparib initiation, he had no cardiac symptoms or hospital presentations until the index admission. He presented with a collapse at home without a clear cause and no acute injuries. In the emergency department, he remained in sinus rhythm and was transferred to the ward on cardiac monitoring. Shortly after arriving on the ward, he developed TdP () with altered conscious status requiring brief cardiopulmonary resuscitation (30 s) followed by a single direct cardioversion shock (200 J biphasic) and 20 mmol/L intravenous magnesium sulphate. Post-arrest, he appeared pale and cachectic with no jaundice, murmurs, or signs of fluid overload. He had a Glascow Coma Scale of 15, with no signs of asterixis. ECG showed a broad junctional rhythm at a rate of 52 b.p.m. (left bundle branch block pattern) with marked U waves in V2\u2013V4 and severe QT prolongation (QTc 680 ms) (). Rucaparib was discontinued immediately. An ECG performed 5 years prior to rucaparib initiation demonstrated first degree atrioventricular block and a long QT interval (QTc 465 ms) (). There was no personal history of coronary artery disease or syncope and no family history of cardiogenic syncope or sudden cardiac death. Notably, an ECG performed 3 months following rucaparib initiation showed marked QT prolongation (QTc interval 589 ms, ), in the absence of syncope. Rucaparib continued as QT interval, both pre- and post-enrolment, are not routinely monitored as part of the TRITON-2 trial and the marked increase in QT interval was not documented during the trial follow-up. The patient did not undergo ECG or Holter monitoring following rucaparib initiation. No other QT prolonging agents were prescribed. The only other regular medication was paracetamol 1 g up to four times per day for pain management in the setting of bony metastases. There was no electrolyte abnormality detected [serum potassium 4.4 mmol/L (normal range 3.5\u20135.0 mmol/L) and serum magnesium 1.0 mmol/L (normal range 0.7\u20131.1 mmol/L)] and both renal and hepatic function were satisfactory. Isoprenaline infusion (2 \u03bcg/min) was introduced due to recurrent rate-related TdP in the context of bradycardia. On day 3 of admission, isoprenaline was ceased and the QT interval was notably shorter (QTc interval 547 ms; ) with an intrinsic heart rate of 93 b.p.m. in atrial flutter. Consideration was given to permanent pacing given an initial projected life expectancy of >12 months, however, despite rhythm stabilization, he deteriorated precipitously while in hospital, likely as a consequence of oncological disease progression with refractory symptoms in addition to the physiological insult of resuscitation in an elderly, already frail, cachectic gentleman with limited reserve. The patient was palliated, and the family subsequently declined post-mortem genetic testing or familial screening for inheritable long QT syndrome (LQTS).", "qa_list": [{"question": "does this patient have castration resistant prostate cancer?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["An 86-year-old man presented with syncope on a background of castration resistant metastatic prostate cancer"]}, {"question": "When was the castration resistant prostate cancer diagnosed?", "answer": "Dec. 12, 2018", "justification": ["diagnosed on Dec. 12, 2018"]}]}
{"id": 42, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04871529", "criterion": "Histologically confirmed high grade upper tract urothelial carcinoma (UTUC) within 56 days prior to registration, with invasion confirmed by either a mass on cross-sectional imaging or a tumor directly visualized during upper urinary tract endoscopy within 56 days prior to registration", "note_date": "2020-08-14", "note": "A 72-year-old Caucasian woman presented with a 5-month history of intermittent gross hematuria and right flank pain. She had no history of cancer and reported a 29-pack-year smoking history. Physical examination demonstrated no palpable lymph nodes or abdominal masses. Her baseline glomerular filtration rate (GFR) was 54 mL/minute/1.73 m2. A CT urogram delineated a 1.5 cm right renal pelvic lesion with no evidence of local advancement or LAD in the abdomen or pelvis.\nCystoscopy showed no bladder lesions and the left retrograde pyelogram was unremarkable. Right ureteroscopy demonstrated a 1.5 cm papillary lesion, which was biopsied with a 2.4F stainless steel flat wire basket. The lesion was treated with the combination neodymium/holmium YAG laser. A ureteral stent was placed for 1 week.\nThe ureteroscopic biopsy and site-specific cytologies demonstrated low-grade UTUC. All options were discussed with the patient and ureteroscopic treatment and surveillance were recommended given the patient's age, comorbidities, low-grade pathology analysis, and relatively small tumor size. The patient was followed endoscopically for the next 36 months, occasionally finding low-volume, low-grade recurrences, amenable to endoscopic treatment. No evidence of high-grade UTUC was noted during this time on biopsies or site-specific cytologies. The patient developed small high-grade, noninvasive bladder tumors 12 months after initial presentation, mandating intravesical therapy with BCG, which was well tolerated and effective.\nThe patient had cross-sectional imaging yearly with contrast-enhanced CT scans of the abdomen and pelvis without findings of local advancement or metastatic disease. At 42 months from initial presentation, the patient developed significant pain in her right upper leg and complained of a 10-pound weight loss. A CT scan of the chest, abdomen, and pelvis demonstrated new onset of right-sided pelvic LAD with a 3.3 cm right external iliac node, 1.6 cm right common iliac node, and 3.2 cm right obturator node. The chest, retroperitoneum, and liver were clear. The kidneys demonstrated no evidence of locally advanced disease. A bone scan demonstrated increased uptake in the right femur consistent with malignancy.\nFormal lymph node biopsy was deferred by the patient, but a fine needle aspiration of the right external iliac lymph node with flow cytometry demonstrated findings consistent with a B-cell lymphoproliferative neoplasm. The patient's right leg pain spontaneously improved. The presumed diagnosis was an insidious B-cell lymphoma and active surveillance was instituted.\nSix months later, a positron emission tomography/computed tomography (PET/CT) scan demonstrated resolution of LAD save for a right axillary node. After formal biopsy, this demonstrated a grade 3A FL. Multiple osseous lesions were now noted but the patient was asymptomatic. Endoscopic surveillance of the right renal unit demonstrated low volumes of recurrent UTUC, which had advanced to high grade. Because of the grade change, a right laparoscopic nephroureterectomy (NU) was performed in January and pathology analysis demonstrated multifocal high-grade UTUC with pTaN0 stage with four negative obturator lymph nodes. Within 3 months, PET/CT scan showed progression of osseous lesions but no significant LAD. The patient underwent five cycles of rituximab, cyclophosphamide, doxorubicin, vincristine, and prednisone. Partial remission was noted on follow-up PET/CT scan.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient had a histologically confirmed diagnosis of high-grade upper tract urothelial carcinoma (UTUC)?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["pathology analysis demonstrated multifocal high-grade UTUC"]}, {"question": "If so, when was this diagnosis made?", "answer": "January 2020", "justification": ["a right laparoscopic nephroureterectomy (NU) was performed in January\", \"Clinical Note Date: 08-14-2020"]}]}
{"id": 17, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-08-23", "note": "The patient is a 25-year-old Caucasian man. Glycogen storage disease type Ia was diagnosed during infancy (fasting hypoglycemia and hepatomegaly), and confirmed by molecular diagnosis (compound heterozygosity for both c.527A>G and c.1039 C>T mutations in the glucose 6 phosphatase gene). This patient also has both Willebrand and Gilbert diseases. He had been treated with growth hormone at 12 years of age, for 1 year, for retarded growth, with no clinical improvement. He had been an active smoker since the age of 15 years, and recently quit smoking. He used to have chronic metabolic imbalance during the second decade of life. Supplementations with uncooked cornstarch since infancy, then enteral nutrition by the age of 17 were not well tolerated because of chronic diarrhea. Blood tests performed at 22 were disturbed as follow: triglyceridemia 19 mmoL/L, uricemia 0.498 mmoL/L, bicarbonate 16 mmoL/L, lactic acid before breakfast 9 mmoL/L. The patient slowly developed hepatic polyadenomatosis. He also developed osteoporosis. When he was 22 years old, uncooked cornstarch (300-420 g/day) was replaced by Glycosade and oral fenofibrate was started. His diet was hyperglucidic, glucides representing 63% of caloric intake. This treatment allowed an improvement of metabolic balance. His metabolic blood tests between 22 and 25 years of age were as follow: triglyceridemia between 2.28 and 4.56 mmoL/L, uricemia between 0.4 and 0.5 mmoL/L, lactic acid before breakfast between 3 and 5 mmoL/L, bicarbonate between 20 and 24 mmoL/L. Hepatic polyadenomatosis remained stable on regular MRI follow-up since the age of 22. He had no renal disease. Proteinuria and microalbuminuria were negative, creatinine clearance was 120 mL/min/1.73 m2 (Cockroft-Gault), calciuria was low. It is noteworthy that renal cysts had never been observed, either on MRI or on ultrasound examination. He was referred to our center this month, as a 25 year-old, for his annual follow-up. His metabolic balance is good and the blood tests he had last week were as follow: creatinine clearance 123 mL/min (Cockroft-Gault), proteinuria <0.02 g/L, microalbuminuria 13.6 mg/L, uric acid 0.438 mmoL/L, triglyceridemia 2.52 mmoL/L, cholesterol 5.07 mmoL/L, hemoglobin 141 g/L, C reactive protein <5 mg/L, aspartate amino transferase 0.54 \u03bcKat/l (32 UI/l), alanine amino transferase 0.38 \u03bcKat/l (23 UI/l), GGT 0.69 \u03bcKat/l (41 UI/l). Glycemias were normal during 24 hours before and after meals, lactic acid were measured between 1.7 and 3.1 mmoL/L during 24 hours. Hepatic MRI showed multiple adenomas and decrease in size of the largest adenoma (41 mm vs 48 mm the year before). Renal MRI showed the appearance of a nodular lesion, at the lower pole of left kidney. The lesion diameter was 28 mm. On T1 weighted images, the lesion was isointense. On T2 weighted images, it was discretely hyperintense, with discrete contrast enhancement after injection (Figure ). The patient underwent partial nephrectomy. The diagnosis of papillary renal cell carcinoma type 2 (grad ISUP2) was confirmed by histological study (Figure ). Nephroprotective treatment was started with ACE inhibitor (ramipril 2.5 mg/day). No relapse had occurred at the last follow-up visit. His blood test 2 years after nephrectomy were as follow: creatinine clearance 148 mL/min/1.73 m2 (Cockroft-Gault), no urinary albumin excretion, uricemia 0.290 mmoL/L, triglyceridemia 1.55 mmoL/L, lactatemia and glycemia normal before and after meals. Due to the rarity of this tumor and the young age of the patient, a genetic cause has been evoked but not confirmed to date (looking for a germline mutation of the fumarate hydratase gene).", "qa_list": [{"question": "What is the most recent creatinine clearance of this patient according to the Cockroft-Gault equation?", "answer": "123 mL/min", "justification": ["creatinine clearance 123 mL/min (Cockroft-Gault)"]}, {"question": "When was the most recent creatinine clearance measured?", "answer": "A week before the note date", "justification": ["the blood tests he had last week were as follow: creatinine clearance 123 mL/min (Cockroft-Gault)"]}]}
{"id": 6, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-08-25", "note": "The patient was an unemployed 65-year-old female patient with height and weight of 158 cm and 48 kg, respectively. Her nationality and race were Korean and Mongoloid, respectively. She visited the outpatient clinic for pain in her knee and hip joints on both sides. The knee pain had developed seven years ago and was more severe on the right than on the left and caused a lot of disruption in her daily life. The patient also had been experiencing knee instability since adolescence, but no special diagnosis or management had been performed. The instability was aggravated by sitting, standing up or pivoting motions. The patient complained of a 3-year history of pain in the hip joints of both sides without any special trauma, which made it difficult to walk more than 500 m without walking aids. The patient had no past or family history of diseases that would be accompanied by multiple joint pain. Upon physical examination, the right knee presented with slight joint effusion and no marked anterior or posterior laxity (negative Lachman and pivot shift tests and anterior/posterior drawer tests), but the patient had an instability on the frontal plane (laxity at the valgus: grade 3, laxity at the valgus; grade 3). The left knee also showed no marked anterior or posterior laxity (negative Lachman and pivot shift tests and anterior/posterior drawer tests), but instability on the frontal plane (laxity at the valgus: grade 3, laxity at the valgus; grade 3) was demonstrated. There was no limitation in the range of motion of either knee. Both hip joints were positive on the Patrick test and rolling test and both joints showed a limited range of motion (right: flexion 90\u00b0, extension 10\u00b0, abduction 25\u00b0, adduction 15\u00b0, internal rotation 10\u00b0, external rotation 20\u00b0; left: flexion 95\u00b0, extension 10\u00b0, abduction 20\u00b0, adduction 15\u00b0, internal rotation 15\u00b0, external rotation 20\u00b0). Blood tests showed that the whole blood cell test, as well as the liver, kidney, thyroid, parathyroid, and adrenal function tests, were all within normal limits. Tests related to autoimmune diseases (rheumatoid factor, antinuclear antibody, anti-cyclic citrullinated peptide, and HLA B27) were all negative. A lower extremity scannogram showed more valgus anatomic axes (right: 12\u00b0, left: 10\u00b0) than normal (reference value: 6\u00b0 \u00b1 3\u00b0) (A). Both knee standing radiographs showed joint space narrowing of the lateral compartment with osteoarthritis (right: Kellgren-Lawrence grade 3, left: Kellgren-Lawrence grade 4) and hypoplasia of the tibial intercondylar eminence and flat trochlea femoralis were also seen (B). Physician-applied varus/valgus stress radiographs revealed lateral and medial compartment joint openings in both knees (). Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) showed reduction of the cartilage thickness in the weight-bearing area of the lateral femoral condyle, a scarcely pronounced intercondylar notch and absence of the ACL (). On both hip anteroposterior views, both hip joints showed severe osteoarthritis (right: K\u2013L grade 4, left: K\u2013L grade 4) (). On the basis of the above clinical and image findings, we diagnosed congenital aplasia of the ACL with secondary knee and hip osteoarthritis. The patient complained of more pain in the right knee and right hip than in the left side, so right total knee and hip arthroplasty (TKA, THA) were performed simultaneously. About one year after the last surgery, the patient presented with more aggravated pain and instability of the left knee and hip joint. She underwent TKR and THR simultaneously (). As a result of the surgeries, the patient's symptoms improved and she was satisfied with the results. After the surgeries and follow-up for more than a year (right 24 months, left 12 months), both her knee and hip were pain-free without evidence of instability on physical examination", "qa_list": [{"question": "Does the patient have a knee osteoarthritis Kellgren-Lawrence grade of 4?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["left: Kellgren-Lawrence grade 4"]}]}
{"id": 23, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-09-10", "note": "A 55-year-old man was referred to the pulmonary clinic due to dyspnea and sputum for a month. He was an ex-smoker with a 45 pack-year history and had tuberculosis 25 years ago. Two years prior, the patient presented with a low back pain and anal incontinence. The tumor appeared to replace most of the prostate and spread to perirectal area and bilateral pelvic wall on computed tomography (CT) (). Extensive pelvic lymphadenopathy and bone metastasis of the 11th thoracic vertebra were also found. He underwent a palliative transurethral resection of the prostate (TURP) and was diagnosed with prostate cancer of Gleason score 9 (4 + 5) on pathologic examination. He started receiving radiation therapy while taking leuprorelin, a gonadotropin-releasing hormone agonist. The prostate-specific antigen (PSA) levels dropped from 78.54 to 0.2 ng/mL and the androgen levels reached within castration concentrations (testosterone 0.13 ng/dL, free testosterone 0.58 ng/dL) for a year. On chest radiographs, bilateral pleural effusions of a small to moderate amount were observed (), with a larger amount on the right side (). No mass-like lesion was found on thoracic CT scan. Bone scans showed newly noted multifocal uptakes in skull, rib cage, sacrum, pelvic bones, humeri, and femurs. For reliable diagnosis and appropriate management, ultrasound-guided percutaneous pigtail catheters were inserted. The drained pleural fluid was turbid yellow with glucose 94 mg/dL, protein 4.4 g/dL, triglyceride 13 mg/dL, lactate dehydrogenase 1,113 U/L, and adenosine deaminase 17.1 IU/L. Its differential count was 7% lymphocytes, 41% macrophages, 5% mesothelial cells, and 47% malignant cells. PSA in pleural fluid and concomitant serum PSA were 21.50 and 44.71 ng/mL respectively. The pleural fluid was prepared with routine conventional smear. The Papanicolaou stained smears showed groups of neoplastic cells arranged in large cell-clusters (). Most of them formed large three-dimensional balls without glandular lumen (), and they consisted of medium sized round to ovoid cells showing coarse, finely granular and vesicular chromatin. Most tumor cells showed smooth nuclear contours with large prominent nucleoli, but some showed irregular nuclear borders. They had hyperchromatic nuclei with a high nuclear to cytoplasmic (N/C) ratio (). Nuclear pleomorphism was minimal to mild and mitosis was hardly found (less than 1/10 high-power field). The architectural and cytologic features were mostly similar on cell block, but a few glandular lumens were found. The tumor cells were in tightly cohesive groups without lumen (). A very few of them had glandular lumen-like space with central necrosis (). They had pale eosinophilic to clear cytoplasm, and the amount of cytoplasm was small to moderate. Based on these findings, the tumor cells were taken to be poorly differentiated carcinoma of unknown origin. Immunocytochemical panel studies were performed on the cell block to determine the origin of cancer metastasis. The tumor cells were immunopositive for PSA (), alpha-methylacylcoenzyme A racemase (AMACR) (), and Nkx 3.1 (). They showed negative immunoreactivity for P40, cytokeratin 5/6 (), thyroid transcription factor-1 and gross cystic disease fluid protein. The patient was finally diagnosed with metastatic castration resistant prostate cancer. He was then treated with a second-line chemotherapeutic agent, biweekly docetaxel and oral dexamethasone. This study was approved by the Institutional Review Board (IRB) of The Catholic University of Korea, Seoul St. Mary\u2019s Hospital (KC17ZESI0451) and was performed in accordance with the principles of the Declaration of Helsinki. The patient informed consent was waived", "qa_list": [{"question": "Does this patient have castration resistant prostate cancer?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["The patient was finally diagnosed with metastatic castration resistant prostate cancer"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the castration resistant prostate cancer diagnosed?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 13, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-09-15", "note": "HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS: Patient is a 59-year-old gentleman diagnosed with metastatic renal cell cancer in 2019-7-5. He underwent a debulking left nephrectomy with Dr. Smith on 2019-8-25, and was diagnosed with metastatic kidney cancer by thyroidectomy in 2019-7-5. This revealed high grade renal cell carcinoma that was metastatic to the adrenal gland. Following debulking nephrectomy, he was found to be presented with severe bone pain. Location of his pain was in the right shoulder. Given that the pain did not resolve, he underwent a MRI which showed ultimately a lytic lesion in the right shoulder and was treated with radiation therapy to the shoulder as well as ultimately undergoing treatment with chemotherapy. He did not respond to chemotherapy and developed a large lytic lesion in the left femur requiring an operative embolization and rod placement in 02/2020. Following that, he had multiple radiation therapies to the spine as well as right scapula as well as left femur. He was seen on multiple occasions over the last several weeks complaining of increasing pain in the right shoulder. CT scan revealed a large lytic lesion. Given that this area had been radiated twice, tentatively booked to see Dr. Polinsky in Radiology for radiofrequency ablation for pain relief. He has been on OxyContin 40 mg p.o. b.i.d. and Morphine elixir for breakthrough pain, and he has been a little better over the last few days.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Does this patient have bone pain?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["he was found to be presented with severe bone pain\",\n\"the pain did not resolve\", and \"He was seen on multiple occasions over the last\nseveral weeks complaining of increasing pain in the right shoulder"]}]}
{"id": 8, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-09-17", "note": "A 74-year-old postmenopausal female presented to dermatology outpatient clinic with the complaint of a mass on dorsum of the left foot and a mass on the middle part of the medial surface of the left lower extremity for a month. A tru-cut biopsy was obtained from malignant necrotic ecchymosis under antibiotic prophylaxis. Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) of the pelvic and MRI of the lower extremity were performed. The results showed a mass obliterating the endometrium and a pathologic lymphadenopathy, measuring 30 \u00d7 15 mm, on the left inguinal region. Vaginal ultrasound was performed and adnexal atrophy and cysts in uterus were detected. Dilatation and curettage was performed on endometrium and patient was diagnosed with high-grade cancer. MRI of the lower extremity showed a heterogeneous mass, which is measuring 56 \u00d7 40 mm and is infiltrating proximal parts of third and fourth metatarsal bones and muscle and fat tissue on dorsal part of left foot. Positron emission tomography\u2013computed tomography (PET-CT) was performed for stating. The results demonstrated a lesion, measuring 10.5 \u00d7 6.5 \u00d7 5.5 cm, extending from skin to extensor muscles and infiltrating proximal fourth and fifth phalanges in intermetatarsal spaces on plantar surface of the foot (SUVmax: 13.6). A primary lesion, measuring 25 mm in diameter, that is extending from medial calcaneus to subcutaneous tissue on proximal and one-third part of the middle part of left lower extremity (SUVmax: 26.5) and a second primary mass, measuring 45 \u00d7 28 mm, that is filling corpus of the uterus (SUVmax: 45.8) are noted. A metastatic lymph node, measuring 2 cm in diameter, is noted (SUVmax: 9.1). The results of the biopsy were evaluated and patient was diagnosed with high-grade DLBCL. The both tumors histopathological features were similar. This was in accordance with germinal centered high-grade non-Burkitt DLBCL. DLBCL-leg was diagnosed when MUM1 (+), CD20 (+), CD3 (\u2212), CD5 (\u2212), CD38 focal (+), CD79a (+), c-myc 20 to 30% (+), bcl-2 (+), bcl-6 (+), and CD10 (\u2212) were evaluated with clinical findings. The uterine tumor was diagnosed as stage IEA DLBCL according to the Lugano modification of Ann Arbor classification, the other tumor was diagnosed as T2aN1M0 according to WHO-EORTC classification and R-CHOP chemotherapy was initiated. After three courses of R-CHOP, PET-CT was performed. The scan showed almost complete regression in mass in uterus; complete regression in lesion on dorsum of the left foot and partial regression in anterior lesion of left lower extremity. After six courses of chemotherapy, PET-CT was performed and it demonstrated a residual mass extending to subcutaneous tissue and muscles of dorsum of left foot (SUVmax: 2.0) ( ). A skin biopsy was performed. The results showed no cutaneous lymphoma, but atrophy of the dermis was detected. No residual mass was noted histopathologically; therefore, salvage RT was not planned.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Was the patient diagnosed with cancer in a lower extremity?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["DLBCL-leg was diagnosed"]}, {"question": "If so, what was the cancer's stage?", "answer": "T2aN1M0", "justification": ["the other tumor was diagnosed as T2aN1M0 according to WHO-EORTC classification"]}]}
{"id": 68, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-09-27", "note": "Admission Date : 2020-09-22 \nDischarge Date : 2020-09-27 \nDate of Birth : 2020-09-22 \nSex : M \nService : CMED CSRU \nHISTORY : Peggy Hammock is a full term baby boy born at 38 1/7 weeks by repeat cesarean section to a 34 year old gravida III , now para II mother . Serologies include blood type O negative , antibody negative , RPR nonreactive . Rupture of membranes at time of delivery . Delivery was by repeat cesarean section and Apgars of 8 and 9 were given at one and five minutes respectively . Baby appeared well and went to the newborn nursery and was breast feeding and undergoing routine newborn care . On the newborn nursery the mother called the nurse for concern of baby turning dusky while feeding . She called the nurses and patted the infant on the back . This episode was also accompanied by gagging motions noted of the infant . A second episode occurred where the baby turned pale . Mother thought the baby just did not look right . The baby did not turn blue at that time . The Neonatal Intensive Care Unit was notified and the baby was transferred to the Newborn Intensive Care Unit for further evaluation. \nHOSPITAL COURSE BY SYSTEMS : \nFluid , electrolytes and nutritions : Weight at time of discharge is 3.13 kilograms . Birth weight was 3.29 kilograms in the 75th percentile . Head circumference was 34.5 cm , 75th percentile , and length was 50.7 cm , also the 75th percentile . Gastrointestinal : Baby was noted to have frequent spitting episodes . This was minimized with limitation of volume at each feed with frequent feeding . He had normal voiding and stooling patterns . The baby demonstrated mild physiologic jaundice with a serum bilirubin obtained on day of life three which was 6.7 with a direct of 0.2 . Mother 's blood type is O negative . Infant 's blood type was O positive and Coombs was noted to be negative . \nHematologic : In addition a complete blood count was obtained on admission with a white count of 10.1 with 43 polys and 0 bands . Hematocrit was noted to 47.5 with platelets of 257,000 . There were no blood products received during hospitalization . \nDISCHARGE DISPOSITION : To home with parents . Primary pediatrician is Dr. Satterlund of Westborough Pediatrics . Telephone number is ( 739 ) 520-0347 . Fax number is ( 617 ) 455-4585 . Appointment is on Lyon , 10-30 .", "qa_list": [{"question": "Was the patient screened for levels of bilirubin in their blood?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["a serum bilirubin obtained"]}, {"question": "If so, what was the date of the bilirubin test relative to the date of the clinical note?", "answer": "2020-09-24", "justification": ["Date of Birth : 2020-09-22", "a serum bilirubin obtained on day of life three"]}, {"question": "Was the level of total serum bilirubin lower than 2.4 mg/dl ?", "answer": "No", "justification": ["with a serum bilirubin obtained on day of life three which was 6.7"]}, {"question": "What was the value of conjugated bilirubin at the day of measurement ?", "answer": "0.2", "justification": ["with a serum bilirubin obtained on day of life three which was 6.7 with a direct of 0.2"]}]}
{"id": 110, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "Pathologic staging of pN0(i+) or pN0(mol+), pN1, pN2, or pN3 disease.", "note_date": "2020-09-28", "note": "The patient is an 82-year-old male that presented to our hospital on January 18th with metastatic, mixed adenocarcinoma/neuroendocrine duodenal cancer. A pancreaticoduodenectomy surgery (Whipple) for definitive treatment was offered to the patient. The patient was reluctant to undergo major surgery and opted for systemic treatment instead. He presented to the ER two months after starting chemotherapy, on March 20, with symptoms of gastric outlet obstruction (GOO) (vomiting, belching, and weight loss). An attempt was made to manage the GOO non-operatively per the patient's wishes with duodenal stenting.\nA self-expanding, 22 mm x 9 cm fully covered, metal stent was placed into the second portion of the duodenum where a large, partially obstructing, ulcerated mass was visualized endoscopically.\nSeveral hours after the procedure, the patient complained of severe abdominal pain. A CT scan of the abdomen revealed that the stent placement resulted in a perforation of the duodenum with extension into the retroperitoneum.\nEmergency pancreaticoduodenectomy versus damage control surgery were the two surgical options offered to the patient. The patient opted for damage control surgery. He was taken emergently for an exploratory laparotomy, washout of the abdomen, wide drainage, duodenostomy tube placement, and pyloric exclusion.\nHis postoperative course was uneventful, and he recovered quickly. After four months of healing, the patient underwent a definitive pancreaticoduodenectomy procedure. Final pathology revealed a mixed adeno-neuroendocrine carcinoma, arising from the duodenum/peri-ampullary area and invading into the pancreas and duodenal serosa (pT3, pN1, cM1) with 3 of 16 lymph nodes positive for metastatic carcinoma and all margins negative. He went on to receive adjuvant systemic treatment and continues to do well postoperatively.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Was this patient ever diagnosed with cancer of the duodenum?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["presented to our hospital on January 18th with metastatic, mixed adenocarcinoma/neuroendocrine duodenal cancer"]}, {"question": "If so, what was the pathologic stage of the patient's duodenal cancer regarding lymph node involvement?", "answer": "pN1", "justification": ["Final pathology revealed a mixed adeno-neuroendocrine carcinoma, arising from the duodenum/peri-ampullary area and invading into the pancreas and duodenal serosa (pT3, pN1, cM1)"]}, {"question": "When was the pathologic staging performed?", "answer": "July 2020", "justification": ["He presented to the ER two months after starting chemotherapy, on March 20", "After four months of healing, the patient underwent a definitive pancreaticoduodenectomy procedure", "Note Date: 2020-9-28"]}, {"question": "What classification system was used for the pathologic staging?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 111, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-09-28", "note": "The patient is an 82-year-old male that presented to our hospital on January 18th with metastatic, mixed adenocarcinoma/neuroendocrine duodenal cancer. A pancreaticoduodenectomy surgery (Whipple) for definitive treatment was offered to the patient. The patient was reluctant to undergo major surgery and opted for systemic treatment instead. He presented to the ER two months after starting chemotherapy, on March 20, with symptoms of gastric outlet obstruction (GOO) (vomiting, belching, and weight loss). An attempt was made to manage the GOO non-operatively per the patient's wishes with duodenal stenting.\nA self-expanding, 22 mm x 9 cm fully covered, metal stent was placed into the second portion of the duodenum where a large, partially obstructing, ulcerated mass was visualized endoscopically.\nSeveral hours after the procedure, the patient complained of severe abdominal pain. A CT scan of the abdomen revealed that the stent placement resulted in a perforation of the duodenum with extension into the retroperitoneum.\nEmergency pancreaticoduodenectomy versus damage control surgery were the two surgical options offered to the patient. The patient opted for damage control surgery. He was taken emergently for an exploratory laparotomy, washout of the abdomen, wide drainage, duodenostomy tube placement, and pyloric exclusion.\nHis postoperative course was uneventful, and he recovered quickly. After four months of healing, the patient underwent a definitive pancreaticoduodenectomy procedure. Final pathology revealed a mixed adeno-neuroendocrine carcinoma, arising from the duodenum/peri-ampullary area and invading into the pancreas and duodenal serosa (pT3, pN1, cM1) with 3 of 16 lymph nodes positive for metastatic carcinoma and all margins negative. He went on to receive adjuvant systemic treatment and continues to do well postoperatively.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Did this patient ever have Whipple surgery?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["the patient underwent a definitive pancreaticoduodenectomy procedure"]}, {"question": "If so, when?", "answer": "July 2020", "justification": ["He presented to the ER two months after starting chemotherapy, on March 20", "After four months of healing, the patient underwent a definitive pancreaticoduodenectomy procedure", "Note Date: 2020-9-28"]}]}
{"id": 112, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "Pathologic staging of pN0(i+) or pN0(mol+), pN1, pN2, or pN3 disease.", "note_date": "2020-09-28", "note": "This is a follow-up examination of Mr. Brian Goodman, a 59-year-old man who initially presented to our clinic 2 years ago with difficulty swallowing. An endoscopic study at the time revealed an ulcerative esophageal tumor 36\u201340 cm from the upper incisors, and biopsy results indicated squamous cell carcinoma. He also had severe funnel chest, and his sternum was almost attached to the vertebral bone. He previously noticed this chest deformity but had no symptoms such as chest pain; therefore, he had not undergone medical examination for this condition. The Haller index (i.e., the distance of the inner rib cage divided by the distance between the sternal notch and the vertebrae) was 9.9. According to the UICC-TNM classification (version 7), the final preoperative diagnosis was stage IIIA, squamous cell carcinoma (cT3, cN1, cM0). Although he had severe funnel chest, the preoperative examination revealed that his condition was generally good and he was fit to undergo surgery under general anesthesia. Two courses of 5-FU (800 mg/m2)/cisplatin (80 mg/m2) were administered as standard neoadjuvant chemotherapy. Then, we planned to perform funnel chest surgery (Nuss method) before esophagectomy, in order to achieve a suitable width in the mediastinum to allow for thoracoscopic surgery.\nFirst, two convex metal bars were inserted under the sternum through small bilateral thoracic incisions. The bars were inserted with the convexity facing posteriorly. When the bars were in position, they were turned over to reconstruct the sternum and widen the mediastinum so that esophagectomy could be performed. Radical thoracoscopic esophagectomy with three-field lymph node dissection was performed with the patient in the left decubitus position, followed by gastric conduit reconstruction through the posterior mediastinum route. Surgery was performed without any complications, and the postoperative course was uneventful. Pathological staging according to the UICC-TNM classification (version 7) indicated stage IIIA (pT3, pN1, cM0). The metal bars were removed 1 year after surgery. The patient is in good condition today, the 2-year follow-up examination.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Was this patient ever diagnosed with esophageal  cancer?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["An endoscopic study at the time revealed an ulcerative esophageal tumor 36\u201340 cm from the upper incisors, and biopsy results indicated squamous cell carcinoma"]}, {"question": "If so, what was the pathologic stage of the patient's duodenal cancer regarding lymph node involvement?", "answer": "pN1", "justification": ["Pathological staging according to the UICC-TNM classification (version 7) indicated stage IIIA (pT3, pN1, cM0)"]}, {"question": "When was the pathologic staging performed?", "answer": "2018", "justification": ["presented to our clinic 2 years ago", "Note Date: 2020-9-28"]}, {"question": "What classification system was used for the pathologic staging?", "answer": "UICC-TNM, version 7", "justification": ["Pathological staging according to the UICC-TNM classification (version 7)"]}]}
{"id": 14, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-09-29", "note": "History of Present Illness:\n70 y/o russian gentleman heavy smoker who was in his usual state of health until day prior to admission, when he started to have episodes of hemoptysis. The amount of blood has increased, now up to 1 cup. He comes in to the ED with about 60 ml of darkred blood, according to him this is much less than what he has coughed up so far. He denies chest pain, dyspnea, weight loss, bone pains, severe headaches or fevers.\n\nPast Medical History:\nHTN, renal injury in 2016 s/p nephrectomy, HLD, colonic polyps\nh/o C.diff colitis, DM2, 50 pack year smoking hx h/o\nhypogammaglobulinemia- no tx necessary", "qa_list": [{"question": "Does this patient have bone pain?", "answer": "No", "justification": ["He denies chest pain, dyspnea, weight loss, bone pains, severe headaches or fevers."]}]}
{"id": 139, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04844749", "criterion": "Patients are excluded if they have known brain metastases or leptomeningeal metastases.", "note_date": "2020-10-14", "note": "2020-10-30 11:35 AM CHEST (PORTABLE AP)\nReason: r/o pna \nAdmitting Diagnosis: BRAIN METASTASES \nMEDICAL CONDITION: 39 year old man with metastatic renal cell CA to lungs and brain \nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION: r/o pna FINAL REPORT HISTORY: Metastatic renal cell carcinoma, with lung and brain metastases. pneumonia. \nCOMPARISON: 2020-10-7. FINDINGS: AP portable semi-upright view. The left subclavian venous catheter and the feeding tube have been removed. The heart and mediastinal contours are stable. At least 2 discrete masses are again noted in the left lower lobe, unchanged since 2020-10-7, and consistent with the known metastatic disease. There is no new parenchymal consolidation. There is no pleural effusion. Radiopaque contrast is noted in the visualized colon. Surgical clips are noted in the visualized right mid-upper abdomen, likely secondary to the right nephrectomy. IMPRESSION: 1) No evidence of pneumonia. 2) Left lower lobe masses consistent with known metastatic disease.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Does the patient have a brain metastasis?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["BRAIN METASTASES", "man with metastatic renal cell CA to lungs and brain"]}, {"question": "If so, when was that metastasis detected?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "Does the patient have a leptomeningeal metastasis?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the leptomeningeal metastasis detected?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 59, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04641351", "criterion": "Patient must not be pregnant", "note_date": "2020-10-30", "note": "Narrative History\nThe patient is here today for the following issues:\n1. Patient is pregnant. No bleeding or cramping. Followed by Dr. Kilgore. She did not intend to get pregnant again but would like to keep this pregnancy. 2. Labs in past indicated hyperthyroidism. This is being followed by endocrine. No palpitations.\n3. DM - Has not been taking insulin since birth of son. HgA1C >10. She will be seen by Endocrine today.\n4. Followed by Dr. Uzzell for CAD. No chest pain. On atenolol, aspirin and imdur.\nProblems\nDiabetes mellitus\nS/P Abortion : SPONTANEOUS 4/15\nChlamydia : CERVICITIS-TREATED\nH/O Abnormal pap test : '11 S/P COLPOSCOPY IN PAST; RECENT PAP NORMAL\nPositive PPD : NEG CXR\nPARONYCHIAL INFECTION : LEFT HAND 13\nEctopic pregnancy : 09\nCoronary artery disease\nAnemia\nShortness of breath\nHypertension\nGastroesophageal reflux disease\nElevated cholesterol\nHyperthyroidism\nObesity\nReview of Systems\nUnless mentioned in the history above the following ROS were asked and are negative: Constitutional, Respiratory, Cardiac, GI, Endocrine, Musculoskeletal.\n\nMedications\nAsa (ACETYLSALICYLIC Acid) 325MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD\nNatalcare Plus 1TAB PO qd\nATENOLOL 100MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD\nImdur (ISOSORBIDE MONONIT.(SR)) 30MG TABLET CR 24HR take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD\nAllergies\nNKA\nSocial History\nNP in Laplace - waiting for researcher job.\nSon born in 2085 name Uri, older child\nVital Signs\nBLOOD PRESSURE 122/70\nWEIGHT 220 lb\nAGE 32y5.7m\nPhysical Exam\nGENERAL: Healthy appearing\nLabs reviewed.\nAssessment and Plan\n1. Pregnancy - Counseled patient- especially on need to control sugars. Limited weight gain. She will discuss with ob and cardiology when to stop aspirin. She will likely be induced early.\n2. Hyperthyroidism - Denies symptoms- repeat today Follow up with Dr. Kirkpatrick.\n3. DM - Followed by diabetes clinic. HgA1C> 10 . Will need to restart insulin - counseled.\n4. CAD - On atenolol, asa, imdur. Followed by Dr. Uzzell.\n25 minutes spent with the patient - the majority counseling on above.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Is the patient pregnant at the time of the clinical note?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Patient is pregnant"]}, {"question": "If so, what is the gestational age at the time of the note?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 26, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-11-01", "note": "A 75-year-old woman who noticed floaters in her left eye for 2 weeks was referred to Tokyo Medical University Hospital in September 2010. She had a history of abdominal surgery for colon cancer (well-differentiated adenocarcinoma) in 2007. At presentation, her best-corrected decimal visual acuity was 0.6 oculus dexter (OD) and 0.9 oculus sinister (OS). Fundus examination revealed an orange-yellow mass that was 8 disc diameter (DD) in size with no measurable height at the inferotemporal side of the fundus OD, and a yellow-white mass 12 DD in size and 4.8 mm in height at the superior side of the fundus OS ( and ). Fluorescein angiography of the left eye showed hyperfluorescence inside the mass from early to late phase ( and ). Serum levels of carcinoembryonic antigen, cancer antigen 19-9, and cancer antigen 125 were within normal limits. A gallium-67 citrate scintigraphy scan showed no obvious abnormal uptake in the whole body including the eyes. Single-photon emission computed tomography with N-isopropyl-p-[123I] iodoamphetamine, which is known to be useful for the diagnosis of uveal melanoma, demonstrated no abnormal uptake in the eyes. In September 2011, the masses at the inferotemporal side OD and at the superior and inferior sides OS had enlarged, but visual acuity was preserved in both eyes. On both T1 and T2-weighted magnetic resonance images of the left orbit, iso-dense regions relative to the cerebral white matter were found consistent with the masses. A systemic workup to search for extraocular primary lesions revealed multiple nodules in the subcutaneous tissues of bilateral breasts on ultrasonography and neoplastic lesions in the right bronchial tubes on chest computed tomography. Histopathology of the tumor from a breast biopsy revealed foci of oval and spindle-shaped cells in alveolar and palisading arrangement (), and that from a lung biopsy showed oval hypertrophic nuclei and proliferation of atypical epithelial cells in rosette-like arrangement. Immunohistochemical staining was positive for CD56, chromogranin A, and synaptophysin. These imaging and histological findings were consistent with breast and lung carcinoid tumors. From the clinical findings, general systemic workup, and clinical course, this case was presumptively diagnosed as choroidal metastasis from breast or lung carcinoid tumor. Fifteen months after the initial examination, the masses in both eyes expanded further. The mass at the inferotemporal side of the right eye was 20 DD in size and 3.5 mm in height. The mass at the superior side of left eye was 28 DD in size and 14.9 mm in height, and the mass at the inferior side was 7 DD in size and 5.5 mm in height. The left optic disc was invisible because of the enlarged mass, and best-corrected visual acuity was reduced to hand motion ( and ). An indocyanine green angiogram of the right eye showed choroidal vessel staining inside the mass from the early phase, and a mixture of hyper- and hypofluorescence in the late phase ( and ). External-beam radiotherapy of 40 Gy was used to treat the tumor in the left eye. Although the tumor in the right eye showed a tendency toward rapid expansion and required aggressive treatment to preserve vision, the tumor was still small and we had reservations about using external-beam radiotherapy due to the risk of adverse effects such as radiation retinopathy. Consequently, PDT was performed on her right eye after obtaining informed consent. Standard PDT was conducted with intravenous infusion of verteporfin at a dose of 6 mg/m2 body surface area over 10 minutes. Treatment parameters were 689 nm at 50 J (600 mW)/cm2 for an exposure time of 83 seconds. The diameter of each spot was 6,500 \u03bcm, and three spots with overlapping margin were administered. The tumor at the inferotemporal side was reduced to 7 DD and no measurable height after treatment. Later, a new mass 4 DD in size appeared at the inferonasal side and remained unchanged. The tumor at the superior side of the left eye was reduced after radiotherapy and the optic disc became visible ( and ). Best-corrected decimal visual acuity was 0.8 OD and 50 cm hand movement OS at 14 months after PDT (30 months after the initial visit) and the patient\u2019s general condition was stable.", "qa_list": [{"question": "has this patient received external-beam radiotherapy?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["External-beam radiotherapy of 40 Gy was used to treat the tumor in the left eye"]}, {"question": "When did this patient received the external-beam radiotherapy?", "answer": "2020-11-01", "justification": ["2020-11-01"]}]}
{"id": 83, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "The patient must not have had a mastectomy", "note_date": "2020-11-16", "note": "A 26-year-old woman presented with an enlarging tender mass in the right breast. Her past medical history was significant for multiple breast tumors. At age 19 years, a sarcoma of the left breast arising from a tubular adenoma was discovered. At that time, she underwent a segmental mastectomy. At age 20 years, she was diagnosed with a borderline PT of the same breast, treated with a nipple sparing mastectomy of the left breast. The patient\u2019s family history was significant for breast cancer in two maternal aunts. On physical examination of the right breast, a moveable mass at three o\u2019clock at a distance of 2 cm from the nipple was palpated. A targeted ultrasound of the right breast revealed a hypoechoic mass at the site of the clinically palpable mass with an abrupt interface, circumscribed margins, a combined pattern of posterior acoustics and an oval/lobulated shape, as seen in Figure .\n\nThe right axilla demonstrated no lymphadenopathy. Because of her significant past medical history, current presentation of an enlarging right breast mass and the sheer size of the tumor, primary breast malignancy was raised as a concern. Subsequently, an ultrasound-guided core needle biopsy of the right breast was performed for a more accurate tissue diagnosis.\n\nHistology of the biopsy revealed sheets of basophilic spindle cells with high nuclear-to-cytoplasmic ratios, atypical mitoses and frequent prominent nucleoli. Malignant stromal cells were seen infiltrating between benign-appearing glans. Due to the high suspicion for malignancy, a computed tomography scan of the thorax, abdomen and pelvis was performed to assess for metastasis.\nThis scan indeed ruled out metastatic disease in this patient. The patient eventually had a simple mastectomy of the right breast. Histology of the mastectomy tissue demonstrated hypercellularity with malignant stromal cells and increased mitotic activity (30 mitoses per 10 high-power fields).\nBenign epithelium and periductal condensation of atypical stromal cells was also present.\nThe tissue showed multinucleated giant cells, which are commonly seen in malignant PTs. Additionally, a leaf-like architecture and hypercellular stroma that resembled fibroblasts and myofibroblasts were noted.\nImmunohistochemical stains were diffusely positive for cluster of differentiation 34 (CD34) and vimentin and focally positive for caldesmon.\nThe tissue was negative for epithelial membrane antigen, cytokeratin AE1/3, cytokeratin 7, desmin, p63 and melan-A. The morphological findings and immunohistochemical staining profile were consistent with the diagnosis of primary malignant PTs of the right breast. Beyond this, metastasis from the previously diagnosed PT from the left breast was ruled out.\nThe patient received one round of adjuvant radiation to the breast and was monitored for recurrence. At two years of oncologic surveillance, the patient did not show any signs of active metastasis.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient had a mastectomy of the left breast?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["At age 19 years, a sarcoma of the left breast arising from a tubular adenoma was discovered. At that time, she underwent a segmental mastectomy"]}, {"question": "If so, when?", "answer": "2013", "justification": ["At age 19 years, a sarcoma of the left breast arising from a tubular adenoma was discovered. At that time, she underwent a segmental mastectomy", "Note Date: 2020-11-16"]}]}
{"id": 84, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "The patient must not have had a mastectomy", "note_date": "2020-11-16", "note": "A 26-year-old woman presented with an enlarging tender mass in the right breast. Her past medical history was significant for multiple breast tumors. At age 19 years, a sarcoma of the left breast arising from a tubular adenoma was discovered. At that time, she underwent a segmental mastectomy. At age 20 years, she was diagnosed with a borderline PT of the same breast, treated with a nipple sparing mastectomy of the left breast. The patient\u2019s family history was significant for breast cancer in two maternal aunts. On physical examination of the right breast, a moveable mass at three o\u2019clock at a distance of 2 cm from the nipple was palpated. A targeted ultrasound of the right breast revealed a hypoechoic mass at the site of the clinically palpable mass with an abrupt interface, circumscribed margins, a combined pattern of posterior acoustics and an oval/lobulated shape, as seen in Figure .\n\nThe right axilla demonstrated no lymphadenopathy. Because of her significant past medical history, current presentation of an enlarging right breast mass and the sheer size of the tumor, primary breast malignancy was raised as a concern. Subsequently, an ultrasound-guided core needle biopsy of the right breast was performed for a more accurate tissue diagnosis.\n\nHistology of the biopsy revealed sheets of basophilic spindle cells with high nuclear-to-cytoplasmic ratios, atypical mitoses and frequent prominent nucleoli. Malignant stromal cells were seen infiltrating between benign-appearing glans. Due to the high suspicion for malignancy, a computed tomography scan of the thorax, abdomen and pelvis was performed to assess for metastasis.\nThis scan indeed ruled out metastatic disease in this patient. The patient eventually had a simple mastectomy of the right breast. Histology of the mastectomy tissue demonstrated hypercellularity with malignant stromal cells and increased mitotic activity (30 mitoses per 10 high-power fields).\nBenign epithelium and periductal condensation of atypical stromal cells was also present.\nThe tissue showed multinucleated giant cells, which are commonly seen in malignant PTs. Additionally, a leaf-like architecture and hypercellular stroma that resembled fibroblasts and myofibroblasts were noted.\nImmunohistochemical stains were diffusely positive for cluster of differentiation 34 (CD34) and vimentin and focally positive for caldesmon.\nThe tissue was negative for epithelial membrane antigen, cytokeratin AE1/3, cytokeratin 7, desmin, p63 and melan-A. The morphological findings and immunohistochemical staining profile were consistent with the diagnosis of primary malignant PTs of the right breast. Beyond this, metastasis from the previously diagnosed PT from the left breast was ruled out.\nThe patient received one round of adjuvant radiation to the breast and was monitored for recurrence. At two years of oncologic surveillance, the patient did not show any signs of active metastasis.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient had a mastectomy of the right breast?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["The patient eventually had a simple mastectomy of the right breast."]}, {"question": "If so, when?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 39, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2021-02-21", "note": "The patient is a 50-year-old man with a 10-year smoking history and a family history of lung and colorectal cancer. In April 2019, he experienced intermittent macrohematuria. Pelvic computed tomography (CT) revealed an irregular mass measuring 3.0 cm \u00d7 2.1 cm located at the anterior wall of the bladder. In early May, diagnostic transurethral resection of bladder tumor (TURBt) indicated that the tumor was cauliflower-like with broad base. The pathology revealed that the tumor was MIBC. As the chest/abdominal/pelvic CT scans indicated that the perivesical fat was invaded, the patient was diagnosed with clinical stage III-A (cT3bN0M0) bladder cancer.\nThe tissue sample collected during TURBt had a purity of 65% and was submitted for next-generation sequencing (NGS) analysis using a 642-gene panel. The tumor mutation burden (TMB) was 19.10 Mutants/Mb and the microsatellite state was stable (MSS). Furthermore, inactivating mutation in the RB1 gene was detected. The immunohistochemistry showed that the combined positive score (CPS) of the PD-L1 expression level was <1, as determined by using a monoclonal mouse anti-human PD-L1 clone (22C3) antibody, and the frequency of infiltrating CD8+ T cells was 2%.\nConsidering the promising efficacy of anti-PD-1 immunotherapy for patients with advanced bladder cancer and the high pCR rate in MIBC-related research, the patient strongly requested neoadjuvant chemotherapy combined with immunotherapy.\nSince May 14, 2019, the patient received the neoadjuvant treatment, which included four cycles of gemcitabine and cisplatin (GC) plus concurrent pembrolizumab. The regimen consisted of gemcitabine (1,000 mg/m2) on days 1 and 8, cisplatin (60 mg/m2) on day 2, and pembrolizumab (200 mg) on day 2. As a grade 3 adverse event of bone marrow suppression arose, the gemcitabine and cisplatin doses were decreased to 850 mg/m2 and 50 mg/m2 in the following cycles. After two cycles of neoadjuvant therapy, pelvic MRI showed that the thickness of the anterior wall of the bladder was lessened, and the thickest area was only 0.5 cm. The patient was considered to have achieved a partial response.\nOn July 28, 2019, pelvic MRI was repeated after the fourth cycle of neoadjuvant therapy. The imaging results showed that light thickening of anterior wall was persisting, but no node or obvious tumor was shown, and the result of urine cytology analysis was negative. Given these results, the patient strongly preferred bladder-sparing treatment.\nOn July 30, 2019, the patient received the second TURBt and randomized biopsies by cystoscopy. The pathological analysis showed inflammation and interstitial edema without any tumor in the bladder and the stage was downgraded to T0.\nConcurrent chemoradiotherapy started 1 month after the second TURBt. The regimen consisted of image-guided intensity-modulated conformal radiotherapy to the true pelvis with 45 Gy in 25 fractions plus the local lesion with 20 Gy in 10 fractions and concurrent cisplatin (40 mg/m2, once per week for 5 cycles). The side effects during chemoradiotherapy included second-degree fatigue and leukopenia. However, the patient recovered after symptomatic treatments. To evaluate the effect of chemoradiotherapy, the patient received pelvic MRI plus chest/abdominal CT on January 7 and cystoscopy on January 10, 2020. The results revealed that the bladder was normal with no sign of tumor recurrence. During this period, the patient received concurrent pembrolizumab (200 mg per 21 days). Finally, the patient achieved bladder preservation.\nIn addition, to monitor the status of the disease, urine tumor DNA sequencing analysis was carried out three times by a 642-gene panel from October 2019 to August 2020. The results showed that the mutation frequency of RB1 decreased significantly. On February 20, 2021, MRI results showed that there was still no tumor in the bladder. Cystoscopy and urine cytology analyses were also negative. The patient has maintained cancer-free status and excellent bladder function for 19 months at the end of follow-up.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Does this patient have histologically documented muscle-invasive bladder carcinoma (MIBC) from transurethral resection of bladder tumor (TURBT)", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["The pathology revealed that the tumor was MIBC"]}, {"question": "If so, when was that diagnosis made?", "answer": "early May 2019", "justification": ["In early May, diagnostic transurethral resection of bladder tumor (TURBt) indicated that the tumor was cauliflower-like with broad base. The pathology revealed that the tumor was MIBC"]}]}
{"id": 51, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2021-05-02", "note": "This is a 67-year-old Caucasian female who presented to our hospital with a chief complaint of persistent bright red blood per rectum. Her medical history was significant for hypertension, hyperlipidemia, diabetes mellitus type 2, coronary artery disease with three prior myocardial infarctions, recurrent cerebrovascular accidents requiring anticoagulation with warfarin, gastroesophageal reflux disease, asthma, and endometrial cancer status post radiation therapy. Fifteen months prior to the current presentation, the patient was noted to have a grade 1 endometrial adenoma but was not considered a good surgical candidate due to multiple comorbidities. Vaginal hysterectomy was considered but due to her long and narrow vagina, this option was deferred initially. Her only treatment option was radiation therapy and brachytherapy. She eventually underwent total abdominal hysterectomy with bilateral salpingo-oopherectomy due to continued pelvic pain. The patient denied any prior history of gastrointestinal (GI) bleeding. Her bleeding was described as one large episode of bright red blood per rectum associated with blood clots. She denied any abdominal pain, nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, constipation, or melena. The most recent colonoscopy was performed four months ago and revealed three diminutive polyps in the transverse colon with pathology confirming tubular adenoma.\nHer physical examination was significant for mild left-sided abdominal tenderness but was otherwise unremarkable. Rectal examination was notable for nonbleeding hemorrhoids and no visible blood. Blood work revealed white blood cells of 14.3k/uL (normal range 4.3-10.0 k/uL) and hemoglobin of 9.6 g/dL (normal range 11.8-14.8 g/dL), which is similar to the patient\u2019s baseline. Creatinine was slightly elevated to 1.2 and blood urea nitrogen was elevated to 39. International normalized ratio was 2.0. Due the large volume of hematochezia and presence of anemia, the patient will be admitted to the hospital and undergo a colonoscopy.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient had a colonoscopy?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["The most recent colonoscopy was performed four months ago"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the most recent colonoscopy performed, relative to the note date?", "answer": "August 2020", "justification": ["The most recent colonoscopy was performed four months ago\u201d, \u201cNote Date: 2020-12-13"]}]}
{"id": 130, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04187833", "criterion": "Prior organ transplantation including allogeneic stem-cell transplantation.", "note_date": "2021-05-19", "note": "35 y/o female with a history of T-cell lymphoma who presented for ablative chemotherapy with TBI Cytoxan followed by cord blood transplantation of a double cord, now transferred to the ICU for initiation of CRRT and management of hyperglycemia. Renal failure, acute (Acute renal failure, ARF) Assessment: CRRT stopped last PM UO has been steadily low throughout day Action: 80mg Lasix IV at noon today Response: Fair response to IV Lasix (~500cc over 3 hours) \nPlan: Repeat IV Lasix this evening Reassess need for CRRT in AM Hyperglycemia Assessment: FSBS persistently > 150 over the last 24 hours Action: Glargine was increased last PM and again this PM Humalog sliding scale tightened Response: Poor glycemic control on current regimen Plan: Continue q2h FSBS and q6h sliding scale Humalog Follow recommendations regarding insulin dosing. Lymphoma (Cancer, Malignant Neoplasm, Lymphoid) Assessment: Action: Response: Plan:", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient ever had an organ transplant ?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the transplantation date?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "Has the patient ever undergone stem-cell transplantation ?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["followed by cord blood transplantation"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the transplantation date?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 144, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04134260", "criterion": "Patients with a history of hepatitis C virus (HCV) infection must have been treated and cured. For patients with HCV infection who are currently on treatment, they are eligible if they have an undetectable HCV viral load within 30 days prior to registration.", "note_date": "2021-05-30", "note": "A 53-year-old woman with CHC genotype 1, biopsy-proven cirrhosis, and previous partial response to polyethylene glycosylated (PEGylated) interferon and ribavirin was started on telaprevir-based therapy. Cirrhosis was well compensated, without ascites or edema before and during therapy. Pretreatment laboratory evaluation revealed albumin 4.4 g/dL, aspartate aminotransferase (AST) 115 U/L, alanine aminotransferase (ALT) 120 U/L, alkaline phosphatase 191 U/L, total bilirubin 1.1 mg/dL, hemoglobin 16.3 g/dL, platelet count 183,000/\u03bcL, and hepatitis C virus (HCV) viral load 3,210,000 IU/mL. Upper endoscopy was negative for varices. Therapy was complicated by anemia requiring ribavirin dose reduction and erythropoietin therapy and rash that resolved after discontinuation of telaprevir. Viral load was 110 IU/mL at treatment week three and undetectable at week eight. PEGylated interferon and ribavirin were discontinued after 48 weeks of therapy. HCV viral load remained undetectable from week eight until the end of therapy. Laboratory evaluation at week 45 revealed albumin 2.7 g/dL, AST 125 U/L, ALT 67 U/L, total bilirubin 1.3 mg/dL, hemoglobin 10.1 g/dL, and platelet count 49,000/\u03bcL. Weight at the end of therapy was 132 lb (60 kg). One month after discontinuation of therapy, the patient presented with 5 lb weight gain (weight 137 lb) and new-onset ascites. Evaluation revealed albumin 3.1 g/dL, AST 77 U/L, ALT 44 U/L, total bilirubin 0.8 mg/dL, blood urea nitrogen (BUN) 8 mg/dL, creatinine 0.7 mg/dL, hemoglobin 13.5 g/dL, platelet count 105,000/\u03bcL, and virologic relapse with HCV viral load of 228 IU/mL. Abdominal magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) revealed a cirrhotic morphology, abdominal ascites, and recanalization of the umbilical vein and left retroperitoneal varices consistent with portal hypertension. The patient refused diagnostic paracentesis. An echocardiogram was obtained, which revealed normal left ventricular systolic and diastolic functions and right ventricular systolic pressure, with no sign of pulmonary hypertension. Ascites rapidly responded to sodium-restricted diet and diuretic therapy (spironolactone 50 mg, furosemide 20 mg daily). Repeat laboratory evaluation after control of ascites revealed an albumin level of 3.9 g/dL. Repeat viral load 3 months after the end of therapy was 528,810 IU/mL. Repeat abdominal MRI 7 months after therapy cessation showed no ascites.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Does the patient have a history of hepatitis C infection?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["A 53-year-old woman with CHC genotype 1"]}, {"question": "If so, has the patient received therapy for the Hepatitis C infection?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Therapy was complicated by anemia requiring ribavirin dose reduction"]}, {"question": "What is the patient's most recent HCV viral load, relative to the note date?", "answer": "528,810 IU/mL", "justification": ["Repeat viral load 3 months after the end of therapy was 528,810 IU/mL"]}, {"question": "When was that viral load measured?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 143, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04134260", "criterion": "Patients with a history of hepatitis C virus (HCV) infection must have been treated and cured. For patients with HCV infection who are currently on treatment, they are eligible if they have an undetectable HCV viral load within 30 days prior to registration.", "note_date": "2021-06-01", "note": "2021-6-1 7:44 AM ABDOMEN U.S. (COMPLETE STUDY); -59 DISTINCT PROCEDURAL SERVICE\nDUPLEX DOP ABD/PEL LIMITED Reason: Evaluate liver, hepatic vasculature, and spleen. \nMEDICAL CONDITION: 63 year old woman with cirrhosis secondary to hepatitis C, perceived increase in abdominal girth REASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION: Evaluate liver, hepatic vasculature, and spleen. Assess for ascites. \nFINAL REPORT ABDOMINAL ULTRASOUND INDICATION: 63-year-old woman with cirrhosis secondary to hepatitis C. perceived increase in abdominal girth. Comparison was performed to the previous ultrasound study from 2020-11-9. FINDINGS: The liver demonstrates diffuse increased echogenicity and coarsened echotexture. There is no evidence of focal masses, even though evaluation for focal masses in these settings is difficult. There is no evidence of intrahepatic or extrahepatic bile duct dilatation. Gallbladder is unremarkable. There is no evidence of free fluid. Right kidney is within normal limits. There is a normal hepatopetal flow in the main portal vein. There is a normal variability in flow direction in the left portal vein, anterior right portal vein and posterior right portal vein. IVC demonstrates normal flow as well. Spleen is not enlarged, measuring 9 cm. IMPRESSION: Diffuse coarsened echotexture of the liver consistent with known history of hepatitis C cirrhosis. Evaluation for the focal masses is limited in these settings. however no mass is seen.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Does the patient have a history of hepatitis C infection?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["cirrhosis secondary to hepatitis C"]}, {"question": "If so, has the patient received therapy for the Hepatitis C infection?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "What is the patient's most recent HCV viral load?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "When was that viral load measured?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 103, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "The interval between the last surgery for breast cancer (including re-excision of margins) and study entry must be no more than 70 days.", "note_date": "2021-06-05", "note": "2021-6-5 1:44 PM\nReason: 71 y/o woman s/p right lumpectomy, radiation for breast canc\nAdventist Health White Memorial Hospital\nMEDICAL CONDITION:\n71 year old woman with\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION:\n71 y/o woman s/p right lumpectomy, radiation for breast cancer\nFINAL REPORT\nDIGITAL DIAGNOSTIC BILATERAL MAMMOGRAM, [**2021-6-5**]\nHISTORY: Right lumpectomy and radiation therapy in 2010. Family history of\nbreast cancer in patient's mother at 44. Annual mammogram.\nFINDINGS: A wire was placed over the upper-outer right breast indicating the\nlumpectomy scar and routine views of both breasts were performed using digital\nmammography interpreted with computer-aided detection. The MLO views are\nsuboptimal due to inability of the patient to tolerate the positioning\nrequirements for these views due to her medical condition. Comparison made\nwith 2020-6-4, 2019-5-24, and film exam from 2018-3-23.\nBoth breasts demonstrate a heterogeneously dense glandular pattern. In the\nmedial right breast at mid/posterior depth, there are loosely associated\npunctate calcifications which are seen within a patch of glandular tissue\nmedially. These are likely benign; however, the patient refuses additional\nmagnification views. Six-month followup is recommended. Otherwise, no\ndominant mass or significant architectural distortion.\nIMPRESSION:\n1. Suboptimal exam due to patient positioning and inability to cooperate for\nadditional views due to her medical condition. Patient refused\nadditional views including magnification views of the right breast for\ncalcifications. Six- month followup right mammogram recommended. The results\nwere discussed by the technologist performing the mammogram with the patient's\nson.\nCedars Sinai Medical Center - RADS 3 - probably benign; six month followup recommended.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient ever had surgery for breast cancer?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["71 y/o woman s/p right lumpectomy, radiation for breast cancer"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the most recent such surgery, relative to the note date?", "answer": "2010", "justification": ["Right lumpectomy and radiation therapy in 2010"]}]}
{"id": 145, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03957876", "criterion": "Known history of HIV or active hepatitis B or C.", "note_date": "2021-06-13", "note": "2021-6-13 12:03 PM MR HEAD W & W/O CONTRAST\nReason: pls assess for HIV related pathology \nAdmitting Diagnosis: WEAKNESS Contrast: MAGNEVIST Amt: 16\nMEDICAL CONDITION: 48 year old man with HIV/AIDS now with bilateral lower extremity weakness, memory problems. REASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION: pls assess for HIV related pathology No contraindications for IV contrast WET READ: WED 2021-6-13 7:58 PM No acute intracranial process. Global cerebral atrophy and chronic small vessel ischemic disease. FINAL REPORT INDICATION: History of HIV/AIDS, now with bilateral lower extremity weakness and memory problems. Assess for HIV-related pathology. TECHNIQUE: MRI of the brain was performed including sagittal T1, axial T1 pre- and post-contrast, axial T2, axial FLAIR, axial T2 susceptibility, sagittal MP-RAGE with axial and coronal reformations, and diffusion-weighted sequences. COMPARISON: NECT head from 2021-6-13. \nFINDINGS: There is no evidence of intracranial hemorrhage, edema, shift of normally midline structures, hydrocephalus, mass, or infarction. Periventricular and subcortical FLAIR-/T2- hyperintense foci are consistent with sequelae of chronic small vessel ischemic disease. Prominence of the ventricles and sulci are consistent with global cerebral atrophy, likely related to known HIV/AIDS. Asymmetry of the lateral ventricles, with the left lateral ventricle larger than the right, is likely congenital/developmental in etiology. There are normal arterial flow-voids throughout. No abnormal enhancement is seen. The orbits are unremarkable. Mucosal thickening is seen within the bilateral maxillary sinuses, bilateral sphenoid and scattered ethmoidal air cells, and scattered bilateral mastoid air cells. IMPRESSION: 1. No acute intracranial process. 2. Findings consistent with sequelae of chronic small vessel ischemic disease. 3. Global cerebral atrophy, consistent with history of HIV/AIDS. 2021-6-13 12:03 PM MR HEAD W & W/O CONTRAST \nReason: pls assess for HIV related pathology Admitting Diagnosis: WEAKNESS Contrast: MAGNEVIST Amt: 16 FINAL REPORT", "qa_list": [{"question": "Does the patient have a history of HIV infection?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["48 year old man with HIV/AIDS"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the patient diagnosed with HIV?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 41, "trial": "https://example.com/", "criterion": "Shoulder biopsy at a certain point in time", "note_date": "2021-07-03", "note": "The patient is 68-year-old man with a 6-month history of a pruritic rash that began on his back and legs and spread to his knees, elbows, shoulders, and chest. Patch testing showed 1+ positivity for both sodium laurel sulfate and benzaprene #4, which were deemed not clinically relevant. On examination, he had scattered erythematous scaly patches on the upper chest, shoulders, and back with overlying excoriation. A biopsy of the right shoulder performed 5 months ago  showed an unremarkable epidermis and a sparse perivascular and interstitial mixed infiltrate containing scattered interstitial eosinophils, consistent with a DHR. Oral prednisone initially cleared the rash, but it recurred on discontinuation. The rash was also recalcitrant to trials of topical steroids, oral antihistamines, and topical tacrolimus. I am therefore transitioning him to dupilumab at standard dosing and he will follow up after 3 months.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient had a shoulder biopsy?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["A biopsy of the right shoulder performed 5 months ago"]}, {"question": "If so, when?", "answer": "February 2021", "justification": ["Note Date: 2021-7-3\u201d, \u201c\u201cA biopsy of the right shoulder performed 5 months ago"]}]}
{"id": 101, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "Oncotype DX Recurrence Score of less than or equal to 18 on diagnostic core biopsy or resected specimen.", "note_date": "2021-07-18", "note": "A 77-year-old Caucasian man with a history of Hodgkin\u2019s lymphoma treated with thymectomy and radiation at the age of 28 presented to the hospital on 2021-6-30 with a chief complaint of a painless mass in his left breast of a few days\u2019 duration. His other comorbidities included atrial fibrillation on anticoagulation, obstructive sleep apnea, and a remote history of pulmonary embolism. He denied any known family history of breast or other types of cancer.\nOn examination of the left breast, the area was non-erythematous with a palpable 1.5 cm firm, circular, painless mass in the left lower quadrant, subareolar region. The patient had a mammogram on July 2 showing a 1.8 cm x 1.8 cm x 1.5 cm left subareolar lobulated mass highly suggestive of malignancy (BIRADS 5). Left breast ultrasound showed a hypoechoic vascular mass with microlobular margins of similar size. Left axillary lymph nodes and right breast appeared normal at the time of imaging. A positron emission tomography (PET) scan for initial cancer screening was performed with no signs of nodal or distant metastasis. Needle core biopsy of the mass was performed and showed infiltrating ductal carcinoma (IDC) Grade 1 (mitotic rate: score 1, pleomorphism: score 2, tubules: score 3, total score: 5). Immunohistochemical results were estrogen receptor (ER) positive (>90%), progesterone receptor (PR) positive (>90%), HER2/Neu 2+ equivocal with no amplification on fluorescence in situ hybrid (FISH), and E-Cadherin positive within tumor cells. The patient tested negative for mutations in the genes BRCA 1 and 2, TP53, PTEN, and PALB2.\nThe patient underwent a left modified radical mastectomy on July 10 and a 1.7 x 1.5 cm solid, pale pink, well circumscribed mass was found subjacent to the nipple with a 0.4 cm central area of hemorrhage. Eight lymph nodes were dissected with one positive for metastatic carcinoma with three metastatic foci in the node. The largest focus measured 0.3 cm and was HER2 negative. Microscopic evaluation determined the patient to have invasive micropapillary carcinoma of the left breast and pathologic staging was evaluated at PT1c N1a Mx. Oncotype DX for breast recurrence was four, distance recurrence risk at nine years at 3%, and no apparent benefit of chemotherapy. After discussing the treatment options at length, the patient opted for surveillance with annual mammograms and no adjuvant chemotherapy, hormonal therapy, or radiation therapy.", "qa_list": [{"question": "What is this patient's Oncotype DX Recurrence Score?", "answer": "4", "justification": [" Oncotype DX for breast recurrence was four"]}, {"question": "When was that score computed?", "answer": "July 2021", "justification": ["The patient underwent a left modified radical mastectomy on July 10", "Note Date: 2021-7-18"]}]}
{"id": 137, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2021-07-28", "note": "TITLE:\n71 year old admit from ED\nadmit there as found down by family covered\nin malaena, recent scope on the 21^st July 2021 showed stable stomach ulcer\nand duodenal ulcer, at that time patient found to be in acute on\nchronic renal failure with creat @ 4.8, this gentleman had renal TX in\n2019, other PMH significant for htn, chole, gout\nhe has a working\nfistula in left arm, lethargic but oreineted on admission with no\ncomplaints of pain\nIn ed HCT dropped 10 points from 31> 21, access issues hot a line in rt\nfem unable to place PIV, received total 1l in St Mary's Hospital transfer to MICU to\nscope\nb/p stable 120-130 systolic with maps > 65, HR 85-90 bpm sinus\nbut with ST depression for which the team area aware and cycling CE..no\nfoley placed ? when last passed urine but unable to place foley, condom\ncath place and passed urine via this at 1800hrs 200cc\nK on admission to\nthe unit > 5.0 therefore received dex/insulin, now on Q1 blood sticks\nand PM labs pending\nGi team scoped at 1800hrs, the patient was receiving x1 uprbcs en route\nfrom ED, and has received x2 more since being here..he received\nfent/versed and 500cc nsaline for transient drop in BP to 90s\ntolerated the procedure well and was found to have the stomach ulcer\noozing which they failed to clip but were able to cortirise\nNow for serial HCTS, b/p HR sats stable at this time and awaiting PM\nlytes", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient had a kidney transplant?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["this gentleman had renal TX"]}, {"question": "If so, when?", "answer": "2019", "justification": ["this gentleman had renal TX in 2019"]}]}
{"id": 113, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "Pathologic staging of pN0(i+) or pN0(mol+), pN1, pN2, or pN3 disease.", "note_date": "2021-07-28", "note": "This is a 59-year-old female who underwent a total gastrectomy on 2018-4-12 with regional lymph node dissection and a jejunal pouch with Roux-en-Y reconstruction for a tumor (6.1 \u00d7 5.1 cm in size) in the upper corpus. Exfoliative cytology of the peritoneal lavage fluid during the operation was positive for adenocarcinoma (CY1). There was no metastasis to the liver. Microscopically, the tumor was a medullary type poorly differentiated adenocarcinoma with lymphoid stroma, infiltrating through the serosa (pT3) and involving regional lymph nodes (pN3; number of metastasis-positive per dissected lymph nodes, 9/23). Based on these surgical findings, the tumor was diagnosed as stage IV (pT3, pN3, sH0, sP0, sM0, CY1), and adjuvant chemotherapy combining 5-FU (total 150 mg), methotrexate (900 mg) and leukovorin (45 mg) was subsequently performed. One year after the operation, endoscopy showed a tumor in the jejunal pouch along the suture line, and examination of a biopsy specimen revealed a poorly differentiated adenocarcinoma. CT demonstrated an intraluminal tumor in the jejunal pouch without any other recurrence. A course of chemotherapy consisting S-1 (2-week regimen) was feasible and repeated 10 times in an outpatient clinic. During the therapy, the recurrent tumor in jejunal pouch completely disappeared, and a biopsy revealed no remnant tumor tissue. The patient has now been well without any evidence of recurrence for 39 months.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Was this patient ever diagnosed with stomach  cancer?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["This is a 59-year-old female who underwent a total gastrectomy"]}, {"question": "If so, what was the pathologic stage of the patient's stomach cancer regarding lymph node involvement?", "answer": "pN3", "justification": ["Based on these surgical findings, the tumor was diagnosed as stage IV (pT3, pN3, sH0, sP0, sM0, CY1)"]}, {"question": "When was the pathologic staging performed?", "answer": "April 2018", "justification": ["underwent a total gastrectomy on 2018-4-12"]}, {"question": "What classification system was used for the pathologic staging?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 138, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2021-07-28", "note": "TITLE:\n71 year old admit from ED\nadmit there as found down by family covered\nin malaena, recent scope on the 21^st July 2021 showed stable stomach ulcer\nand duodenal ulcer, at that time patient found to be in acute on\nchronic renal failure with creat @ 4.8, this gentleman had renal TX in\n2019, other PMH significant for htn, chole, gout\nhe has a working\nfistula in left arm, lethargic but oreineted on admission with no\ncomplaints of pain\nIn ed HCT dropped 10 points from 31> 21, access issues hot a line in rt\nfem unable to place PIV, received total 1l in St Mary's Hospital transfer to MICU to\nscope\nb/p stable 120-130 systolic with maps > 65, HR 85-90 bpm sinus\nbut with ST depression for which the team area aware and cycling CE..no\nfoley placed ? when last passed urine but unable to place foley, condom\ncath place and passed urine via this at 1800hrs 200cc\nK on admission to\nthe unit > 5.0 therefore received dex/insulin, now on Q1 blood sticks\nand PM labs pending\nGi team scoped at 1800hrs, the patient was receiving x1 uprbcs en route\nfrom ED, and has received x2 more since being here..he received\nfent/versed and 500cc nsaline for transient drop in BP to 90s\ntolerated the procedure well and was found to have the stomach ulcer\noozing which they failed to clip but were able to cortirise\nNow for serial HCTS, b/p HR sats stable at this time and awaiting PM\nlytes", "qa_list": [{"question": "Does this patient have a history of hypertension?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["PMH significant for htn"]}]}
{"id": 70, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2021-08-06", "note": "A 52-year-old married HIV infected woman, who had been on ART for the last seven years (Zidovudine + Lamivudine + Nevirapine), was referred for evaluation of skin lesions that had appeared nine months ago. There was no history of any opportunistic infection before the onset of skin nodules. Except arthralgia and mild constitutional symptoms, her general condition was fairly good and all her vitals were within normal limits. On examination, there were multiple, dusky red, large nodules and plaques over the feet, ankles, soles, shins, knees, and elbows. Majority of the lesions were non tender and symmetrically distributed. Few nodules over the soles were painful and ruptured with sero-sanguinous discharge. Some nodules over the shins healed with hyperpigmented macules. Inguinal lymph nodes on both sides were palpable and firm in consistency. There were no lesions elsewhere over the body and no mucosal lesions were present. Systemic examination disclosed no abnormalities. On ophthalmologic examination, there were no lesions in the eyes. Clinically, Kaposi's sarcoma or bacillary angiomatosis was suspected and the case was evaluated. \nLaboratory tests disclosed the following values: Hemoglobin, 10.4 gm/dl; total leukocyte count, 3600 cells/mm3; total red blood cell count, 2.70 million/mm3; erythrocyte sedimentation rate, 80 mm/1st hour; reticulocyte count, 2.5%; packed cell volume, 29.4%; mean corpuscular volume, 108.9 fL; mean corpuscular hemoglobin, 38.5 pg; platelet count, 3, 21,000/mm3, differential count \u2013 59% neutrophils, 32% lymphocytes, 7% eosinophils, 2% monocytes; serum glutamic oxalotransferase (SGOT), 48u/L; serum glutamic phosphotransferase (SGPT), 96 u/L; serum alkaline phosphatase, 102 Iu/L; CD4+ count, 164/mm3; HIV RNA PCR (viral load), 666 IU/ml. Peripheral smear revealed macrocytic normochromic erythropoiesis and negative for immature cells. Mantoux test, serological tests for syphilis (VDRL, TPHA), hepatitis B and C, and anti-nuclear antibodies (ANA) were negative. Chest radiography and abdominal echography were normal. Two biopsies from nodule and plaque lesions were taken. Both specimens showed areas of ribbon-like thickening of collagen and areas with infiltrates of neutrophils and abundant neutrophilic nuclear dust. Few of the vessels showed features of vasculitis with fibrin in their walls. No proliferation of spindle cells was seen. Also, no vascular proliferation was observed. Based on histopathology, a diagnosis of EED was arrived at and the patient's blood was sent for estimation of serum IgA level which was 11.3 g/l (normal, 0.7-4). The patient was treated with oral dapsone 100 mg/day. After 2 weeks period, majority of the lesions resolved, but the patient developed hypersensitivity reaction to dapsone and the drug was withdrawn. After four weeks, colchicine 0.5 mg twice daily was given in place of dapsone. The response was slow and smaller lesions regressed, while larger lesions are in the process of regression. As the patient has low CD4+ count inspite of being on ART since seven years, she was referred to the nearest ART\u2013plus centre for second line therapy. The second line therapy (atazanavir-based) was started in the month of November 2021.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Did the patient have a hypersensitivity reaction to dapsone?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["the patient developed hypersensitivity reaction to dapsone"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the most recent such reaction?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, was dapsone substituted by another treatment ?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["\"colchicine 0.5 mg twice daily was given in place of dapsone\". (5)Answer: NA. Justification: NA"]}]}
{"id": 69, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2021-08-06", "note": "A 52-year-old married HIV infected woman, who had been on ART for the last seven years (Zidovudine + Lamivudine + Nevirapine), was referred for evaluation of skin lesions that had appeared nine months ago. There was no history of any opportunistic infection before the onset of skin nodules. Except arthralgia and mild constitutional symptoms, her general condition was fairly good and all her vitals were within normal limits. On examination, there were multiple, dusky red, large nodules and plaques over the feet, ankles, soles, shins, knees, and elbows. Majority of the lesions were non tender and symmetrically distributed. Few nodules over the soles were painful and ruptured with sero-sanguinous discharge. Some nodules over the shins healed with hyperpigmented macules. Inguinal lymph nodes on both sides were palpable and firm in consistency. There were no lesions elsewhere over the body and no mucosal lesions were present. Systemic examination disclosed no abnormalities. On ophthalmologic examination, there were no lesions in the eyes. Clinically, Kaposi's sarcoma or bacillary angiomatosis was suspected and the case was evaluated. \nLaboratory tests disclosed the following values: Hemoglobin, 10.4 gm/dl; total leukocyte count, 3600 cells/mm3; total red blood cell count, 2.70 million/mm3; erythrocyte sedimentation rate, 80 mm/1st hour; reticulocyte count, 2.5%; packed cell volume, 29.4%; mean corpuscular volume, 108.9 fL; mean corpuscular hemoglobin, 38.5 pg; platelet count, 3, 21,000/mm3, differential count \u2013 59% neutrophils, 32% lymphocytes, 7% eosinophils, 2% monocytes; serum glutamic oxalotransferase (SGOT), 48u/L; serum glutamic phosphotransferase (SGPT), 96 u/L; serum alkaline phosphatase, 102 Iu/L; CD4+ count, 164/mm3; HIV RNA PCR (viral load), 666 IU/ml. Peripheral smear revealed macrocytic normochromic erythropoiesis and negative for immature cells. Mantoux test, serological tests for syphilis (VDRL, TPHA), hepatitis B and C, and anti-nuclear antibodies (ANA) were negative. Chest radiography and abdominal echography were normal. Two biopsies from nodule and plaque lesions were taken. Both specimens showed areas of ribbon-like thickening of collagen and areas with infiltrates of neutrophils and abundant neutrophilic nuclear dust. Few of the vessels showed features of vasculitis with fibrin in their walls. No proliferation of spindle cells was seen. Also, no vascular proliferation was observed. Based on histopathology, a diagnosis of EED was arrived at and the patient's blood was sent for estimation of serum IgA level which was 11.3 g/l (normal, 0.7-4). On 2021-09-15 the patient started treatment with oral dapsone 100 mg/day. After two weeks period, majority of the lesions resolved. But the patient developed hypersensitivity reaction to dapsone and the drug was withdrawn. After four weeks, colchicine 0.5 mg twice daily was given in place of dapsone. The response was slow and smaller lesions regressed, while larger lesions are in the process of regression. As the patient has low CD4+ count inspite of being on ART since seven years, she was referred to the nearest ART\u2013plus centre for second line therapy. The second line therapy (atazanavir-based) was started in the month of November 2021.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Was the patient ever diagnosed with Erythema elevated diutinum?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Based on histopathology, a diagnosis of EED was arrived"]}, {"question": "If so, what is the date of the diagnosis?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "Did the patient ever receive the first line treatment for their EED diagnosis?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["patient started treatment with oral dapsone 100 mg/day"]}, {"question": "If so, when?", "answer": "On 2021-09-15", "justification": ["On 2021-09-15 the patient started treatment with oral dapsone 100 mg/day"]}]}
{"id": 67, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04844749", "criterion": "Participants must have a life expectancy > 3 months.", "note_date": "2021-08-11", "note": "Hepatic failure, fulminant Assessment: AAO x 3, although makes comments incongruent to conversation at hand. Pleasant, cooperative. Afebrile. Upper extremities move against resistance, lower extremities barely move on bed (partially due to prior knee surgeries and/or anasarca. Sclera icteric. Remains on Neosynephrine. Titrated down from 4mcg to 2mcg/kg/min. Midodrine and albumin given today. MAP in 60s for most of shift. Lungs clear in upper airways, diminished in bases. O2 sat > 95% on RA. Abdomen distended with ascites. Hypoactive BS. Some pain upon movement. Treated with Dilaudid 0.25mg IV. Skin jaundiced/bronze. Stage II (broken excoriation) to inner thighs near gluteal folds. Cleaned with foam cleanser and barrier cream applied. Long discussion with wife and patient regarding DNR/DNI status, continuation of care, etc. Pt wishes to remain full code at this time. Also would like to receive dialysis treatment knowing that he is not a candidate for a liver transplant. Pt understands that with dialysis but without a liver, life expectancy is approximately 3 months (per Dr. Brown). Explained to patient and wife that decision does not need to be made immediately, but that constant/frequent conversation needs to occur in revisiting the issue. Plan: Maintain MAP between 55-60. Titrate Neo off as tolerated. Continue to turn and position for comfort being observant of excoriation to inner thighs/gluteal folds. Possible HD tomorrow (per Dr. Brown).", "qa_list": [{"question": "Does this patient have a life expectancy of more than 3 months relative to the date of the clinical note?", "answer": "No", "justification": ["Also would like to receive dialysis treatment knowing that he is not a candidate for a liver transplant. Pt understands that with dialysis but without a liver, life expectancy is approximately 3 months"]}]}
{"id": 60, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04641351", "criterion": "Patient must not be pregnant", "note_date": "2021-08-18", "note": "2021-8-18 10:09 PM\nPELVIS LIMITED; PELVIS U.S., TRANSVAGINAL                       Clip # 82596\nReason: PELVIC PAIN ,EVAL FOR MASS\nCLINICAL INFORMATION & QUESTIONS TO BE ANSWERED:\nFINAL REPORT\nINDICATION: 42 year old quadriplegic woman with several months of vaginal\nbleeding, now increasing. Patient is post menopausal, not pregnant.  Per\npatient report, one ovary has been removed though the patient is not certain\nwhich.\nCOMPARISON: None.\nPELVIC US: Transabdominal and transvaginal examinations were performed.\nTransvaginal examination performed for better assessment of the uterus.\nThis examination was extremely limited as the patient is quadriplegic and\ncontracted. Transvaginal ultrasound reveals a retroverted uterus which\nmeasures roughly 7.1 x 4.3 x 8.6 cm in size.  There are multiple masses\nassociated with the uterus. Several of these masses are hypoechoic and have\nthe appearance of fibroids.  Others are isoechoic and extend anteriorly and to\nthe left of the uterus. These may represent changes in relation with prior\nvesico-vaginal fistula. However, complete evaluation of this area was not\npossible. The endometrium is difficult to visualize and is distorted. Where\nseen, it measures approximately 3 mm in thickness.  No separate adnexal masses\nare identified. The right ovary was tentatively seen though neither ovary was\nidentified with certainty. There is a trace amount of fluid in the pelvis.\nIMPRESSION: Limited pelvic ultrasound. Multiple masses associated with the\nuterus with distorted endometrium. Trace free fluid in the pelvis.  It may be\nhelpful to corellate this exam with a CT of the pelvis for further evaluation.\nDuring the examination, the patient lost a large amount of blood onto the\nexamination table. These results were promptly discussed with Dr. Mark Paterson.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Is the patient pregnant at the time of the clinical note?", "answer": "No", "justification": ["Patient is post menopausal, not pregnant"]}, {"question": "If so, what is the gestational age at the time of the note?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 64, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2021-08-18", "note": "A 23-year-old man presented in 2019 with a white blood cell count of 34 \u00d7 109/L with 87% circulating blasts by manual differential count. Flow cytometric analysis on the peripheral blood (PB) revealed 89.6% blasts by CD45/SSC gating. The blasts expressed CD10, CD19, CD34, HLA-DR, and CD20 (dim); partially expressed CD13, CD15, and CD33; and did not express CD2, CD7, CD56, and CD117. A subsequent bone marrow (BM) biopsy was done the next day but was a dry tap; therefore, flow cytometry and other cytogenetic studies were not performed on the BM sample. Immunohistochemistry (IHC) studies were performed on the BM biopsy showing 95% blasts positive for CD79a, PAX-5, and TdT, and negative for CD20 and myeloperoxidase (MPO). The morphology and immunophenotype of the blasts in the peripheral blood and bone marrow biopsy were consistent with B-lineage lymphoblastic leukemia. We did perform FISH analysis with a B-ALL panel on the peripheral blood specimen which revealed CDKN2A (p16 at 9q21) gene deletion on one or both chromosomes 9. Fusion of BCR and ABL1 was not detected. Intensive chemotherapy was initiated according to the CALGB 10403 \"Adolescent Young Adult\" regimen, and the patient achieved complete remission. He then proceeded to consolidation without consideration of allogeneic hematopoietic cell transplantation (allo-HCT) based on standard of care for B-cell ALL with favorable cytogenetic and molecular profile. However, the patient had prolonged cytopenias during consolidation therapy culminating in treatment delay. In early January of 2020 (approximately 24 weeks after initial diagnosis), the patient's complete blood count revealed 27% blasts. Flow cytometry analysis was performed on the PB; the blasts expressed HLA-DR, CD15, CD33, and CD117; partially expressed CD13 and CD56; and did not express CD2, CD3, CD5, CD7, CD10, CD19, CD20, or CD34. A restaging BM biopsy was performed the same day; unfortunately, it was again a dry tap, so flow cytometric analysis could not be performed. The histology examination of the BM biopsy revealed a hypocellular (30%) marrow with 85% recurrent leukemic blasts. IHC showed the blasts were now positive for MPO, while CD10, PAX-5 CD20, CD79a, and TdT were negative. The overall findings on PB and BM biopsy were consistent with a lineage switch to acute myeloid leukemia (AML). Although it was a dry tap, a very small amount of aspiration specimen was obtained in the EDTA tube. Despite few marrow spicules on the aspiration smear, cytogenetic analysis and FISH studies were performed. FISH analysis with both B-ALL and AML panels showed persistence of a heterozygous CDKN2A deletion, plus the acquisition of a TP53 deletion, and 7q and 17q duplications. Cytogenetic studies now showed a complex karyotype in 18/20 metaphases, 47,X,-Y,add(1)(p36.1),+18,+add(18)(q23) [12]/47\u201348,X,\u2212Y,del(1)(p32p36.1),add(11)(p11.2),+18,+18[cp6]/46,XY. Intensive salvage chemotherapy was initiated with the MEC regimen, and nadir BM evaluation was hypocellular without blasts, although FISH demonstrated low-level CDKN2A deletion, consistent with minimal residual disease. Ten days later, a rising PB blast percentage prompted another BM biopsy which showed persistence of AL with the same phenotype and FISH with CDKN2A deletion. Further intensive chemotherapy was initiated.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Did the patient receive intensive chemotherapy?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Intensive chemotherapy was initiated"]}, {"question": "Was Etoposide part of the patient\u2019s chemotherapy regimen ?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Intensive salvage chemotherapy was initiated with the MEC regimen"]}]}
{"id": 44, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04871529", "criterion": "Participants must have Zubrod performance status 0-2.", "note_date": "2021-10-04", "note": "The patient is a 53-year-old woman suffering from advanced breast cancer with bone pain, who came to our observation for the first time in July 2020. Routine radiological and scintigraphic bone examination confirmed multifocal bone spread with a mixed osteolytic-osteosclerotic pattern. Biphosphonate (Aredia 90 mg/4 weeks) and endocrine treatments were immediately started (Zoladex 3.6 mg/month and Tamoxifen 20 mg/day) together with palliative radiotherapy of left hemipelvis.\nThe first FDG PET scan was ruled out in Gliwice branch of our institution on October 1, 2020 in order to exclude metastatic spread to soft-tissues. It was performed with the use of a Philips Gemini GXL device, 60 min after an injection of 333 MBq of radiotracer. Numerous skeletal lesions were detected, with no metastases outside bones.\nA bone scan showed progression in April 2021. Due to clinical worsening of the patient's condition, with Zubrod score having increased from 2 to 3, Tamoxifen was substituted with an aromatase inhibitor (Femara 2.5 mg/day). The second palliative radiotherapy was performed on the thoracic spine from April to May 2021.\nA clinical improvement was observed last month, with Zubrod score having returned to 2 and a stable bone scan. If the Zubrod score shifts down further to 1 over the next few months, Zoladex will be stopped and the patient will receive only bifosphonate and aromatase inhibitor treatment.", "qa_list": [{"question": "What is this patient\u2019s most recent Zubrod score, relative to the note date?", "answer": "2", "justification": ["A clinical improvement was observed last month, with Zubrod score having returned to 2"]}, {"question": "When was this score observed?", "answer": "September 2021", "justification": ["A clinical improvement was observed last month, with Zubrod score having returned to 2\u201d, \u201cNote Date: 2021-10-4"]}]}
{"id": 46, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04871529", "criterion": "Participants must have a bone scan within 56 days prior to registration if they have bone pain or elevated serum alkaline phosphatase.", "note_date": "2021-10-04", "note": "The patient is a 53-year-old woman suffering from advanced breast cancer with bone pain, who came to our observation for the first time in July 2020. Routine radiological and scintigraphic bone examination confirmed multifocal bone spread with a mixed osteolytic-osteosclerotic pattern. Biphosphonate (Aredia 90 mg/4 weeks) and endocrine treatments were immediately started (Zoladex 3.6 mg/month and Tamoxifen 20 mg/day) together with palliative radiotherapy of left hemipelvis.\nThe first FDG PET scan was ruled out in Gliwice branch of our institution on October 1, 2020 in order to exclude metastatic spread to soft-tissues. It was performed with the use of a Philips Gemini GXL device, 60 min after an injection of 333 MBq of radiotracer. Numerous skeletal lesions were detected, with no metastases outside bones.\nA bone scan showed progression in April 2021. Due to clinical worsening of the patient's condition, with Zubrod score having increased from 2 to 3, Tamoxifen was substituted with an aromatase inhibitor (Femara 2.5 mg/day). The second palliative radiotherapy was performed on the thoracic spine from April to May 2021.\nA clinical improvement was observed last month, with Zubrod score having returned to 2 and a stable bone scan. If the Zubrod score shifts down further to 1 over the next few months, Zoladex will be stopped and the patient will receive only bifosphonate and aromatase inhibitor treatment.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient had a bone scan?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["A bone scan showed progression in April 2021"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the most recent bone scan performed, relative to the note date?", "answer": "April 2021", "justification": ["A bone scan showed progression in April 2021"]}]}
{"id": 118, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04641351", "criterion": "Known or suspected hypersensitivity to Zilretta (or component of Zilretta) or triamcinolone acetonide", "note_date": "2021-10-10", "note": "A 24-year-old woman with keloid scars on her upper back had been treated with multiple intralesional injections of triamcinolone acetonide plus 1% lidocaine (xylocaine) during the previous 10 years without any reaction. After her most recent treatment, she developed generalized urticaria, lip angioedema, numbness on her face, abdominal pain, vomiting, chest tightness, and hypotension 2 minutes after injection. Lidocaine hypersensitivity was suspected. She decided to stop the treatment, without any medication being prescribed for her condition. She was healthy, with no history of any other medication use and no history of drug/food allergy or atopic diseases. After 1 year she returned for intralesional injection of triamcinolone acetonide only (without lidocaine), and was scheduled once a month for this regimen. The first injection was tolerated well. The reaction occurred at the time of the second injection, with numbness on her face developing 15 minutes after injection and 5 minutes later with urticaria on her chest wall and both arms, together with hypotension (blood pressure of 90/60 mmHg). At the emergency room, her vital signs revealed blood pressure 90/60 mmHg, pulse rate 72 beats/min, respiratory rate 20 breaths/min, temperature 37.2\u2103, and oxygen saturation 95% on room air. Immediate treatment with an intramuscular injection of adrenaline, intravenous dexamethasone and chlorpheniramine was given, and the patient quickly recovered. Laboratory investigation showed white blood cells 13.7\u00d7109/L (neutrophils 86%, lymphocytes 11%, monocytes 2%, eosinophils 1%) and serum tryptase 5.89 ng/mL (1.9\u201313.5 ng/mL). Anaphylaxis was diagnosed. The allergology workup was performed 4 weeks after the anaphylaxis event to clarify the identity of the culprit drug. Skin tests with triamcinolone acetonide, lidocaine, and the excipients carboxymethylcellulose (CMC), benzyl alcohol and polysorbate 80, were performed, together with alternative corticosteroids (hydrocortisone, methylprednisolone, and dexamethasone). The skin test concentrations were as previously reported  and are summarized in . Histamine and normal saline were used as positive and negative controls, respectively. The skin prick test (SPT) was considered positive when a wheal of more than 3 mm in diameter presented after 15 minutes. If the SPT was negative, an intradermal test (IDT) was performed by injecting 0.02\u20130.05 mL of the reagent solution intradermally. Results were interpreted after 20 minutes, and a positive result was declared when the wheal and erythema extended more than 2 mm from the initial injection papule. When SPT and IDT were negative, a provocation test was performed. The patient had a positive SPT for triamcinolone acetonide, which confirmed IgE-mediated hypersensitivity. The SPT for the other corticosteroids, including hydrocortisone, methylprednisolone, and dexamethasone, were negative. Subcutaneous provocation with lidocaine (cumulative dose of 3.2 mL of 1% lidocaine) and oral CMC (cumulative dose of 250 mg) was well-tolerated and considered negative.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient ever presented hypersensitivity reaction to triamcinolone acetonide?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["intralesional injection of triamcinolone acetonide only", "The reaction occurred at the time of the second injection, with numbness on her face developing 15 minutes after injection"]}, {"question": "If so, when did the hypersensitivity symptoms appear for the first time?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 148, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2021-10-21", "note": "A 69-year-old Asian female never smoker presented on 12/07/2018 with back and hip pain and was found to have a 4.4-cm left lower lobe mass, a right ischium bone metastasis and malignant adenopathy. CT-guided left lower lobe biopsy confirmed a poorly differentiated adenocarcinoma, and hotspot polymerase chain reaction (PCR) testing identified an activating EGFR L858R mutation but no EGFR T790M. 20 days after diagnosis was established, the patient begun on erlotinib 150 mg orally once daily. She achieved a good partial response and symptomatic improvement lasting 13 months, at which time a new left lower lobe lesion 1.8 \u00d7 1.3 cm as well as increased activity in her known bony disease was seen. A biopsy of the right pelvic mass was performed and was consistent with poorly differentiated adenocarcinoma. Additional hotspot molecular testing post-erlotinib confirmed the EGFR L858R mutation and was negative for EGFR T790M. However, a single-gene droplet-digital PCR test from circulating tumor DNA (ctDNA) performed after progression on erlotinib identified EGFR T790M, and the patient was transitioned to osimertinib in October 2020. She had symptomatic improvement and partial response lasting 12 months, at which point a new left pelvic mass with bony involvement was identified. A left pelvic mass core biopsy from the soft tissue component was subjected to comprehensive genomic profiling (FoundationOne\u00ae, Foundation Medicine, Cambridge, MA, USA), which identified the original EGFR L858R at a mutant allele frequency (MAF) of 50.52%, an EGFR T790M at 37.14%, an EGFR G796S at 38.69%, EGFR amplification at 16 predicted copies, and a low mutational burden (four mutations per DNA megabase). Overlapping sequencing reads spanning the T790M and G796S confirmed cis orientation (). A concurrent ctDNA assay (FoundationACT\u2122, Foundation Medicine) detected the EGFR L858R (MAF 12.8%), EGFR T790M (MAF 11.2%), and the G796S (MAF 11.6%) without other putative resistance alterations. Immunohistochemistry confirmed high PD-L1 expression at 70% by tumor proportion score (Dako 22C3 pharmDx, Agilent Technologies, Santa Clara, CA, USA). Additional genomic alterations are shown in , and no other putative drivers were detected. In the absence of available trials, she was transitioned to carboplatin plus pemetrexed and achieved stable disease after three cycles followed by disease progression. Based on lack of standard therapies and high PD-L1 expression that patient was then enrolled in a clinical trial of pembrolizumab in combination with the oral IDO-1 inhibitor epacadostat (NCT02178722). She has achieved a radiographic partial response and remains on therapy, now 5 months in duration. The patient has provided written informed consent to have the case details and any accompanying images published.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with lung cancer?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["CT-guided left lower lobe biopsy confirmed a poorly differentiated adenocarcinoma"]}, {"question": "If so, what was the date of diagnosis?", "answer": "July 2018", "justification": ["A 69-year-old Asian female never smoker presented on 12/07/2018 with back and hip pain and was found to have a 4.4-cm left lower lobe mass", "CT-guided left lower lobe biopsy confirmed a poorly differentiated adenocarcinoma"]}, {"question": "Did the patient receive treatment for lung cancer?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["the patient begun on erlotinib 150 mg orally once daily"]}, {"question": "If so, when did the treatment start?", "answer": "August 2018", "justification": ["presented on 12/07/2018", "20 days after diagnosis was established"]}]}
{"id": 61, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04641351", "criterion": "Patient must not be pregnant", "note_date": "2021-12-03", "note": "2021-12-3 8:05 AM\nPELVIS U.S., TRANSVAGINAL PORT                                  Clip # 87134\nReason: please eval for ectopic pregnancy\nAdmitting Diagnosis: S/P CARDIAC ARREST\nBeth Israel Hospital MEDICAL CONDITION:\n26 year old woman with 10 weeks pregnancy, s/p arrest\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION:\nplease eval for ectopic pregnancy\nFINAL REPORT\nINDICATION:  26-year-old female with cardiac arrest and 10 weeks pregnant.\nEvaluate for ectopic pregnancy.\nTRANSVAGINAL PELVIC ULTRASOUND:\nAn intrauterine gestational sac is demonstrated measuring 5 mm in average\ndiameter consistent with a 5 weeks 1 day gestational sac.  Within this sac,\nthere is a questionable embryonic pole measuring  2 mm consistent with dates\nof 6 weeks 0 days.  There are additional internal echoes within the\ngestational sac.  No embryonic cardiac activity is demonstrated.\nThe left ovary appears normal in size and architecture measuring 2.0 x 1.9 x\n2.8 cm.  Adjacent and separate to the left ovary is a well-circumscribed\nhypoechoic ovoid structure demonstrating some movement of internal echoes\nmeasuring 3.4 x 6.0 cm which either represents a loop of bowel or a dermoid.\nThe right ovary is not visualized.  There is a moderate amount of free fluid\nwithin the pelvis.\nIMPRESSION: 1. Intrauterine gestational sac and embryonic pole significantly smaller than\nprovided dates.  Internal echoes within the gestational sac along with declining \nbeta-hCG and clinical context are consistent with likely miscarriage. 2. Complex left adnexal mass, unclear of dermoid or bowel loop as etiology. 3. Moderate amount of free fluid in the pelvis.  These findings may be\nrelated to volume overload and third spacing given patient's clinical history of myocardial infarction.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Is the patient pregnant at the time of the clinical note?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["26-year-old female with cardiac arrest and 10 weeks pregnant"]}, {"question": "If so, what is the gestational age at the time of the note?", "answer": "10 weeks", "justification": ["10 weeks pregnant"]}]}
{"id": 32, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2021-12-28", "note": "This is a 53-year-old African American female with 15 years known history of HIV and hepatitis B, and known history of compensated heart failure, COPD, who presented today with complaint of stuck food in her esophagus, bloody cough, and bloody vomiting since 4 o'clock this vomiting, when she ate eggplant parmigiana meal. The back and chest pain is 8/10, no radiation and is constant. She denied fever, abdominal pain, or dysphagia before current event eating bones or fish. This is the first episode of hematemesis and feeling of globus pallidus. In the emergency room, the patient was treated with nitropaste, morphine, and Lopressor with positive results for chest pain. CAT scan of the chest showed diffuse esophageal dilatation with residual food in it, no mediastinal air was identified.,REVIEW OF SYSTEMS: , The patient denied diarrhea, abdominal pain, fever, weight loss, dysphagia before this event. Denied any exertional chest pain or shortness of breath. No headache, limb weakness. No joint pain or muscle ache. No dysuria.,PAST MEDICAL HISTORY: ,Remarkable for:,1. Asthma.,2. Hepatitis C - 1995.,3. HIV, known since 1995 and followed up by Dr. X, ABCD Medical Center, the last visit was 08/2019. The patient does not take HIV medications against medical advice.,4. Hypertension, known since 2008.,5. Negative PPD test, 10/2018.,PAST SURGICAL HISTORY: , Remarkable for hysterectomy in 2001, pilonidal cyst surgery in 2005.,FAMILY HISTORY: , Mother deceased at age 68 of cirrhosis. She had history of alcohol abuse. Father deceased at age 45, also has a history of alcohol abuse, cardiac disease, and hypertension.,ALLERGIES: , Not known allergies.,MEDICATIONS AT HOME: , Lisinopril 5 mg daily; metoprolol 25 mg twice daily; furosemide 40 mg once daily; Isentress 400 mg once daily, the patient does not take this medication for the last 3 months; Norvir 100 mg once daily; Prezista 400 mg once daily. The patient does not take her HIV medications for the last 2 to 3 months. Occasionally, she takes inhalation of albuterol and Ambien 10 mg once daily. PHYSICAL EXAMINATION: , Temperature 99.8, pulse 106, respiratory rate 18, blood pressure 162/97, saturation 99 on room air. African American female, not in acute respiratory distress, but uncomfortable, and showing some signs of back discomfort. Oriented x3, mildly drowsy, calm and cooperative. Eyes, EOMI, PERRLA. Tympanic membranes normal appearance bilaterally. External canal, no erythema or discharge. Nose, no erythema or discharge. Throat, dry mucous, no exudates. No ulcers in oral area. Full upper denture and extensive decayed lower teeth. No cervical lymphadenopathy, no carotid bruits bilaterally. Heart: RRR, S1 and S2 appreciated. No additional sounds or murmurs were auscultated. Lung: Good air entrance bilaterally. No rales or rhonchi. Abdomen: Soft, nontender, nondistended. No masses or organomegaly were palpated. Legs: No signs of DVT, peripheral pulses full, posterior dorsalis pedis 2+. Skin: No rashes or other lesions, warm and well perfused. Nails: No clubbing. No other signs of skin infection. Neurological exam: Cranial nerves II through XII grossly intact. No motor or sensory deficit was found.,CAT scan of the chest, which was done at 8 o'clock in the morning on 01/12/2020. Impression: Cardiomegaly, normal aorta, large distention of esophagus containing food. Chest x-ray: Cardiomegaly, no evidence of CHF or pneumonia. EKG: Normal sinus rhythm, no signs of ischemia.,LABORATORY DATA: , Hemoglobin 10.4, hematocrit 30.6, white blood cells 7.3, neutrophils 75, platelets 197. Sodium 140, potassium 3.1, chloride 104, bicarb 25, glucose 113, BUN 19, creatinine 1.1, GFR 55, calcium 8.8, total protein 8.1, albumin 3.1, globulin 5.0, bilirubin 0.3, alk phos 63, GOT 23, GPT 22, lipase 104, amylase 85, protime 10.2, INR 1, PTT 25.8. Urine: Negative for ketones, protein, glucose, blood, and nitrite, bacteria 2+. Troponin 0.040. BNP 1328.,PLAN:,1. Diffuse esophageal dilatation/hematemesis. We will put her n.p.o., we will give IV fluid, half normal saline D5 100 mL per hour. I discussed the case with Dr. Y, gastroenterologist. The patient planned for EGD starting today. Differential diagnosis may include foreign body, achalasia, Candida infection, or CMV esophagitis. We will treat according to the EGD findings. We will give IV Nexium 40 mg daily for GI prophylaxis. We will hold all p.o. medication.,2. CHF. Cardiomegaly on x-ray. She is clinically stable. Lungs are clear. No radiological sign of CHF exacerbation. We will restart lisinopril and metoprolol after EGD study will be completed.,3. HIV - follow up by Dr. X, (ABCD Medical Center). The last visit was on 08/2018. The patient was not taking her HIV medications for the last 3 months and does not know her CD4 number or viral load. We will check CD4 number and viral load. 4. Hypertension. We will control blood pressor with Lopressor 5 mg IV p.r.n. If blood pressure more than 160/90, we will hold metoprolol and lisinopril.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Is this patient on effective anti-retroviral therapy for HIV?", "answer": "No", "justification": ["The patient was not taking her HIV medications for the last 3 months"]}, {"question": "Has the patient had an undetectable HIV viral load recently?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, how recent was the diagnosis of an undetectable HIV viral load?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 31, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2021-12-28", "note": "Date of Birth: 1972-8-3 Sex: F\nAllergies:\nPatient recorded as having No Known Allergies to Drugs\n\nAttending:Robert Sheen\nChief Complaint:\nfevers, neck pain\n\nMajor Surgical or Invasive Procedure:\nnone\n\nHistory of Present Illness:\n49 yo female with HIV, adult onset Still's disease, and\nhypothyroidism. Presents with fevers, neck pain, and facial\npain. Patient was visiting Guatemala from 2021-12-6 to 2021-12-17\nand initially felt well after her return. She did not receive\nmalaria\nprophylaxis prior to leaving for Guatemala. Additionally, while\npatient was in Guatemala, she missed doses of Remicade and\nmethotrexate. When patient was questioned if she had previously\nexperienced facial and neck swelling, she reports that she\nthinks it happened a year ago. Records review revealed that in\n11/2020, she presented with fevers, submental lymphadenopathy,\nferritin elevation, and hypotension. She was treated with 7 days\nbroad spectrum antibiotics as well as stress-dose steroids.\n\nVital signs upon presentation to the ED were: T 101.5, HR 117,\nBP 104/63, RR 15, O2Sat 100%. Patient spiked a fever to 103 in\nthe ED. To work-up her facial swelling and pain, an xray was\nperformed and a round opacity was seen. CT of neck obtained,\nshowing submental adenopathy and soft tissue mass above vocal\ncords. Upon presentation to the ICU the patient is reporting some\ndifficulty with her breathing. Also notes some new nausea.\n\nPast Medical History:\n1) HIV/AIDS - Diagnosed in 2002, nadir CD4 count= 3, most recent\nCD4 288 on ARVT with atripla, VL undetectable\n2) Hypothyroid s/p iodine ablation in 10/2016 and is on thyroid\nreplacement.\n3) Adult onset Stills disease diagnosed 6-/2020\n4) Anemia\n5) +PPD s/p 9 months INH in 12-14\n6) Shingles 2-2016\n7) Budd-Chiari Type 1 malformation\n", "qa_list": [{"question": "Is this patient on effective anti-retroviral therapy for HIV?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["on ARVT with atripla"]}, {"question": "If so, has the patient had an undetectable HIV viral load recently?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["most recent CD4 288 on ARVT with atripla, VL undetectable"]}, {"question": "If so, how recent was the diagnosis of an undetectable HIV viral load?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 45, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04871529", "criterion": "Participants must have Zubrod performance status 0-2.", "note_date": "2022-01-13", "note": "The patient is a 62-year-old male who was referred to us approximately 2.5 years ago with intermittent gross hematuria and a prostate-specific antigen (PSA) level of 2.42 ng/mL. A digital rectal examination at the time did not reveal any masses or nodules. Ultrasound examination revealed an enlarged prostate (3.4 \u00d7 4.6 \u00d7 3.3 cm) and a normal bladder. He did not present any psychosocial disorders and no one in his family had been diagnosed with a tumor. A 12-core prostate biopsy revealed BCC in one-half of the prostate. A pathology report was obtained from the hospital where the patient was initially diagnosed. The prostate biopsy was immunohistochemically negative for PSA, alpha-methyl acyl-coenzyme A racemase, chromogranin A, and synaptophysin; and positive for cytokeratin-903 (34\u03b2E12), p63, and Ki67 (<1%). An abdominal computed tomography (CT) scan was normal indicating there had not been metastasis. This was confirmed by whole-body bone scintigraphy. Based on these findings, the patient was diagnosed with non-metastatic prostate BCC and was treated with a radical prostatectomy. The pathology report indicated local invasion of the nerve and thrombosis of tumor vessels; however, the margin and seminal vesicles were negative. Immunohistochemical analysis was negative for PSA, alpha-methyl acyl-coenzyme A racemase, P53, cytokine 7 (CK7), and CK20 and positive for 34\u03b2E12, p63, and Ki67 (<1%).\n\nThe patient's TNM classification was pT2NxMx. To reduce the risk of metastasis, our patient received image-guided radiotherapy. The serum PSA level remained unchanged at 0.00 ng/mL before and after radiotherapy. The patient showed no evidence of disease progression until he was medically examined 2 years later. A chest CT scan revealed multiple lung nodules; however, bone scintigraphy showed no metastasis. A biopsy was performed on the nodules, and the patient was diagnosed with metastatic BCC of the prostate. Immunohistochemical analysis was negative for PSA, chromogranin A, synaptophysin, androgen receptor, thyroid transcription factor-1, CD117, CD30, and octamer-binding transcription factor-4 and positive for 34\u03b2E12, P40, CK5/6, low molecular weight cytokeratin, and Ki67 (20%).\n\nInformation regarding the management and outcomes for BCC of the prostate is limited, and there is currently no standard treatment. We reviewed relevant literature to determine the optimal diagnostic and treatment methodology. Hormonal therapy is commonly administered; however, outcomes are poor. Considering that basal cells do not exhibit secretory activity, the patient received three cycles of chemotherapy with docetaxel, but the tumor continued to grow, albeit slowly. Subsequently, we added cisplatin for another three cycles of chemotherapy. This treatment failed and the number of nodules in the patient's lungs increased. Therefore, next-generation sequencing of the patient's sample from a lung nodule was performed free of cost, which revealed mutations in the ataxia telangiectasia-mutated (ATM), SWI/SNF-related matrix-associated actin-dependent regulator of chromatin subfamily b-member 1 (SMARCB1), and phosphoinositide-3-kinase regulatory subunit 1 (PIK3R1) genes. The patient did not receive targeted therapy owing to his financial limitations and there were no clinical trials in which he could enroll. Currently, the patient's Zubrod/ECOG/WHO score is 1. Therefore, following approval by the ethics committee, the patient is scheduled to receive nine cycles of chemotherapy with etoposide (100 mg/day for 10 days, 4 weeks/cycle).", "qa_list": [{"question": "What is this patient\u2019s most recent Zubrod score, relative to the note date?", "answer": "1", "justification": ["Currently, the patient's Zubrod/ECOG/WHO score is 1"]}, {"question": "When was this score observed?", "answer": "January 2022", "justification": ["Currently, the patient's Zubrod/ECOG/WHO score is 1\u201d, \u201cNote Date: 2022-1-13"]}]}
{"id": 47, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04871529", "criterion": "Participants must have a bone scan within 56 days prior to registration if they have bone pain or elevated serum alkaline phosphatase.", "note_date": "2022-01-13", "note": "The patient is a 62-year-old male who was referred to us approximately 2.5 years ago with intermittent gross hematuria and a prostate-specific antigen (PSA) level of 2.42 ng/mL. A digital rectal examination at the time did not reveal any masses or nodules. Ultrasound examination revealed an enlarged prostate (3.4 \u00d7 4.6 \u00d7 3.3 cm) and a normal bladder. He did not present any psychosocial disorders and no one in his family had been diagnosed with a tumor. A 12-core prostate biopsy revealed BCC in one-half of the prostate. A pathology report was obtained from the hospital where the patient was initially diagnosed. The prostate biopsy was immunohistochemically negative for PSA, alpha-methyl acyl-coenzyme A racemase, chromogranin A, and synaptophysin; and positive for cytokeratin-903 (34\u03b2E12), p63, and Ki67 (<1%). An abdominal computed tomography (CT) scan was normal indicating there had not been metastasis. This was confirmed by whole-body bone scintigraphy. Based on these findings, the patient was diagnosed with non-metastatic prostate BCC and was treated with a radical prostatectomy. The pathology report indicated local invasion of the nerve and thrombosis of tumor vessels; however, the margin and seminal vesicles were negative. Immunohistochemical analysis was negative for PSA, alpha-methyl acyl-coenzyme A racemase, P53, cytokine 7 (CK7), and CK20 and positive for 34\u03b2E12, p63, and Ki67 (<1%).\n\nThe patient's TNM classification was pT2NxMx. To reduce the risk of metastasis, our patient received image-guided radiotherapy. The serum PSA level remained unchanged at 0.00 ng/mL before and after radiotherapy. The patient showed no evidence of disease progression until he was medically examined 2 years later. A chest CT scan revealed multiple lung nodules; however, bone scintigraphy showed no metastasis. A biopsy was performed on the nodules, and the patient was diagnosed with metastatic BCC of the prostate. Immunohistochemical analysis was negative for PSA, chromogranin A, synaptophysin, androgen receptor, thyroid transcription factor-1, CD117, CD30, and octamer-binding transcription factor-4 and positive for 34\u03b2E12, P40, CK5/6, low molecular weight cytokeratin, and Ki67 (20%).\n\nInformation regarding the management and outcomes for BCC of the prostate is limited, and there is currently no standard treatment. We reviewed relevant literature to determine the optimal diagnostic and treatment methodology. Hormonal therapy is commonly administered; however, outcomes are poor. Considering that basal cells do not exhibit secretory activity, the patient received three cycles of chemotherapy with docetaxel, but the tumor continued to grow, albeit slowly. Subsequently, we added cisplatin for another three cycles of chemotherapy. This treatment failed and the number of nodules in the patient's lungs increased. Therefore, next-generation sequencing of the patient's sample from a lung nodule was performed free of cost, which revealed mutations in the ataxia telangiectasia-mutated (ATM), SWI/SNF-related matrix-associated actin-dependent regulator of chromatin subfamily b-member 1 (SMARCB1), and phosphoinositide-3-kinase regulatory subunit 1 (PIK3R1) genes. The patient did not receive targeted therapy owing to his financial limitations and there were no clinical trials in which he could enroll. Currently, the patient's Zubrod/ECOG/WHO score is 1. Therefore, following approval by the ethics committee, the patient is scheduled to receive nine cycles of chemotherapy with etoposide (100 mg/day for 10 days, 4 weeks/cycle).", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient had a bone scan?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["bone scintigraphy showed no metastasis"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the most recent bone scan performed, relative to the note date?", "answer": "July 2021", "justification": ["Note Date: 2022-1-13\u201d, \u201cThe patient is a 62-year-old male who was referred to us approximately 2.5 years ago\u201d, \u201che was medically examined 2 years later\u201d, \u201cbone scintigraphy showed no metastasis"]}]}
{"id": 120, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT05223673", "criterion": "Participants should have received previous treatment with commercially available anti-EGFR mAbs for \u2265 4 months", "note_date": "2022-02-05", "note": "The patient is a 60-year-old female cafeteria worker who was originally diagnosed with stage II (cT1N1M0) ER-/PR+/HER2+ IDC of the right breast in 2010 and developed metastatic HER2+ recurrence involving bone and lymph nodes 4 years later. She has no comorbidities and no known family history of breast cancer. Initial treatment for stage II disease was right modified radical mastectomy followed by six cycles of adjuvant TAC (docetaxel, doxorubicin, and cyclophosphamide). The patient has received multiple lines of therapy for MBC, including vinorelbine plus trastuzumab at initial recurrence. After development of lung metastases in 2015, she was treated with T-DM1 on a clinical trial and experienced 4 years of disease control. She again experienced excellent disease control for 1 year with capecitabine plus lapatinib followed by slow progression of pulmonary metastases. Upon FDA approval of neratinib in combination with capecitabine for HER2+ MBC, lapatinib was replaced with neratinib 240 mg qd with continuation of the same dose of capecitabine (1000 mg bid) based on prior tolerability. The patient received prophylactic loperamide 4 mg tid but paused the regimen after 4 days because of grade 2 nausea and grade 1 to 2 constipation. She then reinitiated neratinib with a DE schedule, starting at 120 mg/day with prophylactic loperamide 4 mg bid, with improved tolerability. She was able to titrate the neratinib dose to 160 mg/day after 1 week, to 200 mg/day after 2 additional weeks, and to 240 mg/day by week 5. The patient was able to continue on therapy with loperamide bid with regular bowel movements and no further nausea. Three months into treatment with neratinib plus capecitabine, the patient had a near-complete radiographic response, with residual scarring in the areas of prior pulmonary nodules. She remains free of recurrent diarrhea.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Did the patient ever receive anti-EGFR mAbs?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["She again experienced excellent disease control for 1 year with capecitabine plus lapatinib", "lapatinib was replaced with neratinib"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the starting date of the treatment with mAbs ?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, what was the duration of treatment with mAbs until the date of the note?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 43, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04871529", "criterion": "Histologically confirmed high grade upper tract urothelial carcinoma (UTUC) within 56 days prior to registration, with invasion confirmed by either a mass on cross-sectional imaging or a tumor directly visualized during upper urinary tract endoscopy within 56 days prior to registration", "note_date": "2022-02-05", "note": "This note pertains to a 65-year-old male patient who presented with hematuria, flank pain, and fatigue. A CT scan of the abdomen and pelvis on January 10th, 2022 revealed a mass in the right renal pelvis, which was suspicious for malignancy. The patient underwent an upper urinary tract endoscopy on January 18th, 2022, which confirmed the presence of a large, friable lesion in the right ureter, extending into the renal pelvis.\n\nHistopathological analysis of the biopsy samples obtained during the endoscopy on January 18th, 2022 revealed high-grade invasive UTUC, with infiltration into the muscular layer of the ureter. The tumor was staged as pT2.\n\nThe patient was referred to a multidisciplinary team, including urologists, medical oncologists, and radiation oncologists, and underwent a series of imaging studies and consultations to determine the best course of treatment. After discussion, the patient underwent a right nephroureterectomy with lymph node dissection on February 2nd, 2022. The final pathology report on February 8th, 2022 revealed high-grade UTUC, with invasion into the muscular layer and peripelvic adipose tissue. A total of 8 lymph nodes were removed, with no evidence of metastatic disease.\n\nPostoperative recovery was uneventful, and the patient was discharged home on February 10th, 2022. Follow-up surveillance with imaging and cystoscopy will be performed to monitor for recurrence or metastasis.\n\nIn summary, this patient presented with hematuria, flank pain, and fatigue, and was diagnosed with high-grade invasive UTUC on January 18th, 2022. The patient underwent a right nephroureterectomy with lymph node dissection on February 2nd, 2022. Follow-up surveillance will be performed to monitor for recurrence or metastasis.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient had a histologically confirmed diagnosis of invasive high-grade upper tract urothelial carcinoma (UTUC)?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Histopathological analysis of the biopsy samples obtained during the endoscopy on January 18th, 2022 revealed high-grade invasive UTUC"]}, {"question": "If so, when was this diagnosis made?", "answer": "January 18, 2022", "justification": ["Histopathological analysis of the biopsy samples obtained during the endoscopy on January 18th, 2022 revealed high-grade invasive UTUC"]}, {"question": "How was the invasion confirmed?", "answer": "upper urinary tract endoscopy", "justification": ["The patient underwent an upper urinary tract endoscopy on January 18th, 2022\u201d, \u201cHistopathological analysis of the biopsy samples obtained during the endoscopy on January 18th, 2022 revealed high-grade invasive UTUC, with infiltration into the muscular layer of the ureter"]}]}
{"id": 72, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04134260", "criterion": "Androgen deprivation therapy (ADT) prior to radical prostatectomy", "note_date": "2022-02-22", "note": "INPATIENT CONSULTATION PATIENT: Ulysses Quin \nLMH NUMBER: 9523697 \nREFERRING PHYSICIAN: Dr. Ziemba \nDATE OF Consultation: 2022-02-22 \nPATIENT ID: Mr. Quin is a 74 y/o gentleman with metastatic prostate cancer, new L4 met with pain who is seen for consideration of radiation therapy. HPI: Mr. Quin's oncological history began in 2021 when he was diagnosed with prostate cancer (unknown gleason, PSA). He underwent radical prostatectomy on 06/2021 and salvage XRT in 2022. His care was at BNH and we don't have his XRT records. The patient recalls 37 treatments. The patient was well until he had an elevated PSA of 3.52 on 12/2021. He underwent a bone scan in 11/01/22 showing worrisome uptake at L5. In 15/01 he had a PSA of 17.46. He has also developed lower back pain requiring MS Contin for pain control. His course was complicated by a possible bladder/urethral infection. He is incontinent from his surgery. In 22/01 he had a cystoscopy which revealed nodules in the bladder (TCC vs. prostatic scar/inflammation). The patient's LLP worsened. He reports occasional severe shooting pain that lead to gait imbalance. On the day of presentation, he experienced severe acute back pain while getting out of bed. The pain was so intolerable that he asked his daughter to bring him to the emergency room. Just before arrival to the ED he developed stridor, in his words he was sucking air in and out. ENT was consulted in the ED and determined that he had a limited glottic gap, and that the acute stridor was most likely secondary to anxiety and increased air flow through a restricted glottic opening, recommending humidified air by shovel air mask, steroids, and outpatient followup. MRI of the lumbar spine showed metastatic disease involving of the L4 vertebral body, extending into the pedicles, both L4-5 neural foramina, and the prevertebral soft tissues. No compression of the thecal sac. Mr. Quin reports improved pain since admission. He still has some pain when moving from one position to anther. he denies fecal incontinence, saddle anesthesia, LE weakness or paresthesia. He would like to be cared at the LMH from now on. The patient had an oncologist from BNH but does not remember his name. \nPAST MEDICAL HISTORY: Prostate Ca (history per HPI) HTN PVD ED Type 2 DM on oral agent Vocal cord polyp excision in 2018 H/o COPD \nMEDICATIONS: Bicalutamide 50 mg po qd Glyburide 10 mg po qd HCTZ 12.5 mg po qd MS Contin 30 mg bid Morphine 15 mg po q4h Senna Colace and lactulose prn constipation \nALLERGIES: NKDA \nSOCIAL HISTORY: Notary. CPA and lives with wife in Tonganoxie. Habits: 60 pack year smoking history Past heavy alcohol consumption but none now \nPHYSICAL EXAM: General: Well-appearing, in no acute distress. \nHEENT: PERRL. EOMI. Oropharynx is clear. Neck: Supple Lymph nodes: No cervical, supraclavicular, axillary, or inguinal lymphadenopathy. Cardiac: S1, S2, no murmurs, rubs, or gallops. Chest: Lungs clear to auscultation bilaterally. Abdomen: Soft, nontender, nondistended, with positive bowel sounds. old midline surgical scars. Extremities: Well perfused with no edema. No bony pain to palpation. Neurologic: CN II-XII grossly intact with no focal neurologic deficits. 5/5 LE strength, movements limited by pain. normal gait. toes down bilaterally GU: no penial or testicular abnormalities. +pads IMPRESSION and PLAN: 74 y/o gentleman with metastatic prostate cancer, new L4 metastasis and pain. The patient's LBP is likely due to his spine met. Based on the MRI results, his symptoms and his exam we believe he is an appropriate candidate for palliative radiotherapy to his L-spine. I discussed with Mr. Quin the likely cause of his pain. We then discussed the treatment options. Mr. Quin would like to undergo a course of palliative radiotherapy to relieve his pain. We will simulate (plan) the patient's XRT tomorrow am, with a treatment to follow on the same day. All of the patient's questions were answered to his satisfaction. We would also recommend an GU oncology consultation regarding the patient's ADT and other possible systemic therapies. The patient only had L-spine MRI, a bone scan may be of benefit to establish the extent of metastatic disease. Quenton Zacharie Odell, MD Quanita Ziemer, MD", "qa_list": [{"question": "Did the patient ever have radical prostatectomy?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["He underwent radical prostatectomy"]}, {"question": "If so, when?", "answer": "06/2021", "justification": ["He underwent radical prostatectomy on 06/2021"]}]}
{"id": 56, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT05223673", "criterion": "Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status 0 or 1", "note_date": "2022-02-28", "note": "A 47-year-old man with a 30 pack-year history of smoking presented with hemoptysis in September 2018. An enhanced computed tomography (CT) scan showed a 3.7 cm mass located in the lower right hilum, wrapped by the right intermediate bronchus, and accompanied by mediastinum and hilar lymph node enlargement. A bronchoscopy was performed, and a pathological dsiagnosis of clinical stage cT4N3M0 (stage III) SqCC was confirmed. No EGFR mutations were identified. He was prescribed with concurrent chemoradiotherapy consisting of four cycles of paclitaxel plus cisplatin chemotherapy and 66Gy/33f radiotherapy and achieved a partial response (PR). The patient experienced recurrent hemoptysis in March 2021. He was in poor condition, with an Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status (PS) score of 2. A chest CT showed a 7.3 cm mass in the lower right hilum, an enlarged 6.8 cm lymph node in the left axillary, and pleural effusion on the right side. Serum tumor marker levels, including carcinoembryonic antigen, cytokeratin 19 fragments, and neuron-specific enolase, were high. We recommended immunotherapy with nivolumab at a dose of 3 mg/kg, once every two weeks from 3rd of May 2021 and thoracic perfusion treatment with recombinant endostatin. Pleural effusion was well controlled after four cycles of nivolumab and endostar, but the tumor continued to progress. The patient's condition deteriorated further, to an ECOG PS score of 3. At this time, DNA profiling was introduced, but no mutations in known driver genes (EGFR, ALK, ERBB2, BRAF, MET, RET, ROS1, and KRAS) were identified. This profiling also showed that the patient had a high tumor mutation burden. Nivolumab plus nab-paclitaxel were administered. Two cycles of therapy led to a PR in his tumor, sharply decreased tumor markers, and an improved ECOG PS score of 1. Another two cycles were implemented and the lesion shrank further. Nivolumab therapy was maintained and the patient was regularly followed-up. The response was stable up to January 2022.", "qa_list": [{"question": "What is the patient\u2019s most recent ECOG score relative to the date of the clinical note?", "answer": "1", "justification": ["\"an improved ECOG PS score of 1\","]}, {"question": "When was that ECOG score obtained?", "answer": "August 2021", "justification": [" immunotherapy with nivolumab at a dose of 3 mg/kg, once every two weeks from 3rd of May 2021", "after four cycles of nivolumab", "Nivolumab plus nab-paclitaxel were administered. Two cycles of therapy", "sharply decreased tumor markers, and an improved ECOG PS score of 1."]}]}
{"id": 57, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2022-02-28", "note": "A 47-year-old man with a 30 pack-year history of smoking presented with hemoptysis in September 2018. An enhanced computed tomography (CT) scan showed a 3.7 cm mass located in the lower right hilum, wrapped by the right intermediate bronchus, and accompanied by mediastinum and hilar lymph node enlargement. A bronchoscopy was performed, and a pathological diagnosis of clinical stage cT4N3M0 (stage III) SqCC was confirmed. No EGFR mutations were identified. He was prescribed with concurrent chemoradiotherapy consisting of four cycles of paclitaxel plus cisplatin chemotherapy and 66Gy/33f radiotherapy and achieved a partial response (PR). The patient experienced recurrent hemoptysis in March 2021. He was in poor condition, with an Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status (PS) score of 2. A chest CT showed a 7.3 cm mass in the lower right hilum, an enlarged 6.8 cm lymph node in the left axillary, and pleural effusion on the right side. Serum tumor marker levels, including carcinoembryonic antigen, cytokeratin 19 fragments, and neuron-specific enolase, were high. We recommended immunotherapy with nivolumab at a dose of 3 mg/kg, once every two weeks from 3 May 2021 and thoracic perfusion treatment with recombinant endostatin. Pleural effusion was well controlled after four cycles of nivolumab and endostar, but the tumor continued to progress. The patient's condition deteriorated further, to an ECOG PS score of 3. At this time, DNA profiling was introduced, but no mutations in known driver genes (EGFR, ALK, ERBB2, BRAF, MET, RET, ROS1, and KRAS) were identified. This profiling also showed that the patient had a high tumor mutation burden. Nivolumab plus nab-paclitaxel were administered. Two cycles of therapy led to a PR in his tumor, sharply decreased tumor markers, and an improved ECOG PS score of 1. Another two cycles were implemented and the lesion shrank further. Nivolumab therapy was maintained and the patient was regularly followed-up. The response was stable up to January 2022.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been screened for oncogenic driver mutations ?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["At this time, DNA profiling was introduced, but no mutations in known driver genes (EGFR, ALK, ERBB2, BRAF, MET, RET, ROS1, and KRAS) were identified"]}, {"question": "If so, when?", "answer": "Between May 2021 and late 2021", "justification": ["We recommended immunotherapy with nivolumab at a dose of 3 mg/kg, once every two weeks from 3 May 2021 and thoracic perfusion treatment with recombinant endostatin. Pleural effusion was well controlled after four cycles of nivolumab and endostar, but the tumor continued to progress. The patient's condition deteriorated further, to an ECOG PS score of 3. At this time, DNA profiling was introduced"]}, {"question": "If so, does the patient have BRAF positive lung cancer?", "answer": "No", "justification": ["no mutations in known driver genes (EGFR, ALK, ERBB2, BRAF, MET, RET, ROS1, and KRAS) were identified"]}]}
{"id": 65, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2022-02-28", "note": "A 47-year-old man with a 30 pack-year history of smoking presented with hemoptysis in September 2018. An enhanced computed tomography (CT) scan showed a 3.7 cm mass located in the lower right hilum, wrapped by the right intermediate bronchus, and accompanied by mediastinum and hilar lymph node enlargement. A bronchoscopy was performed, and a pathological diagnosis of clinical stage cT4N3M0 (stage III) SqCC was confirmed. No EGFR mutations were identified. He was prescribed with concurrent chemoradiotherapy consisting of four cycles of paclitaxel plus cisplatin chemotherapy and 66Gy/33f radiotherapy and achieved a partial response (PR). The patient experienced recurrent hemoptysis in March 2021. He was in poor condition, with an Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status (PS) score of 2. A chest CT showed a 7.3 cm mass in the lower right hilum, an enlarged 6.8 cm lymph node in the left axillary, and pleural effusion on the right side. Serum tumor marker levels, including carcinoembryonic antigen, cytokeratin 19 fragments, and neuron-specific enolase, were high. We recommended immunotherapy with nivolumab at a dose of 3 mg/kg, once every two weeks from 3 May 2021 and thoracic perfusion treatment with recombinant endostatin. Pleural effusion was well controlled after four cycles of nivolumab and endostar, but the tumor continued to progress. The patient's condition deteriorated further, to an ECOG PS score of 3. At this time, DNA profiling was introduced, but no mutations in known driver genes (EGFR, ALK, ERBB2, BRAF, MET, RET, ROS1, and KRAS) were identified. This profiling also showed that the patient had a high tumor mutation burden. Nivolumab plus nab-paclitaxel were administered. Two cycles of therapy led to a PR in his tumor, sharply decreased tumor markers, and an improved ECOG PS score of 1. Another two cycles were implemented and the lesion shrank further. Nivolumab therapy was maintained and the patient was regularly followed-up. The response was stable up to January 2022.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient received immunotherapy ?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Pleural effusion was well controlled after four cycles of nivolumab", "Nivolumab plus nab-paclitaxel were administered"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the first cycle of immunotherapy administered?", "answer": "3 May 2021", "justification": ["We recommended immunotherapy with nivolumab at a dose of 3 mg/kg, once every two weeks from 3 May 2021"]}]}
{"id": 78, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04844749", "criterion": "The patient must not have a prior history of a thromboembolic event within the last 6 months.", "note_date": "2022-03-01", "note": "A 51-year-old man presented to us with three episodes of loss of consciousness. He had an aortic valve replacement with a metallic valve a few years ago and did not have any other cardiac risk factors and was fairly active. He took warfarin and his international normalized ratio (INR) was within therapeutic range. The day of the admission, he has been out the whole day and had not eaten or taken the usual amount of liquids; the initiating event took place at a funeral, where he felt nauseous and dizzy. This was in the evening time. At night, he went to operate the water pump and had an unheralded fall and recovered spontaneously. He was brought up to his room where he lay with head propped up. At that time, he felt a griping pain in the abdomen and experienced nausea and passed out. According to the wife, he came around with sprinkling of water. He complained of worsening of the gripe and felt like vomiting. By this time he was totally lying flat in bed. The wife witnessed his eyes rolling up and he had myoclonic jerks. He came around in a couple of minutes and was rushed to the hospital. On examination, he has normal range pulse and BP, while the rest of the exam was unremarkable. His ECG (sinus rhythm with right bundle-branch block), blood work-up and echocardiogram were normal. His ejection fraction (EF) was 55% and the prosthetic aortic valve was functioning normally. His neurological assessment, electroencephalogram (EEG) and scan ruled out a neurologic cause (hemorrhage or thromboembolic event). He then underwent a HUT test, which came out positive at three minutes post nitrate provocation with a cardio-inhibitory response, where the ECG showed severe sinus bradycardia and sinoatrial (SA) exit block. He reproduced and confirmed all the clinical symptoms of an abdominal gripe, nausea, and sweating. He also felt like moving his bowel at the time. He was prescribed hydration, counter-maneuvers and walking. He did not have any recurrence in the follow-up period.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient had a thromboembolic event?", "answer": "No", "justification": ["scan ruled out a neurologic cause (hemorrhage or thromboembolic event)"]}, {"question": "If so, when did the most recent thromboembolic event occur, relative to the note date?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 80, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04844749", "criterion": "The patient must not have a prior history of a thromboembolic event within the last 6 months.", "note_date": "2022-03-01", "note": "Admission Date: 2021-5-16 Discharge Date: 2021-6-28\r\nDate of Birth: 1954-5-10 Sex: F\r\nService: MEDICINE\r\nAllergies:\r\nPenicillins / latex\r\nAttending: Jonathan Greene\r\nChief Complaint:\r\nAltered mental status\r\nMajor Surgical or Invasive Procedure:\r\n- Central Line Placement and Removal\r\nHistory of Present Illness:\r\nMs. Chisorki is a 67 year old woman with a history of prior CVA's.\r\nShe has left sided hemiparesis at baseline and speaks only a few\r\nwords. She lives at a nursing facility. Her daughter visited her\r\non her birthday (5-11). She reports that the patient was\r\nless responsive and kept her mouth open during the whole visit.\r\nIt is unclear if she improved back to her baseline. This AM she\r\nwas reportedly less responsive than normal per the staff at the\r\nnursing facility. She was also diaphoretic. An ambulance was\r\ncalled and she was brought to the hospital ED. Her blood glucose en\r\nroute was 117.\r\nIn the ED, initial vital signs were 84/60 116 99% on room air.\r\nShe spiked a temp to 102 while in the ED. Labs were significant\r\nfor sodium of 173, creatinine of 2.7, troponin of 0.14, and\r\nlactate of 1.3 (after fluid). Urinalysis showed large leuk\r\nesterase. She received 4.5 L of normal saline. Her chest xray\r\nwas clear. There was no evidence of new stroke on CT. Her BP's\r\ncontinued to drop in the ED. A central line was placed and she\r\nwas started on levophed.\r\nOn arrival to the MICU, patient did not respond to questions or\r\nmovement.\r\nPast Medical History:\r\n- s/p thromboembolic CVA w L hemiplegia, nonverbal\r\n- Atrial fibrillation on coumadin\r\n- Hyperlipidemia\r\n- Hypertension\r\n- Seizures\r\nSocial History:\r\nPatient lived at a nursing facility.\r\nFamily History:\r\nUnable to obtain\r\nPhysical Exam:\r\nADMISSION EXAM:\r\nVitals: T:99.0 BP:112/63 P:91 RR:17 O2:98% on RA\r\nGeneral: Awke, nonverbal, no acute distress\r\nHEENT: Sclera anicteric, MMM, oropharynx clear, EOMI grossly\r\nintact but unable to follow commands to track finder, PERRL\r\nNeck: JVP not elevated\r\nCV: Tachycardic and irregular, no murmurs, rubs, gallops\r\nLungs: Clear to auscultation bilaterally on the anterior, no\r\nwheezes, rales, rhonchi\r\nAbdomen: soft, non-tender, non-distended, bowel sounds present,\r\nno organomegaly\r\nGU: foley\r\nExt: warm, well perfused, 2+ pulses, no clubbing, cyanosis or\r\nedema\r\nNeuro: CNII-XII intact grossly, able to move RUE, did not see\r\npatient move LUE/LLE or RLE.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient had a thromboembolic event?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Past Medical History: - s/p thromboembolic CVA w L hemiplegia"]}, {"question": "If so, when did the most recent thromboembolic event occur, relative to the note date?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 149, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03957876", "criterion": "total bilirubin < 2x upper limit of normal (</= 3 x ULN if considered to be due to leukemic involvement or Gilbert's syndrome)", "note_date": "2022-03-01", "note": "On 2020-2-14, a 26-year-old African American male with a history of SCD, HbSS genotype, presented presented to our hospital with a 2-day history of worsening epigastric abdominal pain. On exam, the patient was jaundiced, had abdominal tenderness, but no evidence of hepatosplenomegaly. Total bilirubin was elevated to 24.9 mg/dL (reference range 0.2\u20131.2 mg/dL) along with aspartate transaminase (AST) 176 units/L (reference range 5\u201340 units/L) and alanine transaminase (ALT) 108 units/L (reference range 0\u201355 units/L). Hepatitis B and C as well as HIV testing was negative. An MRI demonstrated no hepatomegaly and an atrophic spleen consistent with chronic SCD. Right upper quadrant ultrasound was notable for cholelithiasis and on his seventh day in the hospital he underwent cholecystectomy and cholangiopancreatography for removal of a common bile duct stone.\nOn day 10 in hospital, he continued to have increased total bilirubin with a peak of 80 mg/dL and also developed a prolonged prothrombin time (PT), 18.9 seconds (reference range 11\u201314.6 seconds). A presumptive diagnosis of SCIC was made, and the patient underwent RBCEx with a goal of 20% HbS utilizing six units of crossmatched-compatible red blood cells (RBC) which were C, E, and Kell phenotypically matched and SICKLEDEX\u00ae (Streck, Omaha, NE) negative on the COBE Spectra Apheresis System (Terumo BCT, Lakewood, CO). His hemoglobin S level decreased from 44.4% to 17.8%. His laboratory markers improved, and the patient was discharged. Today is his 2-years follow-up visit and the patient has returned to his clinical and laboratory baseline without development of chronic SCIC.", "qa_list": [{"question": "List all total bilirubin levels for this patient in temporal order. Each level should be assigned a corresponding time period, with a colon between the level and the time period. Use NA if the time period for a given total bilirubin level is not clear from the note. Different pairs of total bilirubin levels and their corresponding time periods should be separated by semicolons. If a numeric value for total bilirubin is not given for a particular time point but the level is qualitatively characterized as normal, then write 'normal' for the level. Separate the corresponding justifications by semicolons.", "answer": "24.9 mg/dL: 2020-2-14; 80 mg/dL: 2020-2-34; normal: 2022-3-1", "justification": ["On 2020-2-14, a 26-year-old African American male with a history of SCD, HbSS genotype, presented with a 2-day history of worsening epigastric abdominal pain. On exam, the patient was jaundiced, had abdominal tenderness, but no evidence of hepatosplenomegaly. Total bilirubin was elevated to 24.9 mg/dL", "On day 10 in hospital, he continued to have increased total bilirubin with a peak of 80 mg/dL", "Today is his 2-years follow-up visit and the patient has returned to his clinical and laboratory baseline", "Note Date: 2022-3-1"]}]}
{"id": 105, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "The interval between the last surgery for breast cancer (including re-excision of margins) and study entry must be no more than 70 days.", "note_date": "2022-03-15", "note": "A 68-year-old woman with a history of breast cancer (prior lumpectomy and radiation), hypertension, and past surgical history of cholecystectomy, appendectomy, and right knee replacement presented six months ago with a history of back and leg pain. She referred to the emergency room due to an acute exacerbation of progressive back pain and neurogenic claudication. On examination, she had full muscle strength with some paresthesia in bilateral lower extremities. An MRI of the lumbar spine revealed grade 1 spondylolisthesis and severe canal stenosis at lumbar segment four/five (L4/5).\nShe underwent MIS TLIF at L4/5 with bilateral facetectomy and decompression without complication. Intraoperative somatosensory evoked potential/electromyography were uneventful. Immediately, post-operatively, the patient\u2019s paresthesias and radicular pain resolved with full motor strength. On post-operative day 5, she reported subtle weakness (4+/5) which progressively worsened over the 24 hours. At this time, her examination demonstrated lower extremity areflexia, numbness, and weakness in bilateral lower extremities (graded 2-3/5). The patient also reported subjective numbness in bilateral upper extremities and episodes of dyspnea; however, her respiratory rate and upper examination were normal. She denied facial symptoms.\nShe underwent an MRI of the entire spine which revealed a cervical 3/4 cord compression and cord signal change and post-surgical decompression at the L4/5 level with instrumentation. The patient underwent lumbar puncture for cerebral spinal fluid (CSF) analysis, revealing protein of 257 mg/dL (high), nucleated cell count of 1 cell/mcL, and red blood cell count of 24 cells/mcL. Given the examination and laboratory findings, she was diagnosed with GBS.\nThe patient was treated with five sessions of plasmapheresis. She experienced some improvement of her symptoms during treatment and was eventually discharged to inpatient rehabilitation. At three months of follow-up, the patient demonstrated significant improvement; she was ambulatory with a walker, without objective leg weakness, and only slight paresthesia of bilateral lower extremities. Her pre-operative pain remained resolved. She continued to progress and at her six-month follow-up, she was ambulatory without aid and without paresthesia.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient ever had surgery for breast cancer?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["prior lumpectomy and radiation"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the most recent such surgery, relative to the note date?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 109, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2022-04-12", "note": "The pt is a 48-year-old man who had a treatment history for anaplastic astrocytoma twice at the age of 39 and 46. He was referred to our department on Feb 4 for the inspection of progressing anemia. He was suspected as LS due to his specific family history by having two cases of colon cancer within his second relatives. Whole-body examination revealed two foci of advanced stage of carcinoma in descending colon and stomach. A hypo-vascular mass in its size of 15 mm was also detected in S2 of liver. Pathological diagnosis using the biopsied samples and surgically resected specimens were poorly differentiated adenocarcinoma of descending colon, moderately differentiated adenocarcinoma of stomach, and poorly differentiated adenocarcinoma of the liver, suggesting the liver tumor would be metastasis from colon. 5-Fluorouracil-based adjuvant chemotherapy with the combination of oxaliplatin was selected for this case because this case was highly suspected as LS. During postoperative surveillance, repetitive polypectomy for colonic adenomas was performed, one of which was a 10 mm tubular adenoma with severe atypia in the ascending colon.\nDetection of MSI was performed by Biomedical Laboratories, Inc. (Saitama, Japan) using a National Cancer Institute\u2013recommended panel of microsatellite markers (BAT25, BAT26, D2S123, D5S346, and D17S250) and additional markers (D2S136, D3S1067, TP53, D18S51). This analysis showed a positive result for eight markers (except D5S346), indicating a high frequency of MSI (MSI-high). Immunohistochemistry (IHC) for MMR proteins of this patient\u2019s tumors were also performed. Monoclonal antibodies (MLH1: mouse monoclonal, clone ES05, MSH2: mouse monoclonal, clone FE11, MSH6: rabbit monoclonal, clone EP49, PMS2: rabbit monoclonal, clone EP51 {DAKO, Denmark}) were used for the present study. The IHCs of the descending colon cancer demonstrated abnormal nuclear staining of scanty MSH6, concurrent loss of MLH1 and PMS2, whereas the staining for MSH2 was positive. On the other hand, IHCs of the liver metastasis showed complete loss of MSH6, MLH1, PMS2 and the staining for MSH2 was positive. IHCs of the stomach cancer revealed negative staining of MLH1 and PMS2, whereas the staining for MSH2 and MSH6 were positive. Further investigation in IHCs of the colon cancer specimens from his father and brother were performed. Both of them showed the same staining pattern, as of this patient\u2019s stomach cancer.\nA gene mutation of MLH1 was suspected in this family line, because all of the colon cancers demonstrated complete defects of MLH1 and PMS2. Genetic analysis for mismatch repair genes, MLH1, MSH2, MSH6, PMS2, MSH3, PMS1, EPCAM, MLH3, APC, MUTYH, POLD1, POLE, TP53, AXIN2 and BMPR1A was conducted. This genetic testing revealed a frame shift mutation in codon 618 (c. 1852-1854delAAG / p.Lys618del) of MLH1. This mutation is registered on the database of InSiGHT as class 5 and as pathogenic in Clin Var. To investigate the mechanism of the scanty staining pattern of MSH6 in colorectal carcinoma, analysis of the coding region microsatellite (C)8 in exon 5 of MSH6 in this patient\u2019s colon cancer, stomach cancer, and liver metastasis was performed. An intact (C)8 region was shown in a normal tissue of the colon and stomach cancer. An abnormal (C)8 region was seen in the colon cancer and the liver metastasis. The distribution of the mutant alleles in the (C)8 tract was further analyzed by cloning and sequencing analysis. Deletion mutation (\u22121wt) and insertion mutation (wt + 1) were detected in the liver metastasis. Representative electropherograms of wild type, \u22121wt and wt + 1 clones are shown in the Supplementary Figure.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient ever had a brain cancer diagnosis?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["who had a treatment history for anaplastic astrocytoma"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the first such diagnosis made?", "answer": "2013", "justification": ["A 48-year-old man who had a treatment history for anaplastic astrocytoma twice at the age of 39 and 46", "Note Date: 2022-4-12"]}]}
{"id": 107, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2022-04-12", "note": "The pt is a 48-year-old man who had a treatment history for anaplastic astrocytoma twice at the age of 39 and 46. He was referred to our department on Feb 4 for the inspection of progressing anemia. He was suspected as LS due to his specific family history by having two cases of colon cancer within his second relatives. Whole-body examination revealed two foci of advanced stage of carcinoma in descending colon and stomach. A hypo-vascular mass in its size of 15 mm was also detected in S2 of liver. Pathological diagnosis using the biopsied samples and surgically resected specimens were poorly differentiated adenocarcinoma of descending colon, moderately differentiated adenocarcinoma of stomach, and poorly differentiated adenocarcinoma of the liver, suggesting the liver tumor would be metastasis from colon. 5-Fluorouracil-based adjuvant chemotherapy with the combination of oxaliplatin was selected for this case because this case was highly suspected as LS. During postoperative surveillance, repetitive polypectomy for colonic adenomas was performed, one of which was a 10 mm tubular adenoma with severe atypia in the ascending colon.\nDetection of MSI was performed by Biomedical Laboratories, Inc. (Saitama, Japan) using a National Cancer Institute\u2013recommended panel of microsatellite markers (BAT25, BAT26, D2S123, D5S346, and D17S250) and additional markers (D2S136, D3S1067, TP53, D18S51). This analysis showed a positive result for eight markers (except D5S346), indicating a high frequency of MSI (MSI-high). Immunohistochemistry (IHC) for MMR proteins of this patient\u2019s tumors were also performed. Monoclonal antibodies (MLH1: mouse monoclonal, clone ES05, MSH2: mouse monoclonal, clone FE11, MSH6: rabbit monoclonal, clone EP49, PMS2: rabbit monoclonal, clone EP51 {DAKO, Denmark}) were used for the present study. The IHCs of the descending colon cancer demonstrated abnormal nuclear staining of scanty MSH6, concurrent loss of MLH1 and PMS2, whereas the staining for MSH2 was positive. On the other hand, IHCs of the liver metastasis showed complete loss of MSH6, MLH1, PMS2 and the staining for MSH2 was positive. IHCs of the stomach cancer revealed negative staining of MLH1 and PMS2, whereas the staining for MSH2 and MSH6 were positive. Further investigation in IHCs of the colon cancer specimens from his father and brother were performed. Both of them showed the same staining pattern, as of this patient\u2019s stomach cancer.\nA gene mutation of MLH1 was suspected in this family line, because all of the colon cancers demonstrated complete defects of MLH1 and PMS2. Genetic analysis for mismatch repair genes, MLH1, MSH2, MSH6, PMS2, MSH3, PMS1, EPCAM, MLH3, APC, MUTYH, POLD1, POLE, TP53, AXIN2 and BMPR1A was conducted. This genetic testing revealed a frame shift mutation in codon 618 (c. 1852-1854delAAG / p.Lys618del) of MLH1. This mutation is registered on the database of InSiGHT as class 5 and as pathogenic in Clin Var. To investigate the mechanism of the scanty staining pattern of MSH6 in colorectal carcinoma, analysis of the coding region microsatellite (C)8 in exon 5 of MSH6 in this patient\u2019s colon cancer, stomach cancer, and liver metastasis was performed. An intact (C)8 region was shown in a normal tissue of the colon and stomach cancer. An abnormal (C)8 region was seen in the colon cancer and the liver metastasis. The distribution of the mutant alleles in the (C)8 tract was further analyzed by cloning and sequencing analysis. Deletion mutation (\u22121wt) and insertion mutation (wt + 1) were detected in the liver metastasis. Representative electropherograms of wild type, \u22121wt and wt + 1 clones are shown in the Supplementary Figure.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Was the patient\u2019s DNA tested for microsatellite instability?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Detection of MSI was performed"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the most recent such test?", "answer": "between Feb 4 2022 and April 4 2022", "justification": ["was referred to our department on Feb 4", "Note Date: 2022-4-12"]}, {"question": "If so, what was the detected level of microsatellite instability?", "answer": "MSI-H", "justification": ["indicating a high frequency of MSI (MSI-high)"]}]}
{"id": 108, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2022-04-12", "note": "The pt is a 48-year-old man who had a treatment history for anaplastic astrocytoma twice at the age of 39 and 46. He was referred to our department on Feb 4 for the inspection of progressing anemia. He was suspected as LS due to his specific family history by having two cases of colon cancer within his second relatives. Whole-body examination revealed two foci of advanced stage of carcinoma in descending colon and stomach. A hypo-vascular mass in its size of 15 mm was also detected in S2 of liver. Pathological diagnosis using the biopsied samples and surgically resected specimens were poorly differentiated adenocarcinoma of descending colon, moderately differentiated adenocarcinoma of stomach, and poorly differentiated adenocarcinoma of the liver, suggesting the liver tumor would be metastasis from colon. 5-Fluorouracil-based adjuvant chemotherapy with the combination of oxaliplatin was selected for this case because this case was highly suspected as LS. During postoperative surveillance, repetitive polypectomy for colonic adenomas was performed, one of which was a 10 mm tubular adenoma with severe atypia in the ascending colon.\nDetection of MSI was performed by Biomedical Laboratories, Inc. (Saitama, Japan) using a National Cancer Institute\u2013recommended panel of microsatellite markers (BAT25, BAT26, D2S123, D5S346, and D17S250) and additional markers (D2S136, D3S1067, TP53, D18S51). This analysis showed a positive result for eight markers (except D5S346), indicating a high frequency of MSI (MSI-high). Immunohistochemistry (IHC) for MMR proteins of this patient\u2019s tumors were also performed. Monoclonal antibodies (MLH1: mouse monoclonal, clone ES05, MSH2: mouse monoclonal, clone FE11, MSH6: rabbit monoclonal, clone EP49, PMS2: rabbit monoclonal, clone EP51 {DAKO, Denmark}) were used for the present study. The IHCs of the descending colon cancer demonstrated abnormal nuclear staining of scanty MSH6, concurrent loss of MLH1 and PMS2, whereas the staining for MSH2 was positive. On the other hand, IHCs of the liver metastasis showed complete loss of MSH6, MLH1, PMS2 and the staining for MSH2 was positive. IHCs of the stomach cancer revealed negative staining of MLH1 and PMS2, whereas the staining for MSH2 and MSH6 were positive. Further investigation in IHCs of the colon cancer specimens from his father and brother were performed. Both of them showed the same staining pattern, as of this patient\u2019s stomach cancer.\nA gene mutation of MLH1 was suspected in this family line, because all of the colon cancers demonstrated complete defects of MLH1 and PMS2. Genetic analysis for mismatch repair genes, MLH1, MSH2, MSH6, PMS2, MSH3, PMS1, EPCAM, MLH3, APC, MUTYH, POLD1, POLE, TP53, AXIN2 and BMPR1A was conducted. This genetic testing revealed a frame shift mutation in codon 618 (c. 1852-1854delAAG / p.Lys618del) of MLH1. This mutation is registered on the database of InSiGHT as class 5 and as pathogenic in Clin Var. To investigate the mechanism of the scanty staining pattern of MSH6 in colorectal carcinoma, analysis of the coding region microsatellite (C)8 in exon 5 of MSH6 in this patient\u2019s colon cancer, stomach cancer, and liver metastasis was performed. An intact (C)8 region was shown in a normal tissue of the colon and stomach cancer. An abnormal (C)8 region was seen in the colon cancer and the liver metastasis. The distribution of the mutant alleles in the (C)8 tract was further analyzed by cloning and sequencing analysis. Deletion mutation (\u22121wt) and insertion mutation (wt + 1) were detected in the liver metastasis. Representative electropherograms of wild type, \u22121wt and wt + 1 clones are shown in the Supplementary Figure.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient ever had a brain cancer diagnosis?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["who had a treatment history for anaplastic astrocytoma"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the most recent such diagnosis made?", "answer": "2020", "justification": ["A 48-year-old man who had a treatment history for anaplastic astrocytoma twice at the age of 39 and 46", "Note Date: 2022-4-12"]}]}
{"id": 75, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04134260", "criterion": "Current use of 5-alpha reductase inhibitor. NOTE: if the alpha reductase inhibitor is stopped prior to randomization the patient is eligible", "note_date": "2022-05-05", "note": "82 yo male for bp follow up. no complaints. underwent successful turp last month. ros: neg for chest pain, cough or shortness of breath. he does have mild swelling of ankles. \nPROBLEMS Mental retardation Hypertension Anemia H/O peptic ulcer disease \nDX. BY UPPER ENDOSCOPY IN 2021. Benign prostatic hypertrophy s/p turp 4/20 Coronary artery disease ett 12/18: The ECG response to pharmacological stress was nondiagnostic for ischemia. The myocardial perfusion scans show a moderate size, severe, fixed inferior and inferolateral defect indicative of prior infarct with little if any residual ischemia. MEDICATIONS VIOXX (ROFECOXIB) 25MG 1 Tablet(s) PO QD PROSCAR (FINASTERIDE) 5MG 1 Tablet(s) PO QD LISINOPRIL 20MG 1 Tablet(s) PO QD \nALLERGIES HCTZ (HYDROCHLOROTHIAZIDE) \nHYPONATREMIA exam: weight 146 140/60 76 lungs;clear cor:RRRs1s2 with no gallops ext; trace ankle edema a/p: htn: stable. check lytes. cad with mild ankle edema. will send for cardiac echo to assess ef. consider adding lasix. will follow. otherwise no angina or failure. follow up in four months. Xavier U. Combs, M.D.\nBased on the following clinical note, answer the questions below the note and provide text spans from the note that justify the answers.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Was the patient receiving an 5-alpha reductase inhibitor at the time when the note was taken?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["PROSCAR (FINASTERIDE) 5MG 1 Tablet(s) PO QD "]}]}
{"id": 71, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04844749", "criterion": "Persistent toxicities (>Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Event (CTCAE) grade 2) caused by previous cancer therapy, excluding alopecia.", "note_date": "2022-06-28", "note": "A 58-year-old man was diagnosed with locally advanced pancreatic adenocarcinoma in October 2021. The patient had a good performance status score according to the Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) scale, and started neoadjuvant FOLFIRINOX chemotherapy (oxaliplatin 85 mg/m2, irinotecan 180 mg/m2, leucovorin 400 mg/m2 IV, and 5FU 2400 mg/m2 IV by continuous infusion over 48 h, with dexamethasone 10 mg and ondansetron 12 mg IV as pre-medication). According to the schedule, irinotecan was administered as an intravenous infusion over 90 min immediately after oxaliplatin. Subcutaneous atropine (0.25 mg) was given for cholinergic syndrome prophylaxis. About an hour after the start of the irinotecan infusion, the patient developed slurred speech that quickly progressed to dysarthria. CPT-11 infusion was quickly interrupted and symptoms spontaneously decreased and then completely resolved in about 90 min. At clinical examination, he was conscious and alert, neither motor nor sensitive neurological signs were noted, and the patient did not report any other symptoms. Two hours later, we decided to restart the infusion of irinotecan, slowing the infusion rate, without any adverse event. The second cycle was administered maintaining the same dose and with the same pre-medication, and the patient did not show dysarthria or other neurological symptoms. After the second cycle, he developed grade 2 thrombocytopenia according to the CTCAE  and he interrupted CPT-11, continuing the FOLFOX regimen. A partial response in the liver was shown; therefore, he underwent a partial hepatectomy. The patient is alive and disease-free; we closely monitor him with routine CT scans.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Did the patient present an adverse events grade 2 or higher according to CTCAE criteria?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["he developed grade 2 thrombocytopenia according to the CTCAE "]}, {"question": "If so, was the adverse event induced by the patient\u2019s chemotherapy ?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["After the second cycle, he developed grade 2 thrombocytopenia according to the CTCAE and he interrupted CPT-11"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the most recent time the patient experienced such an adverse event?\".", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 58, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04134260", "criterion": "Patients with a history of hepatitis C virus (HCV) infection must have been treated and cured. For patients with HCV infection who are currently on treatment, they are eligible if they have an undetectable HCV viral load within 30 days prior to registration", "note_date": "2022-07-01", "note": "2021-5-25 9:02 AM \nDUPLEX DOPP ABD/PEL Reason: Liver duplex. pls assess portal vein \nAdmitting Diagnosis: LIVER FAILURE\nMEDICAL CONDITION: 50M with EtOH/Hep C cirrhosis, hx ascites \nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION: Liver duplex. pls assess portal vein \nWET READ: PBec \nTUE 2021-5-25 11:00 AM portal vein and branches, as wellas hepatic veins, SMV and splenic all patent. Enlarged heterogenous liver. Nondistended GB with severe GB wall edema (no stones)- findings concerning for acute on chronic hepatitis. If concern for GB pathology, acalculous cholecystitis is a consideration and could be further eval with HIDA. PBishop \nWET READ VERSION #1 \nFINAL REPORT INDICATION: History of alcoholic and hepatitis C cirrhosis, ascites. Please assess portal vein thrombosis. COMPARISON: No prior studies available for comparison. \nFINDINGS: The liver is enlarged with a heterogeneous appearance and a macronodular contour, likely due to known cirrhosis. The main portal vein as well as the right anterior and posterior, and left portal veins are patent with hepatopetal flow. The common hepatic artery is patent with normal arterial flow. The left hepatic, middle, and right hepatic veins are patent with appropriate directionality of flow, as are the inferior vena cava, superior mesenteric, and splenic veins. The gallbladder is nondistended and does not contain gallstones or sludge; however, there is notable gallbladder wall edema measuring 2.8 cm. Given the size of the liver and known hepatitis C. diagnosis, this may suggest an acute on chronic episode of hepatitis. There is a trace perihepatic fluid. The pancreas is incompletely visualized due to overlying bowel gas. The spleen is enlarged consistent with history of cirrhosis, measuring 21 cm. The right kidney does not demonstrate stone, masses, or hydronephrosis. The visualized portions of the aorta and inferior vena cava are of normal caliber. IMPRESSION: 1. Enlarged heterogeneous macronodular liver consistent with history of hepatitis/cirrhosis. 2. Significant gallbladder wall edema in a nondistended gallbladder may be suggestive of acute on chronic hepatitis. Diagnostic cosnideraitons may include acalculous cholecystitis, but that is felt much less likely. 3. Splenomegaly. 4. Patent portal and hepatic veins as well as superior mesenteric vein and inferior vena cava. \n2021-5-25 9:02 AM DUPLEX DOPP ABD/PEL \nReason: Liver duplex. pls assess portal vein Admitting Diagnosis: LIVER FAILURE FINAL REPORT", "qa_list": [{"question": "Does the patient have a history of hepatitis C infection?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["History of alcoholic and hepatitis C cirrhosis"]}, {"question": "If so, has the patient received therapy for the Hepatitis C infection?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "What is the patient's most recent HCV viral load?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "When was that viral load measured?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 73, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04844749", "criterion": "The patient must not have a prior history of a thromboembolic event within the last 6 months.", "note_date": "2022-07-13", "note": "Ms. Angelita Romero is a 42-year-old lady with 56-kg body weight, a patient with a history of severe rhumatic valvular heart disease with pulmonary hypertensoion. She was referred to our hospital 8 days ago with severe acute pain in left lower limb, which developed 16 hours before, due to acute femoral thromboembolic occlusion. She had exertional dyspnoea NYHA class II with palpitation and was receiving warfarin, diuretics, bronchodilators and digoxin. Intravenous heparin 5000 IU was given at a referring hospital 2 hours prior to our procedure. Clinical diagnosis of acute femoral artery thrombo-embolic occlusion with scanty distal flow was confirmed with color doppler. Investigation showed haemoglobin of 16.5 g% with total leukocyte count of 11,400/ml, serum creatinine 1.2 mg/dl, International Normalised Ratio 1.61, Bleeding Time and Clotting Time 2.3 and 5.0 minutes, respectively, prolonged activated Partial Thromboplastin Time beyond measurement and serum K+ 5.2 meq/l. Electrocardiogram showed atrial fibrillation (AF) with ST-T changes, echocardiogram revealed AF without atrial thrombus, severe mitral stenosis (valve area 0.9 cm2), grade II mitral regurgitation, severe aortic stenosis (peak pressure gradient/mean pressure gradient 75/51 mm Hg), severe pulmonary hypertension, severe tricuspid regurgitation with left ventricular hypertrophy. The patient also had poor pulmonary function with room air saturation of 91%.\nThe patient was taken for emergency thrombo-embolectomy. A combined femoral sciatic nerve block was planned. In supine position, a 22-G, 2.5-inch nerve locator (INMED, locator, HN) needle was used for femoral block; posterior branch of femoral nerve was located (by patellar ascension, dancing patella). A mixture of 20 ml local anaesthetic (15 ml of 0.5% bupivacaine + 5 ml of 2% lignocaine) was injected into the femoral sheath with a firm distal digital pressure. Fifteen minutes later, the patient had adequate pain relief. The patient repositioned laterally to perform sciatic block with the classic approach of Labat. Thirty milliliters of 0.25% bupivacaine was injected into the sheath of sciatic nerve using 22-G 10-cm needle (INMED, locator, HN) to identify the nerve eliciting motor responses of plantar flexion.\nAfter 20 minutes of sciatic block, the patient was totally relieved of pain and surgical embolectomy [Figures and ] was performed. Arterial and limb venous blood gas analysis was done prior to and following embolectomy. Total blood loss was 150 ml. Intravenous 2500 units of heparin was administered. Patient was monitored in postoperative ICU. An ultrasound (10 MHz, higher linear frequency probe, Acuson150, Seimens, California, USA) guided evaluation was carried out to rule out haematoma formation and compression on nerves at both sites, twice, till the complete motor and sensory recovery, which was after 7.5 hours. The patient had uneventful recovery and she was discharged earlier today, on the eighth day of her stay here.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient had a thromboembolic event?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["She was referred to our hospital 8 days ago with severe acute pain in left lower limb, which developed 16 hours before, due to acute femoral thromboembolic occlusion"]}, {"question": "If so, when did the most recent thromboembolic event occur, relative to the note date?", "answer": "2022-7-5", "justification": ["She was referred to our hospital 8 days ago with severe acute pain in left lower limb, which developed 16 hours before, due to acute femoral thromboembolic occlusion", "Note Date: 2022-7-13"]}]}
{"id": 121, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03957876", "criterion": "The patient is surgically sterile", "note_date": "2022-07-22", "note": "HPI:\n38yF 1 month post partum s/p b/l laparoscopic tubal ligation on 7-5\np/w abd pain, N/V. Found to have free air, taken to OR and had 1cm\nlaceration to jejunum with gross contamination and free fluid. S/P\nExlap, washout, primary repair (oversewn 2 layer closure).\nChief complaint:\nPMHx:\ngastritis, MDD, brain tumor age 11 with spont resolution, chronic\nmigraines, bell's palsy\nPSH: lap B/l tubal ligation\nSepsis without organ dysfunction\nAssessment:\nVSS, heart reate 70\ns-80\ns. Sbp 110\ns-120\ns. Alert, oriented x\ns 3,\npleasant and cooperative. LS clear and diminished, o2 sat 98% on 4\nliters n.c. Abd. is softly distended, absent bowel sounds. NGT to low\nwall suction draining green bilious drainage. Midline incision is\nc/d/I, post-op dressing still in place. Pt has right IJ CVL\nAction:\nPt ambulated in hallway today, then in chair x\ns 1 hour. IVF changed\nto d5/12 NS with 20meq KCL at 100cc\ns/hr. Coughing/deep breathing and\nincentive spirometry encouraged.\nResponse:\nStable, ambulating, ready for transfer to the floor.\nPlan:\nContinue to ambulate, continue IV antibiotics, NPO for now, continue\nngt to lws, transfer to [**Hospital Ward Name 1437**].\nPain control (acute pain, chronic pain)\nAssessment:\nPt reports pain 2/(10), constant in abdomen\nAction:\nPt using dilaudid pca appropriately, splinting abdomen when\nturning/coughing, etc.\nResponse:\nPain well controlled.\nPlan:\nContinue to monitor.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient undergone a surgical sterilization procedure?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["s/p b/l laparoscopic tubal ligation on 7-5"]}, {"question": "If so, when?", "answer": "2022-7-5", "justification": ["Note Date: 2022-7-22", "s/p b/l laparoscopic tubal ligation on 7-5"]}]}
{"id": 122, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2022-07-22", "note": "HPI:\n38yF 1 month post partum s/p b/l laparoscopic tubal ligation on 7-5\np/w abd pain, N/V. Found to have free air, taken to OR and had 1cm\nlaceration to jejunum with gross contamination and free fluid. S/P\nExlap, washout, primary repair (oversewn 2 layer closure).\nChief complaint:\nPMHx:\ngastritis, MDD, brain tumor age 11 with spont resolution, chronic\nmigraines, bell's palsy\nPSH: lap B/l tubal ligation\nSepsis without organ dysfunction\nAssessment:\nVSS, heart reate 70\ns-80\ns. Sbp 110\ns-120\ns. Alert, oriented x\ns 3,\npleasant and cooperative. LS clear and diminished, o2 sat 98% on 4\nliters n.c. Abd. is softly distended, absent bowel sounds. NGT to low\nwall suction draining green bilious drainage. Midline incision is\nc/d/I, post-op dressing still in place. Pt has right IJ CVL\nAction:\nPt ambulated in hallway today, then in chair x\ns 1 hour. IVF changed\nto d5/12 NS with 20meq KCL at 100cc\ns/hr. Coughing/deep breathing and\nincentive spirometry encouraged.\nResponse:\nStable, ambulating, ready for transfer to the floor.\nPlan:\nContinue to ambulate, continue IV antibiotics, NPO for now, continue\nngt to lws, transfer to [**Hospital Ward Name 1437**].\nPain control (acute pain, chronic pain)\nAssessment:\nPt reports pain 2/(10), constant in abdomen\nAction:\nPt using dilaudid pca appropriately, splinting abdomen when\nturning/coughing, etc.\nResponse:\nPain well controlled.\nPlan:\nContinue to monitor.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Were this patient\u2019s vital signs stable at the time that the note was taken?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Assessment:VSS"]}]}
{"id": 55, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2022-09-30", "note": "I had the pleasure of seeing Mr. Potts in follow up today. He recently had a complicated hospital course. He underwent cardiac catheterization on September 20, which revealed serial stenoses of the LAD including 70% and 90% stenoses. The first marginal branch had a 60% ostial stenosis. The right coronary artery had 60 and 80% stenoses, respectively. The PDA had a 70% narrowing. Given his very significant wish not to have bypass surgery, it was decided to proceed with angioplasty of the right coronary artery as well as the obtuse marginal. It was felt that the LAD was a small vessel, and not worth going after at this time. The RCA was successfully stented, but was complicated by occlusion of the posterior left ventricular branch. By the end of the procedure, flow had been restored to some degree to the posterior left ventricular branch, but Mr. Potts rule in for a small subendocardial myocardial infarction. Due to the closure of the left posterior ventricular branch, the obtuse marginal branch was not dilated.\nMr. Potts underwent two exercise tests post procedure. The second exercise test was performed with MIBI imaging. He exercised for nine minutes on a submaximal Bruce protocol, and experienced chest pain. He had a maximal blood pressure of 148/72 and a heart rate of 121. MIBI images revealed a small nontransmural myocardial infarction of the basal 1/3 of the inferior wall. There was moderate to severe ischemia of the inferolateral territory in the territory of the RCA.\nGiven these findings, it was highly recommended that Mr. Potts undergo bypass surgery. Mr. Potts was discharged on September 22 on aspirin, Ticlid 250 mg b.i.d., Atorvastatin 20 mg q.h.s., Atenolol 50 mg b.i.d., Imdur 60 mg q.d. He also takes vitamin E and a multivitamin.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Is this patient being treated with nitrates?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["Imdur 60 mg q.d"]}, {"question": "If so, when did treatment start?", "answer": "September 22, 2022", "justification": ["Mr. Potts was discharged on September 22 on aspirin, Ticlid 250 mg b.i.d., Atorvastatin 20 mg q.h.s., Atenolol 50 mg b.i.d., Imdur 60 mg q.d."]}, {"question": "If so, what is the dosage and frequency of the nitrate medication?", "answer": "60 mg q.d", "justification": ["Imdur 60 mg q.d."]}]}
{"id": 152, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2022-03-01", "note": "On 2020-2-14, a 26-year-old African American male with a history of SCD, HbSS genotype, presented to our hospital with a 2-day history of worsening epigastric abdominal pain. On exam, the patient was jaundiced, had abdominal tenderness, but no evidence of hepatosplenomegaly. Total bilirubin was elevated to 24.9 mg/dL (reference range 0.2\u20131.2 mg/dL) along with aspartate transaminase (AST) 176 units/L (reference range 5\u201340 units/L) and alanine transaminase (ALT) 108 units/L (reference range 0\u201355 units/L). Hepatitis B and C as well as HIV testing was negative. An MRI demonstrated no hepatomegaly and an atrophic spleen consistent with chronic SCD. Right upper quadrant ultrasound was notable for cholelithiasis and on his seventh day in the hospital he underwent cholecystectomy and cholangiopancreatography for removal of a common bile duct stone.\nOn day 10 in hospital, he continued to have increased total bilirubin with a peak of 80 mg/dL and also developed a prolonged prothrombin time (PT), 18.9 seconds (reference range 11\u201314.6 seconds). A presumptive diagnosis of SCIC was made, and on the same day the patient underwent RBCEx with a goal of 20% HbS utilizing six units of crossmatched-compatible red blood cells (RBC) which were C, E, and Kell phenotypically matched and SICKLEDEX\u00ae (Streck, Omaha, NE) negative on the COBE Spectra Apheresis System (Terumo BCT, Lakewood, CO). His hemoglobin S level decreased from 44.4% to 17.8%. His laboratory markers improved, and the patient was discharged. Today is his 2-years follow-up visit and the patient has returned to his clinical and laboratory baseline without development of chronic SCIC.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient undergone a red blood cell exchange?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["the patient underwent RBCEx"]}, {"question": "If so, when?", "answer": "2020-2-24", "justification": ["On day 10 in hospital, he continued to have increased total bilirubin with a peak of 80 mg/dL and also developed a prolonged prothrombin time (PT), 18.9 seconds (reference range 11\u201314.6 seconds). A presumptive diagnosis of SCIC was made, and on the same day the patient underwent RBCEx"]}]}
{"id": 151, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2022-03-01", "note": "On 2020-2-14, a 26-year-old African American male with a history of SCD, HbSS genotype, presented to our hospital with a 2-day history of worsening epigastric abdominal pain. On exam, the patient was jaundiced, had abdominal tenderness, but no evidence of hepatosplenomegaly. Total bilirubin was elevated to 24.9 mg/dL (reference range 0.2\u20131.2 mg/dL) along with aspartate transaminase (AST) 176 units/L (reference range 5\u201340 units/L) and alanine transaminase (ALT) 108 units/L (reference range 0\u201355 units/L). Hepatitis B and C as well as HIV testing was negative. An MRI demonstrated no hepatomegaly and an atrophic spleen consistent with chronic SCD. Right upper quadrant ultrasound was notable for cholelithiasis and on his seventh day in the hospital he underwent cholecystectomy and cholangiopancreatography for removal of a common bile duct stone.\nOn day 10 in hospital, he continued to have increased total bilirubin with a peak of 80 mg/dL and also developed a prolonged prothrombin time (PT), 18.9 seconds (reference range 11\u201314.6 seconds). A presumptive diagnosis of SCIC was made, and on the same day the patient underwent RBCEx with a goal of 20% HbS utilizing six units of crossmatched-compatible red blood cells (RBC) which were C, E, and Kell phenotypically matched and SICKLEDEX\u00ae (Streck, Omaha, NE) negative on the COBE Spectra Apheresis System (Terumo BCT, Lakewood, CO). His hemoglobin S level decreased from 44.4% to 17.8%. His laboratory markers improved, and the patient was discharged. Today is his 2-years follow-up visit and the patient has returned to his clinical and laboratory baseline without development of chronic SCIC.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient had their gallbladder removed?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["he underwent cholecystectomy"]}, {"question": "If so, when?", "answer": "2020-2-21", "justification": ["on his seventh day in the hospital he underwent cholecystectomy", "On 2020-2-14, a 26-year-old African American male with a history of SCD, HbSS genotype, presented to our hospital"]}]}
{"id": 150, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2022-03-01", "note": "On 2020-2-14, a 26-year-old African American male with a history of SCD, HbSS genotype, presented presented to our hospital with a 2-day history of worsening epigastric abdominal pain. On exam, the patient was jaundiced, had abdominal tenderness, but no evidence of hepatosplenomegaly. Total bilirubin was elevated to 24.9 mg/dL (reference range 0.2\u20131.2 mg/dL) along with aspartate transaminase (AST) 176 units/L (reference range 5\u201340 units/L) and alanine transaminase (ALT) 108 units/L (reference range 0\u201355 units/L). Hepatitis B and C as well as HIV testing was negative. An MRI demonstrated no hepatomegaly and an atrophic spleen consistent with chronic SCD. Right upper quadrant ultrasound was notable for cholelithiasis and on his seventh day in the hospital he underwent cholecystectomy and cholangiopancreatography for removal of a common bile duct stone.\nOn day 10 in hospital, he continued to have increased total bilirubin with a peak of 80 mg/dL and also developed a prolonged prothrombin time (PT), 18.9 seconds (reference range 11\u201314.6 seconds). A presumptive diagnosis of SCIC was made, and on the same day the patient underwent RBCEx with a goal of 20% HbS utilizing six units of crossmatched-compatible red blood cells (RBC) which were C, E, and Kell phenotypically matched and SICKLEDEX\u00ae (Streck, Omaha, NE) negative on the COBE Spectra Apheresis System (Terumo BCT, Lakewood, CO). His hemoglobin S level decreased from 44.4% to 17.8%. His laboratory markers improved, and the patient was discharged. Today is his 2-years follow-up visit and the patient has returned to his clinical and laboratory baseline without development of chronic SCIC.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Does the patient have a history of sickle cell disease?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": [" a history of SCD"]}, {"question": "If so, what is the corresponding disease genotype?", "answer": "HbSS", "justification": ["a history of SCD, HbSS genotype"]}]}
{"id": 53, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2022-09-30", "note": "I had the pleasure of seeing Mr. Potts in follow up today. He recently had a complicated hospital course. He underwent cardiac catheterization on September 26, which revealed serial stenoses of the LAD including 70% and 90% stenoses. The first marginal branch had a 60% ostial stenosis. The right coronary artery had 60 and 80% stenoses, respectively. The PDA had a 70% narrowing. Given his very significant wish not to have bypass surgery, it was decided to proceed with angioplasty of the right coronary artery as well as the obtuse marginal. It was felt that the LAD was a small vessel, and not worth going after at this time. The RCA was successfully stented, but was complicated by occlusion of the posterior left ventricular branch. By the end of the procedure, flow had been restored to some degree to the posterior left ventricular branch, but Mr. Potts rule in for a small subendocardial myocardial infarction. Due to the closure of the left posterior ventricular branch, the obtuse marginal branch was not dilated.\nMr. Potts underwent two exercise tests post procedure. The second exercise test was performed with MIBI imaging. He exercised for nine minutes on a submaximal Bruce protocol, and experienced chest pain. He had a maximal blood pressure of 148/72 and a heart rate of 121. MIBI images revealed a small nontransmural myocardial infarction of the basal 1/3 of the inferior wall. There was moderate to severe ischemia of the inferolateral territory in the territory of the RCA.\nGiven these findings, it was highly recommended that Mr. Potts undergo bypass surgery. Mr. Potts was discharged on aspirin, Ticlid 250 mg b.i.d., Atorvastatin 20 mg q.h.s., Atenolol 50 mg b.i.d., Imdur 60 mg q.d. He also takes vitamin E and a multivitamin.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Does this patient have significant narrowing of a coronary artery?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["He underwent cardiac catheterization on September 26, which revealed serial stenoses of the LAD including 70% and 90% stenoses"]}, {"question": "If so, what is the narrowed artery?", "answer": "LAD", "justification": ["He underwent cardiac catheterization on September 26, which revealed serial stenoses of the LAD including 70% and 90% stenoses"]}, {"question": "If so, what is the largest extent of that narrowing?", "answer": "90%", "justification": ["He underwent cardiac catheterization on September 26, which revealed serial stenoses of the LAD including 70% and 90% stenoses"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the narrowing detected?", "answer": "2022-09-26", "justification": ["He underwent cardiac catheterization on September 26"]}]}
{"id": 15, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2022-12-20", "note": "Past Medical History:\n\n* Hypertension\n* BPH\n* Hypercholesterolemia\n* B12 def dx'd 2y ago by PCP, Dr. Ethan Bloch. \n* Grade I diastolic dysfunction by echo in 10-26 \n* Myeloma/MDS: Kappa light chain myeloma. Presented with MGUS\n\n2014 without evidence of end organ damage. Initially observed until 2016 when monoclonal protein rose and patient treated with 6 cycles melphalan/prednisone. Patient remained stable until 2014 when protein rose again and was treated with 8 cycles melphalan/prednisone finishing 9-25. He then remained off treatment until 9-26 when began to develop anemia/bone pain. Found to have smear consistent with MDS involving all 3 lineages. Began treatment with velcade/revalmid and epo, then mephalan/prednisone d/c'd earlier this year due to inability to tolerate. Also had T9 and T11 involvement s/p radiation in 2021. He was receiving treatment for his Myeloma until December 2022 /dexamethasone/revlamide/alkaran but it was dc'ed 12-22 to inability to tolerate regimen. \n   - h/o hyponatremia\n   - h/o multiple PNAs requiring hospitalization\n   - h/o C.Diff.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Does this patient have bone pain?", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["began to develop anemia/bone pain"]}]}
{"id": 161, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2021-06-06", "note": "Record date: 2021-06-06\r\nProblems\r\nDiabetes mellitus type 2 : 10/20\r\nHyperlipidemia : 10/20\r\nSmoking\r\nFH Uncoded Information:\r\nComments: Father: age + 80 prostate cancer; diabetesMother: age 40 + uterine cancerSiblings:1bMarital status:mChildren:1F - 16FH is notable for the presence (+) or absence(-) of CAD ;Cancer ++ ;diabetes + ;HTN ; genetic disorder\r\nMedications\r\nLipitor (ATORVASTATIN) 10MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) QD\r\nAspirin (ACETYLSALICYLIC ACID) 81MG TABLET EC take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD\r\nAllergies\r\nTetracycline Hcl - headache,\r\nHealth Maintenance\r\nInfluenza Vaccine 02/20/2121 given\r\nCholesterol 03/14/2121 137\r\nM-alb/creat ratio 10/17/2120 9.4\r\nMammogram 07/31/2120 see report in Results\r\nPap Smear 09/13/2120 see report in Results\r\nPneumovax 02/20/2121 11/20\r\nUA-Protein 07/25/12 NEG\r\nOphthal Exam 02/20/2121 set up\r\nTriglycerides 03/14/2121 85\r\nCholesterol-LDL 03/14/2121 76\r\nMicroalbumin 10/17/2120 1.0\r\nBone Density 02/20/2121 set up\r\nHct (Hematocrit) 08/28/2120 40.8\r\nCholesterol-HDL 03/14/2121 44\r\nHgb (Hemoglobin) 08/28/2120 14.0\r\nHbA1c 01/13/2121 7.50\r\nCOLONOSCOPY\r\nVital Signs\r\nBP 120/88\r\nAGE 57y8.4m\r\nComes in today because she was diagnosed yesterday with an oral mucosal cancer\r\nFeels well otherwise\r\nno chest pain or dyspnoea\r\nlesion on floor of mouth\r\nno nodes\r\ncarotid bruits\r\nchest clear\r\nhs 1,2\r\nrefer to oral surgeon\r\nset up carotid us again\r\nreminded about colonoscopy", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with lung cancer", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, did the patient receive chemotherapy for lung cancer", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 160, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "Patient must have undergone axillary staging (sentinel node biopsy and/or axillary node dissection).", "note_date": "2019-08-25", "note": "CHIEF COMPLAINT: Left breast cancer.,\r\nHISTORY: The patient is a 57-year-old female, who I initially saw in the office on 2019/07/12, as a referral from the Tomball Breast Center.  On 2019/07/21, the patient underwent image-guided needle core biopsy of a 1.5 cm lesion at the 7 o'clock position of the left breast (inferomedial).  The biopsy returned showing infiltrating ductal carcinoma high histologic grade.  The patient stated that she had recently felt and her physician had felt a palpable mass in that area prior to her breast imaging.  She prior to that area, denied any complaints.  She had no nipple discharge.  No trauma history.  She has had been on no estrogen supplementation.  She has had no other personal history of breast cancer.  Her family history is positive for her mother having breast cancer at age 48.  The patient has had no children and no pregnancies.  She denies any change in the right breast.  Subsequent to the office visit and tissue diagnosis of breast cancer, she has had medical oncology consultation with Dr. Smith and radiation oncology consultation with Dr. Brown.  I have discussed the case with Dr. Smith and Dr. Brown, who are both in agreement with proceeding with surgery prior to adjuvant therapy.  The patient's metastatic workup has otherwise been negative with MRI scan and CT scanning.  The MRI scan showed some close involvement possibly involving the left pectoralis muscle, although thought to also possibly represent biopsy artifact.  CT scan of the neck, chest, and abdomen is negative for metastatic disease. PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:,  Previous surgery is history of benign breast biopsy in 2015, laparotomy in 2015, 2016, and 2018, right oophorectomy in 2018, and ganglion cyst removal of the hand in 2018. MEDICATIONS:,  She is currently on omeprazole for reflux and indigestion.,ALLERGIES:,  SHE HAS NO KNOWN DRUG ALLERGIES.,REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:,  Negative for any recent febrile illnesses, chest pains or shortness of breath.  Positive for restless leg syndrome.  Negative for any unexplained weight loss and no change in bowel or bladder habits.,FAMILY HISTORY:,  Positive for breast cancer in her mother and also mesothelioma from possible asbestosis or asbestos exposure.,SOCIAL HISTORY:  ,The patient works as a school teacher and teaching high school.,PHYSICAL EXAMINATION,GENERAL:  The patient is a white female, alert and oriented x 3, appears her stated age of 57.,HEENT:  Head is atraumatic and normocephalic.  Sclerae are anicteric.,NECK:  Supple.,CHEST:  Clear.,HEART:  Regular rate and rhythm.,BREASTS:  Exam reveals an approximately 1.5 cm relatively mobile focal palpable mass in the inferomedial left breast at the 7 o'clock position, which clinically is not fixed to the underlying pectoralis muscle.  There are no nipple retractions.  No skin dimpling.  There is some, at the time of the office visit, ecchymosis from recent biopsy.  There is no axillary adenopathy.  The remainder of the left breast is without abnormality.  The right breast is without abnormality.  The axillary areas are negative for adenopathy bilaterally.,ABDOMEN:  Soft, nontender without masses.  No gross organomegaly.  No CVA or flank tenderness.,EXTREMITIES:  Grossly neurovascularly intact.,IMPRESSION: , The patient is a 57-year-old female with invasive ductal carcinoma of the left breast, T1c, Nx, M0 left breast carcinoma.,RECOMMENDATIONS: , I have discussed with the patient in detail about the diagnosis of breast cancer and the surgical options, and medical oncologist has discussed with her issues about adjuvant or neoadjuvant chemotherapy.  We have decided to recommend to the patient breast conservation surgery with left breast lumpectomy with preoperative sentinel lymph node injection and mapping and left axillary dissection.  The possibility of further surgery requiring wider lumpectomy or even completion mastectomy was explained to the patient.  The procedure and risks of the surgery were explained to include, but not limited to extra bleeding, infection, unsightly scar formation, the possibility of local recurrence, the possibility of left upper extremity lymphedema was explained.  Local numbness, paresthesias or chronic pain was explained.  The patient was given an educational brochure and several brochures about the diagnosis and treatment of breast cancers.  She was certainly encouraged to obtain further surgical medical opinions prior to proceeding.  I believe the patient has given full informed consent and desires to proceed with the above.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient undergone sentinel node biopsy", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "Has the patient undergone axillary node biopsy", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 158, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2021-03-15", "note": "Record date: 2021-03-15\r\nCARDIOLOGY\r\nFRANCISCAN HEALTH CENTER\r\nReason for visit:\r\nchest pain, with known LCX lesion admit for cardiac cath in am.\r\nInterval History:\r\n75 yr old male who is admitted with new onset chest pain. Pt has a hx of significant AAA repair and newly diagnosed nonoperable pancreatic cancer. During evaluation of pancreatic cancer, CT revealed pseudoaneurysm of aortic graft. Before start of chemotherapy, pt underwent surgical repair of pseudoaneurysm.\r\n2020-10-01 Pt had successful surgical repair of the pseudoaneurysm, complicated by a intraoperative NSTEMI with a peak troponin of .36.\r\n2020-10-23 echo done showing EF of 70%.\r\n2020-10-23 cath revealing LM normal, LAD 40% stenosis after D1, 95% stenosis at ostium of D1 and LCX 80% at the takeoff of OM2 with 70%ostial OM2 lesion, and RCA non-dominant with no significant disease.\r\nBecause pt was not having any symptoms of angina, the decision was made not to intervene on the LCX lesion and to stress the pt at a later date.\r\nCurrently pt is to begin treatment of his pancreatic cancer with chemotherapy and radiation.  Today pt was to have his first treatment, but starting having chest pain and was sent to the ER for further evaluation.\r\nRecently for the past three days, pt reports on and off chest pain lasting 4-5 hours with raidation to jaw and left arm at rest and excertion. No assciated symptoms of SOB or diaphoresis. Pt thought he was having heartburn symptoms.\r\nIn the ER, EKG showed mild lateral ST depression in V5-V6, initial troponin neg and chest pain relieved with one SL nitrogylcerin. Heparin started and pt transferred pain free to Cardiology.   Upon arrival, pt had one episode of chest pain, EKG showed no acute changes, chest pain relieved with one SL nitrogylcerin.\r\nPast medical history: NIDDM, Spinal stenosis, Kidney stones, HTN, AAA repair\r\nCholecystectomy, Prostate Cancer '19, prostatectomy, Lung Cancer RLL 20, lobectomy\r\nMedications at Home:\r\nGlyburide 10mg BID\r\nLisinopril 5mg daily\r\nASA 81mg daily\r\nMetoprolol 25mg BID\r\nZocor 20mg daily\r\nPlavix 75mg daily\r\nAllergies:\r\nAllergy   IV contrast-parotid swelling\r\nDrug allergy   sudaphed-insomnia  oxycodone-GI intolerance\r\nFamily history:\r\nFather died aged 61 lung cancer\r\nMother died aged 71\r\nSister died of kidney failure\r\nSocial history:\r\nMarried and retired industrial instrument technician. Has five grown children and three grandchildren.\r\nSmoked for 32 years, 1ppd and quit in the 20's. Denies any ETOH.\r\nReview of systems:\r\nDenies any headaches, stroke, visual distrubances, syncope or seizures.\r\nDenies any chest pain, SOB, dizziness, or palpations.\r\nDenis any SOB, cough, or difficulty breathing.\r\nDenies any abd pain, nausea or vomiting, black or bloody stools.\r\nDenies any difficutly with urination.\r\nDenies any weakness, numbness, or tingling in the extremites.\r\nPhysical examination:\r\n-BP: 190/102\r\n-Pulse: 60\r\n-resp. rate: 20  98%  on 2L NC\r\n-temp: 98.2\r\n-General:   No acute distress.\r\n-Skin:   No rashes, anicteric.\r\n-HEENT:   Unremarkable\r\n-Neck:   Carotids 2+ without bruits. JVP no jugular venous distention.\r\n-Chest:   Clear to auscultation.\r\n-Cardiac:   Regular rate and rhythm, normal S1 and S2, with no S3 or S4. There were no murmurs, clicks or rubs. Porta cath noted to the right subclavin.\r\n-Abdomen:   Normal bowel sounds, soft and nontender, with no hepatosplenomegaly or masses appreciated.\r\n-Extremities:   No cyanosis, clubbing or edema. 2+ femoral pulses without bruits. Bilateral vertical incisions noted with steri strips, C,D,I with no redness and no thrill or bruits noted. 2+ pedal pulses.\r\n-Neuro:   A&O x3, MAE.\r\nEKG:\r\nNo acute ST changes, normal axis with good R wave progression and <.5mm ST depression in V5 and V6.\r\nAssessment and plan:\r\n75 yr old male with unoperable pancreatic cancer who is s/p pseudoaneurysm repair and with LCX lesion who is having unstable angina, initial troponin negative and admit for cardiac cath in am.\r\nPlan:\r\nAdmit to Cardiology\r\nCurrently on ASA and Plavix, will continue.\r\nContinue ACE, BUN and Creatine WNL.\r\nContinue BB, HR and BP well controlled.\r\nWill cycle cardiac enzymes.\r\nNPO for cardiac cath in am, pt will dye allergy, will pre medicate with po prednisone and benadryl.\r\nPt with recent surgical repair of pseudoaneurysm with bilateral arteriotomies of femoral arteries, question of sones approach.\r\nFood and Nutrition Consult.\r\nWill continue Heparin  and SS.\r\nPt has porta cath, will be flushed per protocol.\r\nOf note chemotherapy infusion stopped in ER and pump noted at bedside.\r\nDr. Angeline Barajas following for pancreatic cancer.\r\nFurther orders per attending.\r\n-frances cramer, RN\r\nSigned electronically by  frances cramer, RN\r\nDocument Status: Final", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient history of pancreatic cancer", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["newly diagnosed nonoperable pancreatic cancer"]}, {"question": "Has the patient received treatment for pancreatic cancer on a note relative to the clinical note", "answer": "No", "justification": ["Currently pt is to begin treatment of his pancreatic cancer with chemotherapy and radiation.  Today pt was to have his first treatment, but starting having chest pain and was sent to the ER for further evaluation.", "Of note chemotherapy infusion stopped in ER and pump noted at bedside."]}]}
{"id": 157, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2021-09-15", "note": "2021-09-07 12:00:00 AM\r\nOVARIAN MASS .\r\nUnsigned\r\nDIS\r\nReport Status :\r\nUnsigned\r\nADMISSION DATE :\r\n2021-09-07\r\nDISCHARGE DATE :\r\n2021-09-15\r\nPRINCIPAL DIAGNOSIS :\r\nOvarian mass .\r\nASSOCIATED DIAGNOSIS :\r\nPapanicolaou smear positive for somomabodies , incontinence .\r\nPRINCIPAL PROCEDURE :\r\nTotal abdominal hysterectomy , bilateral salpingo-oophorectomy , lysis of adhesions , open laparoscopy , Birch procedure , suprapubic bladder catheter placement .\r\nHISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS :\r\nThe patient is a 52 year old female with gravida 3 para 3 who presents with complains of abdominal pain and enlarged ovary by ultrasound .\r\nThe patient is also complaining of several years urinary incontinence .\r\nThe patient &apos;s recent history is also notable for a Papanicolaou smear which revealed somomabodies .\r\nThe patient also had vaginal bleeding in April 2020 following radiation therapy .\r\nThe patient initially presented with hypercalcemia and underwent a parathyroidectomy on June 22 , 2020.\r\nIt was at that time that her abnormal Papanicolaou smear was obtained .\r\nThe patient is now admitted for exploratory laparotomy .\r\nPAST MEDICAL HISTORY :\r\nThe past medical history is notable for lymphosarcoma in 2005 .\r\nShe was treated with radiation therapy .\r\nIn 2015 , the patient had a left axillary recurrence that was treated with radiation therapy .\r\nThe patient also has a history of hyperparathyroidism secondary to papillary thyroid cancer .\r\nThe history is also notable for gallstones , kidney stones , episodic tachycardia , chronic pancreatitis .\r\nOf note , the patient also has a history of incontinence .\r\nThe patient also has hypothyroidism .\r\nPAST SURGICAL HISTORY :\r\nThe patient &apos;s past surgical history is notable for the removal of a thyroid nodule in February 2013 .\r\nThis revealed papillary thyroid cancer and the patient received radioactive iodine ablation .\r\nIn June 2017 , the patient had a parathyroidectomy and also of note , in September 2019 , the patient had an exploratory laparotomy for pain and chronic pancreatitis .\r\nMEDICATIONS ON ADMISSION :\r\nInclude Librax 1 PO before meals , Pancrease 2 tabs before meals , Synthroid 0.125 mg PO qd .\r\nTenormin 50 mg bid , Valium 5 mg bid to tid , Premarin 0.625 mg qd , Provera 2.5 mg qod , Desyrel 50 mg qhs .\r\nALLERGIES :\r\nThe patient &apos;s allergies include Septra .\r\nSOCIAL HISTORY :\r\nThe patient &apos;s social history is notable for a heavy smoking history .\r\nShe is interested in quitting smoking .\r\nThe patient has no history of alcohol abuse .\r\nPHYSICAL EXAMINATION :\r\nThe patient &apos;s preoperative examination is notable for normal breasts , normal heart and lungs .\r\nThe pelvic examination is normal except for the presence of a full right ovary .\r\nThe rectovaginal examination is normal .\r\nHOSPITAL COURSE :\r\nThe patient was judged to be at risk secondary to her history of somomabodies and vaginal bleeding .\r\nHer differential diagnosis included ovarian cancer .\r\nThe patient was admitted on July 9 to the operating room .\r\nShe underwent an open laparoscopy , total abdominal hysterectomy , bilateral salpingo-oophorectomy , lysis of adhesions , Birch procedure , and suprapubic Foley catheter placement and Jackson-Pratt drain placement .\r\nThe estimated blood loss was 300 cc .\r\nThere were no complications during the procedure and the patient returned to the recovery room in stable condition .\r\nPostoperatively , the patient did well .\r\nHer calcium was followed daily and repleted as needed .\r\nHer Jackson-Pratt drain was removed on postoperative day number two .\r\nThe patient had a temperature of 101.6 on postoperative day two .\r\nHer lungs revealed coarse breath sounds .\r\nShe was encouraged to ambulate and deep breath .\r\nThe patient was started on nebulizer treatment .\r\nThe patient did well and her suprapubic tube was clamped starting on postoperative day four .\r\nThe patient voided spontaneously .\r\nClamping continued until postoperative day six .\r\nAt this time , her post-void residuals range from 2 cc to 25 cc .\r\nThe suprapubic tube was therefore discontinued .\r\nBy postoperative day six , the patient was also tolerating a regular diet and passing flatus .\r\nA chest X-ray was performed secondary to the patient &apos;s coarse breath sounds , however , the chest X-ray was clear except for a small amount of atelectasis .\r\nThe patient was discharged home .\r\nfinal pathology revealed right Fallopian tube and ovary with benign paratubal cysts and adhesions .\r\nThe cervix revealed squamous metaplasia .\r\nThe patient was discharged home on admission medications .\r\nIn addition , she will take Ciprofloxacin for nine more days .\r\nShe will also take Percocet .\r\nDISPOSITION :\r\nThe patient is discharged to home and is to follow up with Dr. White , as well as Dr. Kotefold and Dr. Cancer .\r\nKITRI CURB , M.D.\r\nDICTATING FOR :\r\nEARNRA CANCER , M.D.\r\nTR :\r\nnx / bmot\r\nDD :\r\n2021-09-15\r\nCC :\r\nDr. Ertca Cancer , Dr. Kotefold", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient received immunotherapy on a note relative to the clinical note", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when did the immunotherapy treatment started", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 156, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04844749", "criterion": "Other than metastatic prostate cancer, no evidence (within 5 years) of prior malignancies (except successfully treated basal cell or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin or other cancers treated with curative intent >3 years prior).", "note_date": "2022-09-06", "note": "2022-9-6 3:44 PM\r\nCT HEAD W/ & W/O CONTRAST \r\nReason: staging /  destruction / hxof squamous cell carcinoma\r\nAdmitting Diagnosis: CLAUDICATION\r\nMEDICAL CONDITION:\r\n48 year old man with pt with hx of squamous cell ca / now has lesion on occiput\r\n/ may have destruction / please assess / ? staging\r\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION:\r\nstaging / destruction / hxof squamous cell carcinoma\r\nNo contraindications for IV contrast\r\nFINAL REPORT\r\nINDICATION:  48-year-old man with history of squamous cell carcinoma, now has\r\nlesion on occiput.\r\nHEAD CT WITHOUT CONTRAST:  Comparison was made with a prior head CT dated\r\n2022-2-28.  The overall appearance of the brain is unchanged since prior study,\r\nwith hypoattenuation in bifrontal deep cerebral white matter, more marked on\r\nthe left with encephalomalacia, likely representing prior ischemic or\r\nhemorrhagic event. There are small enephalomalacia in the right basal ganglia.\r\nThere is no acute intracranial hemorrhage, mass effect, shift of normally\r\nmidline structures or hydrocephalus.  There is atherosclerotic disease of the\r\ncarotid and vertebral arteries.\r\nWithin the subcutaneous tissues of the right parieto-occipital location on the\r\nleft, there is a pedunculated fungating soft tissue mass measuring 3.4 x 1.9\r\ncm, new since prior study, suspicious for recurrent tumor in this patient with\r\nhistory of squamous cell carcinoma.  Shows slight enhancement on post-contrast\r\nstudy. There is satellite nodule measuring 7 mm, slightly medial and deeper to\r\nthe primary lesion.  There is no abnormal enhancement within the brain\r\nparenchyma. The paranasal sinuses and mastoid air cells are clear.\r\nIMPRESSION:\r\n1. Overall unchanged appearance of the brain parenchyma with prior ischemic\r\nevent without new lesion.\r\n2. New large pedunculated soft tissue mass in the subcutaneous tissue\r\nextending to the dermal surface in the left occipito-parietal location without\r\nbony erosions, suspicious for recurrent tumor in this patient with history of\r\nsquamous cell carcinoma.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient history of squamous cell carcinoma", "answer": "Yes", "justification": ["48 year old man with pt with hx of squamous cell ca"]}, {"question": "If so, has the patient received treatment for squamous cell carcinoma", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, what was the last day of the treatment for squamous cell carcinoma", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 155, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04844749", "criterion": "Other than metastatic prostate cancer, no evidence (within 5 years) of prior malignancies (except successfully treated basal cell or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin or other cancers treated with curative intent >3 years prior).", "note_date": "2022-09-06", "note": "2022-9-6 3:44 PM\r\nCT HEAD W/ & W/O CONTRAST \r\nReason: staging /  destruction / hxof squamous cell carcinoma\r\nAdmitting Diagnosis: CLAUDICATION\r\nMEDICAL CONDITION:\r\n48 year old man with pt with hx of squamous cell ca / now has lesion on occiput\r\n/ may have destruction / please assess / ? staging\r\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION:\r\nstaging / destruction / hxof squamous cell carcinoma\r\nNo contraindications for IV contrast\r\nFINAL REPORT\r\nINDICATION:  48-year-old man with history of squamous cell carcinoma, now has\r\nlesion on occiput.\r\nHEAD CT WITHOUT CONTRAST:  Comparison was made with a prior head CT dated\r\n2022-2-28.  The overall appearance of the brain is unchanged since prior study,\r\nwith hypoattenuation in bifrontal deep cerebral white matter, more marked on\r\nthe left with encephalomalacia, likely representing prior ischemic or\r\nhemorrhagic event. There are small enephalomalacia in the right basal ganglia.\r\nThere is no acute intracranial hemorrhage, mass effect, shift of normally\r\nmidline structures or hydrocephalus.  There is atherosclerotic disease of the\r\ncarotid and vertebral arteries.\r\nWithin the subcutaneous tissues of the right parieto-occipital location on the\r\nleft, there is a pedunculated fungating soft tissue mass measuring 3.4 x 1.9\r\ncm, new since prior study, suspicious for recurrent tumor in this patient with\r\nhistory of squamous cell carcinoma.  Shows slight enhancement on post-contrast\r\nstudy. There is satellite nodule measuring 7 mm, slightly medial and deeper to\r\nthe primary lesion.  There is no abnormal enhancement within the brain\r\nparenchyma. The paranasal sinuses and mastoid air cells are clear.\r\nIMPRESSION:\r\n1. Overall unchanged appearance of the brain parenchyma with prior ischemic\r\nevent without new lesion.\r\n2. New large pedunculated soft tissue mass in the subcutaneous tissue\r\nextending to the dermal surface in the left occipito-parietal location without\r\nbony erosions, suspicious for recurrent tumor in this patient with history of\r\nsquamous cell carcinoma.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient history of basal cell carcinoma", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, did the patient receive treatment for basal cell carcinoma", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, what was the last day of treatment for basal cell carcinoma", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 153, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2022-01-12", "note": "P-MICU NPN 7p-7a\r\nEvents overnight:  A-line migrated out, unable to replace after multiple attempts.  Insulin gtt re-initiated after FS climbing.\r\nCV:  Remains on levophed 0.100 mcg/kg/min and pitressin 0.04 units/min.  No adjustments made overnight.  BP has remained in the mid 110's.  HR mainly in th80's Afib with occasional PVC's.\r\nResp:  LS coarse, diminished at bases.  Suctioned multiple times for thick tan secretions.  No vent changes made, and unable to draw ABG due to a-line migrating out and multiple failed attempts to replace it.  O2 sats have remained in the mid 90's.\r\nNeuro:  Sedated, but to stimulation and pain.  On fentanyl 25mcg/hr and midaz 1 mg/hr.  Fentanyl had been off throughout the afternoon and was restarted when the a-line was being replaced.\r\nSocial:  No family contact this shift.\r\nGI:  BS absent, No TF's infusing.  Both pedi tube and NG-Tube in place.  Receiving TPN.\r\nGU:  u/o 15-20cc/hr.  BUN/Cr 119/1.8.  Urine concentrated\r\nLines:  TL CL oozing serous fluid, dressing changed.  +blood return.  A-line migrated out, unable to replace, DL PICC line also oozing, dressing replaced multiple times.\r\nEndo:  Sugars 356 down to 202.  Initially on 8u/hr now on 4u/hr.\r\nHeme:  Received the second unit of PRBC's. Am HCT 37.8.  No obvious s/sx of active bleed noted.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient history of prostate cancer", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "Has the patient ever received an androgen receptor agent?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 146, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03957876", "criterion": "Known history of HIV or active hepatitis B or C.", "note_date": "2021-06-13", "note": "2021-6-13 12:03 PM MR HEAD W & W/O CONTRAST\nReason: pls assess for HIV related pathology \nAdmitting Diagnosis: WEAKNESS Contrast: MAGNEVIST Amt: 16\nMEDICAL CONDITION: 48 year old man with HIV/AIDS now with bilateral lower extremity weakness, memory problems. REASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION: pls assess for HIV related pathology No contraindications for IV contrast WET READ: WED 2021-6-13 7:58 PM No acute intracranial process. Global cerebral atrophy and chronic small vessel ischemic disease. FINAL REPORT INDICATION: History of HIV/AIDS, now with bilateral lower extremity weakness and memory problems. Assess for HIV-related pathology. TECHNIQUE: MRI of the brain was performed including sagittal T1, axial T1 pre- and post-contrast, axial T2, axial FLAIR, axial T2 susceptibility, sagittal MP-RAGE with axial and coronal reformations, and diffusion-weighted sequences. COMPARISON: NECT head from 2021-6-13. \nFINDINGS: There is no evidence of intracranial hemorrhage, edema, shift of normally midline structures, hydrocephalus, mass, or infarction. Periventricular and subcortical FLAIR-/T2- hyperintense foci are consistent with sequelae of chronic small vessel ischemic disease. Prominence of the ventricles and sulci are consistent with global cerebral atrophy, likely related to known HIV/AIDS. Asymmetry of the lateral ventricles, with the left lateral ventricle larger than the right, is likely congenital/developmental in etiology. There are normal arterial flow-voids throughout. No abnormal enhancement is seen. The orbits are unremarkable. Mucosal thickening is seen within the bilateral maxillary sinuses, bilateral sphenoid and scattered ethmoidal air cells, and scattered bilateral mastoid air cells. IMPRESSION: 1. No acute intracranial process. 2. Findings consistent with sequelae of chronic small vessel ischemic disease. 3. Global cerebral atrophy, consistent with history of HIV/AIDS. 2021-6-13 12:03 PM MR HEAD W & W/O CONTRAST \nReason: pls assess for HIV related pathology Admitting Diagnosis: WEAKNESS Contrast: MAGNEVIST Amt: 16 FINAL REPORT", "qa_list": [{"question": "Does the patient have been diagnosed with Hepatitis C?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, was HCV Ab value positive on a date relative to the note date ?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, is HCV RNA value positive, on a date relative to the note date?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 136, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03957876", "criterion": "The patient is surgically sterile", "note_date": "2021-07-28", "note": "TITLE:\n71 year old admit from ED\nadmit there as found down by family covered\nin malaena, recent scope on the 21^st July 2021 showed stable stomach ulcer\nand duodenal ulcer, at that time patient found to be in acute on\nchronic renal failure with creat @ 4.8, this gentleman had renal TX in\n2019, other PMH significant for htn, chole, gout\nhe has a working\nfistula in left arm, lethargic but oreineted on admission with no\ncomplaints of pain\nIn ed HCT dropped 10 points from 31> 21, access issues hot a line in rt\nfem unable to place PIV, received total 1l in St Mary's Hospital transfer to MICU to\nscope\nb/p stable 120-130 systolic with maps > 65, HR 85-90 bpm sinus\nbut with ST depression for which the team area aware and cycling CE..no\nfoley placed ? when last passed urine but unable to place foley, condom\ncath place and passed urine via this at 1800hrs 200cc\nK on admission to\nthe unit > 5.0 therefore received dex/insulin, now on Q1 blood sticks\nand PM labs pending\nGi team scoped at 1800hrs, the patient was receiving x1 uprbcs en route\nfrom ED, and has received x2 more since being here..he received\nfent/versed and 500cc nsaline for transient drop in BP to 90s\ntolerated the procedure well and was found to have the stomach ulcer\noozing which they failed to clip but were able to cortirise\nNow for serial HCTS, b/p HR sats stable at this time and awaiting PM\nlytes", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient undergone a surgical sterilization procedure?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 134, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "Paget's disease of the nipple.", "note_date": "2019-05-06", "note": "2019-05-06\n8:03 AM CHEST (PORTABLE AP) \nReason: please eval for free air on this pt with C.Diff colitis and Admitting Diagnosis: SEPSIS\nMEDICAL CONDITION: 77 year old man with c.diff colitis and gout flare, on prednisone. Please obtain upright CXR to eval for free air. \nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION: please eval for free air on this pt with C.Diff colitis and gout flare being treated with prednisone FINAL REPORT PORTABLE CHEST, \n2019-05-05 AT 08:42. COMPARISON STUDY\nCLINICAL INFORMATION: C. difficile colitis, on prednisone, question free air. FINDINGS: Since the prior study, there is mild interval improvement. Right pleural effusion has decreased. Left costophrenic angle has been omitted from the study. There is cardiomegaly. There is continued left lower lobe consolidation/atelectasis. There is continued small left pleural effusion. Upper lung zones are relatively clear. Mediastinum is within normal limits. IMPRESSION: 1. Decreased right pleural effusion. 2. Persistent left lower lobe consolidation, small left pleural effusion.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been diagnosed with Paget\u2019s disease of the nipple ?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, what was the date of the diagnosis?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 131, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04187833", "criterion": "Prior organ transplantation including allogeneic stem-cell transplantation.", "note_date": "2021-05-19", "note": "10:53 AM CHEST (PA & LAT)\nReason: liver transplant eval\nMEDICAL CONDITION: 47 year old man with REASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION: liver transplant eval \nFINAL REPORT 2021-05-19 \nCHEST INDICATION: Evaluation for liver transplantation. FINDINGS: Standard PA and left lateral views. The heart is within normal limits. The pulmonary vessels are unremarkable. The lungs are clear. No pleural effusions are detected. The skeletal structures are unremarkable. IMPRESSION: Essentially negative chest examination.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient ever had an organ transplant?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the transplantation date?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "Has the patient ever undergone stem-cell transplantation ?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the transplantation date?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 128, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "Treatment plan that includes regional nodal irradiation.", "note_date": "2021-09-16", "note": "2021-9-16 3:56 PM ESOPHAGUS Clip\nReason: mass in esophagus, obvious neuromuscular etiology of dysph \nAdmitting Diagnosis: MITRAL REGURGITATION\\RIGHT AND LEFT CARDIAC CATHETERIZATION \nMEDICAL CONDITION: 65 year old man with severe MR, CHF, long h/o GERD and 3 years of dysphagia solids > liquids. REASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION: mass in esophagus, obvious neuromuscular etiology of dysphagia, request barium swallow with visualization of entire esophagus \nFINAL REPORT INDICATION: 65-year-old man with severe mitral regurgitation, CHF, and long history of gastroesophageal reflux now complaining of three years of dysphagia of solids more than liquids. Please evaluate for mass in the esophagus or obvious neuromuscular etiology of dysphagia. COMPARISON: None available. TECHNIQUE: Double contrast esophagram and pharyngogram. FINDINGS: The contrast passed readily into the stomach. Primary and secondary peristaltic waves failed to completely empty the esophagus. Some tertiary contractions were observed. No esophageal narrowing or strictures was noted. Pharyngogram did not show any evidence of aspiration, penetration or narrowing. A 13-mm barium tablet was administered and was readily swallowed without holdup at any point in the esophagus. No hiatal hernia was present and reflux was not observed during the exam. IMPRESSION: Normal esophagram.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Is Regional Nodal Irradation treatment planned for the patent, on a date relative to the note date?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when did the RNI treatment start?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 126, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT05223673", "criterion": "Participants should have received previous treatment with commercially available anti-EGFR mAbs for \u2265 4 months", "note_date": "2022-02-12", "note": "TITLE: Cardiology Physician Note History of Present Illness Date: 2022-2-12\n Initial visit Events / History of present illness: -improved resp status -no response to 80 IV lasix in AM, in PM given lasix 80mg PO with 25mg HCTZ 30minutes before with good result; will continue this now-changed losartan. to repeat CXR showed resolution of possible infiltrate on prior film Medications Unchanged, aspirin 325, vit D, hep sc, tums, metoprolol 50 bupropion, protonix, zoloft, lasix 80 PO BID, HCTZ 25 PO BID,, losartan 50 PO BID, Carbidopa levodopa \nPhysical Exam BP: 125 / 47 mmHg HR: 65 bpm RR: 28 insp/min Tmax C last 24 hours: 37.4 C Tmax F last 24 hours: 99.4 F T current C: 36.2 C T current F: 97.2 F O2 sat: 93 % on Supplemental oxygen: 3L NC Previous day: Intake: 300 mL Output: 1,582 mL \nFluid balance: -1,282 mL Today: Output: 480 mL Fluid balance: -480 mL VS: BP 118/55 (105-150/41-65), HR 76, RR 25, O2 Sat 98% on 40% Venti mask Eyes: (Conjunctiva and lids: WNL) Ears, Nose, Mouth and Throat: (Oral mucosa: WNL), (Teeth, gums and palette: WNL) Neck: (Jugular veins: Not visible) Respiratory: (Effort: WNL), (Auscultation: crackles at bases) Cardiac: (Rhythm: Regular), (Auscultation: S1: WNL, S3: Absent, S4: Absent), (Murmur / Rub: Absent) Abdominal / Gastrointestinal: (Bowel sounds: WNL), (Pulsatile mass: No), (Hepatosplenomegaly: No) Extremities / Musculoskeletal: (Digits and nails: WNL), (Muscle strength and tone: right upper extremity flexed.), (Dorsalis pedis artery: Right: 1+, Left: 1+), (Posterior tibial artery: Right: 1+, Left: 1+), (Edema: Right: 0, Left: 0) Skin: ( WNL) Labs 250 10.1 108 1.0 33 3.5 32 106 149 29.4 7.8\n [2022-2-10] 06:03 PM WBC 13.4 7.8 Hgb 11.2 10.1 Hct (Serum) 32.6 29.4 Plt 270 250 INR 1.2 PTT 33.5 Na+ 143 146 149 K + (Serum) 3.7 3.1 4.4 4.0 3.5 Cl 103 105 106 HCO3 31 30 30 31 33 BUN 33 32 32 Creatinine 1.1 1.0 1.0 Glucose 192 161 108 CK 34 35 Troponin T 0.09 0.08 ABG: / / / 33 / Values as of 2022-2-12 04:01 AM \nAssessment and Plan 80 year old woman with history of chronic systolic congestive heart failure, presenting with shortness of breath. Acute on chronic systolic congestive heart failure: History and presentation consistent with CHF exacerbation. LVEF 20%, with MR. BNP 26,000 on admission. Lung exam with crackles. Unclear initiating factor: dietary indiscretion and medication non-compliance are likely not causes given patient is presenting from Rehab. Possible upper respiratory infection, possible worsening valvular disease. Uncontrolled hypertension is also a possibility. Ischemia is unlikely given negative CEs x 3. Sx improving on IV furosemide. - diuresis switched to lasix 80 PO BID and HCTZ 25mg PO BID. - continue metoprolol; increase losartan to 50 mg  for better BP control - consider digoxin to reduce hospital admissions #Hypernatremia: Likely from restricted access to free water. Will give D5W 1000cc. -D5W 1000cc. # Respiratory status: Patient is breathing comfortably after having been weaned off CPAP after diuresis. - continue to treat heart failure as above - supplemental O2 as needed Leukocytosis: WBC 13.4 this morning from 7.8, differential pending. No fever. No clear sign of infection. reactive leukocytosis. - f/u diff - monitor for signs of infection # CAD: History of MI in 2020 continue aspirin, metoprolol, and losartan. Peripheral vascular disease: S/p bypass. - aspirin, clopidogrel per discussion with PCP # CVA: patient with right sided hemiparesis, right facial droop, expressive aphasia. Hypertension: episodes of hypertension yesterday. - continue metoprolol and increase losartan to 50 mg  Diabetes: Type 2 on insulin. - continue standing insulin in addition to sliding scale. # Parkinson's disease: - continue carbidopa/levodopa TID. Depression: - continue sertraline and bupropion FEN: pureed diet, diabetic consistent carbohydrate ACCESS: PIV's; consider PICC line upon discharge for easier administration of furosemide PROPHYLAXIS: -DVT ppx with heparin sub q, pneumoboots -Pain managment with tylenol, morphine -Bowel regimen colace, senna milk of magnesia CODE: DNR/DNI DISPO: call out to floor later today if stable.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Did the patient ever receive anti-EGFR mAbs?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the starting date of the treatment with mAbs ?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, what was the duration of treatment with mAbs until the date of the note?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 119, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04641351", "criterion": "Known or suspected hypersensitivity to Zilretta (or component of Zilretta) or triamcinolone acetonide", "note_date": "2020-09-22", "note": "10:17 AM CT CHEST W/O CONTRAST Reason: Is there any evidence for hypersensitivity pneumonitis or an Admitting Diagnosis: PNEUMONIA; RENAL FAILURE \nMEDICAL CONDITION: 68 year old man with h/o bilateral upper lobe infiltrates (films from outside hospital) and clinical hx of hypersensitivity pneumonitis. Pt has new hx of renal failure and anemia. \nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION: Is there any evidence for hypersensitivity pneumonitis or another explanation for his pulmonary findings? CONTRAINDICATIONS for IV CONTRAST: Acute renal failure FINAL REPORT CLINICAL INDICATION: Bilateral upper lobe infiltrates at outside hospital with clinical diagnosis of hypersensitivity pneumonitis. Additional history of renal failure. Helical and high-resolution CT imaging of the chest was performed without IV or oral contrast administration. Assessment of the lungs reveals multifocal areas of consolidation, some of which have a distinctly nodular configuration and others of which are more confluent. There is an upper lung zone predominance, particularly of the confluent areas of consolidation, which is also more prominent peripherally than centrally. In contrast, the multiple poorly defined nodular areas of opacification have both peribronchovascular and peripheral distributions. These nodular opacities vary in size but are less than 1.5 cm in diameter. A few of the nodules contain air bronchograms, and some of them have a halo of ground-glass opacification surrounding a central solid nodule. Scattered linear and reticular opacities are noted, but the dominant features are consolidation and nodular opacity. No honeycombing is identified. The central airways appear patent with no obstructing central endobronchial lesions observed. Soft tissue structures of the thorax demonstrate numerous small mediastinal lymph nodes measuring less than 1 cm in short axis dimension. The main pulmonary artery appears enlarged, measuring 4.4 cm in diameter. The heart size is normal. Coronary artery calcifications are present. No pericardial or significant pleural effusion is evident. Within the imaged portion of the upper abdomen, several hepatic calcified granulomas are noted. The imaged portions of the spleen and adrenal glands are unremarkable. There is nonspecific mesenteric stranding in the upper abdomen and numerous small abdominal, mesenteric and retroperitoneal lymph nodes are noted. The presence of soft tissue stranding is noted within the soft tissue structures of the chest and upper abdomen. Skeletal structures demonstrate degenerative changes within the spine. \nIMPRESSION: 2020-9-22 10:17 AM CT CHEST W/O CONTRAST\nReason: Is there any evidence for hypersensitivity pneumonitis or an Admitting Diagnosis: PNEUMONIA; RENAL FAILURE FINAL REPORT (Cont) 1. Bilateral upper lobe distribution of peripheral consolidation and diffuse, ill- defined small pulmonary nodules with both a peribronchovascular and peripheral distribution. The findings are nonspecific, but they favor chronic eosinophilic pneumonia or crytogenic organizing pneumonia. If there is a history of asthma and systemic symptoms , syndrome is an additional possibility. The differential diagnosis also includes atypical infection (fungal) and, less likely, a neoplastic process such as lymphoma. 2. Marked enlargement of main pulmonary artery, suggesting pulmonary hypertension. 3. Nonspecific findings within the upper abdomen, which is incompletely evaluated. This includes soft tissue stranding in the mesentery and multiple small lymph nodes. An active inflammatory or neoplastic process within the abdomen cannot be excluded. Dedicated contrast enhanced abdominal CT scan may be helpful for more complete assessment. 4. Stranding in the soft tissues of the chest and abdomen, likely due to anasarca.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient ever presented hypersensitivity reaction to triamcinolone acetonide?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the first time that the hypersensitivity symptoms were observed?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 114, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "Pathologic staging of pN0(i+) or pN0(mol+), pN1, pN2, or pN3 disease.", "note_date": "2017-01-08", "note": "CHIEF COMPLAINT: Newly diagnosed mantle cell lymphoma.,HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS: , The patient is a 47-year-old woman who presented with abdominal pain in September 2016. On chest x-ray, she had a possible infiltrate and it was thought she might have pneumonia and she was treated with antibiotics and prednisone. Symptoms improved temporarily, but did not completely resolve. By the end of September, her pain had worsened and she was seen in the emergency room at Beth Israel. Chest x-ray was compatible with pleurisy and she was treated with Percocet. Few days later, she was seen and given a prescription for Ultram because Percocet was causing nausea. Eventually, she was seen by Dr. Ng and noted to have splenomegaly. Repeat ultrasound was done and showed the spleen enlarged at 19 cm. In retrospect, this was not changed in comparison to an ultrasound that was done in September. She underwent positron emission tomography (PET) scanning, which showed diffuse hypermetabolic lymph nodes measuring 1 to 2 cm in diameter, as well as a hypermetabolic spleen that was enlarged.,The patient underwent lymph node biopsy on the right neck on 10/27/2016. Pathology is consistent with mantle cell lymphoma.,On 10/31/2016, she had a bone marrow biopsy. This does show involvement of bone marrow with lymphoma.,She was noted to have circulating lymphoma cells on peripheral smear as well.,Although CBC was normal, MCV was low and the ferritin was assessed and was low at 8, consistent with iron deficiency.,ALLERGIES:, NONE.,MEDICATIONS: ,1. Estradiol/Prometrium. ,2. Ultram p.r.n. ,3. Baby aspirin. ,4. Lunesta for sleep. ,5. She has been started on iron supplements.,PAST MEDICAL HISTORY: ,1. Tubal ligation in 1996.,2. Possible cyst removed from the left neck in 2001.,3. Tonsillectomy.,4. Migraines, which are rare.,SOCIAL HISTORY: , She does not smoke cigarettes and drinks alcohol only occasionally. She is married and has two children, ages 24 and 20. She works as a project administrator.,FAMILY HISTORY: ,Father is deceased. He had emphysema and colon cancer at age 68. Mother has arrhythmia and hypertension. Her sister has hypertension and her brother is healthy.,PHYSICAL EXAMINATION: ,GENERAL: She is in no acute distress.,VITAL SIGNS: Her weight is 168 pounds, and she is afebrile with a normal blood pressure and pulse.,HEENT: The oropharynx is benign.,SKIN: The skin is warm and dry and shows no jaundice.,NECK: There is shotty adenopathy in the neck.,CARDIAC: Regular rate without murmur.,LUNGS: Clear to auscultation bilaterally.,ABDOMEN: Soft and nontender and shows the spleen palpable about 10 cm below the right costal margin.,EXTREMITIES: No peripheral edema is noted.,LABORATORY DATA: , CBC and chemistry panel are pending. CBC was normal last week. PT/INR was normal as well.,IMPRESSION:, Newly diagnosed mantle cell lymphoma, admitted now to start chemotherapy. She will start treatment with hyperfractionated cyclophosphamide, vincristine, doxorubicin, dexamethasone. Toxicities have already been discussed with her including myelosuppression, mucositis, diarrhea, nausea, alopecia, the low risk for cardiac toxicity, bladder toxicity, neuropathy, constipation, etc. Written materials were provided to her last week.,PLAN: , Plan will be to add Rituxan a little later in her course because she has circulating lymphoma cells. She will be started on allopurinol today as well as hydration further to avoid the possibility of tumor lysis syndrome.,Plan will be to have her evaluated for bone marrow transplant in first remission. I will have Dr. Y see her while she is in the hospital.,The patient is anxious, and will be given Ativan as needed. We will discontinue aspirin for now, but continue estradiol/Prometrium.,Iron deficiency will be treated with oral iron supplements and we will follow her counts. She may well have gastrointestinal (GI) involvement, which is not uncommon with mantle cell lymphoma. After she undergoes remission, we will consider colonoscopy for biopsies prior to proceeding to transplant.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Was this patient ever diagnosed with parotid cancer?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, what was the pathologic stage of the patient's parotid cancer regarding lymph node involvement?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "When was the pathologic staging performed?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "What classification system was used for the pathologic staging?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 106, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "The interval between the last surgery for breast cancer (including re-excision of margins) and study entry must be no more than 70 days.", "note_date": "2022-04-12", "note": "The pt is 48-year-old man who had a treatment history for anaplastic astrocytoma twice at the age of 39 and 46. He was referred to our department on Feb 4 for the inspection of progressing anemia. He was suspected as LS due to his specific family history by having two cases of colon cancer within his second relatives. Whole-body examination revealed two foci of advanced stage of carcinoma in descending colon and stomach. A hypo-vascular mass in its size of 15 mm was also detected in S2 of liver. Pathological diagnosis using the biopsied samples and surgically resected specimens were poorly differentiated adenocarcinoma of descending colon, moderately differentiated adenocarcinoma of stomach, and poorly differentiated adenocarcinoma of the liver, suggesting the liver tumor would be metastasis from colon. 5-Fluorouracil-based adjuvant chemotherapy with the combination of oxaliplatin was selected for this case because this case was highly suspected as LS. During postoperative surveillance, repetitive polypectomy for colonic adenomas was performed, one of which was a 10 mm tubular adenoma with severe atypia in the ascending colon.\nDetection of MSI was performed by Biomedical Laboratories, Inc. (Saitama, Japan) using a National Cancer Institute\u2013recommended panel of microsatellite markers (BAT25, BAT26, D2S123, D5S346, and D17S250) and additional markers (D2S136, D3S1067, TP53, D18S51). This analysis showed a positive result for eight markers (except D5S346), indicating a high frequency of MSI (MSI-high). Immunohistochemistry (IHC) for MMR proteins of this patient\u2019s tumors were also performed. Monoclonal antibodies (MLH1: mouse monoclonal, clone ES05, MSH2: mouse monoclonal, clone FE11, MSH6: rabbit monoclonal, clone EP49, PMS2: rabbit monoclonal, clone EP51 {DAKO, Denmark}) were used for the present study. The IHCs of the descending colon cancer demonstrated abnormal nuclear staining of scanty MSH6, concurrent loss of MLH1 and PMS2, whereas the staining for MSH2 was positive. On the other hand, IHCs of the liver metastasis showed complete loss of MSH6, MLH1, PMS2 and the staining for MSH2 was positive. IHCs of the stomach cancer revealed negative staining of MLH1 and PMS2, whereas the staining for MSH2 and MSH6 were positive. Further investigation in IHCs of the colon cancer specimens from his father and brother were performed. Both of them showed the same staining pattern, as of this patient\u2019s stomach cancer.\nA gene mutation of MLH1was suspected in this family line, because all of the colon cancers demonstrated complete defects of MLH1 and PMS2. Genetic analysis for mismatch repair genes, MLH1, MSH2, MSH6, PMS2, MSH3, PMS1, EPCAM, MLH3, APC, MUTYH, POLD1, POLE, TP53, AXIN2 and BMPR1A was conducted. This genetic testing revealed a frame shift mutation in codon 618 (c. 1852-1854delAAG / p.Lys618del) of MLH1. This mutation is registered on the database of InSiGHT as class 5 and as pathogenic in Clin Var. To investigate the mechanism of the scanty staining pattern of MSH6 in colorectal carcinoma, analysis of the coding region microsatellite (C)8 in exon 5 of MSH6 in this patient\u2019s colon cancer, stomach cancer, and liver metastasis was performed. An intact (C)8 region was shown in a normal tissue of the colon and stomach cancer. An abnormal (C)8 region was seen in the colon cancer and the liver metastasis. The distribution of the mutant alleles in the (C)8 tract was further analyzed by cloning and sequencing analysis. Deletion mutation (\u22121wt) and insertion mutation (wt + 1) were detected in the liver metastasis. Representative electropherograms of wild type, \u22121wt and wt + 1 clones are shown in the Supplementary Figure.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient ever had surgery for breast cancer?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the most recent such surgery, relative to the note date?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 102, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "Oncotype DX Recurrence Score of less than or equal to 18 on diagnostic core biopsy or resected specimen.", "note_date": "2021-07-18", "note": "2019-3-26 2:40 PM\nUNILAT UP EXT VEINS US\nReason: Please evaluate for DVT\nAdmitting Diagnosis: SEPSIS\nKindred Hospital\nMEDICAL CONDITION:\n79 year old woman with Lung CA, a/w sepsis, PICC in RUE,\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION:\nPlease evaluate for DVT\nFINAL REPORT\nINDICATION: 79-year-old woman with lung cancer, sepsis and PICC in right\nupper extremity, please evaluate for DVT.\nCOMPARISON: None.\nRIGHT UPPER EXTREMITY ULTRASOUND: Grayscale, color and Doppler sonography of\nthe right internal jugular, subclavian, axillary, brachial, basilic and\ncephalic veins were performed. A PICC is visible and a non-compressible right\ncephalic vein, which does not demonstrate flow. There is normal flow,\ncompression and augmentation seen in the right IJ, subclavian, axillary,\nbrachial and basilic veins.\nIMPRESSION: Evidence of focal superficial venous thrombus in the right\ncephalic vein surrounding an indwelling PICC. Thrombus does not extend into\nthe axillary, subclavian or IJ veins - no DVT is present.\nFindings discussed with Dr. Jason Chang at 9:40am 2019-3-27.", "qa_list": [{"question": "What is this patient's Oncotype DX Recurrence Score?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "When was that score computed?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 96, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2018-02-10", "note": "Record date: 2018-02-10\nREASON FOR VISIT: Followup for diabetic cheiropathy. Rule out other diabetes-related musculoskeletal syndrome. Monitoring of Ultracet therapy and left shoulder injection.\nINTERVAL HISTORY: Left shoulder injection was helpful but only last short time. Just a week or so. Ultracet was relieving pains but was not able to afford it. Feels stable and not worse since last seen. Telling me he is cutting down his medications and he is letting his doctors know about this. No acute swelling or further different joint complaints other than what was described in my previous notes. Rest of review of systems again unchanged.\nMEDICATIONS: The medication file is same as last time, except for addition of Tylenols now.\nPHYSICAL EXAMINATION: BP 100/70. Other VS WNL. Wt. 170lb. Gait: Slow. Cooperative. VSS. HEENT: Halitosis. Poor teeth hygiene. Lungs: Clear. Heart: Unremarkable. Abdomen exam: Slight sensitiveness in epigastrium. A little low-frequency tremor in extremities. Musculoskeletal examination: Both shoulders with limited ROM. Left shoulder active ROM is improved compared to the last description. Hands with prayer's sign present. Elbows again show lesser degree of flexion contracture. Range of motion in both shoulders diminished,\nmore in the left side. Hardening of skin on the palm side of hands. Has atrophy of intrinsic muscles of hands. The rest of joint examination, free of inflammation. Unchanged from last description.\nIMPRESSION: Diabetic cheiropathy. Rule out other diabetes-related musculoskeletal syndrome esp in shoulders. Helped by Ultracet. Osteoarthritis changes of early stage. Status post olecranon bursitis. Elevated creatinine.\nPLANS:\n1. Continue Ultracet up 2 tablets prn once twice a day; Samples given.\n2. May consider low-dose narcotics, given his multiple comorbidity and sensitive renal function to nonsteroidal therapy. 3. Close followup for diabetes care with other physicians.\nDISPOSITION: Followup in 4 months or so.\nVirgil Gregory, M.D.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Was this patient ever diagnosed with cervical cancer?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when was that diagnosis made?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 92, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2018-04-20", "note": "Record date: 2018-04-20\nPINELLAS GENERAL HOSPITAL\nPINELLAS Internal Medicine Associates\n58 Topaz Drive\nPetersham, NJ 81697\nIckes, William\n81071628\n04/20/18\nHISTORY: This is a 71-year-old gentleman accompanied by wife who comes in with\nepisodic complaint of polyuria, polydipsia and weight loss. He is followed in PIMA for\nmultiple medical problems. Refer to the problem list.\nHISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS: The patient reports that he was informed that he\nhad borderline diabetes in the past. He apparently called Dr. Frantz with present poly\nsymptoms. He was advised to come to the office for serum glucose check. The patient\ndoes have a brother with diabetes. To his knowledge, neither one of his parents had\ndiabetes. The patient does not have much knowledge regarding diabetes. He basically is\nnow complaining of polyuria, polydipsia, and weight loss. He reports that he has had an\n18 pound weight loss since 1/78, visit with Dr. Frantz.\nOBJECTIVE: Serum glucose in the office random is 376. Weight is 173.75 pounds.\nDiabetes instructions as follows, pathophysiology of diabetes is reviewed. Action and\nrationale for oral agent versus insulin reviewed. Hyper and hypoglycemic symptoms\nreviewed. Acute and chronic complications of diabetes reviewed. Gross no concentrated\nfruits diet reviewed. Creatinine has been in the 1.3 to 1.5 range, over the last year.\nASSESSMENT: Markedly elevated glucose now.\nPLAN: Per consult of Dr. Frantz, M.D., we will start glyburide 5 mg tablet one p.o. q.d.,\nsince not able to use metformin in view of the patient's elevated creatinine. The patient\nwas given prescription for glucometer. He will return to the office and will be instructed\nin the use of the glucometer. Bring in glucose log at next visit. Alternate FBS with predinner glucoses.\nWanda Lucero, M.D.", "qa_list": [{"question": "What was this patient's most recently measured PSA level?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "When was this measurement obtained?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 91, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04844749", "criterion": "The patient has received at least one androgen receptor targeting agent (e.g. abiraterone, enzalutamide, darolutamide, or apalutamide).", "note_date": "2018-04-20", "note": "Record date: 2018-04-20\nPINELLAS GENERAL HOSPITAL\nPINELLAS Internal Medicine Associates\n58 Topaz Drive\nPetersham, NJ 81697\nIckes, William\n81071628\n04/20/18\nHISTORY: This is a 71-year-old gentleman accompanied by wife who comes in with\nepisodic complaint of polyuria, polydipsia and weight loss. He is followed in PIMA for\nmultiple medical problems. Refer to the problem list.\nHISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS: The patient reports that he was informed that he\nhad borderline diabetes in the past. He apparently called Dr. Frantz with present poly\nsymptoms. He was advised to come to the office for serum glucose check. The patient\ndoes have a brother with diabetes. To his knowledge, neither one of his parents had\ndiabetes. The patient does not have much knowledge regarding diabetes. He basically is\nnow complaining of polyuria, polydipsia, and weight loss. He reports that he has had an\n18 pound weight loss since 1/78, visit with Dr. Frantz.\nOBJECTIVE: Serum glucose in the office random is 376. Weight is 173.75 pounds.\nDiabetes instructions as follows, pathophysiology of diabetes is reviewed. Action and\nrationale for oral agent versus insulin reviewed. Hyper and hypoglycemic symptoms\nreviewed. Acute and chronic complications of diabetes reviewed. Gross no concentrated\nfruits diet reviewed. Creatinine has been in the 1.3 to 1.5 range, over the last year.\nASSESSMENT: Markedly elevated glucose now.\nPLAN: Per consult of Dr. Frantz, M.D., we will start glyburide 5 mg tablet one p.o. q.d.,\nsince not able to use metformin in view of the patient's elevated creatinine. The patient\nwas given prescription for glucometer. He will return to the office and will be instructed\nin the use of the glucometer. Bring in glucose log at next visit. Alternate FBS with predinner glucoses.\nWanda Lucero, M.D.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient been treated with at least one androgen receptor targeting agent?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the most recent such treatment?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 85, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04852887", "criterion": "The patient must not have had a mastectomy", "note_date": "2020-04-12", "note": "P Is a 70 yo male, who had been in the nearby Presbyterian hospital a few days ago\nfor treatment of a UTI.  While there, he received 2 doses of SQ\nheparin.  While following up with his PCP, Dr. Sanders had labs drawn and was\nfound to have a hct of 29 ( down from 40 on 4-02).  Arrived to ED,\nNG lavage was negative.  Pt without complaints.    Placed on octrotide\ngtt.  To MICU for further monitoring.\n.H/O gastrointestinal bleed, other (GI Bleed, GIB)\nAssessment:\nHemodynamically stable.  BP 70\ns-80\ns afib with occasional PVCs.  BP\n113-148/51-82.  EGD performed this morning.  Incomplete study secondary\nto food in stomach.  Severe portal gastropathy detected.  No stool this\nshift.\nAction:\nPt transfused 1 unit PRBC.  Octreotide drip infusing at 50mcg/hr.\nResponse:\nRepeat HCT  28.6%.  EGD incomplete study secondary to food in stomach\nPlan:\nContinue to monitor.  EGD in am.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient had a mastectomy of the left breast?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 82, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03957876", "criterion": "Patients who are postmenopausal for at least 1 year before the screening visit.", "note_date": "2021-05-12", "note": "4 ICU NPN 0700-1900 Becoming more tachycardic & tachypneaic throughout the shift. Lactate 4.8. Abg on 3L NP 7.45/30/69/21/-1. KUB revealing free air in abd. Surgical evaluation for ? perforated bowl. Not surgical candidate. Dr. Scott (gyn/onc) aware. ICU team spoke with pt re goals of care & status. Pt thinking about what she would want. ICU currently meeting with pt's dtr. RESP: tachypneaic with increased work of breathing. RR 30's to low 50's. ABG as above. Unable to tol Cpap after approx five minutes. Given lasix for resp distress, CVP 13-15 for mod response CV: 115 to 139 this afternoon. BP initially 120's, down to low 100's. NS 500 cc bolus with slight improvement in HR, BP. C/O thirst GI: No BM since admit. Colace senna, lactulose X2 given. C/O abd cramping. mild abd pain across upper abd. Passed small, brown, OB negative stool Abd remains, distened, taught. More tight, distended than previous 24 hrs. ID: Afeb flagly, levo d/c'd. To start on fluconazole, zosyn. GU: UO adequate. Sediment in urine. UC negative Oriented. Attempted to gey OOB this eve. A/P: ? perf bowl. Not surgical candidate. Await decision re goal of care. Antibiotics. Support to family\nCONCLUSION: 1. Replacement of the PICC line by the midline catheter. 2. Highly probable high-grade stenosis of the left subclavian vein near the left first anterior rib. The stenosis could not be characterized anatomically due to known clinical history of allergic reaction to iodinated contrast material in the past, without appropriate premedication.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient reach menopause?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when did menopause start?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 79, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT05020912", "criterion": "History of a photosensitivity disease, e.g.,porphyria cutanea tarda", "note_date": "2021-08-21", "note": "2020-8-21 6:58 AM CT ABDOMEN W/CONTRAST; CT PELVIS W/CONTRAST CT CHEST W/CONTRAST Reason: COLON CA EVAL DISEASE PROGRESSION Contrast: OPTIRAY Amt \nMEDICAL CONDITION: 66 year old woman with history of Colon cancer on FOLFOX with Avastin, evaluate disease progression \nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION: evaluate disease progression No contraindications for IV contrast \nFINAL REPORT HISTORY: 66-year-old female with history of colon cancer, on FOLFOX, evaluate disease progression. COMPARISON: 2021-5-15. TECHNIQUE: MDCT axial images were obtained from the thoracic inlet to the symphysis pubis with administration of IV and oral contrast. Coronal and sagittal reformations were obtained. CT OF THE CHEST WITH IV CONTRAST: Heart and pericardium are normal, without pericardial effusion. There are no pathologically enlarged mediastinal, hilar or axillary lymph nodes. There are post-surgical changes following wedge resections of the right upper and lower lobes. Emphysema with areas of bronchiectasis medially are unchanged. Numerous bilateral pulmonary nodules are again noted. The dominant nodules are slightly increased in size. A left upper lobe (2:27) nodule measures 6 mm (previously 4 mm). A nodule within the left lower lobe (2:36) measures 9 mm (previously 7 mm). The remainder of the pulmonary nodules is largely stable. There is no pleural effusion. The esophagus demonstrates circumferential wall thickening throughout its entire length, similar in appearance from 2021-5-15, concerning for esophagitis. \nCT OF THE ABDOMEN WITH IV CONTRAST: The liver, spleen, adrenal glands, and pancreas are unremarkable. Patient is status post cholecystectomy. Prominent extrarenal pelvis bilaterally is seen, with a small rounded hypodensity in the upper pole of the right kidney too small to characterize, but unchanged. Otherwise, the kidneys are unremarkable. The stomach and small bowel are within normal limits. Anastomotic sutures are seen within the rectosigmoid, otherwise, the colon is unremarkable. There is no free fluid, free air, or pathologic adenopathy. \nCT OF THE PELVIS WITH IV CONTRAST: The rectum, uterus, and bladder are within normal limits. There is no pelvic free fluid or adenopathy. OSSEOUS STRUCTURES: Previously noted sclerosis of the left sacra is not as well appreciated on this study. Sclerotic foci within the left femoral head as well as left ilium are unchanged. There are mild multilevel degenerative (Over) \n2021-8-21 6:58 AM CT ABDOMEN W/CONTRAST; CT PELVIS W/CONTRAST \nCT CHEST W/CONTRAST Reason: COLON CA EVAL DISEASE PROGRESSION Contrast: OPTIRAY Amt: FINAL REPORT (Cont) changes throughout the thoracolumbar spine. Fracture deformities of the right 4th and 5th ribs are unchanged. IMPRESSION: 1. Slight interval increase in size of the dominant nodules within the left lung, specifically within the left upper lobe as well as in the left lower lobe. Otherwise, the remainder of the nodules are stable. 2. Diffuse circumferential wall thickening of the esophagus throughout its entire length, similar in appearance from prior study, and may reflect esophagitis. 3. No new lesions identified.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has the patient presented any photosensitivity disease?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when did he present photosensitivity symptoms?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 77, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04844749", "criterion": "The patient must not have a prior history of a thromboembolic event within the last 6 months.", "note_date": "2022-06-21", "note": "2022-6-21 8:59 PM\nCT HEAD W/O CONTRAST\nReason: S/P BIKE VS CAR\nFINAL ADDENDUM\nAddendum:\nAdditional information has been obtained from CareWeb Clinical Lookup since\nthe approval of the original report. Reason for exam should also state\nconcussion.\n2022-6-21 8:59 PM\nCT HEAD W/O CONTRAST\nReason: S/P BIKE VS CAR\nMEDICAL CONDITION:\n24 year old woman s/p bike vs car accident\nREASON FOR THIS EXAMINATION:\ntruama?\nNo contraindications for IV contrast\nWET READ: AJy WED 2022-6-21 9:46 PM\nno hemorrhage, edema or mass effect. no fracture.\nFINAL REPORT\nINDICATION: 24-year-old female status post bike versus car accident.\nCOMPARISON: None available.\nNON-CONTRAST HEAD CT: There is no hemorrhage, edema, or mass effect. There\nis no shift of midline structures. The basilar cisterns are preserved.\nVentricles, sulci, and cisterns are within normal limits in caliber and\nconfiguration given the patient's age. There are no abnormal extra-axial\nfluid collections. Osseous structures demonstrate no fracture. The\nvisualized paranasal sinuses and mastoid air cells are normally aerated.\nIMPRESSION: No evidence for hemorrhage, edema, or mass effect.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient had a thromboembolic event?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when did the most recent thromboembolic event occur, relative to the note date?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 76, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04844749", "criterion": "The patient must not have a prior history of a thromboembolic event within the last 6 months.", "note_date": "2018-09-20", "note": "NICU TRIAGE/ADMISSION NOTE Asked by Dr. Goldstein to evaluate this term female for sepsis. 3255 gm product of a term gestation pregnancy born to a 38 year old G4 P3\u21924 woman. EDC 2016-8-7. Prenatal Screens: B+/antibody negative/RPR non-reactive/Rubella immune/HepBSAg negative/GBS positive. Mount Sinai medical history notable for lupus, Dr. Brown+. Normal amnio this pregnancy. Spontaneous onset of labor. No maternal fever, ROM at delivery. Maternal intrapartum antibiotic prophylaxis started less than 1 hour prior to delivery. No fetal tachycardia noted. Infant born by SVD, Apgars 9, 9. Infant admitted to NICU at 1 1/2 hours of life. Vital Signs: T=98.5 R HR=130 RR=54 BP=79/42 M=55. PE Active, alert term female in no acute distress; color pink, skin dry, peeling, no rashes; anterior fontanel open, level; sutures opposed; normal facies; breath sounds clear/=; RRR, no murmur; normal S1 S2; femoral pulses +2; abdomen soft, no masses; active bowel sounds; normal female genitalia; spine straight; shallow closed sacral dimple; patent anus; moving all extremities; normal tone and reflexes. CBC and blood culture obtained. Glucose=75. IMPRESSION: well-appearing term female; only sepsis risk factor maternal GBS colonization, less than 4 hours intrapartum prophylaxis. Infant without any obvious signs of neonatal lupus. PLAN: Observe in Newborn Nursery. If CBC abnormal, will treat infant with IV antibiotics pending culture results. Confirm normal platelet count in setting of maternal lupus. Parents aware of our impression and plan of care.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient had a thromboembolic event?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when did the most recent thromboembolic event occur, relative to the note date?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 63, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04641351", "criterion": "Patient must not be pregnant", "note_date": "2020-06-28", "note": "Admission Date :\n2020-06-28\nDischarge Date :\n2020-07-01\nDate of Birth :\n2000-02-01\nSex :\nF\nService :\nORTHOPEDIC\nHISTORY OF THE PRESENT ILLNESS :\nThis is a 20-year-old female with no significant past medical history , who was the unrestrained passenger in a high speed rollover motor vehicle accident on 2020-06-27 .\nBy report , the patient was ejected from the vehicle on impact and found curled in the fetal position at the rear of the vehicle at the scene.\nThe vehicle was noted to be extensively damaged .\nBy report , the patient was noted to be awake , but confused at the scene of the accident with no memory of the incident .\nShe was immobilized in the C-spine collar at the scene of the accident and subsequently transported by EMS to the New England Sinai Hospital & Rehab Center Emergency Department for further management .\nPHYSICAL EXAMINATION :\nExamination on presentation to the emergency room revealed the following :\nTemperature 35.4 Celsius , blood pressure 116/63 , pulse 105 , respiratory rate 18 , oxygen saturation 98% on room air .\nThe patient was alert and oriented times three in no apparent distress .\nBoston Coma Scale of 15 .\nTympanic membranes were noted to be clear .\nPupils were equal , round , reactive to light at approximately 4 mm .\nThe patient 's trachea was noted to be midline .\nThe patient 's lung examination revealed the lungs to be clear to auscultation bilaterally , no crepitus , and a left clavicular deformity was grossly apparent on examination .\nCARDIAC :\nCardiac examination demonstrated regular rate and rhythm , no murmurs , rubs , or gallops .\nABDOMEN :\nSoft , nontender , nondistended .\nRECTAL :\nExamination was guaiac negative with good rectal tone .\nThe patient 's pelvis was stable to AP and lateral compression .\nA 5 cm laceration was noted over the patient 's occiput on further inspection with no exposed underlying bone .\nRight upper extremity examination demonstrated intact motor , sensory , and vascular function .\nLeft upper extremity examination demonstrated no gross deformities , tenderness to palpation in the mid forearm , intact motor function in the median , radial , and ulnar nerve distributions , intact sensation to light touch in the median and radial nerve distributions , decreased sensation in the ulnar-nerve distribution , warm and well perfused limb with 2+ radial pulses .\nRight lower extremity examination demonstrated mild swelling and ecchymosis of the right posterior thigh and approximately a 3 cm laceration in the lower leg , expressive of moderate amounts of standard sterile\nfashion .\nNo gross deformities .\nMotor , sensory , and vascular examinations were intact in all distributions .\nLeft lower extremity examination demonstrated no gross deformities and intact motor , sensory , and vascular examinations in all distributions .\nRadiographic studies demonstrated an inferior displaced left midclavicular fracture , no evidence of\npneumothorax .\nTrauma series demonstrated no evidence of a pelvic fracture .\nHead CT demonstrated no evidence of intracranial bleeding .\nTrauma CT demonstrated mild pulmonary contusions , but no pelvic fracture .\nCervical spine imaging demonstrated no evidence of cervical spine injury .\nRight tibial-fibular film series demonstrated no evidence of fracture displacement .\nLeft humerus film series demonstrated no evidence of fracture or displacement .\nRight foot and femur series demonstrated no evidence of fracture displacement .\nLeft forearm and wrist series demonstrated transverse mid shaft radial fracture with ulnar displacement .\nDiagnosis peritoneum lavage times two was negative for any signs of intra-abdominal bleeding .\nLABORATORY DATA :\nStudies on admission revealed the following :\nWhite blood cell 12.9 , hemoglobin 11.5 , hematocrit 32.8 , platelet count 197,000 , sodium 141 , potassium 3.6 , chloride 110 , bicarbonate 21 , BUN 20 , creatinine 0.7 , glucose 189 , PT 13.3 , INR 1.2 , PTT 30.0 , amylase 57 , arterial blood gas 7.32 , 35 , 159 , 19 , -7 .\nUrinalysis was within normal limits with 6 to 10 red blood cells .\nToxicology screen was negative .\nCONDITION ON DISCHARGE :\nThe patient is to be discharged to home .\nDISCHARGE STATUS :\nStable .\nDIAGNOSIS :\n1. Left transverse mid shaft radial fracture with ulnar displacement status post left radial open reduction and internal fixation .\n2. Left midclavicular fracture managed nonoperatively .\n3. Occipital scalp laceration .\n4. Right anterior tibial laceration .\nDISCHARGE MEDICATIONS :\nPercocet one to two tablets PO q.4h. to 6h.p.r.n. pain .\nFOLLOW-UP CARE :\nThe patient is medically cleared for a flight to return to her home in the United Kingdom .\nThe patient is to maintain her figure-of-eight clavicular splint and left posterior forearm splint in place for fourteen days following discharge .\nThe left forearm and right lower leg wound should be kept clean and dry with regular dressing changes with dry gauze once per day .\nScalp laceration should be kept clean and dry for five days following discharge after which point the patient may once wash her hair .\nPercocet for pain as needed .\nThe patient is to followup with an orthopedist in the United Kingdom fourteen days following discharge at which point repeat x-rays of her left forearm should be obtained and her left forearm scalp and right lower leg sutures and staples may be removed .\nQuestions regarding follow up may be referred to Dr. Ronda Lopez at the Ayer Orthopedic Group .\nTelephone #:\n( 658 ) 842-8661 .\nOrtiz V Baugher , M.D.\n75-285\nDictated By : Catherine K Thomas , M.D.\nMEDQUIST36\nD : 2020-06-30 17:18\nT : 2020-06-30 17:39\nJOB #:\n03326\nSigned electronically by : DR. Kisha Jones on : Jose 2020-07-01 8:27 AM", "qa_list": [{"question": "Is the patient pregnant at the time of the clinical note?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, what is the gestational age at the time of the note?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 54, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2022-09-30", "note": "I had the pleasure of seeing Mr. Potts in follow up today. He recently had a complicated hospital course. He underwent cardiac catheterization on September 26, which revealed serial stenoses of the LAD including 70% and 90% stenoses. The first marginal branch had a 60% ostial stenosis. The right coronary artery had 60 and 80% stenoses, respectively. The PDA had a 70% narrowing. Given his very significant wish not to have bypass surgery, it was decided to proceed with angioplasty of the right coronary artery as well as the obtuse marginal. It was felt that the LAD was a small vessel, and not worth going after at this time. The RCA was successfully stented, but was complicated by occlusion of the posterior left ventricular branch. By the end of the procedure, flow had been restored to some degree to the posterior left ventricular branch, but Mr. Potts rule in for a small subendocardial myocardial infarction. Due to the closure of the left posterior ventricular branch, the obtuse marginal branch was not dilated.\nMr. Potts underwent two exercise tests post procedure. The second exercise test was performed with MIBI imaging. He exercised for nine minutes on a submaximal Bruce protocol, and experienced chest pain. He had a maximal blood pressure of 148/72 and a heart rate of 121. MIBI images revealed a small nontransmural myocardial infarction of the basal 1/3 of the inferior wall. There was moderate to severe ischemia of the inferolateral territory in the territory of the RCA.\nGiven these findings, it was highly recommended that Mr. Potts undergo bypass surgery. Mr. Potts was discharged on aspirin, Ticlid 250 mg b.i.d., Atorvastatin 20 mg q.h.s., Atenolol 50 mg b.i.d., Imdur 60 mg q.d. He also takes vitamin E and a multivitamin.", "qa_list": [{"question": "What is this patient\u2019s most recent Zubrod score, relative to the note date?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "When was this score observed?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 50, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04871529", "criterion": "Participants must have a bone scan within 56 days prior to registration if they have bone pain or elevated serum alkaline phosphatase.", "note_date": "2020-12-13", "note": "This is a 67-year-old Caucasian female who presented to our hospital with a chief complaint of persistent bright red blood per rectum. Her medical history was significant for hypertension, hyperlipidemia, diabetes mellitus type 2, coronary artery disease with three prior myocardial infarctions, recurrent cerebrovascular accidents requiring anticoagulation with warfarin, gastroesophageal reflux disease, asthma, and endometrial cancer status post radiation therapy. Fifteen months prior to the current presentation, the patient was noted to have a grade 1 endometrial adenoma but was not considered a good surgical candidate due to multiple comorbidities. Vaginal hysterectomy was considered but due to her long and narrow vagina, this option was deferred initially. Her only treatment option was radiation therapy and brachytherapy. She eventually underwent total abdominal hysterectomy with bilateral salpingo-oopherectomy due to continued pelvic pain. The patient denied any prior history of gastrointestinal (GI) bleeding. Her bleeding was described as one large episode of bright red blood per rectum associated with blood clots. She denied any abdominal pain, nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, constipation, or melena. The most recent colonoscopy was performed four months ago and revealed three diminutive polyps in the transverse colon with pathology confirming tubular adenoma.\nHer physical examination was significant for mild left-sided abdominal tenderness but was otherwise unremarkable. Rectal examination was notable for nonbleeding hemorrhoids and no visible blood. Blood work revealed white blood cells of 14.3k/uL (normal range 4.3-10.0 k/uL) and hemoglobin of 9.6 g/dL (normal range 11.8-14.8 g/dL), which is similar to the patient\u2019s baseline. Creatinine was slightly elevated to 1.2 and blood urea nitrogen was elevated to 39. International normalized ratio was 2.0. Due the large volume of hematochezia and presence of anemia, the patient will be admitted to the hospital and undergo a colonoscopy.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient had a bone scan?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the most recent bone scan performed, relative to the note date?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 49, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04871529", "criterion": "Participants must have a bone scan within 56 days prior to registration if they have bone pain or elevated serum alkaline phosphatase.", "note_date": "2021-08-23", "note": "One week after a positive COVID-19 result, this 57-year-old male was admitted to the ICU because of oxygen desaturation (70%) with worsening tachypnea and dyspnea. Physical therapy started immediately after ICU admission. We found a highly dyspneic patient with a high breathing frequency and significant symptom exacerbation from the slightest effort. With hands-on physical therapy guidance, the patient managed to achieve a 135-degree prone position and to perform deep-breathing exercises resulting in an increase in oxygen saturation from 88% to 96%. Intensive physical therapy and positioning was continued along with 6 to 12 L/min of oxygen therapy over the next days and intubation was avoided. The major challenges in achieving a prone position were the patient's profoundly reduced respiratory capacity and the high risk of exacerbating his symptoms. However, standard ICU monitoring enabled safe implementation at an individually adapted pace to allow sufficient time for convalescence. After 3 days with this regime, he could be transferred to the normal ward, where physical therapists carried on his rehabilitation with walking and strength training. The patient's severe instability remained a challenge. Nevertheless, 9 days after ICU admission, the patient was able to leave the hospital as a pedestrian.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient had a bone scan?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the most recent bone scan performed, relative to the note date?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 40, "trial": "https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04871529", "criterion": "Histologically documented muscle-invasive bladder carcinoma (MIBC) from transurethral resection of bladder tumor (TURBT) within 56 days prior to registration", "note_date": "2021-07-03", "note": "The patient is 68-year-old man with a 6-month history of a pruritic rash that began on his back and legs and spread to his knees, elbows, shoulders, and chest. Patch testing showed 1+ positivity for both sodium laurel sulfate and benzaprene #4, which were deemed not clinically relevant. On examination, he had scattered erythematous scaly patches on the upper chest, shoulders, and back with overlying excoriation. A biopsy of the right shoulder performed 5 months ago  showed an unremarkable epidermis and a sparse perivascular and interstitial mixed infiltrate containing scattered interstitial eosinophils, consistent with a DHR. Oral prednisone initially cleared the rash, but it recurred on discontinuation. The rash was also recalcitrant to trials of topical steroids, oral antihistamines, and topical tacrolimus. I am therefore transitioning him to dupilumab at standard dosing and he will follow up after 3 months.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Does this patient have histologically documented muscle-invasive bladder carcinoma (MIBC) from transurethral resection of bladder tumor (TURBT)?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when was that diagnosis made?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 38, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2019-11-13", "note": "I saw this patient with the resident, Dr. Louvinia Duvall. Please\nsee her note for further details. I confirm that I have\ninterviewed and examined the patient, reviewed the resident's\ndocumentation on the patient's chart, and discussed the\nevaluation, plan of care, and disposition with the patient.\nHISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS: The patient is a 78-year-old male\nwith a history of diabetes, hypertension, atrial fibrillation,\ncongestive heart failure, prostate cancer, chronic renal\ninsufficiency, and Parkinson disease previously hospitalized 2\nweeks prior for right lower extremity cellulitis, which he had a\nPICC line placed, and was discharged to home on vancomycin.\nSince that time, he has had progressively increase in his\ncreatinines despite decreasing doses of vancomycin. He was\nconcerned and requested that the patient to come in for a\npossible acute renal failure secondary to the antibiotic. There\nis also concern that cellulitis had worsened, as the patient was\nexperiencing increasing weakness. He is denying currently any\nfevers, chills, or constitutional symptoms. His baseline\nshortness of breath has been going on for months. No GI\ncomplaints. He has had a mild headache, but no visual changes,\nno focal motor or sensory loss.\nREVIEW OF SYSTEMS: The systems reviewed and found to be negative.\nMEDICATIONS: He has a long list of medications Please see the chart.\nALLERGIES: Morphine.\nSOCIAL HISTORY: Reviewed and found to be noncontributory.\nFAMILY HISTORY: Reviewed and found to be noncontributory.\nPAST SURGICAL HISTORY: Cholecystectomy and bilateral total hip replacement.\nPHYSICAL EXAMINATION: He is awake, alert, nontoxic appearing,\nand in no acute distress. Vital signs reviewed and found to be\nwithin normal limits. Afebrile at 95.6. HEENT exam is\nunremarkable. Mucosal membranes are moist. Neck is supple.\nLungs are clear bilaterally. Heart is regular rate and rhythm,\nno murmurs or gallops. Abdomen: Soft, nondistended, and\nnontender with normoactive bowel sounds. Skin is warm and dry.\nExtremity exam: He has right lower extremity cellulitis with 2\nsmall ulcerations and serosanguineous drainage is minimal. No\nevidence of pus. It is about where it was at the start based on\nthe initial skin markings.\nLABORATORY DATA: Hematocrit of 32. However, his BUN has been\n150 and creatinine of 3. This has significantly increased from\nhis baseline of 1.8-2 he has had in the past. Vancomycin level was sent.\nDIAGNOSIS: Cellulitis with acute renal insufficiency most likely\nsecondary to vancomycin. This was discussed with his primary care provider.\nDISPOSITION: He is admitted to the Medicine Service.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient been diagnosed with MDS or MDS/MPN according to 2016 WHO criteria?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when was the diagnosis made?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 33, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2021-12-28", "note": "This is a 61-year-old, white male with onset of chest pain at 04: 30 this morning, with history of on and off chest discomfort over the past several days. CPK is already over 1000. There is ST elevation in leads II and aVF, as well as a Q wave. The chest pain is now gone, mild residual shortness of breath, no orthopnea. Cardiac monitor shows resolution of ST elevation lead III.\nDESCRIPTION OF PROCEDURE: Following sterile prep and drape of the right groin, installation of 1% Xylocaine anesthesia, the right common femoral artery was percutaneously entered and 6-French sheath inserted. ACT approximately 165 seconds on heparin. Borderline hypotension 250 mL fluid bolus given and nitroglycerin patch removed. Selective left and right coronary injections performed using Judkins coronary catheters with a 6-French pigtail catheter used to obtain left ventricular pressures and left ventriculography. Left pullback pressure. Sheath injection. Hemostasis obtained with a 6-French Angio-Seal device. He tolerated the procedure well and was transported to the Cardiac Step-Down Unit in stable condition.\nHEMODYNAMIC DATA: Left ventricular end diastolic pressure elevated post A-wave at 25 mm of Mercury with no aortic valve systolic gradient on pullback.\nDISCUSSION: Recent inferior myocardial infarction with only minor contrast thinning distal RCA remaining on coronary angiography with resolution of chest pain and ST segment elevation. Left coronary system has one hemodynamically significant stenosis (a 90% ostial stenosis at the first diagonal branch, which is a 2 mm vessel). Left ventricular function is reduced with ejection fraction 40 to 45% with inferior wall motion abnormality.,PLAN:, Medical treatment, including Plavix and nitrates, in addition to beta blocker, aspirin, and aggressive lipid reduction", "qa_list": [{"question": "Is this patient on effective anti-retroviral therapy for HIV?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "Has the patient had an undetectable HIV viral load recently?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, how recent was the diagnosis of an undetectable HIV viral load?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 29, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-01-01", "note": "The patient was a 28-year-old woman, Gravida 2 Parity 1 Live Birth 1, who presented at 38 weeks of gestation with epigastric pain radiating to her back with a history of recent travel and symptoms of subjective fevers with a new sense of smell and taste disorders for 1 week. The patient had received regular prenatal care, and her past obstetric history was uncomplicated, with one full-term vaginal delivery. She was overweight (body mass index = 25.7) and had no significant past medical history and drug history.", "qa_list": [{"question": "does this patient have castration resistant prostate cancer?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "When was the castration resistant prostate cancer diagnosed?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 27, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-12-11", "note": "58-year-old Caucasian (American) male with an unremarkable past medical history presented for evaluation of nausea, vomiting, and a 30-pound weight loss over the past two months at our hospital. He also reported dark-colored urine and intermittent episodes of hemoptysis during the same period. Specifically, he stated that his symptoms started four days after receiving his second dose of the mRNA-1273 (Moderna) vaccine for COVID-19. His first dose taken three weeks earlier was well tolerated. He denied any flank or abdominal pain, melena, fever, cough, hematuria, urinary frequency or urgency, and trauma. He denied smoking. Vital signs were stable upon admission. Physical examination was insignificant for any lower extremity pitting edema, petechiae, or rash. The patient was not on any medication prior to his hospitalization. Laboratory analysis was remarkable for serum creatinine of 4.1 mg/dL (0.8-1.4 mg/dL) along with hematuria and sub-nephrotic proteinuria of 1796 g/24 hours (<150 mg/24 hours). Our differential diagnosis at this point was wide including all nephritic syndromes given AKI, hematuria and proteinuria. All serological workup was subsequently sent. C-ANCA (anti-neutrophil cytoplasmic antibodies) were elevated 160 AU/mL (20-25 AU/mL) and anti-proteinase 3 (anti-PR3) antibodies were also elevated >100 EU/ mL (normal <3.5 EU/mL) (Table ). Immunohistochemical staining for the SARS-CoV-2 spike protein was not performed. All previous routine laboratory parameters including urinalysis were within normal range. He underwent computed tomography (CT) scan of the chest for evaluation of hemoptysis that showed a right upper lobe consolidation and moderate bilateral pleural effusion. The renal ultrasound was unremarkable. Renal biopsy was subsequently performed and showed acute, pauci immune, focal necrotizing, and diffuse crescentic glomerulonephritis (Figures , ). The patient was diagnosed with anti-PR3-associated ANCA glomerulonephritis. He received intense immunosuppression with plasma exchange x 5 cycles, intravenous prednisone 1 gram x 3 doses followed by prednisone 60 mg daily, cyclophosphamide x 2 doses, and rituximab x 4 doses. The patient achieved remission after 10 weeks of diagnosis with a resolution of symptoms and improvement in renal function with a creatinine of 1.5 mg/dl. He is following in our nephrology office regularly since discharge.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Has this patient received external-beam radiotherapy?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}, {"question": "If so, when did the patient receive the external-beam radiotherapy?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 16, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-08-30", "note": "Date of Birth: 1956-12-19 Sex: M\nService: NEUROSURGERY\nAllergies:\nNo Known Allergies / Adverse Drug Reactions\nAttending: Brian Goodman\nChief Complaint:\nleft sided brain lesion\nMajor Surgical or Invasive Procedure:\n2-25 Left Craniotomy for mass resection\nHistory of Present Illness:\nJohn Tex is a 62-year-old left-handed man who is here for a follow up of his left sphenoid meningioma. I last saw him on 2019-11-17 and his head CT showed growth of the left sphenoid meningioma. He is seizure free. Today, he is here with his wife and daughter. Mr. Tex does not have headache, nausea, vomiting, urinary incontinence, or fall. His neurological problem began on 2012-6-22 when he became confused and disoriented in a hotel bathroom. At that time, he was visiting his daughter for a wedding. His wife found him slumped over in the bath tube. According to her, his eyes looked funny. He could not stand up. His verbal output did not make sense. He was brought to the hospital and woke up 7 to 8 hours later in the emergency room. He felt very tired after the event. He was hospitalized from 2012-6-22 to 2012-6-25. He had a cardiac pacemaker placement due to irregular heart rate and bradycardia. He also had a head MRI that showed a less than 1 cm diameter sphenoid meningioma.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Does this patient have bone pain?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
{"id": 5, "trial": "NA", "criterion": "NA", "note_date": "2020-11-05", "note": "A 22-year-old male presented in the emergency department with acute onset of swelling and redness over the right side of the neck and chest wall for the last three days. He had features of septicemia such as drowsiness or Glasgow Coma Scale score of 11/15, respiratory rate of 26 breaths per minute, pulse rate of 130 beats per minute, blood pressure of 84/56 mmHg, and urine output of 15 mL/hour. He had no history of chronic disease, drug reaction, trauma, unknown bite, or significant familial disease. Blood investigations revealed low hemoglobin of 7.6 g/dL, raise leukocyte count of 28000/mm3, low albumin of 2.2 g/dL, raised serum creatinine of 2.23 mg/dL, serum urea of 174 mg/dL, and low sodium of 125 mEq/L. Serological markers including erythrocyte sedimentation rate (95 mm/hour) and procalcitonin (25.2 ng/mL) were higher. X-ray of the chest was grossly normal , and contrast-enhanced computed tomography (CECT) of the neck revealed irregular, well-defined, hypodense, non-enhancing area in the right parotid gland with extension into the neck spaces, larynx, and subcutaneous planes. CECT of the chest revealed mild effusion in bilateral pleural space secondary to acute infection and no evidence of lymphadenopathy or osteomyelitis. Ziehl-Neelsen (ZN) staining from pleural fluid was negative for acid-fast bacillus (AFB bacilli). The patient was managed in the intensive care unit with ventilator support due to acute respiratory distress syndrome. He was diagnosed with acute progressive necrotizing fasciitis with multiple organ dysfunction syndromes due to an unknown cause of septicemia. He underwent multiple aggressive debridements of the neck and chest wall. The cartridge-based nucleic acid amplification test (CBNAAT) and ZN staining revealed positive mycobacteria and AFB bacilli for pathological tissue. Therefore, the pus collected in the parotid region and neck space was likely secondary to tubercular infection. A split-thickness graft was applied in multiple fractions after three weeks of anti-tubercular chemotherapy. The patient had a long hospital stay due to the difficult location and complexity of the ulcer over the neck. He was followed up for six months in good clinical condition after discharge.", "qa_list": [{"question": "Does the patient have a knee osteoarthritis Kellgren-Lawrence grade of 4?", "answer": "NA", "justification": ["NA"]}]}
